<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="28"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.6.            The following basic services are


                        available:


                        S.6.2.  Student Development;

                                        S.6.2.2.  Student Organization


                                                         and Activities;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Student Handbook]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[2.6.   Exercise his rights and in the knowledge that he is answerable for
                                     any  infringement  or  violation  of  the  welfare  and  of  the  rights  of
                                     others
                              2.7.    Strive to lead an upright, virtuous and useful life
                              2.8.   Love, respect, and obey his parents, and cooperate with them to
                                     maintain the family solidarity
                              2.9.   Respect  the  customs  and  traditions  of  our  people,  the  duly
                                     constituted authorities, the laws of the country and the principles
                                     of democracy
                              2.10.  Help  in  the  observance  and  exercise  of  individual  and  social
                                     rights,  the  strengthening  of  freedom  everywhere,  the  fostering  of
                                     cooperation among nations in the pursuit of progress, prosperity
                                     and world peace
                              2.11.  Respect  and  cooperate  with  teachers,  fellow  students  and
                                     university authorities in the attainment and preservation of order
                                     in university and in the society.

                       Section 3. Freedom of Expression and Advocacy

                              Students have the right or freedom of speech, petition and assembly, so
                       long as the exercise thereof is peaceful and does not interfere with, obstruct or
                       disrupt the normal operation of the University and does not violate the rights of
                       others.
                              The  time,  place  and  manner  of  exercising  speech  and  advocacy  on  the
                       campus shall be subject to regulations adopted by the University to minimize
                       any conflict between the exercise and use of University facilities, as well as the
                       possible  interference  with  the  responsibilities  of  the  University  as  an
                       educational institution.
                              Registered  student  organizations  may  invite  speakers  who  do  not come
                       from the University academic community to address meetings or convocations
                       sponsored  by  them  on  campus  with  the  permission  of  the  Dean  of  Student
                       Affairs.  Approval  of  the  invitations  does  not  necessarily  mean  that  the
                       University endorses the views expressed by the resource speaker.

                       Section 4. Student Organizations
                              4.1.   Student organization shall refer to association, club, or any other
                                     organized  groups  of  cultural  and/or  civic  organization  whose
                                     members  are  students  of  the  University.  Those  of  provincial,
                                     sectional,  or  regional  in  character  or  orientation  (e.g.  Ilocano,
                                     Bicolano, Batangueño) are discouraged. Greek letter organizations
                                     such as fraternities and sororities are not allowed.
                              4.2.   A  University-wide  student  organization  shall  be  one  whose
                                     members belong to two or more units. A unit organization shall be
                                     one  whose  members  belong  exclusively  to  only  one  unit  of  the
                                     University and a class organization shall be composed of members
                                     of any class of the University.
                              4.3.   All  University  organizations  (except  those  classified  as  official
                                     performing  arts  group)  shall  be  directly  under  the  supervision  of




                 Excerpts from OSAS Manual (Page 7-19)]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[the  Over-all  Coordinator  of  the  Student  Development  Services  of
                                     the  Office  of  Student  Affairs.  The  official  performing  arts  groups
                                     shall  be  under  the  supervision  of  the  Culture  and  Arts
                                     coordinator.
                              4.4.   Every student organization shall have one or more faculty advisers
                                     recommended by such organizations and approved by the Dean of
                                     Student Affairs. No student organization may hold any meeting or
                                     undertake any activity for any purpose whatsoever, except that of
                                     adopting  a  constitution,  before  its  adviser  or  advisers  are
                                     appointed and have assumed office as such.
                              4.5.   No  student  organization  shall  be  allowed  to  operate  without  a
                                     constitution and by-laws approved by the Dean of Student Affairs.
                              4.6.   No student organization that advocates physical contact as a form
                                     of  initiation  or  trial  for  membership  shall  be  recognized  by  the
                                     University and is, therefore, not allowed to operate on campus or
                                     any other campuses of the University.


                       Section 5. Classification of Student Organizations
                              5.1.   Central Student Government and College Student Council shall be
                                     composed  of  students  enrolled  in  the  collegiate  and  high  school
                                     levels, respectively.
                              5.2.   Unit organization shall be one whose members belong exclusively
                                     to one unit of the College and high school.
                              5.3.   Class organization shall be composed of any class or section in the
                                     college and high school.
                              5.4.   Non-Class Organization shall be made up of   students  who  may
                                     want to join such organizations without compulsion provided said
                                     students are not      included  in  the  delinquency  list.    These
                                     organizations maybe of social, cultural, arts and others of special
                                     concerns in nature.

                     Section 6. Formation of Student Organizations


                              6.1.   Only  bonafide  students  of  CvSU  may  organize.  Any  direct  or
                                     indirect  involvement  of  an  individual  not  connected  with  the
                                     University  in  organizing  or  running  the  student  organization  is
                                     absolutely  prohibited.  However,  DepEd  endorsed  organizations
                                     like YCSC and BSP are exempted.
                              6.2.   A letter of request to organize must be submitted to the Dean of
                                     Student Affairs and Services, with the following requirements:
                                     6.2.1.  Objectives of the organization
                                     6.2.2.  List of prospective members with their signatures, course
                                              and  year,  home  and  campus  address  and  name  of
                                              parents/guardian
                                     6.2.3.  Name  of  at  least  two  (2)  prospective  advisers  who  are
                                              regular  faculty  members  of  CvSU  with  their  signatures
                                              and letters of acceptance]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[6.2.4.  Program/calendar of activities. Activities should be in line
                                              with the objectives of the organization as stipulated in the
                                              constitution of the student organization

                       Section 7. Recognition of Student organizations

                              7.1.   A  newly  formed  organization  shall  be  recognized  on  probation
                                     basis  for at least one (1) semester.
                              7.2.   A duly accomplished application for        recognition   must         be
                                     submitted along with the following requirements:
                                     7.2.1.  Proposed organization’s Constitution and By-Laws signed
                                              by its officers;
                                     7.2.2.  List of members and their signatures;
                                     7.2.3.  List of officers with their signatures, complete  home and
                                              campus  addresses,  year  and  section  and  the  college  to
                                              which they belong;
                                     7.2.4.  Bio-data  and  two  (2)  passport  size  picture    (2x2)  of  the
                                              head of the organization;
                                     7.2.5.  Work plan/Calendar of Activities for the school year with
                                              their corresponding dates. This should include:
                                              7.2.5.1.  Proposed date of activity
                                              7.2.5.2.  Title of activity
                                              7.2.5.3.  Objectives of the activity
                                              7.2.5.4.  Type of activity
                                              7.2.5.5.  Strategies
                                              7.2.5.6.  Target clientele
                                              7.2.5.7.  Resource/budgetary requirements
                                              7.2.5.8.  Expected output
                              7.3.   Existing organizations and those which were on probation in the
                                     previous      semester/year  that  wish  to  continue  must  submit
                                     the following:
                                     7.3.1.  Constitution and By-Laws
                                     7.3.2.  Updated list of members and their signatures;
                                     7.3.3.  Bio-data and two (2) passport size  photos of the head of
                                              the organization;
                                     7.3.4.  Work plan/calendar of activities for the year;
                                     7.3.5.  Letter  of  acceptance  by  at  least  two  regular  faculty  and
                                              staff members of CvSU with their signatures;
                                     7.3.6.  Accomplishment report during the previous year; and
                                     7.3.7.  Audited  financial  statement  (certified  by  the  Board  of
                                              Auditors)

                              7.4.   New and existing organizations including class organizations and
                                     the Central Student Government shall be required to submit their
                                     schedule of activities for the current school year not later than one
                                     and a half (1 ½) months after the opening of classes for the first
                                     semester.  Failure  of  socio-cultural  organizations  to  submit  their
                                     schedule of activities within this period would forfeit their chance]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[of  being  recognized  by  OSA  and  are  therefore  not  allowed  to
                                     operate in the University.
                              7.5.   OSAS shall design and implement an accreditation system for the
                                     recognition  and  operation  of  student  organizations,  including
                                     performing  arts  group.  The  system  shall  be  from  Level  I  to  Level
                                     III, Level III being the highest. Such an accreditation system shall
                                     include  but  not  limited  to:  I)  honors  and  awards  received  by
                                     members individually or as a group; ii) improved GPA of members;
                                     iii)   representation      of    the     University     in     different
                                     contests/training/workshops/domestic  travels  or  overseas,  etc
                                     sponsored  by  outside  agencies;  iv)  records  of  misdemeanor  of
                                     members;  v)  rate  of  attrition  of  members;  and  achievements  of
                                     scheduled activities.
                              7.6.   OSAS shall monitor all student organizations and be subjected to
                                     accreditation  by  the  middle  of  February  of  each  academic  year.
                                     These  organizations  shall  be  required  to  submit  for  review  all
                                     pertinent documents required for accreditation. The accreditation
                                     performance  of  student  organizations  and  the  recommendations
                                     for  their  recognition  or  non-recognition  shall  be  reported  to  the
                                     University President through the OVPAA.
                              7.7.    A  new  student  organization  shall  be  allowed  to  operate  for  one
                                     year  on  probationary  (Level  I)  status.  It  shall  no  longer  be
                                     recognized  the  succeeding  year  if  it  is  unable  to  reach  Level  II
                                     Accreditation.
                              7.8.   An  existing  student  organization  that  is  unable  to  reach  Level  II
                                     status  shall  be  subjected  to  probationary  period  of  at  least  one
                                     school  year.  If  the  same  organization  is  unable  to  reach  Level  II
                                     status  the  succeeding  year,  it  shall  no  longer  be  recognized  and
                                     allowed to operate in the University.
                              7.9.    An existing student organization that is unable to reach Level II
                                     status  may  appeal  to  the  OSAS  for  recognition  in  cases  when
                                     calamities prevented their performance or completion of scheduled
                                     activities  and  other  unforeseen  factors  such  as  leadership  crisis
                                     and  changes  in  activity  priorities  as  demanded  by  the  academic
                                     and social atmosphere in the University.
                              7.10.  The  accreditation  system  shall  not  apply  to  class  organizations
                                     and  the  Central  Student  Government  and  the  federation  of
                                     student governments.  However, these organizations shall also be
                                     required to submit to OSAS a comprehensive list of activities to be
                                     undertaken the whole school year.
                              7.11.  Procedure for Recognition
                                     7.11.1.  Upon  submission  of  the  complete  copy  of  the  needed
                                              requirements  for  newly  formed  organizations,  the
                                              president,  secretary  and  treasurer/representative  of  the
                                              organization  may  confer  with  the  Student  Development
                                              coordinator;
                                     7.11.2.  Organization shall secure and process recognition permit
                                              with  the  necessary  signatures  (Chairman/President,
                                              Secretary, Treasurer, Coordinators, Head of SOSCA, etc.)
                                              at the OSA;]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[7.11.3.  After  securing  the  approval  of  the  Student  development
                                              coordinator,  obtain  the  approval  of  the  Dean  of  Student
                                              Affairs and Services (OSAS);
                                     7.11.4.  Return  to  the  Student  Development  coordinator  and
                                              submit the approved copy of the permit; and
                                     7.11.5.  Secure  the  certificate  of  recognition  from  OSAS  after  the
                                              induction ceremonies.
                              7.12.  Qualifications of Officers
                                     7.12.1.  Must have no failing grades in any subject in the previous
                                              semester and while in office.
                                     7.12.2.  Must not have been involved in any disciplinary case.
                                     7.12.3.  A  student  may  serve  as  an  officer  of  not  more  than  two
                                              organizations;  a  major  position  in  one  (i.e.  President  or
                                              Vice  President),  and  minor  position  in  another  (i.e.
                                              Treasurer or Secretary).
                              7.13.  Responsibilities of Officers
                                     7.13.1.  The  main  duties  and  responsibilities  of  officers  shall  be
                                              those  specified  in  their  respective    organization’s
                                              constitution and  by-laws;
                                     7.13.2.  Consult with SDS/OSAS on matters concerning advisers.
                                     7.13.3.  Must exercise vigilance at all times in the conduct of their
                                              affairs and shall be accountable for  their actions as well
                                              as those of their members; and
                                     7.13.4.  Attend  meetings  as  per  invitation  by  SDS/OSAS  on
                                              organization matters.

                       Section 8. Central Student Government and Student Council

                              8.1.   The Central Student Government (CSG) and the Student   Council
                                     (SC) shall have the following duties:
                                     8.1.1.  develop school spirit and promote general welfare among
                                              the ranks of students;
                                     8.1.2.  organize and direct student activities;
                                     8.1.3.  inform the President through the Dean of Student Affairs
                                              and Services of all the activities of the organization; and
                                     8.1.4.   exercise  such  powers  and  perform  other  such  functions
                                              in accordance with University rules and regulations.

                              8.2.   All matters pertaining to the election of its members and officers
                                     shall be in accordance with the rules and regulations promulgated
                                     by the Committee on Election.
                              8.3.   After the federation of all main and branch campuses, the Student
                                     Government Chairman or President of such federation shall
                                     represent the students in the Administrative and the Academic
                                     Council of the University and shall automatically become the
                                     student representative in the Board of Regents.
                              8.4.   Advisers of Student Organizations are elected by the members of
                                     the organization and nominated to the SDS and then appointed by
                                     the University President upon recommendation of OSAS.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Appointment is issued upon taking the oath.   He/she shall serve
                                     a term of one academic year.
                                     8.5.1.  Qualifications
                                              8.5.1.1.  Must  be  a  regular  member  of  the  University
                                                         faculty and staff;
                                              8.5.1.2.  A  faculty  or  staff  may  serve  as  Coordinator  of
                                                         not  more  than  two    (2)  organizations,  a  Senior
                                                         Adviser of one (1) and Junior of the other; and
                                              8.5.1.3.  Must     not    have    been    involved    in   any
                                                         disciplinary/administrative case.

                                     8.5.2.  Responsibilities
                                              8.5.2.1.  Must  be  actively  involved  in  the  preparation  of
                                                         the  work  plan/program  of  activities  of  the
                                                         organization;
                                              8.5.2.2.  Must  be  present  in  all  approved  activity  of  the
                                                         organization;
                                              8.5.2.3.  Shall    be    a   signatory    in   any    certified
                                                         accomplished activity of the organization;
                                              8.5.2.4.  Must  take  responsibility  for  any  violations
                                                         committed by the organization;
                                              8.5.2.5.  Are    expected     to   refer   to   the   Student
                                                         Development  coordinator  and  Dean  of  Student
                                                         Affairs and Services on any problem; and
                                              8.5.2.6.  Shall perform other tasks as may be required by
                                                         the  Dean  of  Student  Affairs  and  Services  and
                                                         the University President.

                                     8.5.3.  Duties/Functions
                                              8.5.3.1.  Assist/supervise  organizational  unit  in  the
                                                         programming of calendar of activities;
                                              8.5.3.2.  Coordinate  and  monitor  activities  of  the
                                                         organization in the execution/implementation
                                              8.5.3.3.  Monitor/evaluate program of activities;
                                              8.5.3.4.  Conduct/act       as    chaperon     in   seminars,
                                                         symposia,  convocation,  contest,  field  trips  and
                                                         the like;
                                              8.5.3.5.  Act  as  guide  in  the  policy  revisions  of  the
                                                         Constitution and By-Laws;
                                              8.5.3.6.  Act  as  member  of  the  board  of  canvassers
                                                         during election;
                                              8.5.3.7.  Coordinate with the Board of Student Discipline
                                                         in  cases  of  student  misconduct  in  consonance
                                                         with the student norm of conduct
                                              8.5.3.8.  Review and/or edit reports of the organization
                                              8.5.3.9.  Submit  to  the  SDS,  semester  and  annual
                                                         accomplishments of the organization
                                              8.5.3.10.  Encourage/moral  support  to  students  to
                                                         participate in campus  activities
                                              8.5.3.11.  Coordinate with SDS from time to time.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Section 9. Conduct of Activities

                              9.1.   Activities of all student organizations shall require prior approval
                                     of  the  University  President  as  recommended  by  the  Dean  of
                                     Student Affairs and  Services and the VP for Academic  Affairs. In
                                     no case an activity is conducted without prior approval.
                              9.2.   Except  for  the  Central  Student  Government  -  sponsored
                                     convocations,  social  activities  that  would  tend  to  disrupt  the
                                     normal schedule of classes shall no longer be allowed. University
                                     sponsored  programs  are  exempted  from  this  provision.  Any
                                     activity  shall  be  approved  at  least  a  week  before  its
                                     implementation.
                              9.3.   Evening  activities  during  regular  class  days  from  Monday  to
                                     Thursday and on Sunday shall be up to 9pm only. The proposed
                                     activity  should  include  a  security  plan.  Such  security  plan
                                     requires  prior  coordination  and  approval  of  the  Office  of  the
                                     Director for Civil Security Services. Evening activities shall require
                                     parent’s permits using the prescribed OSAS form.
                              9.4.   Off-campus  student  activities  shall  be  discouraged  with  the
                                     exception provided in Section 7f.
                              9.5.   Fund  raising  activities  such  as  raffle,  bingo  socials  and  other
                                     games which will incur contribution or solicitation shall no longer
                                     be allowed. Sale of tickets and promotions from students, faculty
                                     members and staff shall be minimized.
                              9.6.   Activities  including  educational  field  trips  that  would  require
                                     contribution  from  members  exceeding  Php  500.00  shall  not  be
                                     allowed.  The  OSA  shall  set  the  limit  for  such  contribution.
                                     Exceptions  to  this  are  HRM  and  other  skills-oriented  courses.
                                     However,  departments  concerned  shall  be  required  to  submit  to
                                     OVPAA  the  schedule  of  student  activities  and  the  corresponding
                                     estimates  of  expenditures.  Provided  however,  that  the  proposed
                                     educational field trip has been specified in the course analysis of
                                     the teacher concerned.
                              9.7.   Educational  field  trips  of  students  in  the  HRM  and  other  skills-
                                     oriented courses shall require approval from OVPAA and  not the
                                     OSA  but  the  same  permit  form  shall  be  used.  In  the  case  of
                                     branch  campuses,  their  respective  deans  shall  approve  the  HRM
                                     activities.
                              9.8.   Any  student  activity  shall  be  held  with  an  approved  activity
                                     proposal and activity permit. These include the following:
                                     9.8.1.  Fund raising
                                     9.8.2.  Socials
                                     9.8.3.  Services
                                     9.8.4.  Field trips
                                     9.8.5.  Initiation/Induction Rites
                                     9.8.6.  Recruitment, recognition, and orientation of new members
                                     9.8.7.  Convocation, seminar, workshop and symposium
                                     9.8.8.  Organization meeting]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[9.9.   No student activity shall be allowed:
                                     9.9.1.  During class hours (7am-12noon; 1pm-5pm)
                                     9.9.2.  A week before the midterm and final examinations

                              9.10.  Preparing activity proposal
                                     9.10.1.  The  organization  shall  prepare  and  process  its  own
                                              activity permits;
                                     9.10.2.  Secure      the     necessary       signatures      (President,
                                              Advisers/Coordinators,  Department  Chairman,  Dean,  In
                                              charge of the building, etc.);
                                     9.10.3.  Submit  the  activity  permit  to  the  Student  Development
                                              coordinator  at  least  three  (3)  days  before  the  date  of  the
                                              proposed activity;
                                     9.10.4.  After securing the approval of OSAS, submit the approved
                                              Activity Permit to:
                                              9.10.4.1.  Security Office
                                              9.10.4.2.  Person In-charge of the building
                                              9.10.4.3.  Secretary of the organization
                                              9.10.4.4.  Person In-charge of the Hall
                                              9.10.4.5.  Submit a file copy to SD coordinator.
                                     9.10.5.  Permit  may  be  denied  or  withdrawn  whenever  the
                                              circumstances so warrant.


                              9.11.  Certification  of  Activity  Accomplishments/Financial  Report  must
                                     be submitted to SD coordinator within one week after the activity.
                                     Said  certification/report  shall  be  prerequisite  for  the  approval  of
                                     succeeding activity/withdrawal permit.

                       Section10.   Student Funds
                       10.1.  Membership Fees. As provided for in the approved Constitution and By-
                              laws,  each  student  organization  may  collect  a  reasonable  amount  of
                              semestral/annual membership fee from its members, provided however,
                              that every collection shall be correspondingly covered by receipts issued
                              by  the  treasurer  of  the  organization,  and  provided  further  that  any
                              amount  as  may  accrue  to  the  organization,  whether  from  voluntary
                              contribution of the members or otherwise, be properly accounted for.
                       10.2.  Disbursements.  Any disbursements from the funds of the organization
                              shall be effected only upon the approval of its governing board, through a
                              resolution/permit  and  upon  concurrence  of  the  coordinators,  provided
                              however that the actual withdrawal from the depository of such amount,
                              as  may  be  necessary  each  time,  shall  be  made  by  the  head  of  the
                              organization or by its representative, upon his written authorization.
                       10.3.  Depository.  Funds  of  the  organization  must  be  deposited  at  the  bank
                              recommended  by  OSAS  and  VPAA  and  approved  by  the  University
                              President.    Any  amount  from  such  funds  shall  be  released  upon
                              presentation of a resolution/permit.
                       10.4.  Procedure for Withdrawal.
                              10.4.1.  Accomplish  the  form  for  Permit  to  Withdraw  that  includes  the
                                       following:]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[10.4.1.1.  Name of organization
                                       10.4.1.2.  Purpose
                                       10.4.1.3.  Amount involved
                                       10.4.1.4.  Nature of Expenses
                              10.4.2.  Have  it  duly  signed  by  the  treasurer,  chairman/president,  and
                                       adviser/  coordinator,  Student  Development  coordinator  and
                                       Dean of OSAS;
                              10.4.3.  Have the withdrawal slip signed by the SD coordinator, Dean of
                                       OSAS  and  student  representative.  Withdrawal  of  funds  can  be
                                       allowed only if proper voucher record is        properly
                                       accomplished and audited;
                       10.5.  Liquidation of previously withdrawn  fund shall be made  before another
                              withdrawal is granted.
                       10.6.  Book  of  Accounts  shall  be  maintained  by  each  student  organization,
                              which  shall  indicate  all  collections,  disbursements  of  the  organization.
                              The book of accounts shall be open  for inspection during regular office
                              hours by any member of the organization, by the advisers/ coordinators,
                              by OSAS and the Board of Auditors whenever such is warranted.
                       10.7.  On expenditures and Audit
                              10.7.1.  All  treasurers  of  the  organizations  recognized  by  the  Office  of
                                       Student Affairs should submit themselves to auditing.
                              10.7.2.  Auditing  shall  be  done  not  later  than  one  week  after  an
                                       organization has sponsored an affair, incurred expenses and/or
                                       solicited contributions.
                              10.7.3.  Auditing shall be administered by appointment of the treasurers
                                       with the members of the Board of Auditors.
                              10.7.4.  The Board of Auditors shall consist of two regular staff members
                                       of CvSU and one bona fide student of the University who shall be
                                       selected by the Dean of OSAS.
                              10.7.5.  The  treasurer  should  submit  to  the  members  of  the  Board  of
                                       Auditors quadruplicate copies of the detailed expenses incurred
                                       and/or contributions solicited on written or voucher records. In
                                       case  of  contributions,  name  of  contributors  together  with  the
                                       name of the recipient should be presented.
                              10.7.6.  Each  expense  should  be  supported  by  sales  invoice  properly
                                       signed by the dealer of the commodity bought. The sales invoice
                                       number  should  be  correctly  written  in  the  voucher’s  record.
                                       Expenses without any supporting documents will be disallowed.
                              10.7.7.  Receipts of incidental expenses should be duly signed by the one
                                       who spent the amount, properly authenticated and approved by
                                       the  treasurer,  the  auditor  and the  advisers/coordinators  of  the
                                       organization.
                              10.7.8.  All  voucher  records  should  be  signed  by  the  treasurer  and
                                       approved by all members of the Board of Auditors, and Head of
                                       SOSCA.
                              10.7.9.  Every financial accountability should be settled one week before
                                       the semester ends.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Section 11.   Guidelines for the Management of CSG Funds (BOR no 49 s. 2014
                       dated September 18, 2014)

                       11.1.  CSG Fee of Php 200 inclusive of Php 50 for student handbook shall be
                              collected  to  support  the  offering  of  acceptable  and  reasonable  student
                              services  that  will  tap  the  full  potentials  of  the  students  and  ultimately
                              equip students with well- defined skills and competencies.
                       11.2.  Specifically, the CSG Fund shall be used to support:
                              11.2.1.  Student publication
                              11.2.2.  Cultural and Literary activities
                              11.2.3.  Student and Leadership development
                              11.2.4.  Subsidies and allowances
                              11.2.5.  Mutual aid and benefits
                              11.2.6.  Insurances
                              11.2.7.  Student Organizations’ activities and facility improvement
                       11.3.  Collection of CSG fee shall be on a  semestral basis. Collection shall be
                              facilitated  by  CSG  Officers  under  the  strict  supervision  of  OSAS.  The
                              collected fees for every semester shall be managed by CSG officers under
                              the strict monitoring of OSAS.
                       11.4.  After the collection period, a detailed financial and work plan of student
                              organizations shall  be prepared under the supervision of the respective
                              advisers. Careful analysis on the relevance, need and urgency of student
                              activities shall be implemented in the allocation and utilization of funds
                              for the specific semester.
                       11.5.  The student organizations’ work and financial plan shall be consolidated
                              and reviewed by the Dean of the Office of Student Affairs and Services for
                              endorsement  to  the  Academic  and  Administrative  council  and  for  final
                              approval of the BOR.
                       11.6.  The CSG financial and work plan must form part of the OSAS financial
                              and work plan which must be approved by the University President.
                       11.7.  Recognized organizations can avail the CSG fund provided the activity or
                              items  being  requested  are  supported  by  approved  proposal  and
                              resolution  duly  adopted  by  the  concerned  student  organization.  The
                              proposed activity should be included in the approved work and financial
                              plan.
                       11.8.   A  report  of  expenditures  supported  by  receipts  and  proof  of  purchase
                              shall  be  submitted  a  week  after  the  completion  of  the  funded  activity.
                              This shall undergo auditing which shall be conducted by members of the
                              Board  of  Auditors,  duly  designated  by  the  University  President  as
                              recommended by the OSAS Dean and VPAA.
                       11.9.  Should savings be realized, this shall be allocated as reserve fund which
                              shall be utilized subject to approval of additional relevant expenditures to
                              specifically support the welfare and development of students.

                       Section 12.   Guidelines  for  the  Management  of  Funds  of  All  Recognized
                       Student Organizations

                       12.1.  All recognized student organizations with funds exceeding one thousand
                              pesos  (P  1,000.00)  are  required  to  open  a  bank  account  subject  to
                              existing bank regulations .]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[12.2.  The treasurer of the organization shall be responsible for the safe keeping
                              of the bankbook of the organization during regular school days. However,
                              all  treasurers  are  required  to  deposit  the  PASSBOOK  at  OSAS  during
                              semestral breaks and/or vacation or in cases where the treasurer stops
                              schooling or take a leave of absence of more than one  (1) week (this  is
                              aside  from  the  financial  reports  required from  each  organization  at  the
                              end of each semester).
                       12.3.  All  forms  of  deposits  or  withdrawals  from  the  bank  accounts  of  the
                              organization  shall  be  made  by  the  Chairman  or  Treasurer  of  the
                              organization who shall sign the deposit or withdrawal slips with the SD
                              coordinator and the Dean of OSAS. For this purpose, the Chairman and
                              Treasurer of each organization shall submit to the bank the name of the
                              President/Chairman  and  Treasurer  with  his/her  signature  (3  specimen
                              signatures) at the beginning of the school year or immediately after the
                              new set of officers are elected by the organization.
                       12.4.  The  Treasurer  of  each  organization  shall  keep an  updated  record of  all
                              deposits/withdrawals,  income/expenditure  of  the  organization.  OSAS
                              has the right to conduct auditing procedures anytime it feels necessary
                              in  which  case  the  Treasurer  shall  surrender  to  the  Board  of  Auditors
                              including the passbook upon receipt of a written notice from them.
                       12.5.  The  organization  has  the  sole  right  to  spend  its  funds  in  whatever
                              manner  it  feels  necessary.  However,  each  organization  is  required  to
                              retain or leave behind at least twenty five percent (25%) of its total funds
                              in their Bank Accounts for use as seed money for the next set of officers
                              and members.

                       Section 13.  Non-recognition and Suspension of Organization/Activities

                       13.1.  Grounds for non-recognition/or suspension:
                              13.1.1.  Non-compliance of requirements
                              13.1.2.  Lack of worthwhile projects based on point system
                              13.1.3.  Failure to submit required reports (Financial/Accomplishments)
                              13.1.4.  Preventive suspension for violations of policies may be imposed
                                       pending decision   of the investigating body.

                       13.2.  In case of violation of any policies on organization of other college rules,
                              the following procedures shall be affected:
                              13.2.1.  Upon receipt of the violation report, the Dean of OSAS shall call
                                       the  officers  and  other  concerned  members  of  the  said
                                       organization for a fact finding meeting.
                              13.2.2.  If  the  case  warrants  punishments  beyond  admonition  or
                                       reprimand,  the  Dean  of  OSAS  shall  forward his  findings  to  the
                                       Preliminary Investigating Committee.

                      Section 14.    Privileges of recognized organizations
                       14.1.  Only fully recognized organization may:
                              14.1.1.  Use the facilities of the University such as classrooms, grounds,
                                       lights, etc. with approval from proper authority;
                              14.1.2.  Participate in inter-organizational activities/competitions;]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14.1.3.  Compete for awards;
                              14.1.4.  Officially bear the name of the University when engaging in off-
                                       campus activities;
                              14.1.5.  Have  their  organizational  activities  publicized  in  any  credited
                                       student publication.
                       14.2.  Organizations  on  probation  can  only  avail  of  certain  privileges  as
                              specified below:
                              14.2.1.  Shall avail only of privileges 13.1.1 and 13.1.2
                              14.2.2.  Shall avail only privileges 13.1.1, 13.1.2 and 13.1.5

                       Section 15. Incentives/Awards

                       15.1.  Five  (5)  best  student  organizations  shall  be  selected  at  the  end  of  the
                              school  year.  The  Accreditation  criteria  shall  be  used  in  the  selection.
                              Trophies shall be awarded to the winners.
                       15.2.  An outstanding student leader shall likewise be chosen. A committee for
                              this  purpose  shall  be  formed  by  OSAS  to  draft  selection  criteria  and
                              select the recipient. The winner shall receive a plaque of recognition.

                       Section 16. Prohibited Activities
                       16.1.  Any student activity that is subversive in nature and one which incites
                              insurgency  including  those  against  the  existing  University  Rules  and
                              regulations  is  strictly  prohibited  and  disallowed.  Hazing  and  inflicting
                              any form of physical injury are strictly prohibited.
                       16.2.  The  violator/s  as  well  as  the  officers  of  the  student  organization
                              including  the  faculty  coordinator  if  warranted  by  the  circumstances  of
                              each  case  shall  be  held  administratively  liable  for  the  illegal  activity  of
                              the organization without prejudices to criminal prosecution.
                       16.3.  In  addition  to  the  revocation  of  the  authority  to  operate,  the  student
                              organization may be reprimanded, suspended or dropped from the roll of
                              the school or expelled from the University depending on the seriousness
                              of the offense committed.


                       Section 17. Convocations, Fora and Concerts

                              Any recognized organization of the University may sponsor convocations,
                       fora and concerts provided that a written proposal to this effect is approved by
                       the Dean of Student Affairs.

                              Any  person  from  within  the  University  or  outside  the  University  may
                       speak before student groups or University Organizations subject to provision of
                       Par. 3, Section 2 above.


                       Section 18. Student Publication
                       18.1.  There shall be a student publication which shall be the official organ of
                              the students of the University anchored on the principle of freedom of the
                              press.  The  mission  orientation,  goals  and  objectives  of  the  student]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[publication  should  aim  to  support  the  University  in  its  quest  for
                              educational  excellence  particularly  in  the  improvement  of  instruction,
                              promotion  of  research  and  involvement  in  meaningful  activities  of  the
                              community.
                       18.2.  Aims  and  Purposes  of  Student  Publication  (please  refer  to  the
                              Implementing Rules and Regulations of RA 7079 otherwise known as the
                              “Campus Journalism Act”).
                       18.3.  Furthermore, the student publication should exercise its leadership and
                              influence to foster and enhance the attainment of the goals for national
                              development.
                       18.4.  The     editor-in-chief,   associate     editor,    section     editors    and
                              business/circulation  manager  are  the  senior  staff  members  of  the
                              student publication.
                       18.5.  The  reporters,  art/layout  staff,  typists,  among  others,  composed  the
                              support  personnel  of  the  publication  who  shall  assist  the  senior  staff
                              members in the performance of their official functions.
                       18.6.  The  Editor-in-Chief  shall  be  selected  during  the  first  two  months  after
                              the  beginning  of  classes  for  the  first  semester/term  through  a  written
                              examination and evaluation by the selection committee.
                       18.7.  The selection of Editor-in-Chief and other members of the staff of tertiary
                              student publication shall be through competitive examinations prepared,
                              conducted  and  supervised  by  the  selection  committee  composed  of  a
                              representative  of  the  school  administration,  one  faculty  member,  one
                              mass  media  practitioner  who  is  acceptable  to  both  (School
                              Administration and Editorial Board) and two past editors to be chosen by
                              the  outgoing  editorial  board.  Secondary  and  Elementary  student
                              publication staffers should pass a qualifying examination conducted by a
                              committee composed of the student publication adviser, who shall act as
                              chairperson,  the  past  student-editor  as  vice-chairman,  one  (1)  faculty
                              member  and  two  (2)  former  student-editors.  (Adopted  from  Campus
                              Journalism Act RA 7079 Rule 7)
                       18.8.  In  the  event  of  vacancy  in  the  position  of Editor-in-Chief  by  reasons  of
                              illness, transfer, removal from office, resignation and/or similar causes,
                              the same shall be filled immediately according to the next-in-rank rule.
                              The new Editor–in-Chief shall serve the remaining term within the school
                              year.
                       18.9.  Student writers are required to maintain a grade point average of 2.25 or
                              better  with  no  dropped  subjects  or  failing  grades  (BOR  Res.  No.  84  s.
                              2006 dated Sept. 14, 2006).
                       18.10. The  members  of  the  editorial  board  and  staff  receive  honoraria  every
                              semester. Senior staff members are also given Service Scholarships.

               Article 7. Institutional Student Services
                       Section 1. Admission Services
                       Section 2. Scholarship and Financial Assistance
                       2.1.   The Scholarship and Financial  Assistance Services Unit of the Office of
                              Student Affairs and Services shall be responsible for the implementation
                              of the University Student Financial Assistance Program.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Student Organizations’ By Laws]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                      Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                    (046) 414-3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                        FUTURE ADMINISTRATORS, MANAGERS AND EXECUTIVES (FAME) Society

                                             CONSTITUTION AND BY- LAWS

                                                       PREAMBLE

                    We, the members of the FAME Society, in order to promote and encourage interest in the field
                of business management, do ordain and establish this constitution for ethical and good governance
                of our organization.



                                                       ARTICLE 1

                               NAME, LOCATION AND NATURE OF THE ORGANIZATION

               Section 1:

                       Name: FUTURE ADMINISTRATORS, MANAGERS AND EXECUTIVES (FAME) SOCIETY

               Section 2:

                       Location:  FAME  Society  is  a  duly  recognized  academic  organization  located  at  CAVITE
                                  STATE  UNIVERSITY  (CvSU)  –  Tanza  Campus,  Phase  2  Pabahay  Katuparan,
                                  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite.

               Section 3:

                        Nature of the organization: FAME Society is an academic, non-stock, non-profit and student
                 organization. The purpose of this organization is to create chances for students to interact, learn, and
                 lead, allowing them to pursue their passions, and interests alongside other students while gaining
                 leadership  and  organizational  abilities.  No  part  of  its  income  shall  insure  to  the  benefit  of  or  be
                 distributed as dividends to its members, trustees, or officers. Any profit which the organization may
                 obtain as an incident to its operation shall, whenever necessary or proper, be used for the furtherance
                 of the purpose for which it has been organized.


                                                           ARTICLE II

                                           VISION, MISSION, GOALS AND OBJECTIVES

               Section 1:

                       Vision:  To  become  professional  individuals  develop  by  time  spent  in  the  organization  by
                       furthering  the  professional  development  of  students  through  leadership  training  and
                       involvement  in  the  field  of  Business  Management  such  as  entrepreneurial  development,
                       marketing  management,  marketing  and  business  researches  and  plan,  finance, human
                       resources, technology, and operations.

                       Mission: A professional student organization, by furthering the professional development of
                       students on leadership training and development activities through academic excellence and
                       participation in national training and conferences, and membership to marketing organizations.]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Section 2:

                       Goals:  To  promote  academic  excellence,  leadership  training  and  conferences,  encourage
                       students  to  be  members  of  different  marketing  organization.  Nurture  the  students  through
                       training and seminars related to their chosen profession. To establish the best organization for
                       the benefit of management students of CvSU – Tanza Campus. The students should be able
                       to advance their leadership and management skills, and serves as a good example to fellow
                       students.

                       Objectives: In addition to, and in support of its mission and vision, incorporated in this by  -
                       laws, the organization should be able to:
                       1.  build high performing organization with critical teamwork and camaraderie;
                       2.  develop the leadership skills, creativity, and innovativeness of the members;
                       3.  extend utmost help and support to each member of the organization;
                       4.  conduct activities that will enhance the marketing and entrepreneurial skills of the business
                          management students; and
                       5.  increase community outreach.

               Section 3:
















               The logo reflect and represent the organization’s vision, mission, and objectives. The logo is in a circle
                shape which means unity and commitment. The name and the year of the organization were formed
                and printed in the logo.

               Psychologically, the blue color in the logo is associated with trust, honesty, and dependability, and
                hence important for business people to attract and retain customers. The organization wants to build
                high performing organization with critical teamwork.

               The  yellow  color  represents  creativity  and  innovativeness  that  embodies  the  talent  of  business
                management  students  to  find  new  ways  of  doing  things  and  they  are  practical  thinkers,  not  just
                dreamers.  The organization conducts activities that will enhance the marketing and entrepreneurial
                skills of the business management students.

               The handshake represents deals, agreements,  and  promises  with  respect  to  others'  presence  that
                creates peace.  The organization aims to extend the utmost help and support to each member of the
                organization and create relationships and networks with different business professional organizations
                in the Philippines.

               The growth chart represents the success and achievement of members in every step they take in their
                academic and professional careers. It also represents the continuous development of the organization
                itself.

               The  globe  represents  the  broad  range  of  what  business  and  business  management  students  can
                achieve. As part of Cavite State University, members of the organization aim to be globally competitive.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[The puzzle pieces combined together represent the connection of every symbol in the logo and the
                relationship of diverse, creative, and innovative members of the organization.


                                                           ARTICLE III

                                             MEMBERSHIP AND RESPONSIBILITIES

               Section 1:

                       FAME Society shall accept members only if they are: (1) bona fide students of Cavite State
                       University (CvSU) Tanza Campus; and (2) if they are taking up Bachelor of Science in Business
                       Management.


               Section 2:

                       Responsibilities  of  FAME  Society  Members:  Members  shall  have  the  following
                       responsibilities:

                       3.1   Regularly attend sessions, gatherings, and functions requiring their presence.
                       3.2   Abide the constitution and by-laws of the organization.
                       3.3  Participate in all the activities of the organization.


               Section 3:
                       Rights of Active Members in Good Standing: Every active member in good standing shall
                       have  the  following  rights  and  privileges.  A  member  in  good  standing  means  he/she  is
                       participative in all activities, practice social responsibility, and accountability, and is achieving
                       academic excellence.

                       4.1    Attend all meetings, regular and special, of the general assembly of the organization;
                              to speak threat, subject to reasonable rules of order; and to vote therein on any matter
                              properly brought before the meeting of the members of the organization for any purpose
                              whatsoever, voting by proxy shall not be allowed.
                       4.2    Vote in the election of FAME Society;
                       4.3    Be voted as an officer of FAME Society, provided, the member to be nominated has no
                              failing grades on their courses/subjects;

                       4.4    Avail all the benefits that the organization will offer to its members;
                       4.5    Attend training and seminars are related to their field and priority in assistance given
                              by the organization.
                       4.6    Renew membership subject to the rules set by the organization and decisions carried
                              by the organization.


               Section 6:
                       Non-Transferability of Membership in the Organization: Membership in the organization and
                       all rights and privileges arising therefrom, are personal and non-transferable.

               Section 7:

                       Suspension,  Expulsion,  and  Termination:  Suspension,  expulsion,  and  termination  of
                       membership shall be after due notice for conduct in convention of the objectives or otherwise
                       detrimental to the interest of the organization.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[An active member in good standing may be fined if he/she violated the organization’s rules
                       regarding  wearing  of  corporate  attire,  absences  set  by  the  organization  or  has  received
                       suspension as disciplinary measure as affirmed by the majority of the officers.

                       Any member of the organization may file charges against a member by filing a written complaint
                       addressed to the President.

                       Membership may be terminated voluntarily by the resignation of the member, or compulsorily
                       by the action of the majority of the officers as provided in the above preceding paragraph.


                                                        ARTICLE IV

                                                 ELECTION OF OFFICERS
               Section 1:

                       Nomination and election of officers of FAME Society shall be held at the end of the second
                semester of an academic year.

               Section 2:

                       Electoral process for FAME Society Officers shall follow these guidelines:

                       2.1    All members will be gathered to participate in the CvSU-Tanza Campus FAME Society
                              Officers election or there should be at least a quorum or half number plus one of the
                              total number of members of the organization present.
                       2.2    The current President shall lead the nomination and election of the new President.
                              Members shall vote for their candidate by raising their right hand. A candidate with the
                              greatest number of votes shall be declared as the newly-elected President for the next
                              academic year.
                       2.3    The newly elected President shall be in charge of the nomination and election of the
                              remaining positions.

                       2.4    Absent voters will not be given any chance of being nominated and elected.


               Section 3:

                       Election by appointment is a careful joint election that shall be  made by the FAME Society
                       Officers with the presence of the adviser/s for special task positions in accordance to the ability
                       and qualifications of the member to be appointed as officer.
               Section 4:


                       Appointment and replacement are different. It shall mean that when an officer is grounded
                       for termination, no more election produce shall take place. Instead, a replacement of a qualified
                       active  member  in  good  standing  passing  the  qualifications  shall  be in  power  replacing  the
                       terminated one.




                                                           ARTICLE V

                                                    FAME SOCIETY CAMPUS

                                                           OFFICERS

               Section 1:

                       The elected campus officers of FAME Society will be serving the organization for a term of  one]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[(1) academic year.

               Section 2:

                       Qualifications: Members who will be elected in any position should be a recognized member
                       of the organization, active, responsible and respectable that has undergone training related to
                       leadership, capable of handling and motivating co-leaders and members; and a God-dependent
                       individual. He/she should not have any failing grades for the courses/subjects he/she has taken.


               Section 3:

                       A  member  passing  the  qualifications  and  has  been  elected  to  any  of  the  position  shall
                       automatically become certified and must consider these guidelines:


                       3.1    Required attendance to meetings and sessions related to position, and does all his/her
                              responsibilities up to the expiration of his/her term.

                       3.2    Required to live a good example and uphold FAME Society ideals.

                       3.3    Required to lead and actively participate in all functions and activities called upon by
                              the organization requiring his/her presence.


                                                       ARTICLE VI

                                 FUNCTIONS AND POWERS OF FAME SOCIETY OFFICERS


               Section 1:
                       President


                      1.1. The one who prepares agenda, calls and presides over all the meetings of the FAME
                           Society.
                       1.2. He/she is the one who represents the FAME Society in all the meetings inside and outside
                           the campus.
                       1.3. He/she is the one who signs all important correspondences, legal documents and contracts
                           of the organization.
                       1.4.  Shall  represent  the  organization  in  all  its  affairs  wherein  it  has  interest  and  whatever
                           function to which it may be deemed invited to participate.
                       1.5.  Delegate  different  tasks  to  the  officers/members  of  the  organization  especially  during
                           events/ activities.
                       1.6. Assign working committees in every event/activity conducted by the organization
                       1.7. Preside in decision making in case of disputes, termination, appointment and other matters
                           related to the organization

               Section 2:

                       Vice President:

                       2.1. Shall coordinate the activities of different operating committees to prevent overlapping of
                           functions and ensure efficiency and success in all undertakings.
                       2.2. Shall perform his/her duties, exercise the powers and discharge the responsibilities of the
                           President in his/her absence or temporary incapacity.
                       2.3. Assist the president in all of his/her duties.
                       2.4. Assure that all responsibilities assigned by the President to each officer and member is
                           properly done.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Section 3:

                       Secretary

                       3.1 Keeps and takes care of all the documents of the FAME Society.
                       3.2 Sends sufficiently in advance notices of general and special meetings to all officers and
                           members of the organization.
                       3.3 Makes letters for any activity/meeting that the organization needs.
                       3.4 Keeps minutes of meetings.
                       3.5 Documents all activities/meetings done by the organization.
                       3.6 Submits and compiles all pertinent documents needed for renewal of the organization to
                           the OSAS or for any other purposes.
             Section 4:

                       Assistant Secretary

                       4.1 Assists the secretary in all his/her duties and responsibilities
                       4.2 In case the secretary cannot do his/her duties, the assistant secretary will perform the same.

             Section 5:

                       Treasurer:

                      5.1 In charge of safekeeping the fund, receipts, and disbursements of FAME Society.
                      5.2 Keep all money and other valuables of the organization.
                      5.3 The one who keep and have charge of the book of accounts and have custody of its financial
                           and other related records
                      5.4  The  one  who  creates  and  submit  financial  statements/reports  every  after  any  activity
                           sponsored by the organization.
                      5.5  Ensure  that  all  transactions  are  properly  recorded  5.6  Ensure  the  confidentiality  of  all
                           financial information.
                      5.7 Assists the business manager in managing the financial transactions in all the businesses
                           of the organization.
                      5.8 Assists the business manager in buying necessary resources for the businesses of the
                          organization.
             Section 6:

                       Auditor:
                       6.1 Reviews all contracts within 7 days from signing (sponsorship, rentals, major purchase sales
                          of assets, and others.)
                       6.2 Reviews receipts and disbursement of the organization every month.
                       6.3 Verifies all approvals of disbursement whether they are official and authorized.
                       6.4 Checks completeness of all receipts received by the organization
                       6.5 Checks all entries on the financial statement of the organization.

             Section 7:

                       Business Manager:


                       7.1 In-charge of generation and development of all resources of FAME Society.
                       7.2 In charge of managing the business of the FAME Society.
                       7.3 Take charge of marketing its business activities.
                       7.4 Keeps records of all business-related activities.
                       7.5 Remits all records and cash received to the treasurer every end of semester.

             Section 8:]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Public Relation Officer (P.R.O)

                       8.1 Disseminates information that are only about the organization’s meetings, activities, events
                          and other important announcements.
                       8.2 Conducts activities and promotes the organization to the campus and initiates programs
                          that will advertise its projects.
                       8.3 Make sure that all incoming activities, projects and programs of the organization are well
                          promoted to the members.
                       8.4 In charge of making and maintaining a social media page for dissemination of information
                          related to FAME Society only.
             Section 9:

                       Representatives

                       9.1 Assist the PRO in all its duties and responsibilities.
                       9.2 Every representative is in charge of accepting concerns, complaints, suggestions
                          and recommendations from their jurisdiction and relaying it to the officers of the
                          organization.
                       9.3 Resolve minor disputes under his/her jurisdiction. In case of major disputes, he/she
                          should consult the officers in a meeting.



                                                        ARTICLE VII
                                                ORGANIZATION MEETINGS
             Section 1:

                       Regular  Meetings:  Regular  meetings  of  the  members  of  the  organization  presided  by the
                       officers shall be held once a month. Meetings of officers shall be held twice a month.


             Section 2:

                       Special Meetings: Special meetings of the officers may be held at any time upon the call of
                       the FAME Society President, adviser/s or at least three (3) officers. Notice of the special
                       meetings, stating the date, time and place should be provided by the Secretary or Assistant
                       Secretary. Any and all matters within its competence may be taken up at the regular meetings
                       of the officers.

             Section 3:

                       Quorum: Half number of the members plus one constitutes a quorum shall be required in every
                       decision of at least a majority of the Officers present at a meeting at which a quorum is valid as
                       a corporate act, except for the election of officers of the organization, which requires the vote
                       of a majority of all FAME Society Officers. Members who cannot attend cannot vote proxy.



                                                          ARTICLE VIII

                                      DISCIPLINE OF FAME SOCIETY OFFICERS AND MEMBERS

             Section 1:

                       It shall be the policy of the FAME Society to require its officers and members to perform their
                       duties in the highest degree of responsibility, integrity, loyalty and efficiency. It shall be required
                       that the members of the organization abide in its existing rules, regulations and policies. Any
                       violation shall lead to imposition of disciplinary action compulsorily by action of the officers as
                       provided in the above preceding sections.]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Section 2:

                       Fines and/or Disciplinary Actions: The following fines and/or disciplinary actions shall be
                       observed by all the members of the organizations and should properly be implemented by the
                       officers.



                      2.1 If a member fails to attend a meeting or participate in any activity without valid reasons,
                           he/she shall pay Php50.00. If a member will be absent in three (3) consecutive meetings
                           and did not participate in the activities, he/she will be terminated from his/her membership
                           in the organization.
             Section 3:

                       Reinstatement: The officer facing disciplinary actions shall have no right to vote in any of the
                       disciplinary proceedings but can requests reinstatement if he/she wishes to return to position,
                       provided that he/she should explain and justify his/her side with affirmative vote of two-thirds
                       (2/3) of the officers, he/she can be reinstated back into office. A terminated member who wishes
                       to be a member again should explain and justify his/her side to the officers and will conduct
                       community  service  with  proper  implementation  and  observance  from  the  officers  of  the
                       organization.


                                                       ARTICLE IX


                                                   AMENDMENTS AND
                                                      EFFECTIVITY

             Section 1:

                       Amendments: These by laws, or any provision thereof, may be amended or replaced by a
                       majority vote of the members or by all officers agreed by their adviser/s at any regular or special
                       meeting duly held for the purpose.
             Section 2:

                       Effectivity: This constitution and by-laws shall take effect immediately upon its ratification by a
               majority of the votes cast by the members duly called its purpose.






                                               AIRA ANGELLA P. ABEJAR
                                                        President




                                                  JESSICA P. RAMOS
                                                      Vice President




                                                 ISHA MAE V. OLANOSA
                                                        Secretary]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[FLORENZ MAE DEONAN
                                                   Assistant Secretary



                                                ANGELIE V. DELA PEÑA
                                                        Treasurer


                                                CHRISTINE A. ANCHETA
                                                         Auditor


                                                   ROBIN S. OLORIS
                                                    Business Manager



                                                 IRISH JOY G. BRIGOLI
                                                  Public Relations Officer




                                                 CHRISTIAN B. REYLLO
                                             First year – Section 1 Representative





                                                 MIKAELA ROSE A. DEO
                                             First year – Section 2 Representative



                                             HARBHEE CLYDE B. MALINAO
                                             First year – Section 3 Representative




                                                AILA JEMIMAH J. SAGUID
                                             First year – Section 4 Representative





                                                   KIMBERLY ANDAYA
                                           Third year – Section 1 Representative





                                              STRAWBERRY JOY BURATA
                                           Third year – Section 2 Representative]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Noted:

                    DEBBIE ROSE B. FABIAN                              JOHNNY RICK S. APELLANES
                    Adviser                                            Junior Adviser

             Recommending Approval:


                    MELONA I. SAQUIN                                   RITCH M. BANATE
                    Coordinator, OSAS                                  Department Chairperson

             Approved:


                    GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                    Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Approved Plan of Activities]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                    Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                        FUTURE ADMINISTRATORS, MANAGERS AND EXECUTIVES SOCIETY

                                              CALENDAR OF ACTIVITIES

                                                    A.Y. 2022 - 2023
                                    MONTH                          ACTIVITIES


                         November           Entreneurship Seminar
                                            FAME Society Annual Christmas Caroling
                         December           #FAMEShares: FAMESKONG HANDOG 2021

                                            From Art we Make Expressions
                                            (FAME) Society LOGO MAKING CONTEST
                         January            “FAME-Uno”
                                            FAME Top Student of the 1st Semester
                         February           Leadership Seminar
                         March              “FAME Muse & FAME Escort”
                                            Mr. and Ms. FAME 2023
                         April              Entreneurship Seminar


                         May                Tree Planting Project
                                            #Let’sGrowTogether
                         June               “FAME-Uno”
                                            2ND SEM FAME TOP STUDENT

               Prepared by:

               ISHA MAE V. OLANOSA
               FAME, Secretary


               AIRA ANGELLA P. ABEJAR

               FAME, President

               Noted:

               DEBBIE ROSE B. FABIAN                                     JOHNNY RICK S. APELLANES
               FAME, Adviser                                             FAME, Adviser



               Recommending Approval:                                    Approved:

               MELONA I. SAQUIN                                          GIL D. RAMOS
               Head, OSAS                                                Campus Administrator]]></page></pages></Search>