<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="60"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.8.            Instruction is enriched through, at least


                        10 of the following strategies:


                        I.8.2.  projects;]]></page><page Index="2"/><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Individual Projects]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Creation of Lesson Plan]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CvSU Vision                      Republic of the Philippines              CvSU Mission
                                                                                        Cavite State University shall
               The       premier               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY              provide excellent, equitable and
            university  in  historic                   Tanza Campus                 relevant educational opportunities
            Cavite  recognized  for                                                 in  the  arts,  science  and
            excellence  in   the                   Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite            technology  through  quality
            development of globally                   (046) 414-3979               instruction and relevant research
            competitive and morally                  www.cvsu.edu.ph                and development activities.
            upright individuals.                                                        It shall produce professional,
                                                                                    skilled  and  morally  upright
                                                                                    individuals  for    global
                                                                                    competitiveness.


                                            Semi-Detailed Lesson Plan



               I. LEARNING OBJECTIVES
                At the end of the discussion, the students will be able to:
                    1. Differentiate verbal from nonverbal communication,
                    2. Identify the different types of nonverbal communication, and;

                    3. Communicate effectively by using proper verbal and nonverbal cues.


               II. SUBJECT MATTER
               Lesson: Verbal and Nonverbal Communication
               Reference: Flores, R. S. (2016). Oral Communication in Context. Rex Bookstore.
               Materials: laptop, projector, PowerPoint presentation, and printed instructional
               materials



               III. PRIMING
               A. Preliminaries
                       Greetings
                       Prayer

                       Attendance
               B. Motivational Activity | Previous Lesson Recall - Process of Communication
                       The class will be grouped into three. Each group will think of a scenario where process of
                        communication is taking place. They can choose representatives to portray the scenario in
                        front. The rest of the students will identify the elements of the process of communication in
                        the scenarios given.


               IV. ANALYSIS

               1. What did you learn from the previous lesson?
               2. How is it important to be an effective communicator?


               V. ABSTRACTION
                       From the student’s different viewpoints, the teacher will explain how important it is to know
                        the elements of communication and everything you say and do means something.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Oftentimes, misunderstanding occurs when the message perceived is different from the
                        intended message. To prevent such, we will talk about verbal and nonverbal cues.
                       Differentiate verbal from nonverbal communication.
                              VERBAL COMMUNICATION - means sharing things by means of

                                                       words, whether spoken or written.
                              NONVERBAL COMMUNICATION - is communication without
                                                      words,only visual cues.
                       Introduction of different types of verbal communication: oral and written
                       Introduction of different types of nonverbal communication:
                       a. Facial expressions – The principal source of feedback.
                       b. Eye contact – The most expressive element in face-to-face communication.

                       c. Body movements & posture – The way you stand and hold your body also
                                     sends messages.
                       d. Gestures – The movement that you make with a part of your body,
                       especially your hands.
                       e. Haptics – also known as “touching”.
                       f. Proxemics – refers to the amount of space that individuals naturally

                       maintain between each other which communicates meanings.
                       g. Voice – The way in which a message is spoken is as important as what is
                       said.


               VI. APPLICATION
                       The class will be divided into four groups. Each group will be required to have a short
                        scenario to be performed in front. Of course, before coming up with the performance,there

                        must be a script. The script should contain verbal and nonverbal cues. For example: “Girl:
                        Yes! (nodding)”
                       It is up to the group leaders how they will divide the tasks. As long as all of the members will
                        participate, a script will be produced, and a short role play will be performed. The rubrics will
                        be given by the teacher.



               VII. GENERALIZATION
                       To make sure that the lesson is learned, the teacher will call students to answer and
                        complete these statements:
                                                  “I have learned that…”
                          “Knowing verbal and nonverbal communication is important because…”


                VIII. ASSESSMENT

               The class will be divided into four groups. Each assigned leader will pick a random task (see below).
               Each group will be given 10 minutes to prepare before presenting their output in front of their
               classmates. The rubrics will be given by the teacher.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Tasks (Draw lots):
               1. Create a jingle about the importance of verbal and non-verbal cues.
               2. Create a short skit about misunderstandings when the message perceived is different from the

               intended message.
               3. Present a speech choir about the importance of verbal and non-verbal cues.
               4. Craft a slogan about verbal and non-verbal communication and explain your concept in front of the
               class.


               IX. ASSIGNMENT

                   Do an advanced reading on “Effective Communication Skills” and prepare for a graded recitation.




               Prepared by:                                                        Checked by:


               Marie Russel Daquila Martin                                                Ivory Mojica, LPT
                        Student                                                               Instructor]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[MODEL LESSON PLAN

               Name: Vanessa H. Rosas


               Section: Bsem 3-1

               Subject: Mathematics

               Topic: Solids

               Reference: Mathematics Learner’s Module 7




               General Objective: Student will:

               1. Know the terms vertices, faces and edges

               2. Understand the relation between vertices, faces and edges

               3. Build the Euler's relationship

               4. Apply the Euler's relationship to solve the problems

               Approach: Contructivist (5e Model)


               Method: Activity Base

               TLM: Different type of solids like cube, regular tetrahedron and A4 shits.



               TIME     STEPS       TEACHERS ACTIVITIES                STUDENTS ACTIVITIES        TLM


               20 min   Engage      Make five groups of students and   Identifies how many        Cubiod
                                    distribute cuboids, cubes, regular   vertices, faces and edges.
                                    tetrahedrons, and A4 shits. Then                              Cube
                                    students ask to find out how many   Find a connection among
                                    vertices, faces, and edges they have   the faces, edges       Regular
                                                                                                  tetrahedron
                                    and whether there is a connection   andvertices.
                                    between the faces, edges, and      Complete the work with     A4 shits
                                    vertices. Then they compare with   teacher and peer help.
                                    other groups and come to a
                                    conclusion.

               5 min    Explore     Helps student to complete the task.   Note down their         A4 shits
                                                                       observation.
                                    Ask students to exchange their
                                                                       Find how many vertices,]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[objects and do the same thing again.  faces and edges and find a
                                                                       connection among the
                                                                       faces, edges and vertices.




               10 min   Explain     Listen to students' findings from   Each student group
                                    each group and ask them to explain   representative explains
                                    whether there is a relation between   and justifies their findings
                                    c and d. Also provides explanation   to the teacher as needed.
                                    and justification where ever needed.


               20 min   Elaborate   Relates c/d to π. Introduce the c   Take the diameter as
                                    formulae c = πd.                   d=7cm, and use the
                                                                       formulae c = πd.
                                    Find the circumference of a circle
                                    with the diameter of 7cm.

               5 min    Evaluate    Students work evaluated.           Solves problem on it.



               Home Assignment:

               1. Find the circumference of the circle which has the radius 3.5cm.


               2. If the circumference is 220cm find the diameter of that circle.



               Closure/Reflection:]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[MODEL LESSON PLAN

               Name of the School: Tanza National Trade School                                 Name of teacher: Maria Angela A. Capuz

               Class: VII                                                                      Subject: Mathematics

               Average age: 13+ yrs                                                            Unit :


               No. of students: 40                                                             Topic : Law of Exponent

               Duration: 50 mins                                                               Name of the book : Mathematics – Grade 7 Teacher’s Guide

               Date: 01/12/2021                                                                Publisher : Department of Education




               Concept Mapping:










                     (n times)                              product of a power                    law for zero exponent
                                                                                                   0
                      n
                     a = a • a • a • a • a.…                a • a = a m+n                         a = 1
                                                                 m
                                                             n
                                                                                quotient of a power                      law for negative exponent
                                           power of powers                       a n                                     a n
                                             n m
                                           (a ) = a nm                           a m  = a n-m                             a m    = a n-m]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[MODEL LESSON PLAN

 Name of the School: Tanza National Trade School  Name of teacher: Maria Angela A. Capuz

 Class: VII  Subject: Mathematics

 Average age: 13+ yrs  Unit :


 No. of students: 40  Topic : Law of Exponent

 Duration: 50 mins  Name of the book : Mathematics – Grade 7 Teacher’s Guide

 Date: 01/12/2021  Publisher : Department of Education




 Concept Mapping:










 (n times)  product of a power  law for zero exponent
               0
 n
 a = a • a • a • a • a.…  a • a = a m+n  a = 1
 m
 n
 quotient of a power                law for negative exponent
 power of powers  a n                a n
 n m
 (a ) = a nm  a m  = a n-m            a m    = a n-m]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[General Objective: Student will:

               1. Know the term Exponent.

                                              n
               2. Understand the meaning of a where n is a positive integer.
               3. Apply the law of exponents to solve problems.


               4. Analyze word problems to the answer from a given conditions.

               5. Evaluate among law of exponent.

               Approach: Constructivist (5E Model)

               Method: Demonstration cum Explanation, Problem Solving

               Technique: Activity based

               TLM:Power Point Presentation]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[General Objective: Student will:

 1. Know the term Exponent.

 n
 2. Understand the meaning of a where n is a positive integer.
 3. Apply the law of exponents to solve problems.


 4. Analyze word problems to the answer from a given conditions.

 5. Evaluate among law of exponent.

 Approach: Constructivist (5E Model)

 Method: Demonstration cum Explanation, Problem Solving

 Technique: Activity based

 TLM:Power Point Presentation]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[TIME         STEPS                   TEACHERS ACTIVITIES                          STUDENTS ACTIVITIES                      TLM

                                           The teacher will flash a fill in the box activity on

                                           the google meet. The activity will direct students They think and construct their own    Activity will flash on


                                           to fill the boxes with correct letters to complete the understanding about exponent.     Google    meet    using

               5 min         Engage        word. The letters consist of problems related to                                         Power             Point

                                           the law of exponent.                                                                     Presentation

                                           ACTIVITY                                           Students will complete the activity.

                                           T 3x3 =                                            .

                                               1
                                           O 8 =
                                           X 2*2*2*2*2*2*2 =
                                           E (5)(5)(5) =

                                                2
                                           N 10 =
                                           E 1 =
                                               0
                                           P 6*6*6*6*6 =

                                           N 4x4x4x4x4x4 =




                                            15   128   7776   8   4096    1    100    9]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[TIME  STEPS  TEACHERS ACTIVITIES  STUDENTS ACTIVITIES   TLM

 The teacher will flash a fill in the box activity on

 the google meet. The activity will direct students They think and construct their own  Activity will flash on


 to fill the boxes with correct letters to complete the understanding about exponent.  Google  meet  using

 5 min  Engage  word. The letters consist of problems related to  Power  Point

 the law of exponent.                           Presentation

 ACTIVITY  Students will complete the activity.

 T 3x3 =  .

 1
 O 8 =
 X 2*2*2*2*2*2*2 =
 E (5)(5)(5) =

 2
 N 10 =
 E 1 =
 0
 P 6*6*6*6*6 =

 N 4x4x4x4x4x4 =




 15  128  7776  8  4096  1  100  9]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Findings:

               6 min           Explore     Guides student to complete the task.                E   X    P    O   N    E   N    T

                                                                                               15  128 7776  8  4096  1   100  9

                                           Listens to the explanation of the students about Students explain of their findings in

                                           their findings, ask students to justify where ever each letter and justifies where ever

                                           necessary and give feedback. Also, provides necessary.

               10 min          Explain     explanation and justification where ever needed

                                           about the lesson connected to the activity.


                                           Introduces the other law of exponent and solve

                                           problem. Then, students are asked to elaborate Students justify their observation,

                                           on:                                                learns new concepts, definition of

               20 min                                                                         terms,  other   law  of   exponents

                             Elaborate                                                        and solves problems.






                                           1. Did you notice something?


                                           2. What can you conclude about



                                           3. What will you do with a, n and m?]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Findings:

 6 min  Explore  Guides student to complete the task.  E  X  P  O  N  E  N  T

           15  128 7776  8  4096  1   100  9

 Listens to the explanation of the students about Students explain of their findings in

 their findings, ask students to justify where ever each letter and justifies where ever

 necessary and give feedback. Also, provides necessary.

 10 min  Explain  explanation and justification where ever needed

 about the lesson connected to the activity.


 Introduces the other law of exponent and solve

 problem. Then, students are asked to elaborate Students justify their observation,

 on:      learns new concepts, definition of

 20 min   terms,  other   law  of   exponents

 Elaborate  and solves problems.






 1. Did you notice something?


 2. What can you conclude about



 3. What will you do with a, n and m?]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[6 min          Evaluate     Students’ responses and answers are checked.




               Home Assignment:Create a graphic organizer of the law of exponent using canva, ppt or any editing application. Show your creativity and enjoy.


               Closure/Reflection:]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[6 min  Evaluate  Students’ responses and answers are checked.




 Home Assignment:Create a graphic organizer of the law of exponent using canva, ppt or any editing application. Show your creativity and enjoy.


 Closure/Reflection:]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Demonstration Teaching


                            Solving Quadratic Equation]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[BSEM 22
                                             College and Advanced Algebra
                                                          Project

               Objective: Students should be able to discuss quadratic equations and how to solve them.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Screenshots from the video discussion and PowerPoint presentation of Ms. Ruth Ann
                                                  Tubid from BSEM 1-1.]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Screenshots from the video discussion and PowerPoint presentation of Ms. Daisy Mae
                                                Mendoza from BSEM 1-2.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Creating of Mind Map]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[BSEM 40


                                                                                                 Assessment and Evaluation in Mathematics



                                    Name                     :         Ma. Woodelyn P. Reyes                                            Output no. 1             :              Mind Map



                                    Year & Section :                   BSEM 3-1                                                         Date of Submission :                    March 12, 2021




                                    Complete the mind map on the 21st century assessment by filling the main characteristics in the big circles and the sub-


                                    points in the smaller circles. You may add smaller circles, if necessary.





                                                                          Feedback

                                                                         is targeted

                                                                         to the goal
                                                                               and

                                                                          outcome.                                                                                Assessment


                                                                                                                                                                   need to be
                                                                                                                                                                  adaptable to

                                           Visible                                                                                                                   students’                           21st century

                                           performance-based                                                                                                         settings.                           approaches

                                           work (as a result of                                         1. RESPONSIVE                                                                                       are more
                                           assessment)                                                                                                                                                      versatile.

                                           generates data that

                                           inform curriculum
                                           and instruction.

                                                                                                                                                                         2. FLEXIBLE






                            is part of a
                        comprehensive                                                                                                                                                       Your text goes here

                       and well-aligned

                           assessment                                                                                                                                                                                        Assessments are

                               system
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      to be

                                                                                                                                                                                                                             incorporated into
                                                                    8. SYSTEMATIC                                                                                                                                                 day-to-day

                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    practice.


                                                                                                                                  ST
                    balanced and                                                                                                21 CENTURY                                           3. INTEGRATED

                    inclusive of all                                                                                            ASSESSMENT
                        students,

                  constituents, and

                     stakeholders
                                                       designed to

                                                          support

                                                 improvement at all
                                                           levels





                                                                                                                                                                           4. INFORMATIVE

                                                                                                                                                                                                                               goals and

                                                                                                                                                                                                                            objectives are

                                                                                                                                                                                                                            clearly stated
                                                                                                                                                                                                                             and explicitly

                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  taught.

                                            7. TECHNICALLY
                                                  SOUND








                                                                        Your text goes here
                                                                                                   6. COMMUNICATED


                                                                                                                                                                 5. MULTIPLE

                                                                                                                                                                   METHODS






                         Adjustments and                                                                                                                                                                    Authentic and
                      accommodations are                                                                                                                                                                    performance-

                             made in the                                                                                                                                                                          based

                       assessment process                                                                                                                                                                   assessment is

                     to meet the students’                                                                                                                                                                   emphasized.
                       needs and fairness.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Comic Strip]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Logo Making]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY


                                                     Tanza campus
                                                    Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite


               Subject: CvSU101: INSTITUTIONAL ORIENTATION
               Name: SEPARA, MARC LORENZ C.
               Course: BSEM 1 - 1
               Professor: MR. FAHAD GOTE
               Date: OCTOBER 4, 2021


               I. OBA #4: ILLUSTRATE A LOGO
               DIRECTIONS: Draw and illustrate your suggested new Cavite State University logo.


                                                                                     THIS CADUCEUS
                       THE STARS REPRESENTS
                       THE EXCELLENCE OF THE                                        REPRESENTS THE
                            UNIVERSITY                                            MEDICAL COURSES IN
                                                                                    THE UNIVERSITY.


                 THIS SYMBOL                                                              THIS HAND REPRESENTS
                REPRESENTS THE                                                             THE SOCIAL RELATED
                 AGRICULTURAL                                                                COURSES IN THE
               THRUSTS OF CAVITE                                                               UNIVERSITY.

















                                                                                            THIS GEAR REPRESENTS
                                                                                             THE TECHNOLOGICAL
               THE FIRE REPRESENTS                                                            AND ENGINEERING
               BURNING PRIDE AND                                                              COURSES OF THE
                 WISDOM OF THE
                   UNIVERSITY                                                                    UNIVERSITY


                    THIS ATOMIC
                     STRUCTURE                                                          THE THREE SHADES OF
                   REPRESENTS THE                     THE YEAR WHEN OUR                GREEN REPRESENTS THE
                    UNDERTAKING                      UNVERSITY START THEIR             THREE CORE VALUES OF
                  RESEARCH OF THE                     HUMBLE BEGINNING                    THE UNIVERSITY
                     UNIVERSITY.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Group Projects]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Poster Making]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[GROUP 1                                                      Roles of School                                                                                                     1      Socialization





                                                         2     Preservation and Promotion of Culture








          5    Civic Training




                                                                                                                                                  3       Transmission of culture and values





                                              4         Social Agreeableness






        6       Promotion of Democratic Values




                                                                                                      9      Character Building                                        7
                                                                                                                                                                             Development of Activities








              8       Fullfilment of National Aims

















                                                                                10         Propagation of Civilization and Culture



                                                                                                                                                                                   12         Social Control









    11       Development of Personality














                                                                                                  13       Social Integration














   14         Determination of Status






                                                          15       Provides Route for Social Mobility                                                                        16        Social Development



























                          Functions of School                                                                                                                                           Internatonal







                                                                                        Cultural




    Technical

















                                                                                                                                                         Social                                            Political






                                             Economic                                                   Human]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Story Telling]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[The Most Important Question









                 The Kingdom
                                                                      Once upon a time there was a
                 of the Prince

                                                                      prince who always want what’s
                                                                       best for his Kingdom. He get
                                                                       this being perfectionist to his

                                                                      late Mother Queen. He always
                                                                        looking for an answer to his
                                                                      exceptional question. One day,
                                                                      a bright and unusual question

                                                                     came to his mind but he did not
                                                                          know the answer. So he
                                                                        decided to give a reward to

                                                                      those who will answer his one

                                                                          important question. The
                                                                        question is what is the right
                                                                       thing to do and when was the

                                                                                  right time?]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[But then again others
                                                                       said there were some
                                                                      things which could not
                                                                       wait to be laid before,
          After hearing the announcement of the Prince, the gre  at    but about which one
          men of every kingdom came to give their answers. They        had at once to decide

         answered the question differently. The first man replied that   whether to undertake
          to know the right time to take an action, you must plan it       them or not.

         ahead of time, one must draw up in advance, and must live
         strictly according to it. Only thus, said he, could everyth  ing
            be done at its proper time and the right thing to do as

           well.  Others declared that it was impossible to decide                                 In order to decide
           beforehand the right time for every action; but that, not                                that, one must

          letting oneself be absorbed in idle pastimes, one should                                 know beforehand

          always attend to all that was going on, and then do what                                what was going to
                                                                                                   happen. It is only
        was most needful. Some, again, said that however attentive                                  magicians who

        the Prince might be to what was going on, it was impossible                                 know that; and,
           for one man to decide correctly the right time for every                               therefore, in order

          action and the right decision to make, but that he should                                to know the right

          have a council of wise men, who would help him to fix the                                 time for every
                         proper time for everything                                                action, the prince

                                                                                                     must consult
                                                                                                      magicians






                                                                           The Prince was not satisfied with
                                                                            the answers of the learned and

                                                                           intelligent men. He did not agree
                                                                              with any of those incredible
                                                                           answers. But still he is not giving

                                                                           up that someone will answer this
                                                                             very important question. One
                                                                           day a little boy came to him and
                                                                           told him that he has an old friend

                                                                             in the forest who is witty and
                                                                               wise and he knows all the
                                                                             answers to all questions. His

                                                                            Majesty did not waste time and
                                                                             he hurriedly went to the forest
                                                                             together with his guard but he
                                                                           left his guards at the opening of

                                                                             the forest so that the old man
                                                                              would not be frightened and
                                                                                  answer his question.]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[When the Prince reached the hut of the old wise man he saw the latter fixing something on his fence. He
          went pounding and pounding and he noticed that the old man was exhausted and tired as a horse carrying a
           bunch of load. When the old man noticed the Prince, he greeted him and gave respect and asked him what

           he can do for the Prince and what made him go to that forest. The Prince replied” a little boy recommended
          a witty and wise man who answers all the questions.” The old wise smiled and continued his repair. What is

          that most important question that made you decide to go into this peculiar and freaky forest? The Prince saw
               the weakness of the man so he took the hammer   to the latter and he continued pounding and said.


            It came to my mind that to be the
          best Prince, what was the right thing
           to do and when was the right time?

















             The old wise man answered in figurative words “you are now

           doing the right thing at the right time, you have been answered.”

          The Prince furrowed his brow and was confused. He said, what do
           you mean and how was it answered while you were not? The old,

                        weak, frail, wise man smiled and replied,





                                                                                         The moment you decided to help

                                                                                          me without hesitation that you
                                                                                          might be get dirty and the fact

                                                                                         that you are a Prince doing this
                                                                                         kind of thing is the right decision
                                                                                        and thing to do, and the right time
                                                                                        was the time you decided to help.
                                                                                           Being a Prince, the will and
                                                                                         enthusiasm to help regardless of
                                                                                         the status and ability to pay back
               The Prince left the                                                        with no hesitation and regrets
                                                                                         and the sacrifices are the “most
             forest very happy and                                                       right thing” in this world and from
             ordered his council to                                                      the moment you decided to help
                                                                                        was the “most right time”. You will
             make the old man one                                                           be the best Prince in your
                                                                                                   Kingdom.
               of his advisers.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Prepared by:

                                                  Cedillo, Aubrey


                                                Gambala, Haydee


                                                 Zabala, Romulo

                                                      BSEE 2-1




                                                   Presented to:


                                             Mr. Audreyson Borilla

                                 BSEE 32 – Children and Adolescent



                                                      Literature]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Time Line]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[DEVELOPMENT OF CHILDREN’S



                                     LITERATURE AND ADOLESCENT]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[(Ancient Greece and Rome)


                                                    Oral         literature        was        the       principal
                                                      entertainment for most people during this

                                                      period.
                                                    Purpose            of      storytelling           was        for

                                                      entertainment,  comfort,  instruction  for


                                                      young  in  living  and  to  pass  on  their
                                                      religious and cultural heritage.
                                                    Kept ancient stories alive.
                                                    Children  and  adults  shared  a  common

                                                      literature.
                                                    No distinction between adult and children

                                                      literature.

                                                    GREEK STORIES (500 BCE):


                                               -Trojan  War  (from  Homer’s  Iliad),  Travels  of
                                               Odysseus (from Homer’s Odyssey, Jason and
                                               the  Golden  Fleece  and  adventures  of
                                               Hercules.


                                               -  Aesop’s  Fables:  animal  tale  with  moral  to
                                               instruct  children  and  cultural  and  personal

                                               values.]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[ ROMAN STORIES (100 CE)

                                              -Tales  of  Virgil’s  Aeneid,  (Stories  of  Aeneas,
                                              Trojan  hero  credited  for  founding  the  Roman


                                              race.
                                              -Tales  of  Ovid’s  Metamorphose,  (tales  of  gods,

                                              goddesses, heroes, and heroines of the classical
                                              world.


                                                   MODERN  RETELLING  OF  GREEKS  AND
                                                     ROMAN STORIES

                                              -Most famous are Padraic Colum’s, The Children

                                              of Homers, The Golden Fleece, etc.

                                              -Bulfinch’s Mythology (Thomas Bulfinch)


                                               age of Fables, stories of gods and heroes.]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[(Between the fall of Rome and


                                                           The Rise of the Renaissance)


                                                   Roman  Catholic  Church  dominated  the
                                                     social  and  political  scene;  responsible  for

                                                     what education there was.



                                                   Religious Tales

                                              -Biblical  stories  were  very  popular;  the  lives  of

                                              saints  were  used  to  set  example  for  young
                                              people in didactic purpose.


                                                   Romantic Tales

                                              -Secular stories (Medieval  Romances) were also
                                              popular  such  as  King  Arthur  and  his  knights  in

                                              the  round  table,  The  epic  describing  the heroes
                                              Roland etc.]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[ Children’s version for these tales

                                                  -Rosemary Sutcliff’s Dragon Slayer- a retelling

                                                       of Beowulf and her King Arthur stories:

                                                  “Sword and Circle”, “Light beyond the forest”,

                                                                      “Road to Camlann”
                                                   -Bulfinch’s Mythology (By Thomas Bulfinch)


                                                       Beowulf; Children’s Bible stories, God’s
                                                                      Stories for Children.]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[(A time for a Rebirth of the ideals of ancient

                                                                     Greece and Rome)


                                                    The rise of Education books.


                                                    During this period printing press were


                                                      invented which made it possible to make
                                                      multiple copies of books, invented by

                                                      Johannes Gutenberg.

                                               -during the early Renaissance most books for

                                               children were textbooks or educational books.
                                               “Books of courtesy” giving lesson in proper
                                               behavior for young gentlemen.


                                               -Woman’s did not yet merit their own books.

                                                     -Orbis Sensualism Pictus by John

                                                       Comenius (1658)
                                                       -The first children’s picture book.
                                                          st
                                                       -1  appeared in German/Latin Version
                                                       (1658)
                                                          nd
                                                       -2  as an English/Latin Version (1659)]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[ Two specific influence needs of the child.
                                                     -Spiritual Development

                                                     -Intellectual Development


                                                   New England Primer

                                                     - The most famous early school books,


                                                         first appearing around 1690. It introduced
                                                         young puritan children to the alphabet
                                                         through rhymes, reading material, and all
                                                         religious intent.

                                                   Chapbooks
                                                     - Small and cheaply made books
                                                         containing fairy tales and other secular

                                                         books.

                                              -Thought’s concerning Education, famous essay
                                              written by John Locke, He believed every child

                                              had equal capabilities to learn and adult had the
                                              responsibility to provide proper education.


                                                   Children continue to adopt certain adult
                                                     works of literature.
                                                   Some famous work were retold and

                                                     rewritten from time to time in various
                                                     versions for children.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[ Publishing of Children’s books

                                                        -began notably  by John Newberry (1713-
                                                        1778)

                                                        -books  were  largely  collections  of  story

                                                        and  poems  with  Crude  woodblock

                                                        illustrations.

                                                      A Little Pretty Pocket Book (1744)
                                                        -One  of  the  first  published  children’s

                                                        books  to  entertain  children  and  teach
                                                        them.
                                                      Rousseau and Moral Tale
                                                        -Rise of Moralistic tales

                                                        -express  his  ideas  in  education  and
                                                        emphasize  the  importance  of  moral
                                                        development.

                                                        -Rousseau  followers  wrote  didactic  and
                                                        moralistic books to teach children.
                                                        Most writers were woman]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[ Folktales  from  old  tradition  revived
                                                       during this time.

                                                     Tales of Mother Goose

                                                       -retold  and  published  by  the  Frenchman
                                                       Charles Parrault (1697)

                                                       -usually retold for moral purpose.

                                                     Tales from the Arabian Nights
                                                       -published  by  Elizabeth  Newberry  (1791)
                                                       first  children  edition  of  the  Middle

                                                       Eastern tales.
                                                     Han’s  Christian  Anderson’s  Fairy  Tales
                                                       (1835,  Denmark)  considered  the  first
                                                       book containing modern fairy tales.]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[ During        the  reign  of  Queen  Victoria  (1837-
                                                     1901)
                                                     -Children’s literature first blossomed




                                                   Rise of Modern Fantasy
                                                     -Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland (1865) by
                                                     Lewis Carroll (England)
                                                     Beginning a new era in Children’s literature.


                                                     -The Adventures of Pinocchio (1883) by Carlo
                                                     Collodi’s (Italy)

                                                     Most famous puppet story.

                                                     -The Wonderful Wizard of Oz (1900) by Frank
                                                     Baum (U.S)

                                                     The  first  classic  U.S  modern  fantasy  for
                                                     children’s.]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[-The  Tale  of  Peter  Rabbit  (1901)  by
                                                          Beatrix Potter.
                                                          Early         important           modern            picture

                                                          storybook in English.

                                                        Rise of Realistic Stories


                                                          -Little  Woman  (1868)  by  Louisa  May
                                                          Alcott (U.S).
                                                          Early  family  story  of  great  popularity

                                                          (girl’s story)

                                                          -Treasure Island (1881) by Robert Louis

                                                          Stevenson (England).
                                                          Famous classic adventures story (Boy’s
                                                          story)]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[ Children’s  literature  began  to  flourish  on  a
                                                   variety of fronts.

                                                Theme is focused on children themselves.

                                                Fantasy stories and realistic fiction has been

                                                   popular.



                                               - Winnie the Pooh (1926) by A.A. Milne (U.K).
                                                   Early classic personified by toy animal story.


                                               - Little  house  in the  big wood (1932) by  Laura
                                                   Ingalls Wilder (U.S).
                                                   Classic historical fiction based in the authors’

                                                   childhood.

                                                Popularity  of  the  publication  of  picture
                                                   storybooks.

                                                Popularity  of  fantasy  stories  and  series
                                                   books.]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[- The  lion,  the  witch,  and  the  wardrobe


                                                        (1950) and sequels by C.S Lewis.
                                                        Early classic quest adventure for children



                                                     - Charlotte’s Web (1952) by E. B. White.
                                                        Classic U.S animal fantasy



                                                             Rise of new realism (After world war
                                                               II)
                                                             A  variety  of  cultures  presented  in

                                                               Children’s books
                                                             Emergence  of  awards  for  children’s
                                                               books         (the       earliest       one        was
                                                               Newberry Medal in 1922. U.S)

                                                             Study  of  children’s  literature  began
                                                                                                        th
                                                               in the last quarter of the 20  century.]]></page></pages></Search>
