<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="16"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.2.  Retirement, separation or termination


                    benefits are implemented in accordance

                    with institutional and government (CSC,


                    GSIS/DBM) policies and guidelines.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  53


                              as all other citizens and is subject to the same responsibilities as
                              well.

                          d)  No  teaching  personnel  in  the  University  shall  inculcate  certain
                              tenets  in  any  of  his  teaching,  nor  use  his  position  directly  or
                              indirectly to influence students or attendance at the University for
                              or  against  any  particular  church  or  religious  sect,  ideology,  or
                              political party under penalty of dismissal by the Board of  Regents.

                          e)  If  the  conduct  of  a  teacher  in  his  classroom  or  elsewhere  should
                            give  rise  to  doubts  concerning  his  fitness  for  his  position,  the
                            question  shall  in  all  cases  be    submitted  first  to  an  Investigation
                            Committee  of  the  faculty  appointed  by  the  President  of  the
                            University and in no case shall any member of the teaching staff be
                            dismissed  before  the  normal  termination  of  his  period  of
                            appointment without full and open hearing by the Board of Regents
                            should he desire it, and only upon sufficient notice.

                          f) The University shall assume no responsibility for views expressed by
                            members  of  its  staff;  that  the  faculty  members  themselves  shall
                            make clear that they are expressing their personal opinion.

                   Article  7.  Resignation  and  Transfer.  No  resignation  by  a  faculty  or
                       employee shall take sooner than 30 days after the same shall have been
                       filed,  submitted  in  writing  to  the  President  through  channels,  unless
                       sooner approved by the President.

                          The Acceptance of Resignation in writing by the University President
                       which  should  indicate  the  date  of  effectivity  of  resignation  shall  be
                       submitted to the CSC office concerned for record purposes.

                          A  faculty  or  employee  under  administrative  investigation  may  be
                       allowed  to  resign  pending  decision  of  his/her  case  but  it  shall  be
                       without  prejudice  to  the  filing  of  any  administrative/  criminal  case
                       against him / her for any act committed while still in the service.

                   Article  8.  Fellowships.  The  University  shall  formulate  policies  and
                       guidelines  for  faculty  and  staff  fellowships,  which  may  be  revised  from
                       time to time as the need arises. The full text of the current guidelines for
                       faculty and staff development in this manual.







                                                                                                           53]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  68


                   Article 18. Insurance and Retirement. The University shall participate in
                       the  Government  Service  Insurance  System  (GSIS).  However,  the
                       University may augment funds for its faculty and employees by means of
                       an equitable schedule in the renewals and benefits available under the
                       Government Service Insurance System.

                          The  following  shall  be  followed  for  the  insurance  and  retirement  of
                       faculty and employees of the Universities:

                          a)            In  case  of  leave  of  absence  without  pay  of  members  of  the
                          faculty and other personnel of the University, the University shall pay
                          the government share in the life insurance premium corresponding to
                          the  first  year  of  leave.  There-after,  the  person  concerned  except  in
                          meritorious  cases  shall  pay  both  the  personnel  and  the  government
                          share;

                           b)     Retired members of the academic and non-academic staff shall
                          enjoy library privileges and shall receive free of charge publications of
                          the  University.  They  may  also  be  entitled  to  such  other  privileges,
                          which the University is in a position to grant in accordance with the
                          law  and  they  shall  be  invited  to  participate  in  major  University
                          programs and activities;

                           c)   A retired faculty member with the rank of full professor may be
                          appointed Professor Emeritus subject to the following conditions:

                                    1.  He  must  have  rendered  at  least  20  years  of  active  and
                                 faithful service to the University.

                                     2.  He  must  achieve  marked  distinction  as  a  productive
                                 scholar,  scientist,  and  artist  or  is  widely  acknowledged  as  an
                                 effective and dedicated professor.

                                 A  special  committee  constituted  by  the  President  of  the
                          University,  among  members  of  the  faculty  in  active  duty  shall  be
                          responsible  for  evaluating  nominations  of  retired  professors  for
                          emeritus      appointment.        The     committee       shall     submit      its
                          recommendation (s) through the President to the Board of Regents for
                          approval.








                                                                                                           68]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  77


                          Section 5.  Appeals from the decision of the proper authorities affecting
                                         administrative staff shall likewise be in accordance with the
                                         rules and regulations promulgated by the Board of Regents
                                         within the limits prescribed by the existing Civil Service rules
                                         and regulation.

                   Article 34. Benefits under the GSIS Act of 1997 (8291). Republic Act (RA)
                                 8291 revised the 20-year old charter of the GSIS, P.D. 1146 to
                                 expand and increase the coverage and benefits of the GSIS; and
                                 introduce institutional reforms for the GSIS to have more flexibility
                                 and thus perform its mission of providing social security protection
                                 more effectively.  This RA took effect on 24 June 1997.

                          Section  1.     All  laws  or  parts  of  laws  specifically  inconsistent  with  RA
                                         8291  were  repealed  or  modified  accordingly,  provided  that
                                         the rights under existing laws, rules and regulations vested
                                         upon  or  acquired  by  an  employee  who  is  already  in  the
                                         service as of the effectivity of this Act shall remain in force
                                         and  effect.  The  affected  laws  include:  1)  P.D  1146;  2)  R.A
                                         660; and 3) R.A. 1616.

                          Section 2. Membership to the GSIS shall be compulsory for all receiving
                                         compensation, irrespective of employment status, which has
                                         not  reached  the  compulsory  retirement  age  at  the  time  of
                                         election or appointment.

                              All  members  of  the  GSIS  shall  be  covered  with  life  insurance  and
                          social  security  protection  including  retirement,  disability,  survivorship,
                          separation  and  unemployment  benefits,  and  such  other  benefits  and
                          protection  as  may  be  extended  to  them  by  the  GSIS,  subject  to  the
                          limitations provided by law.

                          Section 3.   The benefits under RA 8291 can be availed of by an eligible
                                         member in the event of the following contingency occurring
                                         on or after 24 June  1997:

                                a) Retirement
                               b) Unemployment
                               c) Separation
                               d) Disability
                                          •  Permanent total
                                          •  Permanent Partial
                                          •  Temporary total-

                                e)  Survivorship

                                                                                                           77]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  78



                               f)   Death (Life Insurance and Funeral)

                              g)  Unemployment benefit will be payable to eligible members who will
                                 be  voluntarily  separated  from  the  service  due  to  reorganization,
                                 merger or privatization.

                              h) The separation benefit consisting of cash payment of 18 times the
                                 BMP at time of separation and a life pension to start at age 60 will
                                 be  given  to  those  who  separate  from  the  service  with  at  least  15
                                 years  service  and  are  below  60  years  of  age.  Under  PD  No.1146,
                                 the old law, the separated member will have to wait until he is 60
                                 years of age to receive any separation benefit.

                              i)  A member who has rendered at least three years but less than 15
                                 years  of  service  is  eligible  for  separation  benefit  in  the  form  of  a
                                 cash  payment  equivalent  to  100  percent  of  the  Average  Monthly
                                 Compensation for every year of service payable upon reaching age
                                 60 or upon separation, whichever comes later, if he is not receiving
                                 a monthly pension benefit from total disability.

                               j)  A member who has rendered at least 15 years service and who is
                                 below 60 years of age at time of resignation or separation is eligible
                                 for separation benefit in the form of cash payment equivalent to 18
                                 times Basic Monthly Pension payable at time of separation plus the
                                 basic monthly pension for life starting at age 60.

                          Section 4.   The following are the benefits paid to GSIS member:

                              - Maturity                       - Burial                             - Death Claim
                              - Dividends                      - Cash Surrender Value    - Retirement
                              - Accidental Death         - Unemployment *             - Separation*
                              - Disability (permanent, partial and temporary)

                          Section 5.    Loans that may be availed of by a GSIS member:
                            - Salary Loan                 - Educational Loan              - Housing Loan
                            - Policy Loan                   - Calamity Loan

                          Section 6.   Retirement benefits of government employees are covered
                                                by Republic Acts (RA) as follows:

                              a)  RA 1616

                                         The  members  have  completed  at  least  20  years  of
                                 government  service  irrespective  of  age  and  status  of
                                 appointment.
                                                                                                           78]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  79



                                            •  The last 3 years of service must be continuous
                                            •  Leave  of  absence  without  pay  should  not  exceed
                                                one year during the last three years of service
                                            •  The  member  must  be  in  the  service  as  of  31  May
                                               1977

                                         Benefits  payable  by  GSIS  under  RA  1616:  Refund  of
                                 retirement contributions, personal share with 3 percent interest
                                 and  government  share  without  interest  which  shall  be
                                 processed by the GSIS including the maturity of policy contract
                                 or cash surrender value of the policy.

                              b)  RA  8291      -  otherwise  known  as  the  GSIS  Act  of  1997  was
                                                   enacted last 30 May1997 and took effect on 24
                                                   June 1997.

                                  Eligibility:

                                         •  He /She has rendered at least 15 years of service

                                         •  He/She  is  at  least  60  years  of  age  at  time  of
                                            retirement.

                                         •  He/She  is  not  receiving  a  monthly  pension  benefit
                                            from permanent

                                         •  total disability

                                 Under this law, a retiree may choose any of the two options:

                                         1)  The 5- year lump sum (60 x basic monthly pension) for
                                            life  starting      at  the  end  of  the  5-year  guaranteed
                                            period; or

                                         2)  The cash payment (18 x basic monthly pension) plus
                                            the basic monthly pension for life starting immediately
                                            upon retirement.

                          c)  RA 660

                                         He /She must pass the “Magic 87 “criteria, that is, when
                                 the length of service and age of retirement are summed up, the
                                 total is at least “87”. These last three years of service must be
                                 continuous.

                                                                                                           79]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  80



                                 Options:

                                 a) For those who come into service before 01 June 1997
                                         a.1.   RA  8291  and  PD  1146  may  be  availed  of  if  an
                                                employee  has  rendered  at  least  (60)  years  of  age
                                                upon retirement

                                         a. 2.  RA 1616 may be available of if he / she has
                                                rendered service for at least (20) years

                                         a.  3.  RA  660  –  If  he/she  has  passed  the”  Magic  87”
                                                criteria that is, when the length of service and age
                                                 of  retirement  are  summed  up,  the  total  is  at  least
                                                “87”

                                 b)  For those who come into service after 31May 1997, the two
                                     options available to them are RA 8291 and PD1146.

                                 c)  For those who come into service on or before 24 June 1977
                                     the only option open to them is RA 8291.

























                                                                                                           80]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                            Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                      Indang, Cavite
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



                                  HUMAN RESOURCE DEVELOPMENT OFFICE



                                        HRDO ADVISORY NO. 10, s. 2022
                                               September 21, 2022


                          RE:   ATTENDANCE TO GSIS PRE-RETIREMENT SEMINAR



                1.  Please  be  advised  that  the  Government  Service  Insurance  System  (GSIS)  NCR
                    Operations Group will conduct a Pre-Retirement Webinar on September 23, 2022,
                    Friday, at 9:00 a.m. for all GSIS members age 55-64 years old.


                2.  All concerned faculty members and employees are encouraged to attend the said
                    seminar. This is in support of the University’s adherence to CSC MC No. 15, s. 2019
                    –  Attendance  to  the  GSIS  Pre-Retirement  Seminar  for  retiring  Government
                    Employees.

                3.  Kindly  register  on  or  before  September  22,  2022  using  the  link  below.  Once
                    registered, please confirm your registration to Ms. Kristel M. Mojica, HRDO staff.

                    https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScO1MDcbMNFQ91aghVrcV46GW-
                    Ar_kdxCPjJfRmN9GpCnld0Q/viewform?vc=0&c=0&w=1&flr=0

                4.  Please be guided accordingly.

                5.  Thank you.



                                                                      FLORINDO C. ILAGAN, Ph.D.
                                                                               Director






















                                                  (046) 419-4527 / 09497721045
                                                  email: cvsuhrd@cvsu.edu.ph]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                             Don Severino delas Alas Campus
                                                       Indang, Cavite


                                    HUMAN RESOURCE DEVELOPMENT OFFICE


                                                    ADVISORY No. 29
                             RE: ATTENDANCE TO GSIS PRE-RETIREMENT SEMINAR
                                                      August 23, 2021


                       Please  be  advised  that  the  Government  Service  Insurance  System  (GSIS)  NCR
               Operations Group will conduct a Pre-Retirement Seminar on August 27, 2021, 9:00 to 11:30 am
               via Zoom meeting for all GSIS members under 55 to 64 years of age.

                       In this regard, all concerned faculty members and employees are encouraged to attend
               the said seminar, as part of the University’s support and adherence to CSC MC No. 15, s. 2019-
               Attendance to the GSIS Pre-Retirement Seminar for Retiring Government Employees.

                       Please take note that only 500 slots are available and zoom link will be emailed upon
               registration.

                       Attached are the CSC MC No. 15, s. 2019 and the GSIS advisory for your reference.

                       Thank you.





                                                                         MARY JANE D. TEPORA, Ph.D.
                                                                                    Director]]></page></pages></Search>