<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="34"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[AREA IV












                           SUPPORT TO






                                STUDENTS]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[PARAMETER E












                               RESEARCH,





            MONITORING AND






                           EVALUATION]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[IMPLEMENTATION]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[I.1.            Researches on student affairs and


                        services are conducted.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Survey Forms and Results





          (Research proposal presented




          during the University research




                              presentation 2021)]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[UREC-QF-02

                                               Republic of the Philippines
                                         CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                           Don Severino delas Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite


                                        RESEARCH PROPOSAL (PROJECT)


                                                 A.  BASIC INFORMATION
             Project Title                 Workplace Performance of CvSU-Tanza Graduates: Inputs to
             (if applicable):              Curriculum Development
             Component Study Titles:       Study 1:   Level  of  Workplace  Preparedness  and  Attitudes  of
                                                     CvSU-Tanza Graduates

                                           Study 2:  Employers’ Satisfaction on the Workplace Performance
                                                     and Attitudes of CvSU -Tanza Graduates

                                           Study 3:  Employers’     Perceived     Quality   of    Workplace
                                                     Performance  of  CvSU  –  Tanza  Graduates  and
                                                     Relevance and Responsiveness of Curricular Programs
                                                     to Industry Needs

                                           Study 4:  Acceptability and Usability of CvSU-TC Graduate Tracing
                                                     Mobile Application

             Proponents:                   Project Leader/Study Leader 1:
                 Name / Role in the               Melona I. Saquin
                 Program                          Instructor 1
                 College/Campus/Unit              Department of Management
                 Position/Designation             Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                 Mobile Number                    Tanza, Cavite
                 Email Address                    e-mail address: melona.igmasine@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                  Ritch M. Banate
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Department of Management
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: ritchbanate@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                  Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Department of Management
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: debbiebanag@cvsu.edu.ph


                                           Study Leader 2:
                                                  Joyce Erika S. Senaris
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Department of Information Technology
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: joycesenaris@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[2

                                                  Prof. Gil D. Ramos
                                                   Campus Administrator
                                                   e-mail address: gil.ramos@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                  Mary Rose E. Elamparo
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Department of Management
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: maryrhose02@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                  Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Department of Arts and Sciences
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: mcsibulo@cvsu.edu.ph


                                           Study Leader 3:
                                                  Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                  Assistant Professor IV
                                                  Teacher Education Department
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: mildred.sebastian@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                  Mary Joy R. Angelique Mojica
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Teacher Education Department
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: maryjoy.mojica@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                  Gerry Mae T. Silvero
                                                  Instructor I
                                                  Teacher Education Department
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: gerry.silvero@cvsu.edu.ph


                                           Study Leader 4:
                                                  Charmaine T. Banag
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Department of Information Technology
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: charmainebanag@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                      Jeffrey F. Delgado
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Department of Information Technology
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite


                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[3

                                                  e-mail address: jeffrey.delgado@cvsu.edu.ph

                                                       Erika Precia
                                                  Instructor 1
                                                  Department of Information Technology
                                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                  Tanza, Cavite
                                                  e-mail address: erika.precia@cvsu.edu.ph
             Cooperating Agency/           Cavite State University-Tanza
             College/Campus/Unit:          Office of Student Affairs and Services

             Location/Site:                CvSU-Tanza and respective employment institutions/sites

             Duration:                     2 years
                                           (May 2021-May 2023)
             Total Budget Requested
             (PhP):                        PhP 80,320.00
             Funding Scheme Sought          ☒       CRG                       ☐      FSRCEP

             Classification                  ☒     Basic                      ☐     Applied
             Thematic Area/s:                ☐     Agri-Fisheries Food Security

                                             ☐     Biodiversity and Environmental Conservation
                                             ☒     Smart Engineering, ICT and Industrial Competitiveness

                                             ☒     Societal Development and Equity
                                             ☐     Public Health and Wellness












































                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[4



                                                B.  TECHNICAL DESCRIPTION
          Rationale:
                                  Employability  is  more  than  merely  getting  a  job  but  implies  a  set  of
                           achievement  in  terms  of  skills,  understandings  and  personal  attributes.  Developing
                           competent graduates whose skills and capabilities can readily respond to the dynamic
                           needs of the industry is a vital role of higher education institutions (HEIs).  HEIs are
                           challenged  to  evaluate  their  curriculum  to  ensure  the  fit  between  graduate
                           competencies  and  those  required  by  employers,  stressing  on  specific  and  well-
                           targeted  skills  to  guarantee  an  effective job market placement  of  its  graduates.   In
                           addition, Javier (2018) reiterated that graduates should have gained the appropriate
                           competencies  and  skills  in  their  field  of  specialization  upon  graduation  and  before
                           applying to the workplace of their choice.

                                  One  way  of  evaluating  the  results  of  education  and  training  provided  in  the
                           HEIs is the conduct of a graduate tracer study.  It is an efficient mechanism to monitor
                           graduates’  employability,  evaluate  their  workplace  performance,  and  establish  the
                           effectiveness  and  responsiveness  of  curricular  programs  offered  in  any  HEI.    Data
                           generated  from  the  tracer  study  could  re-evaluate  the  factors  affecting  and
                           contributing to the status of employment of graduates.

                                  Cavite State University – Tanza Campus, being a primary tertiary education in
                           the municipality of Tanza, Cavite, aims to ensure that graduates of the campus have
                           extensive  education  and  training  for  them  to  be  equipped  with  competencies,
                           knowledge and skills in their field of study and be prepared to become part of their
                           chosen industry.  In order for the campus to monitor its graduates on a periodic basis,
                           the conduct  of  tracer study  is necessary.    Hence,  a  graduate  tracer study  is  being
                           proposed  to  determine  the  workplace  performance  of  CvSU  –  Tanza  Campus
                           graduates.  Consequently,  the  study  could  provide  insights  about  the  level  of
                           workplace  preparedness  and  attitude  of  its  graduates  as  well  as  the  employers’
                           satisfaction  on  the  workplace  performance  and  attitudes.  In  addition,  the  study  will
                           also determine the relevance and responsiveness of CvSU – TC curricular programs
                           to the needs of the industry based on its graduates’ quality of performance. Moreover,
                           the  results  of  the  findings  will  serve  as  significant  inputs  to  the  curriculum
                           development of the University to meet local and global demands for a highly skilled
                           labor force.


          Objectives:               The industry relies so much on higher education institutions in training and
                           preparing graduates for the workplace.  Due to this, higher education institutions find
                           ways to make their curriculum responsive to the needs of the industry. Cavite State
                           University – Tanza finds it crucial to ensure that effective and efficient programs are
                           provided  to  produce  a  human  workforce  capable  of  contributing  to  national
                           development.  Thus,  this  study  will  be  conducted  to  determine  the  workplace
                           performance  of  CvSU  –  Tanza  graduates.  Furthermore,  it  also  aims  to  develop  a
                           graduate tracer mobile application and information system that can be used by the
                           office of student affairs and services to find required alumni data which can be used
                           for accreditation and other purposes.

                                  The  four  component  studies  are  specifically  done  to  obtain  answers  to  the
                           following objectives:

                           Study 1. Level of Workplace Preparedness and Attitudes of  CvSU – Tanza
                                    Graduates


                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[5

                                                B.  TECHNICAL DESCRIPTION


                                        1. Determine the profile of CvSU – Tanza graduates in terms of:
                                        a.  age;
                                        b.  sex;
                                        c.  civil status;
                                        d.  educational attainment;
                                        e.  status of employment;
                                        f.  nature of employment;
                                        g.  area of employment;
                                        h.  job title;
                                        i.  monthly income;
                                    2.  Determine  the  level  of  workplace  preparedness  in  terms  of  following
                                      competencies, as perceived by the graduates:
                                        a.  Effective Communication Skills;
                                        b.  Self-awareness;
                                        c.  Critical Thinking Skills;
                                        d.  Data Analyzing Skills and Use of Technology;
                                        e.  Problem Solving;
                                        f.  Working Effectively with others;
                                        g.  Initiative and Enterprise Development;
                                        h.  Self-management;
                                        i.  Social responsibility;
                                        j.  Professionalism;
                                    3. Determine the level of attitudes of graduates towards their  workplace; and
                                    4. Identify competencies and attitudes that needs to be included/enhanced in
                                      the curriculum, based on the findings.


                           Study 2:   Employers’  Satisfaction  on  the  Workplace  Performance  and  Attitudes  of
                                      CvSU -Tanza Graduates

                                    1. Determine the organization's profile in terms of:
                                          a. nature of organization;
                                          b. location;
                                          c. size;
                                    2.  Determine  the  employer's  satisfaction  on  the  quality  of  workplace
                                      performance of CvSU-Tanza graduates in terms of:
                                          a. effective communication skills;
                                          b. self-awareness;
                                          c.  critical thinking skills;
                                          d. data analyzing skills and use of technology;
                                          e. problem solving;
                                          f.  working effectively with others;
                                          g. initiative and enterprise development;
                                          h. self-management;
                                          i.  social responsibility;
                                          j.  professionalism; and
                                    3.   Determine the employer's satisfaction on the attitude towards work of
                                         CvSU-Tanza graduates.






                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[6

                                                B.  TECHNICAL DESCRIPTION


                           Study 3:   Employers’ Perceived Quality of Workplace Performance of CvSU  – Tanza
                                      Graduates  and  Relevance  and  Responsiveness  of  Curricular  Programs  to
                                      Industry Needs

                                    1.  Characterize CvSU-Tanza graduates’ workplace performance as
                                       perceived by employers in terms of:
                                       k.  Effective Communication Skills;
                                       l.  Self-awareness;
                                       m.  Critical Thinking Skills;
                                       n.  Data Analyzing Skills and Use of Technology;
                                       o.  Problem Solving;
                                       p.  Working Effectively with others;
                                       q.  Initiative and Enterprise Development;
                                       r.  Self-management;
                                       s.  Social responsibility;
                                       t.  Professionalism; and

                                    2.  Determine the relevance and responsiveness of curricular programs as
                                       perceived by CvSU – Tanza Graduates and their respective employers in
                                       terms of:
                                       a.  attainment of program objectives;
                                       b.  adequacy of quality training in preparing students;
                                       c.  adequacy of course experience;

                                    3.  Determine the level of attainment of CvSU-Tanza curricular program
                                       objectives based on the employers’ perception of CvSU-Tanza
                                       graduates’ workplace performance; and

                                    4.  Recommend intervention activities to improve curricular programs based
                                       on graduates’ and employer’s feedback.


                           Study 4:  Acceptability and Usability of CvSU-TC Graduate Tracing Mobile
                                     Application

                                   1.  Design a graduate tracer mobile application with the following features:
                                        a.  input of alumni details through mobile application;
                                        b.  sending of announcement or messages to alumni through the mobile
                                           application;
                                        c.  generation and printing of reports;
                               2.  Create the application using mobile application and web development tools;
                               3.  Test the functionality and portability of the developed system; and
                               4.  Evaluate the usability and end user acceptance of the developed system
                                  using the adapted ISO 25010 quality model.











                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Theoretical/Conceptual
                            Framework:








                                                                                  INPUT                              PROCESS                               OUTPUT                            OUTCOME

                                                                          CvSU-Tanza                                                                 Employment
                                                                             Graduates’                                                                  data report
                                                                             Profile                                                                  Employers’                              Improved
                                                                          Employers’                                 Analysis of                        feedback to                           curricular

                                                                             Profile                               employers and                         graduates                             program
                                                                          Competencies                               graduates’                      Intervention                            offerings
                                                                             and Behavior                              feedback                          activities for
                                                                          Work Attitudes                                                                curriculum
                                                                          Program                                                                       development
                                                                             Outcomes                                                                 Mobile
                                                                             (based on the                                                               Application
                                                                             CMO of the
                                                                             program)





















                                                                                                                                                                                                                    V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Theoretical/Conceptual
 Framework:








    INPUT   PROCESS                 OUTPUT                            OUTCOME

     CvSU-Tanza               Employment
    Graduates’                    data report
    Profile                    Employers’                              Improved
     Employers’   Analysis of    feedback to                           curricular

    Profile   employers and       graduates                             program
     Competencies   graduates’    Intervention                        offerings
    and Behavior   feedback       activities for
     Work Attitudes              curriculum
     Program                     development
    Outcomes                   Mobile
    (based on the                 Application
    CMO of the
    program)





















                                                                                             V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[12

          Detailed
          Methodology:         A. Locale of the Study
                                       The study will be conducted at Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                  and the respective employment sites where the CvSU-Tanza graduates were
                                  employed.

                               B. Sampling Procedure
                                       Complete enumeration of the CvSU-Tanza graduates from 2016 – 2020
                                  will be employed.  A total of 217 graduates will be considered in this study.
                                  Table  1  presents  the  distribution  of  graduates  per  program  and  year  of
                                  graduation.

                                                         YEAR OF GRADUATION
                                 PROGRAM                                                       TOTAL
                                               2016     2017     2018      2019      2020
                                   BSBM         11       10        9        10        10          50
                                    BSIT        11       19        12       24        10          76
                                    BSE         12       17        15       12        5           61
                                  BSHRM          2        1        5         6         -          14
                                    ACT          6       10        -         -         -          16
                                   TOTAL        42       57        41       52        25         217
                               Table 1.  Distribution of Graduates based on Program and Year of Graduation

                               C. Data Collection Procedure
                                         There  will  be  two  questionnaires  to  be  used  in  this  study.    The  first
                                  questionnaire,  The Workplace Preparedness  and Attitudes  Inventory  (please
                                  see  Appendix  1),  has  three  parts  and  will  be  answered  by  the  CvSU  TC
                                  Graduates.  The first part will determine the profile of CvSU TC graduates as
                                  to their status, nature and area of employment.  The second part is expected
                                  to determine the level  of workplace preparedness and attitudes of CvSU-TC
                                  Graduates.    This  was  adapted  from  the  Employability  Skills  Framework  by
                                  Jackson,  D.,  Sibson,  R.  &  Riebe,  L.  (2013).  The  third  part  determines  the
                                  graduates’ workplace attitudes using the ten personal qualities of employees
                                  adapted  from  the  study  of  Plantilla  in  2017.The  fourth  part  determines  their
                                  perception of relevance and responsiveness of their curricular program to their
                                  current employment.
                                         The  second  questionnaire,  The  Employer’s  Feedback  (please  see
                                  Appendix 2), is intended for the employers of the CvSU-TC Graduates.  It has
                                  three  parts.    The  first  part  contains  information  relative  to  the  employer’s
                                  profile.  The second questionnaire determines their perception and satisfaction
                                  towards  quality  of  workplace  performance  of  CvSU  TC  graduates  who  were
                                  employed in their organization which was also adapted from the Employability
                                  Skills  Framework  (Jackson,  et.al,  2013).      The  third  part  determines  their
                                  perception  of  relevance  and  responsiveness  of  the  CvSU-TC  curricular
                                  programs based on the workplace performance of the latter’s graduates.
                                         The data that will be collected from the three studies will be utilized as
                                  basis for graduate tracing mobile application development.
                                         Prior  to  the  actual  distribution  of  the  instrument,  the  developed
                                  questionnaire  will  be  pre-tested  to  selected  graduating  students  and  some
                                  organization  leaders  who  were not part of  the study  to  determine  its validity
                                  and reliability.  Once validity and reliability are established, this will be sent to
                                  the  graduates  and  their  employers.    Simultaneously,  each  graduate  will  be
                                  contacted through any communication forms available such as, but not limited
                                  to,  texts,  social  media  sites,  and  emails.    An  online  form  (or  a  mobile
                                  application)  of  these  questionnaires  will  be  prepared  to  reduce  the  cost  of


                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[13

                                  transportation and reproduction of research instruments.

                                  D.  Data Analysis
                                         The developed questionnaires will be subjected to validation by some
                                   experts in the field.  Cohen’s Kappa coefficient will be used to measure the
                                   inter-rater reliability or agreement between two or more experts to assess the
                                   validity  of  these  documents.    On  the  other  hand,  Cronbach’s  alpha  will  be
                                   used  to  determine  the  internal  consistency  of  the  constructs  used  in  the
                                   survey when answered by a group of participants.
                                         All  data  to  be  gathered  will  be  tabulated  and  analyzed  accordingly.
                                   Descriptive  statistics  such  as,  but  not  limited  to,  frequency  counts,  ranks,
                                   means, and percentages, will be used to describe the primary data that will be
                                   collected among the graduates and employers.  Likert scales will be used to
                                   describe  the  variables  in  this  study.    Furthermore,  correlation  tests  will  be
                                   used to explore relationships among the variables involved in this study.  The
                                   data will be analyzed using the Statistical Packages for Social Sciences v. 22.
                                         Weighted  means  will  be  computed  based  on  the  participants’
                                   responses and will be converted accordingly:

                                  Table 2.  Conversion table for the range of weighted means
                                     RANGE OF
                                    WEIGHTED           LEVEL OF            LEVEL OF           LEVEL OF
                                      MEANS        PREPAREDNESS          AGREEMENT          SATISFACTION
                                                       Extremely
                                     4.21 – 5.00                         Strongly Agree      Highly satisfied
                                                        prepared
                                     3.51 – 4.20       Prepared              Agree           Very satisfied
                                     2.61 – 3.40    Slightly prepared     Slightly Agree       Satisfied
                                     1.81 – 2.60      Unprepared            Disagree          Dissatisfied
                                                       Extremely                                Highly
                                     1.00 – 1.80                        Strongly  Disagree
                                                      Unprepared                              dissatisfied

                                      Table 3.  Conversion table for the range of weighted means
                                        RANGE OF
                                        WEIGHTED           RELEVANCE AND RESPONSIVENESS OF
                                                                  CURRICULAR PROGRAMS
                                          MEANS
                                         1.21 – 2.00             Highly relevant and responsive
                                         0.41 – 1.20           Moderately relevant and responsive
                                        -0.41 – 0.40                        Baseline
                                       (-1.21) – (-0.40)          Less relevant and responsive
                                       (-2.00 – -1.20)             Not relevant and responsive


          Major Activities:     Activity    Major Activities     Planned Start        Planned       Duration
                                  No.                                               Completion      (months)
                                    1      Secondary data
                                           collection to identify
                                           sample sites and
                                           respondents,
                                           meeting/coordinatio   March 15,2021    March 30, 2021     10 days
                                           n with collaborating
                                           institutions,
                                           reconnaissance of
                                           sample sites, site
                                           selection
                                    2      Preparation of         May 17, 2021     May 29, 2021      12 days
                                           interview schedule,

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[14

                                           pre-testing and
                                           finalization of
                                           interview schedule;
                                           orientation and
                                           training of project
                                           support staff
                                    3      Primary data
                                           collection; checking
                                           and editing of filled-  June 1, 2021   August 31,2021    3 months
                                           up interview
                                           schedules
                                    4      Requirement
                                           analysis for           September 1,     September 16,     10 days
                                           graduate tracing           2021             2021
                                           mobile application
                                    5      Development of
                                           graduate tracing      September 20,    March 20, 2022    6 months
                                           mobile application         2021
                                    6      Testing of mobile     March 28, 2022    April 14, 2022    12 days
                                           application
                                    7      Evaluation of mobile   April 18, 2022    May 5, 2022      12 days
                                           application
                                    8      Data encoding and                       September 9,
                                           processing             May 9, 2022          2022         4 months
                                    9      Data analysis         September 12,     December 12,     3 months
                                                                      2022             2022
                                   10      Report writing       January  3, 2023   March 3, 2023    2 months
                                   11      Presentation,
                                           finalization and      March 6, 2023    May 6, 2023       2 months
                                           submission of report


          Expected Output:       Employment data report
                                 Employers’ feedback to graduates
                                 Intervention activities for curriculum development
                                 Mobile Application
          Potential Impact:
                                          The results of the findings will provide insights to CvSU-Tanza and other
                               researchers  about  the  level  of  workplace  preparedness  and  attitude  of  its
                               graduates as well as the employers’ satisfaction on their employment skills and
                               attitudes. In addition, it will also determine the relevance and responsiveness of
                               CvSU  –  TC  curricular  programs  to  the  needs  of  the  industry  based  on  its
                               graduates’ quality of performance. Moreover, the findings will serve as significant
                               inputs to the curriculum development of the University  to meet local and global
                               demands for a highly skilled labor force.

          Target                     Office of Student Affairs and Services Unit
          Beneficiaries:             Curriculum Development Unit

          Potential
          Intellectual               Intervention activities for curriculum development
          Property:                  CvSU-TC Graduate Tracing Mobile Application




                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[16

                                      preparedness
                               Pang, E., Wong, M., Leung, C.H., Coombes, J. (2018). Competencies for fresh
                                   graduates’ success at work: Perspectives of employers. Retrieved from
                                   https://doi.org/10.1177/0950422218792333
                               Pang, E, Hung, H (2012). Designing and evaluating a personal skills development
                                   programme for management education. Journal of College Teaching and
                                   Learning (Online) 9(3): 159.
                               Plantilla, Ariel (2017). Graduates Performance in the Workplace: Employers
                                   Perspective. Asia Pacific Journal of Multidisciplinary Research, Vol. 5, No. 2
                               Ryan, G, Emmerling, RJ, Spencer, LM (2009). Distinguishing high-performing
                                   European executives: the role of emotional, social and cognitive
                                   competencies. Journal of Management Development 28(9): 859–875.
                               Shah M, Grebennikov L, Nair C.S. (2015). A decade of study on employer
                                   feedback on the quality of university graduates. Quality Assurance in
                                   Education Vol. 23 (3), 262-278
                               Stewart, C, Wall, A, Marciniec, S (2016). Mixed signals: do college graduates
                                   have the soft skills that employers want?”. Competition Forum 14(2): 276–
                                   281.

          Line Item Budget:                                QUANTITY/      UNIT COST
                                          ITEM                                            AMOUNT (PhP)
                                                              UNIT           (PhP)
                                Study 1:   Level of Workplace Preparedness and Attitudes of CvSU-
                                           Tanza Graduates
                                Bond paper, subs20, A4       7 reams         200.00          1,400.00
                                Ballpen                      2 boxes         120.00            240.00
                                Expanding Envelop             3 pcs           50.00            150.00
                                Staple wire                  2 boxes          45.00             90.00
                                Gasoline and                   set            5,000             5,000
                                Transportation
                                Ink-Epson printer, 4          4 sets         600.00          2,400.00
                                colors/set
                                Sub-Total                                                    9,280.00
                                Study 2:  Employers’  Satisfaction  on  the  Workplace  Performance  and
                                           Attitudes of CvSU -Tanza Graduates
                                Bond paper, subs20, A4       5 reams         200.00          1,000.00
                                Ballpen                      2 boxes         120.00            240.00
                                Ink-Epson printer, 4          2 sets       1,200.00          2,400.00
                                colors/set
                                Staple wire                  1 boxes          45.00             90.00
                                Communication/ Internet     14 months      1,500.00         21,000.00
                                Gasoline and                   set           10,000            10,000
                                Transportation
                                Expanding Envelop             3 pcs           50.00            150.00
                                       Sub-Total                                            34,880.00
                                Study 3:  Employers’ Perceived Quality of Workplace Performance of
                                          CvSU – Tanza Graduates and Relevance and
                                          Responsiveness of Curricular Programs to Industry Needs
                                Bond paper, subs20, A4       5 reams         200.00          1,000.00
                                Ballpen                      2 boxes         120.00            240.00
                                Expanding Envelop             3 pcs           50.00            150.00
                                Ink-Epson printer, 4          4 sets         600.00          2,400.00
                                colors/set
                                       Sub-Total                                             3,790.00
                                Study 4:  Acceptability and Usability of CvSU-TC Graduate Tracing
                                         Mobile Application
                                 Bond paper, subs20, A4      5 reams       200.00            1,000.00


                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[17

                                         Ballpen              1 box        120.00              120.00
                                   Expanding Envelop          3 pcs         50.00              150.00
                                   Ink-Epson printer, 4       2 sets       800.00            1,600.00
                                        colors/set
                                    Mobile Application         set         25,000           25,000.00
                                    development cost
                                      Web hosting            18 months       250             4,500.00
                                       Sub-Total                                            32,370.00
                                     GRAND TOTAL                                             80,320.00



          Detailed Work Plan   Please see attached form.


          Curriculum Vitae

                                                      Melona  I.  Saquin  is  an  Instructor  1  at  Cavite  State
                                                      University-Tanza Campus since 2014 where she teaches
                                                      management  and  marketing  subjects.  She  finished
                                                      Bachelor  of  Science  in  Business  Management  major  in
                                                      Marketing  Management,  Cum  laude  at  CvSU-Tanza  in
                                                      2013    and    completed    her   Master   in   Business
                                                      Administration  at  San  Sebastian  College  Recoletos  De
                                                      Cavite in 2017. She is currently enrolled in the Doctor of
                               Philosophy in Management Program of Cavite State University- Main Campus.
                                            Ms.  Saquin  is  currently  designated as  the  Office  of Student  Affairs  and
                               Services (OSAS) Coordinator of CvSU-Tanza. She was also part of the recently
                               completed  GAD  research  about  Gender-Based  Differentiation  among  Public
                               Elementary  Teachers  of  Cavite,  as  a  study  leader.  She  is  also  affiliated  with
                               different  educational  organization  such  as  the  Philippine  Council  of  Deans  and
                               Educators in Business and Philippine Association for the Advancement of Science
                               and Technology.




                                               C.  PROFILE OF PROPONENT/S
                                                                                         Percent Time to be
                       Name               Role for the Project   Field of Specialization
                                                                                        Devoted to the Project
             Melona I. Saquin           Project/Study Leader 1   Business Management           100%
             Joyce Erika S. Senaris     Study Leader 2         Information Technology,         100%
                                                               Technology Education
             Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian   Study Leader 3       Applied Mathematics,            100%
                                                               Education
             Charmaine T. Banag         Study Leader 4         Information Technology          100%
             Ritch M. Banate            Member, Study 1        Business Management             100%
             Debbie Rose T. Banag       Member, Study 1        Business Management             100%
             Prof. Gil D. Ramos         Member, Study 2        History, Political Science      100%
             Mary Rose E. Elamparo      Member, Study 2        Information Technology          100%
             Mark Joel C. Sibulo        Member, Study 2        Hospitality Management          100%
             Mary Joy Angelique Mojica   Member, Study 3       Mathematics Education           100%

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[18

             Gerry Mae T. Silvero       Member, Study 3        Mathematics Education           100%
             Jeffrey F. Delgado         Member, Study 4        Information Technology          100%
             Erika Precia               Member, Study 4        Information Technology          100%


            SUBMITTED BY:



                           MELONA I. SAQUIN                                             April 5, 2021
                   Program Leader’s Name and Signature                                      Date

                             TANZA CAMPUS
                             Department/Unit




            CHECKED/RECORDED BY:



                      JOYCE ERIKA S. SENARIS, MIT
                   R&D Coordinator’s Name and Signature                                     Date

                             TANZA CAMPUS
                           Campus/College/Unit



            ENDORSED BY:



                         GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                   Dean/Unit Head’s Name and Signature                                      Date


                             TANZA CAMPUS
                           Campus/College/Unit





























                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Survey Forms and Results





                    (Proposed Survey Form)]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Appendix 1. Graduates’ Survey Questionnaire


                                             Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                                  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                         GRADUATES’ SURVEY QUESTIONNAIRE

            I.  Profile of Participants
              Name (Optional):   ___________________         Age: _____
              Sex                                            Civil Status:
              ☐   Male                                       ☐    Single           ☐  Separated
              ☐   Female                                     ☐    Married          ☐  Widowed

               Educational Attainment:
               ☐   College graduate, course __________
               ☐   MS/A  units, Field of Specialization __________________
               ☐   MS/A graduate, Field of Specialization: _______________

               ☐   PhD units, Field of Specialization: ___________________

               ☐   PhD graduate, Field of Specialization: _______________


               Status of Employment:     Nature of Employment:           Area of Employment:
               ☐   Employed              ☐   Private                 ☐  Local
               ☐   Unemployed            ☐   Government              ☐  Overseas/international
                                         ☐   Self-employed

            II.  Graduate Students’ Perception towards Workplace Preparedness.  Please evaluate the level of your
               preparedness using the scale below by ticking the box that corresponds to your rating.
                                    Descriptive
                        Scale                                   Qualitative Description
                                      Rating
                                    Extremely       The  graduate's  preparedness  almost  exceeds  the
                          5
                                     prepared       required competency.
                                                    The  graduate's  preparedness  meets  and  often
                          4          Prepared       exceeds the required competency.
                                                    The  graduate's  preparedness  meets  the  required
                          3      Slightly prepared
                                                    competency.
                                                    The graduate needs more preparation in order to
                          2        Unprepared       meet the required competency.

                                    Extremely       The graduate is lacks preparation to meet the
                          1
                                   Unprepared       required competency.

                                                                                           SCALE
                         COMPETENCY AND CORRESPONDING BEHAVIOR
                                                                                    5    4    3    2    1
                 A.  Communicating Effectively (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Verbal communication
                        Communicates orally in a clear and sensitive manner which is
                        appropriately varied according to different audiences and   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        seniority levels.
                     2.  Giving and receiving feedback
                        Gives and receives feedback appropriately and constructively.   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                     3.  Public speaking                                           ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[23

                        Speaks publicly and adjust the style according to the nature of
                        the audience.
                     4.  Meeting participation                                     ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        Participate constructively in meetings.
                     5.  Written communication
                        Presents knowledge, in a range of written formats, in a    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        professional, structured and clear manner.
                 B.  Self-Awareness (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Meta-cognition
                        Reflects on and evaluates personal practices, strengths and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                        weaknesses in the workplace.
                     2.  Life-long learning
                        Actively seeks, monitors and manages knowledge and
                        sustainable opportunities for learning in the context of   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        employment and life.
                     3.  Career management
                        Developing meaningful and realistic career goals and pathways   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        for achieving them in light of labor market conditions.
                 C.  Critical Thinking (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Conceptualization
                        Recognize patterns in detailed documents and scenarios to   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        understand the ‘bigger’ picture.
                     2.  Evaluation
                        Recognize, evaluate and retain key points in a range of    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        documents and scenarios.
                 D.  Ability to Analyze Data and Technology Use (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Numeracy
                        Analyze and use numbers and data accurately and manipulate   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        into relevant information.
                     2.  Technology
                        Select and use appropriate technology to address diverse tasks  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        and problems.
                     3.  Information management
                        Retrieve, interpret, evaluate and interactively use information in   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        a range of different formats.
                 E.  Problem Solving (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Reasoning
                        Use rational and logical reasoning to deduce appropriate and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        well-reasoned conclusions.
                     2.  Analyzing and diagnosing
                        Analyze facts and circumstances and ask the right questions to   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        diagnose problems.
                     3.  Decision making
                        Make appropriate and timely decisions, in light of available   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        information, in sensitive and complex situations.
                 F.  Working Effectively with Others (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Task collaboration
                        Completes group tasks through collaborative communication,   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        problem solving, discussion and planning.
                     2.  Team work
                        Operates within, and contribute to, a respectful, supportive and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☒   ☐
                        cooperative group climate.
                     3.  Social intelligence
                        Acknowledges the complex emotions and viewpoints of others   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        and respond sensitively and appropriately
                     4.  Cultural and diversity awareness
                        Works productively with people from diverse cultures, races,   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        ages, gender, religions and lifestyles.
                     5.  Influencing others
                        Defends and asserts their rights, interests and needs and   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[24

                        convince others of the validity of one’s point of view.
                     6.  Conflict resolution
                        Addresses and resolves contentious issues with key         ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        stakeholders.
                 G.  Initiative and Enterprise Development (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Entrepreneurship/ Intrapreneurship
                        Initiate change and add value by embracing new ideas and
                        showing ingenuity and creativity in addressing challenges and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        problems.
                     2.  Lateral thinking/creativity
                        Develop a range of solutions using lateral and creative thinking.   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                     3.  Initiative
                        Take action unprompted to achieve agreed goals.            ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     4.  Change management
                        Manage change and demonstrate flexibility in their approach to   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        all aspects of work.
                 H.  Self-Management (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Self-efficacy
                        Having self-confidence in dealing with the challenges that   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        employment and life present.
                     2.  Stress tolerance
                        Persevere and retain effectiveness under pressure or when   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        things go wrong.
                     3.  Work/life balance
                        Demonstrate the importance of wellbeing and strive to maintain   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        a productive balance of work and life
                     4.  Self-regulation
                        Reflect on and regulate their emotions and demonstrate self-  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                        control.
                 I.  Social responsibility (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Social responsibility
                        Behave in a manner which is sustainable and socially
                        responsible (e.g., consistent with company policy and/or   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        broader community values).
                     2.  Accountability
                        Accept responsibility for own decisions, actions and work   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        outcomes.
                     3.  Personal ethics
                        Remain consistently committed to and guided by core values   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        and beliefs such as honesty and integrity.
                     4.  Organizational awareness
                        Recognize organizational structure, operations, culture and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                        systems and adapt their behavior and attitudes accordingly.
                 J.  Professionalism (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Efficiency
                        Achieve prescribed goals and outcomes in a timely and      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        resourceful manner.
                     2.  Multi-tasking
                        Perform more than one task at the same time.               ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     3.  Autonomy
                        Complete tasks in a self-directed manner in the absence of (or   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        with minimum) supervision.
                     4.  Time management
                        Manage their time to achieve agreed goals.                 ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     5.  Drive
                        Go beyond the call of duty by pitching in, including undertaking   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        menial tasks, as required by the business.
                     6.  Goal and task management
                        Set, maintain and consistently act upon achievable goals,   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        prioritized tasks, plans and realistic schedules.

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[25



             III.  Graduate Students’ Workplace Attitudes.  Please evaluate the level of your agreement using the scale
                below by ticking the box that corresponds to your answer.
                                    Descriptive
                        Scale                                   Qualitative Description
                                      Rating
                                                    The graduate’s workplace attitude always exceeds
                          5       Strongly Agree
                                                    the job requirements.
                                                    The graduate’s workplace attitude meets and often
                          4           Agree         exceeds the job requirements.

                                                    The graduate’s workplace attitude meets job
                          3       Slightly Agree
                                                    requirements.
                                                    The graduate’s workplace attitude needs some
                          2          Disagree       development to meet job requirements.

                                     Strongly       The graduate’s workplace attitude fails to meet job
                          1
                                     Disagree       requirements.

                                                                                           SCALE
                            EMPLOYEE’S ATTITUDE TOWARDS WORK
                                                                                    5    4    3    2    1
                  1.   Flexibility                                                 ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                      Responds well to change.
                  2.   Creativity
                      Identifies new approaches to problem.                        ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                  3.   Empathy
                      Understands the situations, feelings, or motives of others.    ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                  4.   Reliability                                                 ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                      Can be depended on to complete work assignments.
                  5.   Integrity                                                   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                      Understands and applies ethical principles to decisions.
                  6.   Self-discipline                                             ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                      Exhibits control of personal behavior.
                  7.   Work Optimism
                      Positive attitude toward work.                               ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                  8.   Enthusiasm                                                  ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                      Willingness to learn.
                  9.   Compliance                                                  ☐  ☐  ☐  ☐  ☐
                      Understands and takes directions for work assignments.
                  10.  Accountability
                      Accepts responsibility for consequences of actions.          ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐


              IV.  Relevance and Responsiveness of Curricular Programs

                                    Descriptive
                        Scale                                  Qualitative Description
                                      Rating
                                  Highly relevant    The curricular program is highly appropriate in
                         +2
                                  and responsive        preparing graduates for the workplace.
                                    Moderately           The curricular program is moderately
                         +1        relevant and        appropriate in preparing graduates for the
                                    responsive                       workplace.
                                                     The curricular program prepares graduates for
                          0          Baseline
                                                                   the workplace.
                                 Less relevant and     The curricular program is getting worse in
                          -1
                                    responsive          preparing graduates for the workplace.
                                 Not relevant and        The curricular program fails to prepare
                          -2
                                    responsive               graduates for the workplace.

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[26


                      RELEVANCE AND RESPONSIVENESS OF CURRICULAR                           SCALE
                                           PROGRAMS                                 5    4    3    2    1
                 A.1.  Attainment of Program Outcomes (BSBM Graduates)
                 The graduate has the ability to:
                     1.  Application of business concepts
                        apply theories and principles of business management.      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     2.  Innovativeness and Inventiveness
                        develop comprehensive business plans.                      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     3.  Business Solution Providers
                        conduct an in-depth analysis and provide creative solutions on   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        various business situations both in the local and international
                        setting.
                     4.  Morally Upright Business Managers
                        exemplify ethically responsible and gender sensitive behavior in  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        all business undertakings.
                     5.  Collaboration and Knowledge-Sharing
                        design knowledge–sharing arrangements /linkages and        ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        effectively deliver desired value contributions to the various
                        sectors of the society.
                     6.  Social Responsibility
                        conduct relevant trainings and developmental extension     ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        activities among various stakeholders.
                 A.2.  Attainment of Program Outcomes (BSIT Graduates)
                 The graduate has the ability to:
                     1.  Application of Technological Knowledge
                        apply knowledge of utilization of both hardware and software
                        technologies involving planning, installing, customizing,   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        operating, managing and administering, and maintaining
                        information technology infrastructure that provides computing
                        solutions to address the needs of an organization.
                     2.  Innovativeness and Inventiveness
                        conduct relevant researches ad extension program activities in   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        the field of information technology;
                     3.  Information Technology Development and Transfer
                        promote the development and transfer of appropriate        ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        information technology.
                     4.  Morally Upright IT Professions
                        become morally upright IT professionals with primary or    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        secondary job roles.
                     5.  Social Responsibility
                        promote environmental conservation and protection on projects   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        and enterprises related to information technology
                 A.3.  Attainment of Program Outcomes (BSE Graduates)
                 The graduate has the ability to:
                     1.  Pedagogical Knowledge
                        articulate the rootedness of education in philosophical, socio-  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        cultural, historical, psychological, and political contexts;
                     2.  Content Knowledge
                        demonstrate mastery of subject matter/discipline;          ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     3.  Technological Knowledge
                        apply skills in the development and utilization of ICT to promote   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        quality, relevant and sustainable educational practices;
                     4.  Facilitator of Learning
                        facilitate learning using a wide range of teaching methodologies   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        and delivery modes appropriate to specific learners and their
                        environment;
                     5.  Curriculum planner
                        develop innovative curricula, instructional plans, teaching   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[27

                        approaches, and resources for diverse learners;
                     6.  Innovativeness and Inventiveness
                        demonstrate a variety of thinking skills in planning, monitoring,   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        assessing, and reporting learning processes and outcomes;
                     7.  Morally Upright Professional Teacher
                        practice professional and ethical teaching standards sensitive   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        to the local, national, and global realities; and
                     8.  Professional Development
                        pursue lifelong learning for personal and professional growth   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        through varied experiential and field-based opportunities.
                 B.  Adequacy of quality training in preparing students
                     1.  The institution provides/allows its students to attend various
                        trainings, seminars, workshops, and conferences that provide   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        updates in the field on a periodic basis.
                     2.  The trainings attended by the students match the job
                        requirements in their field.                               ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                 C.  Adequacy of Course Experience (Hard Skills)
                     1.  The course helped graduates to develop their ability to work as
                        a team member.                                             ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     2.  As a result of the course, the graduate is confident about
                        tackling unfamiliar problems                               ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     3.  The course sharpened the graduates’ analytic skills.      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     4.  The course developed the graduates’ problem solving skills   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                     5.  The course developed the graduates’ written communication
                        skills.                                                    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     6.  The course helped the graduates to develop the ability to plan
                        his/her own work.                                          ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐





























                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[28
              Appendix 2. Employers’ Survey Questionnaire

                                                Republic of the Philippines
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                                  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                    (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                         EMPLOYERS’ SURVEY QUESTIONNAIRE

            I.   PERSONAL INFORMATION
                 Name and Address of the
                 Company:
                 Name of Employer:
                 Company’s Major            ☐  Financial Services and Banking
                 Business/Industry:
                                            ☐  Retail
                                            ☐  Education
                                            ☐  Hospitality Management
                                            ☐  Information Technology
                                            ☐  Others, please specify: ___________________
                 Number of Employees:
                 Name of Evaluator and
                 Position in the Company:
                 Name of Employee (CvSU-
                 TC Graduate):
                 Employee Position in the
                 Company:

            II.   Employer’s Satisfaction towards CvSU-TC Graduates’ Workplace Performance.
                 Please evaluate our graduate using the scale below by ticking the box that corresponds to your rating.

                                    Descriptive
                        Scale                                  Qualitative Description
                                      Rating
                                                    The performance almost always exceeds the job
                          5       Highly satisfied   requirements. The graduate is an exceptional
                                                    role model.
                                                    The performance meets and often exceeds the
                          4        Very satisfied   job requirements.

                          3          Satisfied      The performance meets job requirements.
                                                    The performance needs some development to
                          2        Dissatisfied     meet job requirements.
                                      Highly
                          1                         The graduate fails to meet job requirements.
                                    dissatisfied

                                                                                           SCALE
                     EMPLOYMENT SKILLS AND CORRESPONDING BEHAVIOR
                                                                                    5    4    3    2    1
                 K.  Communicating Effectively (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Verbal communication
                        Communicates orally in a clear and sensitive manner which is   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        appropriately varied according to different audiences and
                        seniority levels.
                     2.  Giving and receiving feedback                             ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        Gives and receives feedback appropriately and constructively.
                     3.  Public speaking                                           ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        Speaks publicly and adjust their style according to the nature of


                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[29

                        the audience.
                     4.  Meeting participation                                     ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        Participate constructively in meetings.
                     5.  Written communication
                        Presents knowledge, in a range of written formats, in a    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        professional, structured and clear manner.
                 L.  Self-Awareness (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Meta-cognition
                        Reflects on and evaluates personal practices, strengths and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                        weaknesses in the workplace.
                     2.  Life-long learning
                        Actively seeks, monitors and manages knowledge and         ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        sustainable opportunities for learning in the context of
                        employment and life.
                     3.  Career management
                        Developing meaningful and realistic career goals and pathways  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        for achieving them in light of labor market conditions.
                 M.  Critical Thinking (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Conceptualization
                        Recognize patterns in detailed documents and scenarios to   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        understand the ‘bigger’ picture.
                     2.  Evaluation
                        Recognize, evaluate and retain key points in a range of    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        documents and scenarios.
                 N.  Ability to Analyze Data and Technology Use (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Numeracy
                        Analyze and use numbers and data accurately and manipulate   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        into relevant information.
                     2.  Technology
                        Select and use appropriate technology to address diverse tasks  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        and problems.
                     3.  Information management
                        Retrieve, interpret, evaluate and interactively use information in   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        a range of different formats.
                 O.  Problem Solving (Hard Skills)
                     1.  Reasoning
                        Use rational and logical reasoning to deduce appropriate and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        well-reasoned conclusions.
                     2.  Analyzing and diagnosing
                        Analyze facts and circumstances and ask the right questions to   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        diagnose problems.
                     3.  Decision making
                        Make appropriate and timely decisions, in light of available   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        information, in sensitive and complex situations.
                 P.  Working Effectively with Others (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Task collaboration
                        Completes group tasks through collaborative communication,   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        problem solving, discussion and planning.
                     2.  Team work
                        Operates within, and contribute to, a respectful, supportive and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        cooperative group climate.
                     3.  Social intelligence
                        Acknowledges the complex emotions and viewpoints of others   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        and respond sensitively and appropriately
                     4.  Cultural and diversity awareness
                        Works productively with people from diverse cultures, races,   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        ages, gender, religions and lifestyles.
                     5.  Influencing others
                        Defends and asserts their rights, interests and needs and   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        convince others of the validity of one’s point of view.

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[30

                     7.  Conflict resolution
                        Addresses and resolves contentious issues with key         ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        stakeholders.
                 Q.  Initiative and Enterprise Development (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Entrepreneurship/ Intrapreneurship
                        Initiate change and add value by embracing new ideas and
                        showing ingenuity and creativity in addressing challenges and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        problems.
                     2.  Lateral thinking/creativity
                        Develop a range of solutions using lateral and creative thinking.   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                     3.  Initiative                                                ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        Take action unprompted to achieve agreed goals.
                     4.  Change management
                        Manage change and demonstrate flexibility in their approach to   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        all aspects of work.
                 R.  Self-Management (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Self-efficacy
                        Having self-confidence in dealing with the challenges that   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        employment and life present.
                     2.  Stress tolerance
                        Persevere and retain effectiveness under pressure or when   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        things go wrong.
                     3.  Work/life balance
                        Demonstrate the importance of wellbeing and strive to maintain   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        a productive balance of work and life
                     4.  Self-regulation
                        Reflect on and regulate their emotions and demonstrate self-  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                        control.
                 S.  Social responsibility (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Social responsibility
                        Behave in a manner which is sustainable and socially       ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        responsible (e.g., consistent with company policy and/or
                        broader community values).
                     2.  Accountability
                        Accept responsibility for own decisions, actions and work   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        outcomes.
                     3.  Personal ethics
                        Remain consistently committed to and guided by core values   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐
                        and beliefs such as honesty and integrity.
                     4.  Organizational awareness
                        Recognize organizational structure, operations, culture and   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                        systems and adapt their behavior and attitudes accordingly.
                 T.  Professionalism (Soft Skills)
                     1.  Efficiency
                        Achieve prescribed goals and outcomes in a timely and      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        resourceful manner.
                     2.  Multi-tasking                                             ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        Perform more than one task at the same time.
                     3.  Autonomy
                        Complete tasks in a self-directed manner in the absence of (or   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        with minimum) supervision.
                     4.  Time management                                           ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        Manage their time to achieve agreed goals.
                     5.  Drive
                        Go beyond the call of duty by pitching in, including undertaking   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        menial tasks, as required by the business.
                     6.  Goal and task management
                        Set, maintain and consistently act upon achievable goals,   ☐   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        prioritized tasks, plans and realistic schedules.


                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[31

             III.  Employer’s Satisfaction towards CvSU-TC Graduates’ Work Attitudes.
                 Please evaluate our graduate using the scale below by ticking the box that corresponds to your rating.

                                    Descriptive
                        Scale                                  Qualitative Description
                                      Rating
                                                    The graduate’s work attitude almost always
                          5       Highly satisfied   exceeds the job requirements. The graduate is
                                                    an exceptional role model.
                                                    The graduate’s work attitude meets and often
                          4        Very satisfied   exceeds the job requirements.
                                                    The graduate’s work attitude meets job
                          3          Satisfied
                                                    requirements.
                                                    The graduate’s work attitude needs some
                          2        Dissatisfied     development to meet job requirements.

                                      Highly        The graduate’s work attitude fails to meet job
                          1
                                    dissatisfied    requirements.

                                                                                           SCALE
                        EMPLOYEE’S ATTITUDES TOWARDS WORKPLACE
                                                                                    5    4    3    2    1
                  1.  Flexibility                                                  ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     Responds well to change.
                  2.  Creativity
                     Identifies new approaches to problem.                         ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                  3.  Empathy                                                      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     Understands the situations, feelings, or motives of others.
                  4.  Reliability                                                  ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     Can be depended on to complete work assignments.
                  5.  Integrity                                                    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     Understands and applies ethical principles to decisions.
                  6.  Self-discipline
                     Exhibits control of personal behavior.                        ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                  7.  Work Optimism                                                ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     Positive attitude toward work.
                  8.  Enthusiasm                                                   ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     Willingness to learn.
                  9.  Compliance
                     Understands and takes directions for work assignments.        ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                 10. Accountability                                                ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     Accepts responsibility for consequences of actions.

              V.  Relevance and Responsiveness of Curricular Programs

                                    Descriptive
                        Scale                                  Qualitative Description
                                      Rating
                                  Highly relevant    The curricular program is highly appropriate in
                         +2
                                  and responsive        preparing graduates for the workplace.
                                    Moderately           The curricular program is moderately
                         +1        relevant and        appropriate in preparing graduates for the
                                    responsive                       workplace.
                                                     The curricular program prepares graduates for
                          0          Baseline
                                                                   the workplace.
                                 Less relevant and     The curricular program is getting worse in
                          -1
                                    responsive          preparing graduates for the workplace.
                                 Not relevant and        The curricular program fails to prepare
                          -2
                                    responsive               graduates for the workplace.




                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[32

                      RELEVANCE AND RESPONSIVENESS OF CURRICULAR                           SCALE
                                           PROGRAMS                                 5    4    3    2    1
                 A.4.  Attainment of Program Outcomes (BSBM Graduates)
                 The graduate has the ability to:
                     7.  Application of business concepts
                        apply theories and principles of business management.      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     8.  Innovativeness and Inventiveness
                        develop comprehensive business plans.                      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     9.  Business Solution Providers
                        conduct an in-depth analysis and provide creative solutions on   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        various business situations both in the local and international
                        setting.
                     10. Morally Upright Business Managers
                        exemplify ethically responsible and gender sensitive behavior in  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        all business undertakings.
                     11. Collaboration and Knowledge-Sharing
                        design knowledge–sharing arrangements /linkages and
                        effectively deliver desired value contributions to the various   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        sectors of the society.
                     12. Social Responsibility
                        conduct relevant trainings and developmental extension     ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        activities among various stakeholders.
                 A.5.  Attainment of Program Outcomes (BSIT Graduates)
                 The graduate has the ability to:
                     6.  Application of Technological Knowledge
                        apply knowledge of utilization of both hardware and software
                        technologies involving planning, installing, customizing,
                        operating, managing and administering, and maintaining     ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        information technology infrastructure that provides computing
                        solutions to address the needs of an organization.
                     7.  Innovativeness and Inventiveness
                        conduct relevant researches ad extension program activities in   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        the field of information technology;
                     8.  Information Technology Development and Transfer
                        promote the development and transfer of appropriate        ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        information technology.
                     9.  Morally Upright IT Professions
                        become morally upright IT professionals with primary or    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                        secondary job roles.
                     10. Social Responsibility
                        promote environmental conservation and protection on projects   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        and enterprises related to information technology
                 A.6.  Attainment of Program Outcomes (BSE Graduates)
                 The graduate has the ability to:
                     9.  Pedagogical Knowledge
                        articulate the rootedness of education in philosophical, socio-  ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        cultural, historical, psychological, and political contexts;
                     10. Content Knowledge
                        demonstrate mastery of subject matter/discipline;          ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     11. Technological Knowledge
                        apply skills in the development and utilization of ICT to promote   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        quality, relevant and sustainable educational practices;
                     12. Facilitator of Learning
                        facilitate learning using a wide range of teaching methodologies   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        and delivery modes appropriate to specific learners and their
                        environment;
                     13. Curriculum planner
                        develop innovative curricula, instructional plans, teaching   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                        approaches, and resources for diverse learners;

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[33

                     14. Innovativeness and Inventiveness
                        demonstrate a variety of thinking skills in planning, monitoring,   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        assessing, and reporting learning processes and outcomes;
                     15. Morally Upright Professional Teacher
                        practice professional and ethical teaching standards sensitive   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        to the local, national, and global realities; and
                     16. Professional Development
                        pursue lifelong learning for personal and professional growth   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        through varied experiential and field-based opportunities.
                 D.  Adequacy of quality training in preparing students
                     3.  The institution provides/allows its students to attend various
                        trainings, seminars, workshops, and conferences that provide   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐
                        updates in the field on a periodic basis.
                     4.  The trainings attended by the students match the job
                        requirements in their field.                               ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                 E.  Adequacy of Course Experience (Hard Skills)
                     7.  The course helped graduates to develop their ability to work as
                        a team member.                                             ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     8.  As a result of the course, the graduate is confident about
                        tackling unfamiliar problems                               ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     9.  The course sharpened the graduates’ analytic skills.      ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     10. The course developed the graduates’ problem solving skills   ☐   ☐   ☐   ☐    ☐
                     11. The course developed the graduates’ written communication
                        skills.                                                    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
                     12. The course helped the graduates to develop the ability to plan
                        his/her own work.                                          ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐    ☐
































                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Appendix 3. Evaluation instrument for graduate tracer mobile application                      34



                                                Republic of the Philippines
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                                  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                    (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                   EVALUATION INSTRUMENT FOR GRADUATE TRACER MOBILE APPLICATION

            Name (Optional): ______________________________ Date: _______________
            Address: (Optional): ___________________________________________
            Profession: _____________________________ Specialization: ____________

            Instruction: Please evaluate using the given scale and placing a checkmark ( ) on the appropriate
            column corresponding to your response.
            Numerical Rating: 5 – Excellent 4 – Very Good 3 – Good 2 – Fair 1 – Poor

                                     INDICATORS                        5     4      3     2     1
                     A. Functionality
                     1. The functions covers all the tasks and user
                     objectives.
                     2. The application provides the correct result
                     with the needed degree of precision.
                     3. The functions facilitate the accomplishment
                     of specified tasks and objectives.
                     B. Usability
                     1. The user can recognize whether the
                     application is appropriate for their needs.
                     2. The application can be used by specified
                     users to achieve specified goals of learning to
                     use the application with effectiveness,
                     efficiency, freedom from risk, and satisfaction in
                     a specified context of use.
                     3. The application has attributes that make it
                     easy to operate and control.
                     4. The application protects the users against
                     making errors.
                     5. The user interface enables pleasing and
                     satisfying interaction for the user.
                     6. The application can be used by people with
                     the widest range of characteristics and
                     capabilities to achieve a specified goal in a
                     specified context of use.
                     C. Reliability
                     1. The application meets needs for reliability
                     under normal operation.
                     2. The application is operational and accessible
                     when required for use.
                     3. The application operates as intended despite
                     the presence of hardware or software faults.
                     4. In the event of an interruption or a failure, the
                     application can recover the data directly

                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[35

                     affected and re-establish the desired state of
                     the system.
                     D. Efficiency
                     1. The response and processing times and
                     throughput rates of the application, when
                     performing its functions, is fast and reasonable.
                     2. The amounts and types of resources used
                     by the application, when performing its
                     functions, meet requirements.
                     E. Portability
                     1. The application can effectively and efficiently
                     be adapted for different or evolving hardware,
                     software, or other operational or usage
                     environments.
                     2. The application can be successfully installed
                     and/or uninstalled in a specified environment.


            Any further comments regarding the software:

                                                                               _________________________
                                                                                    Signature of the Evaluator




















































                                                                                               V01-2018-05-30]]></page></pages></Search>