<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="177"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.            The extension agenda is in

                                consonance of local, regional


                                and national development


                                thrusts and priorities.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[BOR APPROVED CVSU


                                      EXTENSION AGENDA]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[1
                                            EXTENSION MANUAL OF OPERATIONS

                                                          Volume 5

                                                    EXTENSION SERVICES

                                                       INTRODUCTION

                   As   mandated, the   University   shall “provide   advanced   instruction   and professional training in
               agriculture, science and technology, education and other related fields, undertake research and extension
               services, and provide progressive leadership in these areas.”  (Republic Act No. 8468, converting the Don
               Severino Agricultural College into University Status, to be called Cavite State University).

                   The  Republic  Act  No.  8435,  or  the  Agriculture  and  Fisheries  Modernization  Act of  1997  (AFMA)
               under  section  86  stated:  “It  is  hereby  declared  the  policy  of  the state to promote science and
               technology, as essential for national development and progress.   The State shall give priority to the
               utilization  of  research  results  through  formal  and  non-formal  education,  extension,  and  training
               services.”

                   “Extension refers to the act of communicating, persuading, and helping specific sectors or target
               clientele to enable them to effectively improve production, community and/or institutions, and quality
               of life” (CHED CMO No. 08, s 2008).


               Article 1. Extension Services Vision, Mission, Goal, Objectives, Agenda, Banner Program, Interventions,
               Program/Projects, and Activities

                    Section  1.  Vision.    Alleviating the standard of living of the economically and socially disadvantaged
               sectors of society

                    Section  2.  Mission.  To  engage  in  the  improvement  of  the  quality  of  life  of  farmers/fisherfolks,
               women, out-of-school youths, local government employees, and other clients through the conduct of
               relevant  education  and  training;  farm  and  business  advisory  services;  demonstration  services;  and
               information, communication, and technology services

                   Section  3.  Goal. The  Extension  Services  of  Cavite  State  University  (CvSU) shall be geared towards
               the  improvement  of  the  lives  of  the  community especially those that  belong  to  economically  and
               socially  disadvantaged  sectors  through  the  conduct  of relevant  education  and  training;  farm  and
               business  advisory  activities;  demonstration projects; and information, communication, and technology
               services.

                   Section  4.  Objectives.  The  University  shall  provide  excellent  and  socially-responsive  extension
               services to its target clientele.




               1  Approved during the September 13, 2022 Administrative Council Meeting

                                                                                                            1]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Specifically, it aims to:

                    1.  Conceptualize, coordinate, and conduct relevant, efficient, gender-responsive, and sustainable
                       interdisciplinary extension programs, projects, and activities;
                    2.  Establish linkages with government and private agencies engaged in extension and community
                       development;
                    3.  Coordinate, monitor, and evaluate the extension programs, projects, and activities of various
                       colleges, campuses, and other extension implementing units of the University;
                    4.  Promote community and social enterprises; and
                    5.  Coordinate with the Office of Business Affairs (OBA) in promoting agricultural and other potential
                       income-generating projects.

                   Section 5. University Extension Agenda.   The University shall pursue extension agenda which are
               responsive to the specific needs of the community brought by present environmental and developmental
               challenges. Guided by the local and national development thrusts, the University research and extension
               agenda shall be focused on but not limited to the following:

                   1.  Agri-Fisheries and Food Security.   This thematic area emphasizes developing agriculture and food
                       systems that are economically viable and sustainable to ensure food security as well as to improve
                       the quality of life of farmers and fisherfolks. Research and extension activities on the following
                       commodities shall be given priority: coffee; kaong; makapuno; rice; corn; root crops; high-value
                       crops (banana, pineapple, mango, cacao, and vegetables); poultry and livestock; fisheries and
                       aquaculture; urban agriculture; and organic agriculture.

                   2.  Biodiversity  and  Environmental  Conservation.      This  thematic  area  is  concerned  with
                       environmental stewardship and equitable allocation and sustainable use of natural resources.
                       Emphases include environmental protection; biodiversity assessment and monitoring; cleaner
                       environment;  climate  change;  inclusive  risk  reduction  management;  renewable  energy  and
                       green technologies; natural resource management; and ecotourism.

                   3.  Smart  Engineering,  Information,  and  Communication  Technology  (ICT),  and  Industrial
                       Competitiveness.   The term smart engineering covers the methods, processes, systems, and
                       tools for the cross-disciplinary, system-oriented development of innovative and interconnected
                       products, services, and infrastructures in the field of engineering. Products and process models
                       shall  be  developed  in  which  networking  encompasses  all  stages  of  development,  from
                       interdisciplinary design, to production processes and piloting, right the way through product
                       usage and disposal. Smart engineering is about the integration of appropriate product planning,
                       development, and management to ensure the rapid market-ready implementation of innovative
                       products and services and industrial competitiveness through digital development process.

                       The convergence of the latest computer science and ICT developments in the areas of micro-
                       devices, mobile communication, hardware infrastructures, internet and software technologies,
                       image  recognition  and  processing,  parallel  computing,  complex  adaptive  systems  and
                       bioinformatics shall be given emphasis. Strong focus shall also be given to mathematics and
                       statistics  applications  such  as  industrial  and  biological  modelling,  biomedical,  social  and
                       theoretical  statistics,  computational  mathematics,  discrete  pure  mathematics  and
                       physics/engineering.



                                                                                                            2]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[4.   Social   Development and Equality. This thematic area focuses on educational, criminological,
                       and  social  sciences  researches  and  development  initiatives  with  emphasis  on  sustainable
                       development,  economic  development,  gender  and  development,  community  development,
                       governance, poverty alleviation, social behavior, attitude and norms, capacity building, peace
                       process  and  conflict  resolution,  inclusive  disaster  risk  management  and  social  transitions,
                       pedagogy, special education, ICT and education, among others.

                       This  area  aims  to  create  inclusive  growth  and  development,  social  harmony,  and  equal
                       opportunities among the different social groups and to lessen economic divide, inequality, and
                       marginalization in the society.

                   5.   Public  Health  and  Welfare.   This  area  deals  with  researches  on  protecting and improving
                       human health and welfare which includes researches on diseases or conditions  that may be
                       transmitted to humans from humans or animals and vice versa as well as those connected with
                       the  environment  as  a  whole.  Disciplines  that  are  also  covered  are  those  dealing  with
                       epidemiology, statistics, environment,  behavior and sociology, economics, mental health, public
                       policy,  public  safety, delivery of  health  services,  occupational  safety and other related fields.

                    The Extension Services shall facilitate the regular review of extension programs and projects of the
               University  to  guarantee  that  they  are  responsive  to  the  approved  University  Extension  Agenda.
               Meanwhile,  the  University  Extension  Agenda  shall  be  updated/revised  every  four  years  or  whenever
               necessary. The Extension Services shall also ensure that all stakeholders are consulted during the process.

                   Section 6. Banner Program.   The CvSU Poverty Alleviation Program through Ugnayan 2.0 Approach
               is a BOR-approved extension banner program of the University (Figure 1).  It is the updated version of the
               previous Ugnayan Program which was originally intended as a Unified Research and Extension Program.
               Ugnayan is a Tagalog word which connotes coordination and cooperation.

                   The  Ugnayan  2.0  as  an  approach  is  multidisciplinary  and  focuses  on  the  utilization  of  matured
               technologies as inputs. It also emphasizes communication, coordination, cooperation, collaboration, and
               convergence among the University’s colleges, campuses, and other extension implementing units; local
               government units; partner agencies; and other stakeholders in providing the necessary knowledge and
               technical assistance to target communities. Ugnayan 2.0 aims to increase the number of communities
               trained, demonstration areas set-up, technologies adopted, adopters, linkages and partnerships formed,
               and businesses established, and eventually reduce the poverty level in the province of Cavite.





















                                                                                                            3]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Figure 1. Conceptual Framework of CvSU Poverty Alleviation Program through Ugnayan 2.0 Approach



                   Section  7.  Interventions, Programs/Projects, and Activities.    The University shall engage in the
               following Extension Services:

                   1.  Capability building programs. Refer to non-degree/non-credit training programs offered by the
                       colleges,  campuses,  and  other  extension  implementing  units  of  the  University;  it  includes
                       technical, vocational, and livelihood trainings, agriculture, fisheries, and environment trainings,
                       continuing education for professionals, basic education, gender and development, and other
                       related trainings
                   2.  Technical  assistance,  advisory  services,  consultancy,  and  other  support  services.  May  be
                       provided to individuals, groups, associations, organizations, or communities in need
                   3.  Communication and information services. Refer to the dissemination of knowledge and skills to
                       different clientele groups using various multimedia formats such as print media, outdoor media,
                       broadcasting media, and digital media
                   4.  Technology   promotion,    transfer,   utilization,   and   commercialization.   Include
                       programs/projects/activities of promoting, marketing, and deployment of research outputs or
                       technologies to potential users
                   5.  Community-Based  Development  Projects,  social  innovations,  and  other  high-impact  and
                       integrated  extension  programs/projects.  Refer  to  internally  and  externally  funded
                       programs/projects consist of different extension approaches, strategies, and methods and aim
                       to encourage community participation, accelerate community development, and contribute to
                       the attainment of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)
                   6.  Community outreach activities and volunteer programs. Involve endeavors that would provide
                       an immediate response to communities in need and inculcate the spirit of volunteerism








                                                                                                            4]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Article 2. Extension Organization and Management

                   Section 1. Research and Extension Council (REC)

                   1.1. Composition.  The  Research  and  Extension  Council  (REC)  is  headed  by  the  Vice  President  for
                       Research  and  Extension  as  Chairperson.  Its  members  shall  include  the  Director  of  Research
                       Center, Director for Extension Services, Director of Knowledge Management Center, Director of
                       National  Coffee  Research,  Development,  and  Extension  Center,  and  research  and  extension
                       experts from different colleges, campuses, and units of the University.

                   1.2. Functions. The REC shall perform the following functions:
                       •  Formulate policies, guidelines, rules and regulation governing research and extension and
                          recommend them to the Board of Regents (BOR) through the University Council, for
                          approval;
                       •  Determine the research and extension priorities and agenda of the university;
                       •  Review and recommend amendments to improve established policies and guidelines for
                          research and extension for the approval of the BOR;
                       •  Recommend allocation of funds for research and extension programs/projects/activities;
                       •  Make recommendations on policies and procedures related to the ethical conduct of
                          research, extension, human resource development and management of research and
                          extension fundings; and
                       •  Provide insights to the University Academic Council on the development of academic degree
                          programs or courses that involve research and extension training, internationalization, and
                          collaboration.

                   1.3. Meetings. The Council shall hold at least one meeting every quarter. The time, date, and venue
                       of  the  meeting  shall  be  determined  by  the  Chairperson  with  attendance  in  all  its  meetings
                       required of every member. The notice of the meeting indicating the date, time, venue, and agenda
                       shall be disseminated among its members at least a day before the date of the meeting. A quorum
                       of the Council shall consist of a majority of all its members, excluding those on official leave or
                       travel.

                   Section 2. Extension Services

                   2.1. Composition. The Extension Services as shown in Figure 2 shall be directly under the supervision
                       of the Office of the Vice President for Research and Extension (OVPRE). The office has five major
                       divisions:  Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division  (CEERD),  Technology
                       Promotion Division (TPD), Training and Courseware Development Division (TCDD), Technology
                       Demonstration  Farm  Division  (TDFD),  and  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Division  (MED).  It  also
                       oversees  all  extension  concerns  of  the  different  colleges,  campuses,  and  other  extension
                       implementing units of the University.

                   2.2. Functions of the Extension Services.   The Extension Services performs the third major function
                       of the University.   It links this educational institution with the community through the conduct
                       of  technology  promotion;  non-formal  education  and  trainings;  technology  demonstration;
                       advisory services; and other community development activities for farmers, fisherfolks, women





                                                                                                            5]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[and  children,  persons  with  disabilities,  out-of-school  youths,  disadvantaged  families  and/or
                       households, workers, migrants, and other clients.

                       The Extension Services performs the overall coordinative function. It is tasked to perform the
                       major extension activity of the University and to assist in the conceptualization, implementation,
                       evaluation,  and  monitoring  of  extension  programs,  projects,  and  activities  of  the  different
                       colleges, campuses, and other extension implementing units.




                                                          President


                                                       Vice President for
                                                                                 Research and
                                                         Research and
                                                          Extension            Extension Council


                                                      Extension Services
                                                                               College/Campus/
                                                                                 Unit Extension
                                                                                 Coordinators
                                Support Staff
                                                                                    Faculty
                                                                                 Extensionists



                               Community    Technology    Training and   Technology   Monitoring

                              Engagement     Promotion    Courseware   Demonstration    and
                              and External    Division    Development   Farm Division   Evaluation
                                Relations                  Divisi  on                  Division
                                Division


                                      Figure 2. Organizational structure of Extension Services



                   2.3. Functions of the Major Divisions

                       a.  Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division  (CEERD).  The  Community
                           Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division  facilitates  the  conduct  of  community  needs
                           assessment, development of extension programs, projects and other community outreach
                           activities, and establishment of partnerships and linkages with various stakeholders.

                       b.  Technology  Promotion  Division  (TPD).  The  Technology  Promotion  Division  validates,
                           packages, and disseminates appropriate and matured technologies.



                                                                                                            6]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[c.  Training  and  Courseware  Development  Division  (TCDD).  The  Training  and  Courseware
                           Development Division plans and conducts training programs based on the needs of the target
                           communities/clienteles.

                       d.  Technology  Demonstration  Farm  Division  (TDFD).  The  Technology  Demonstration  Farm
                           Division  oversees  the  operations  of  the  techno-demo  farm  and  showcases  agri-fisheries
                           matured technologies.

                       e.  Monitoring and Evaluation Division (MED). The Monitoring and Evaluation Division takes
                           charge  of  the  overall  monitoring  and  evaluation  of  on-going  and  completed  extension
                           programs,  projects,  and  activities  of  the  colleges,  campuses,  and  other  extension
                           implementing units of the University.

                   2.4. Duties and Responsibilities

                       a.  Director, Extension Services.  The Director of Extension Services shall perform the following
                           functions:
                           •  Prepare and implement the strategic and development plan of the Extension Services;
                           •  Prepare budgetary estimates for all extension programs, projects, and activities of the
                              unit in coordination with the division heads and project in-charge;
                           •  Initiate  the  conceptualization  of  new  extension  programs,  projects,  and  other
                              community outreach activities;
                           •  Lead the coordination, monitoring, and evaluation of extension programs, projects, and
                              activities of all the colleges, campuses, and other extension implementing units;
                           •  Spearhead  the  establishment  of  partnerships  and  linkages  with  various  government
                              agencies,  non-government  organizations,  industries,  enterprises,  communities,  and
                              other stakeholders for the effective implementation of extension programs, projects,
                              and activities of the University;
                           •  Propose revisions on policies, rules, and regulations affecting the Extension Services;
                           •  Prepare  and  submit  yearly  performance  target  and  accomplishment  reports  of  the
                              Extension Services;
                           •  Sign vouchers and RIVs up to amount approved by the University, subject to Commission
                              on Audit (COA) rules and regulations; and
                           •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by higher authorities.

                       b.  Head,  Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division.    The  Head  of  the
                           Community Engagement and External Relations Division shall perform the following duties:
                           •  Oversee all community development projects including the conduct of community needs
                              assessment  and  conceptualization  of  extension  programs  and  projects,  and  other
                              community outreach activities;
                           •  Establish partnerships and linkages with various government agencies, non-government
                              organizations,  industries,  enterprises,  communities,  and  other  stakeholders  for  the
                              effective  implementation  of  extension  programs,  projects,  and  activities  of  the
                              University;
                           •  Assist  in  maintaining  active  partnership  and  good  relationship  with  all  partner
                              communities and agencies/institutions;




                                                                                                            7]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[•  Handle all outside requests for extension services, technical assistance, advisory services,
                              and other community outreach activities;
                           •  Coordinate   the   extension   programs, projects, and activities   of   all   the   colleges,
                              campuses, and other extension implementing units;
                           •  Provide the necessary data and information to other divisions of the Extension Services;
                           •  Prepare reports and submit to the Director of Extension Services; and
                           •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by higher authorities.

                       c.  Head, Technology Promotion Division.  The Head of the Technology Promotion Division shall
                           perform the following duties:
                           •  Coordinate  with  the  Research  Center,  colleges,  campuses,  and  other  extension
                              implementing  units  to  identify  and  validate  technologies  ready  for  promotion  and
                              transfer;
                           •  Package  identified  and  validated  technologies  and  develop  appropriate  Information,
                              Education, and Communication (IEC) materials in various multimedia formats;
                           •  Spearhead the promotion of technologies through websites and social media networks,
                              dissemination  of  IEC  materials,  and  conduct  and  participation  to  technology  fora,
                              consultative dialogues, trade fairs, exhibits, and other related events;
                           •  Assist in the conduct of Community Needs Assessment to determine the technology/ies
                              needed by the community/clientele;
                           •  Assist in establishing partnerships and linkages with the target communities and other
                              stakeholders;
                           •  Assist the other divisions of Extension Services as well as the various colleges, campuses,
                              and other extension implementation units in the promotion of its extension activities and
                              technologies;
                           •  Prepare reports and submit to the Director of Extension Services; and
                           •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by higher authorities.

                       d.  Head,  Training  and  Courseware  Development  Division.    The  Head  of  Training  and
                           Courseware Development Division shall perform the following duties:
                           •  Conduct    training    needs    assessment;
                           •  Prepare and submit training proposals for implementation;
                           •  Prepare   and package training   materials/modules   appropriate   to   target clientele;
                           •  Conduct and facilitate planned/approved/requested trainings in the community;
                           •  Prepare  proceedings  of  trainings,  seminars,  and  other  related  activities  of  Extension
                              Services;
                           •  Assist colleges, campuses, and other extension implementing units in the coordination
                              of their trainings;
                           •  Prepare reports and submit to the Director of Extension Services; and
                           •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by higher authorities.

                       e.  Head, Technology Demonstration Farm Division.   The Head of Technology Demonstration
                           Farm Division shall perform the following duties:
                          •  Supervise the day-to-day operations of the techno-demo farm;
                          •  Coordinate  with  the  Technology  Promotion  Division,  Research  Center,  colleges,
                              campuses, and other extension implementing units to identify technologies and outputs
                              of research ready for demonstration;


                                                                                                            8]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[•  Manage the showcase of agri-fisheries technologies among the on-site visitors and other
                              clientele;
                          •  Make necessary recommendations for the improvement of the techno-demo farm;
                          •  Prepare reports and submit to the Director of Extension Services; and
                          •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by higher authorities.

                       f.  Head, Extension Monitoring and Evaluation Division.   The Head of Extension Monitoring
                           and Evaluation Division shall perform the following duties:
                          •  Conduct regular and periodic monitoring and annual evaluation of the different extension
                              programs,  projects,  and  activities  of  all  colleges,  campuses,  and  other  extension
                              implementing units;
                          •  Provide proponents feedback/results of the monitoring and evaluation
                          •  Monitor the status of partnerships and techno-demo farms and conduct of technology
                              promotion activities, trainings, and advisory services, of colleges, campuses, and other
                              extension implementing units;
                          •  Conduct follow-ups and updates on the trainees and adopters;
                          •  Prepare tracer studies on the adopters and clienteles;
                          •  Conduct impact assessments of extension programs, projects, and activities; and
                          •  Prepare and submit regular monitoring and evaluation reports (i.e., monthly, quarterly,
                              and annually); and
                          •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by higher authorities.

                      g.  College/Campus/Unit  Extension  Coordinators.  The  College/Campus/Unit  Extension
                          Coordinator shall perform the following duties:
                          •  Prepare and implement the annual extension plan of the college/campus/unit;
                          •  Assist  the  budget  officer  and  extension  program/project  leader  in  the  preparation  of
                              budgetary  estimates  for  all  extension  programs,  projects,  and  activities  of  the
                              college/campus/unit  in  coordination  with  the  department  extension  coordinators  and
                              project in-charge;
                          •  Initiate the conceptualization of new extension programs, projects, and other community
                              outreach activities of the college/campus/unit;
                          •  Initiate the coordination, monitoring, and evaluation of extension programs, projects, and
                              activities of the college/campus/unit;
                          •  Establish partnerships and linkages with various government agencies, non-government
                              organizations,  industries,  enterprises,  communities,  and  other  stakeholders  for  the
                              effective  implementation  of  extension  programs,  projects,  and  activities  of  the
                              college/campus/unit;
                          •  Coordinate with the University Extension Services the extension programs, projects, and
                              activities of the campus/college/unit;
                          •  Serve as a link between the college/campus/unit and the University Extension Services;
                          •  Attend regular meetings and other related activities of Extension Coordinators;
                          •  Represent  the  college/campus/unit  during  the  Extension  in-house  reviews  and  other
                              extension-related activities of the University Extension Services; and
                          •  Prepare   and   submit   progress   and   accomplishment   reports (i.e., monthly, quarterly,
                              and annually) to the University Extension Services;
                          •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by higher authorities.



                                                                                                            9]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[h.  Designated Faculty Extensionist.     The designated College/ Campus/Unit Faculty Extensionist
                          shall perform the following duties:
                          •  Assist in the conceptualization of new extension programs, projects, and other extension
                              interventions of the college/campus/unit;
                          •  Package  proposals  and  implement  community-based  development  projects,  social
                              innovations, and other high-impact and integrated extension programs and projects of
                              the college/campus/unit;
                          •  Establish partnerships and linkages with various government agencies, non-government
                              organizations,  industries,  enterprises,  communities,  and  other  stakeholders  for  the
                              effective  implementation  of  extension  programs,  projects,  and  activities  of  the
                              college/campus/unit;
                          •  Attend regular meetings and other related activities of designated faculty extensionists;
                          •  Prepare   and   submit   progress   and   accomplishment   reports (i.e., monthly, quarterly,
                              and annually) to the campus/college/unit and/or University Extension Services; and
                          •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by higher authorities.

               Article 3. Extension Services Resources

                   Section 1. Human Resources

                   a.  Extension Services Director.  The Extension Services Director must possess the following
                       qualifications:
                       •  Must  have  at  least  a  Master’s  Degree,  preferably  with  Doctoral units/degree
                       •  Must have at least one (1) year of administrative experience
                       •  Must have at least one (1) year of experience in extension work
                       •  Must hold a permanent position
                       •  Must have no administrative or criminal case

                   b.  Support Staff. The Extension Services support staff should be of different disciplines related to
                       the  thrusts  of  the  University.  They shall  be  selected using  the  evaluation  system  stated  in
                       Sections 1 to 5 of Rule VIII (Terms and Conditions of Employment) of the University Code. All
                       support staff shall be selected based on the qualifications set by  the Civil Service Commission.

                   c.   College/Campus/Unit Extension Coordinator. The College/Campus/Unit Extension Coordinator
                       is designated by the College Dean/Campus Administrator/Unit Director. He/she must possess the
                       following qualifications:

                       •  Must have at least a Master’s Degree
                       •  Must have at least one (1) year of experience in extension work
                       •  Must hold a permanent position
                       •  Preferably do not have other designations
                       •  If a faculty, preferably do not have a teaching load of no more than 6 units per semester
                       •  Must have no administrative or criminal case

                   c.  Designated  Faculty  Extensionist.  At  least  one  (1)  faculty  extensionist  shall  be  selected  and
                       designated per College/Campus. He/she must possess the following classifications:



                                                                                                           10]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[•  Must have at least a Master’s Degree
                       •  Must have at least one (1) year of experience in extension work
                       •  Must hold a permanent position
                       •  Preferably do not have other designations
                       •  Preferably do not have a teaching load of no more than 6 units per semester

                       The designation of faculty  extensionist is renewable every two years subject to performance
                       evaluation.

                   Section  2.  Facilities.   The  Extension  Services  houses  the  Technology Demonstration Farm which
               serves as a showcase platform of different farming systems and agri-fisheries technologies. This aims to
               assist the farmers, fisherfolks, students, and other clients to have actual exposures and experiences in
               the operation of a farm or an agro-entrepreneurial project.

                   Section 3. Finance

                   a.  Sources  of  Funds.          Financial  resources  are  generated  through  grants,  donations,  bilateral
                       agreements,  and  collaborations  with  government  agencies,  non-government  organizations,
                       foreign funding institutions, and other agencies and councils.

                       There are two major classifications of fund sources: the internal and external funds. The internal
                       funds come from the general appropriation allocation  (GAA)  of  the  Philippine  government.
                       The  Unit  also  generates fund from various income generating projects of the University and a
                       portion of which is allocated for the conduct of the University’s extension activities.

                       On  the  other  hand,  the  external  funds  can  come  from  government  agencies  such  as
                       Department of Agriculture (DA), Department of Science and Technology (DOST), Department of
                       Interior and Local Government (DILG), Department  of  Agrarian  Reform  (DAR),  Department  of
                       Social  Welfare  and  Development  (DSWD),  Local  Government  Unit  (LGUs);  non-government
                       organizations; private individuals; and other institutions both in the Philippines and abroad.

                   b.  Handling  of  Extension  Funds.   All  funds  of  Extension  Services  are  handled by the  Finance
                       Management Office in coordination with the Office of the Extension Services Director.   Books
                       of   Accounts   are   kept   by   the   Accounting Department which is under the supervision of the
                       Vice President for Administrative and Support Services (VPASS). Personnel is assigned at the
                       Accounting Department to handle documents of all extension programs, projects, and activities
                       of the University to expedite processing.

                       External grants are treated as trust funds. Funds are released to the Accounting Department by
                       project allotment whereby program/project leaders handle the processing of papers to release
                       the  fund  meant  for  their  extension  programs/projects  in  coordination  with  the  Office  of
                       Extension  Services  Director.  Funds  allocated  from  the  income  generating  projects  are  also
                       handled by the Accounting Department and managed by the Extension Services Director.

                   c.   Management of Extension Services Funds.  Extension Services funds shall be reported in terms
                      of  obligation  or  liquidation.  The  Accounting  Department  monitors  the  expenditures  in
                      accordance  with  the  items  in  the  budget  and  sub-allotment.  Payrolls,  vouchers,  request  for
                      supplies and materials and other obligation of the projects shall be paid through the Accounting


                                                                                                           11]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Department  with  approval  from  the  Vice  President  for  Administrative  and  Support  Services
                      following the accounting and auditing rules and regulations.

                       As  with  any  government  agency,  expenditures  incurred  in  the  implementation  of  extension
                       programs in State Universities and Colleges (SUCs) shall be subjected to auditing procedures
                       prescribed  by  the  COA.  The  internal  audit  which  is  under  the  supervision  of  the  Office  of
                       University President and a representative from COA shall conduct the auditing.


               Article  4.  Submission  of  Proposal,  Implementation,  and  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Extension
               Programs, Projects, and Activities

                    Section 1. Extension Interventions, Programs/Projects, and Activities. The University shall engage
               in  the  following  extension  interventions,  programs/projects,  and  activities:  (1)  Capability  Building
               Programs;  (2)  Technical  Assistance,  Advisory  Services,  Consultancy,  and  Other  Support  Services;  (3)
               Communication  and  Information  Services;  (4)  Technology  Promotion,  Transfer,  Utilization,  and
               Commercialization; (5) Community-Based Development Projects,  Social Innovations, and Other High-
               Impact  and  Integrated  Extension  Programs/Projects;  and  (6)  Community  Outreach  Activities  and
               Volunteer Programs.

                    1.1. College/Campus/Unit-Funded. All colleges, campuses, and extension implementing units shall
                        package program/project/activity proposals and submit for evaluation and approval prior to
                        implementation.  All  proposals  must  be  aligned  with  the  approved  University  and
                        College/Campus/Unit  Extension  Agenda  and  program  offerings  of  the  college/campus  or
                        mandate of the extension unit.

                         1.1.1. Program/Project. College/campus/unit program/project proposal must be prepared
                               using the prescribed format of the Extension Services and must be endorsed by the
                               College  Dean/Campus  Administrator/Unit  Director  to  the  Extension  Services.  An
                               extension  project  is  a  unique  and  temporary  endeavor  composed  of  various
                               approaches, strategies, methods, and interrelated activities which must be completed
                               to attain a certain outcome over a specified period. An extension program is composed
                               of at least two related extension projects.

                         1.1.2.  Activity. Other extension activities that are not part of any program or project must be
                               approved prior to implementation. An activity proposal must be prepared using the
                               prescribed  format  of  the  Extension  Services  and  must  be  endorsed  by  the  College
                               Dean/Campus Administrator/Unit Director to the Extension Services. Activity proposals
                               included  in  the  approved  extension  plan  of  the  college/campus/unit  shall  be
                               prioritized. Extension activities shall include conduct of trainings, provision of technical
                               assistance,  advisory  services,  consultancy,  and  other  support  services,  provision  of
                               communication and information services, and conduct of community  outreach and
                               volunteer activities.

                         1.1.3. Eligibility of the Proponent. Any faculty or extension staff (temporary or permanent) is
                               eligible and encouraged to submit program/project/activity proposals. The extension
                               worker  must  possess  the  academic  qualifications  and  track  record  of  successful
                               implementation of programs/projects/activities.


                                                                                                           12]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[1.1.3.  Screening  and  Approval.  Program/project  proposal  submitted  by  the  college/
                               campus/unit  shall  be  recorded  and  prescreened  by  the  Extension  Services.  After
                               passing  the  prescreening,  it  shall  be  presented  by  the  proponent  to  the  selected
                               members of the REC for evaluation. Once the proposal passed the evaluation, it shall
                               be endorsed to the OVPRE for the subsequent approval of the President. It shall also
                               be forwarded to the Administrative Council for subsequent endorsement to the Board
                               of Regents for confirmation.

                               Activity  proposal  submitted  by  the  college/campus/unit  shall  be  recorded  and
                               evaluated by the Extension Services. After passing the evaluation, it shall be forwarded
                               to the OVPRE for subsequent endorsement to the President for approval.

                    1.2.  Extension Grant.  Each year, the college/campus/unit shall allocate funds to support and give
                         priority to community-based development projects, social innovations, and high-impact and
                         integrated extension programs/projects that are multidisciplinary and shall utilize research
                         outputs.  The  extension  project  must  be  a  unique  and  temporary  endeavor  composed  of
                         various approaches, strategies, methods, and interrelated activities and must be completed
                         to  attain  a  certain  outcome  over  a  specified  period.  An  extension  program  can  also  be
                         considered for funding if it is composed of at least two related extension projects.

                         The  conduct  of  impact  assessment  of  extension  project/s  may  also  be  funded  under  the
                         extension  grant.  The  Extension  Services/college/campus/unit  shall  tap  and  commission
                         expert/s from other agencies who has/have the education, experience, and skills required to
                         perform the assessment.

                         1.2.1.  Eligibility of the Proponent. Any faculty or extension staff (temporary or permanent)
                               is  eligible  and  encouraged  to  submit  proposals.  The  extension  implementer  must
                               possess the academic qualifications and track record of successful implementation of
                               projects.

                               The  Extension  Services  and/or  OVPRE  may  directly  solicit  proposals  from  selected
                               faculty and staff as the need arises.

                         1.2.2. Submission of Proposal.  All colleges/campuses/units shall be encouraged to package
                               and submit   program/project proposal using the prescribed format of the Extension
                               Services  and it must be  endorsed by the College Dean/Campus Administrator/Unit
                               Director to the Extension Services.

                         1.2.3.  Amount of Grant. A maximum of PhP 200,000 grant money per proponent shall be
                               awarded for a one-year extension project. A higher amount may be granted based on
                               justifiable reasons and soundness of the proposal. Once all legal and documentary
                               requirements  have  been  accomplished,  70%  of  the  total  amount  of  grant  shall  be
                               released  to  the proponent. The  remaining  balance shall only be released  after the
                               Monitoring and Evaluation Division (MED) had issued Certificate of Acceptability. It
                               means that the project had undergone and passed on-site monitoring, semi-annual
                               review, and financial monitoring.



                                                                                                           13]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[In the case of multi-year projects (with duration of more than one year), release of
                               grant money shall be on an annual basis and shall depend on its yearly budgetary
                               requirement. Funds for the succeeding year/s shall only be released after the MED had
                               issued Certificate of Acceptability.

                   1.2.4.    Screening  and  Approval.  Extension  Grant  program/project      proposal  submitted  by  the
                          college/campus/unit shall be recorded  and  prescreened by the Extension Services. After
                          passing the prescreening, it shall be presented by the proponent to the selected members of
                          the REC for evaluation. Once the proposal passed the evaluation, it shall be endorsed to the
                          OVPRE for the subsequent approval of the President. New program/project proposals not
                          under the existing banner program of the University, colleges, campuses, and units, shall be
                          forwarded to the Administrative Council for its subsequent endorsement to the Board of
                          Regents for approval.


                    1.2.  External Grants. The Extension Services, colleges, campuses, and other extension implementing
                         units  are  tasked  to  prepare  project  proposals  for  external  funding  to  be  submitted  in
                         accordance  with  the  funding  agency‘s  extension  thrusts  and  priorities  and  following  the
                         agency’s prescribed format. However, in the absence of any desired format, the CHED’s format
                         for extension proposal may be used (Appendix A. CHED NAFES Proposal Format).   In   the
                         event   that   the   funding   agency requires   counterpart funds, the matter shall be first
                         discussed with the  OVPRE and  with consideration of the  Commission on Audit (COA) and
                         Department of Budget and Management (DBM) Rules and Regulations.

                         1.2.1. Eligibility of the Proponent. Any faculty or extension staff (temporary or permanent) is
                               eligible and encouraged to submit proposals. The extension worker must possess the
                               academic qualifications and track record of successful implementation of projects.

                               The  Extension  Services  and/or  OVPRE  may  directly  solicit  proposals  from  selected
                               faculty and staff as the need arises.

                         1.2.2. Submission of and Prescreening of Proposal.  Prior to submission of the proposal to the
                               funding agency, it must be endorsed by the College Dean/Campus Administrator/Unit
                               Director  to  the  Extension  Services.  Once  recorded  and  prescreened,  the  Extension
                               Services shall assist in requesting the endorsement of the proposal from the Office of
                               the  Vice  President  for  Research  and  Extension  and  Office  of  the  President  to  the
                               funding agency. The proposal shall also be forwarded to the REC and Administrative
                               Council for subsequent endorsement to the Board of Regents for confirmation.












                                                                                                           14]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Section 2. Evaluation of the Extension Program/Project Proposal

                    2.1.    Submission   of   Program/Project   Proposal.  The Extension Services requires that proposals
                         be  submitted  in  electronic  copy  together  with:  (1)  endorsement  letter  from  the  College
                         Dean/Campus Administrator/Unit Head; (2) accomplished HGDG checklist; and (3) curriculum
                         vitae of the proponent.

                         Copy  of  the  proposal  including  the  necessary  attachments  must  be  sent  via  email  at
                         extension@cvsu.edu.ph. Endorsement letter should be addressed to:

                         The Director
                         Extension Services
                         Cavite State University
                         Don Severino delas Alas Campus
                         Indang, Cavite

                         Note: Prior to submission, all proposals must have been pre-evaluated by the proponent using
                         the Harmonized Gender and Development Guidelines (HGDG) Program/Project Development
                         Evaluation Checklist.

                    2.2.  Pre-Screening of Program/Project Proposal.  All proposals submitted shall be prescreened by
                         the MED of the Extension Services to determine its completeness, conformity with the format,
                         non-duplication, and alignment with the University Extension Agenda.

                         A  representative  from  the  concerned  Commodity  RDE  Center  shall  also  be  requested  to
                         initially screen commodity-specific extension proposals (i.e., coffee, makapuno, and kaong)
                         received from the colleges/campuses.

                         In case there is a need for revision, one week shall be given to the proponent to revise the
                         proposal.

                    2.3.  En Banc Evaluation of Program/Project Proposals. Once program/project proposal (for funding
                         of the University) passed the prescreening, it shall be presented by the proponent to the
                         selected  members  of  the  REC  for  evaluation.    The  following  criteria  shall  be  used  for
                         evaluation:

                         a.  Contribution of the program/project to regional/national development (30%)
                         b.  Contribution to the advancement of target community/ clientele (30%)
                         c.  Quality of information/technology to be promoted/ disseminated (20%)
                         d.  Appropriateness of approaches/strategies/methods (20%)

                         Proponents shall be notified of the results of the evaluation whether their proposal passed,
                         needs revision or rejected.  If it needs revision, the proponent shall be given ample time to
                         revise the proposal.

                         For program/project seeking external funds, the proposal shall no longer be presented to the
                         REC.



                                                                                                           15]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Section 3. Budget Allocation. Upon approval of the REC, the program/project proposals shall be
               endorsed to the OVPRE for the subsequent approval of the President. Once finally approved, the budget
               shall  be  allocated  for  the  implementation  of  the  extension  programs/projects  to  be  funded  by  the
               University either through the college/campus/unit or the Extension Grant.

                   The GADRC and/or concerned Commodity R&E Center shall be furnished with copy of the approved
               proposals.

                   Extension projects seeking external fund must conform to the requirements and procedures of the
               funding agency. The proponents are required to submit to the Extension Services copy of the approval
               letter,  signed  and  notarized  memorandum  of  agreement,  approved  program/project  proposal,
               photocopy of the check voucher or other records of fund transfer, and other pertinent documents.

                   Section 4. Endorsement of Program/Project Proposal. All program/project proposals which passed
               the evaluation by the REC shall be endorsed to the OVPRE for the subsequent approval of the President.
               New  program/project  proposals  not  under  the  existing  banner  program  of  the  University,  colleges,
               campuses, and units, shall be forwarded to the Administrative Council for its subsequent endorsement
               to the Board of Regents for approval.

                   Section 5. Processing of Funds.    The Extension Services shall assist in facilitating the processing of
               funds for extension programs/projects approved under the Extension Grant. The release of funds shall
               depend  on  the  approved  line-item  budget  subject  to  usual  accounting  and  auditing  rules.  It  is  the
               responsibility of the proponent to liquidate cash advances and expenses related to the program/project.

                   For  extension  programs/projects  (including  approved  activity  proposals)  to  be  funded  by  the
               college/campus/unit, the proponent shall facilitate the processing and disbursement of funds according
               to the approved line-item budget.

                   Section  6.  Program/Project  Implementation.  After  approval  of  the  proposal  for  funding,  the
               program/project proponent/s must attend a pre-implementation meeting to finalize the project timeline,
               activities, and deliverables of the program/project and to be reminded of their duties and obligations
               during and after the period of implementation.

                    6.1.  Pre-Implementation Meeting.   A pre-implementation meeting shall be conducted prior to the
                         start  of  implementation  of  extension  program/project.  It  aims  to  fine-tune  or  finalize  the
                         program/project  implementation  timelines  as  well  as  the  monitoring  and  evaluation
                         arrangements.

                         During  the  said  meeting,  a  Special  Order  indicating  the  proponent/s  and  their  terms  of
                         reference, Notice to Proceed, and first tranche of project funds (if program/project is under
                         the Extension Grant) shall be issued/released to the proponent. Also, duration (start and end)
                         of the program/project shall also be adjusted (if necessary) and finalized.

                         The Extension Services shall set the schedule and venue of the meeting. Pre-implementation
                         meeting is usually conducted only once but in case there are issues or recommendations not
                         threshed out during the meeting, a follow-up pre-implementation meeting may be agreed
                         upon.



                                                                                                           16]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[The following are expected to attend the pre-implementation meeting:

                         b.  Extension Services Director/representative
                         c.  Extension M&E Division Staff (shall serve as the moderator during the meeting)
                         d.  Proponent/s
                         e.  Extension   Coordinator   of   the   College/Campus/Unit   where   the proponent belongs
                         f.  Representative from OVPRE
                         g.  Representative from Administration Office
                         h.  Representative from Finance Office
                         i.  Technical expert (identified by the Extension Services) *

                         * The identified expert shall serve as one of the evaluators for the whole duration of the
                         project.

                         During the pre-implementation meeting, the proponent shall present the general framework
                         of the program/project, its strategies for implementation including the work plan and budget
                         summary. The M&E Division staff of the Extension Services shall discuss the parameters for
                         monitoring and evaluating the project. Meanwhile, representatives from the Administration
                         and Finance Offices shall present the guidelines for purchasing supplies and materials, hiring
                         project staff, among others. All comments and recommendations shall be documented by the
                         M&E Division. Afterwards, a copy of the highlights of the meeting shall be distributed to all
                         the attendees for their guidance.

                         External funding agencies also require pre-implementation meetings. The proponent must
                         invite at least the campus/college/unit extension coordinator concerned and a representative
                         from the Monitoring and Evaluation Division of the Extension Services  to  attend  the pre-
                         implementation meeting organized by the external funding agency.

                    6.2.   Hiring/Appointment of   Personnel   and Professional Services. Upon the approval of the
                         proposal, the proponent or the appointed project leader is authorized to hire the necessary
                         project  staff  or  expert  required  to  conduct  and  complete  the  deliverables  of  the  project
                         (internally and externally funded). The hired or appointed staff must be paid for the services
                         they rendered; provided that the terms, conditions, and salary rates are strictly in accordance
                         with the approved line-item budget of the project and following the accounting and auditing
                         rules and regulations of the University.

                    6.3.    Responsibilities of the Program/Project Personnel

                         a.  Program  Leader.        The  Program  Leader  shall  perform  the  following  functions  in  the
                             implementation of the program:
                             •  Provide overall direction in terms of setting common directions of the projects under
                                the program;
                             •  Set the work plan of the various projects to establish synchronicity and coordination
                                between  project  activities  and  schedule  in  order  to  attain  the  objectives  of  the
                                program;
                             •  Represent the program in dealing with collaborating and other external agencies; and
                             •  In cases where the Program Leader is concurrently the Project Leader of a component
                                project, he/she must also accomplish the duties expected of a Project Leader.


                                                                                                           17]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[b.  Project  Leader.          The  Project  Leader  shall  perform  the  following  functions  in  the
                             implementation of the program:
                             •  Plan, organize and direct the overall conduct of the project;
                             •  Spearhead the conduct of extension activities;
                             •  Hire   and   recommend   the   appointment   of   the   required   project personnel;
                             •  Recommend payment   of salaries and   compensations of project personnel; and
                             •  Prepare and submit progress reports, annual reports, and terminal report

                         c.  Project Staff/Extension Officer
                             •  Assist  the  Project  Leader  in  planning  and  managing  overall  extension  project
                                operations;
                             •  Initiate the daily conduct of extension activities;
                             •  Supervise  the  collection  of  necessary  data  and  materials  related  to  the  extension
                                activities; and
                             •  Assist the Project Leader in preparing progress reports

                   6.4.   Collaborations.   Established linkages and collaborations must have either a Memorandum of
                         Agreement  or  Memorandum  of  Understanding  forged  between  the  University  and  the
                         collaborating  agency/institution/establishment.  The  agreement  must  be  reviewed  by  the
                         University’s Legal Officer. The document shall be duly signed by the parties involved and shall
                         be notarized by authorized legal authorities.

                         Terms of reference, responsibilities of each party, contents and other pertinent items shall be
                         discussed between the concerned parties before drawing the agreements.

                   6.5.   Conduct of Trainings.  The conduct of trainings/seminars/ workshops related to the extension
                         program/project shall be in accordance with the approved work and financial plan. An activity
                         proposal must be prepared using the prescribed format of the Extension Services and must be
                         endorsed by the College Dean/Campus Administrator/Unit Director to the Extension Services.
                         It  shall  be  recorded  and  prescreened  by  the  Extension  Services.  Afterwards,  it  shall  be
                         forwarded to the OVPRE for subsequent endorsement to the President for approval.

                         Request   from   other   stakeholders   and   partner communities and agencies may also be
                         conducted provided that they have sent letter of request to the University President who has
                         the sole authority to approve the request.

                    6.6.  Resource  Persons/s  for  Trainings  and  Other  Related  Activities.  The  proponent  may  invite
                         expert/s from other local and international agencies to serve as resource person if necessary.
                         The  invited  resource  persons  shall  be  granted  with  honoraria.  The  DBM  Budget  Circular
                         Number  2007-01  (Guidelines  on  the  Grant  of  Honoraria  to  lecturers,  resource  persons,
                         coordinators,  and  facilitators)  shall  be  adopted  (Appendix  B).  For  DOST  funded
                         programs/projects/activities,  DOST  Memorandum  Circular  No.  001,  Series  of  2009
                         (Amendment to Memorandum Circular No. 001, Series of 2003, otherwise known as “Revised
                         Implementing Guidelines on the Grant of Honoraria to personnel whose Services are Engaged
                         by the National Science and Technology System”) (Appendix C) shall be used as basis.




                                                                                                           18]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Section 7. Monitoring and Evaluation of Extension Programs/Projects.  To ensure efficient and
               effective  program/project  implementation,  monitoring  and  evaluation  shall  be  conducted  by  the
               Monitoring and Evaluation Division with the identified technical expert.

                   7.1.   Progress Reports.  All project proponents are required to submit an electronic copy of their
                         quarterly  reports  (for  a  one-year  program/project),  semi-annual  (for  a  multi-year
                         program/project)  and  annual  reports  duly  endorsed  by  the  College  Dean/Campus
                         Administrator/Unit Director. The concerned Commodity R&E Center shall be furnished with a
                         copy of the progress reports.

                         For externally funded projects, the Extension Services shall be furnished with copy of the
                         progress report/s submitted by the proponent/s to the funding agency.

                         For  PCAARRD  funded  projects,  the  Southern  Tagalog  Agriculture,  Aquatic  and  Resources
                         Research, Development, and Extension Consortium (STAARRDEC) shall be furnished with all
                         the reports submitted to PCAARRD.

                         Note: Prior to submission of the annual report, all programs/projects must have been pre-
                         evaluated  by  the  proponent  using  the  Harmonized  Gender  and  Development  Guidelines
                         (HGDG) Project Monitoring and Evaluation Checklist.

                   7.2.   On-site/Field  Monitoring.  If  necessary,  on-site  or  field  monitoring shall  be  conducted  to
                         validate the progress reports submitted by the proponent. The schedule shall be set by the
                         Extension Services MED.

                   7.3.   Semi-Annual/Annual Review.   Semi-annual and annual reviews are conducted to determine
                         the continuance or termination of an extension program/project. Schedule of which shall be
                         set by the Extension Services. Selected members of REC and/or experts from other institutions
                         shall be invited as evaluators during the review.

                         During the review, proponents shall present the progress and plans for the continuation of
                         implementation    of   the   program/project.   Evaluators   shall   provide   their
                         comments/suggestions/ recommendations on the progress report and presentation. The MED
                         shall document, integrate/consolidate the given comments and suggestions. The same shall
                         provide  the  proponents  copy  of  the  review  results  for  their  guidance.  Once  the
                         program/project  passed  the  review,  a  Certificate  of  Acceptability  shall  be  issued  to  the
                         proponent.

                         The  Extension  Services  reserves  the  right  to  discontinue  the  project  anytime  upon  due
                         consultation with the proponent and the technical expert/s and upon the approval of the
                         President  if  there  is  a  violation  of  the  contract  or  if  the  soundness  of  the  extension
                         program/project becomes questionable.

                    Section 8. Annual Extension Conference.  The Extension Conference is regularly carried out by the
               Office of Extension Services to evaluate all extension programs/projects of various colleges, campuses,
               and  other  extension  implementing  units  of  the  University  either  completed  or  on-going  during  the
               particular  year  under  review.  During  reviews,  extensionists  present  the  progress/highlights  of  their
               projects to effectively disseminate the significant accomplishments and best practices as well as to help


                                                                                                           19]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[identify areas for improvement in the implementation of on-going projects. Experts within and outside
               the University are invited to serve as reactors.

                    8.1.    Goals.  The goals of conducting annual extension conference are to:

                         a.  Establish an additional institutional mechanism for the monitoring and evaluation of the
                             different extension programs/projects/activities of the University;
                         b.  Increase   faculty   and   staff   participation   in   extension   programs/projects/activities;
                         c.  Acquire papers on extension which are acceptable for publication; and
                         d.  Improve techniques, strategies and/or approaches in extension.

                    8.2.    Objectives.  In  general,  the  annual  extension  conference  aims  to  disseminate  the  most
                         significant  extension  findings  and  best  practices  of  the  colleges,  campuses,  and  other
                         extension implementing units of the University. Specifically, it aims to:

                         a.  Evaluate  completed  and  on-going  extension  projects  regarding  the  attainment  of
                             objectives and adherence to the approved program of activities;
                         b.  Identify  problems  met  during  the  project  implementation  and  recommend  specific
                             courses of action;
                         c.  Evaluate significant results/information for policy formulation and planning; and
                         d.  Recognize and award commendable extension programs/projects/activities.

                   8.3.   Schedule.   The annual extension conference shall be conducted every third quarter of the year.

                   8.4.    Discussant/Reactor.  The University shall invite experts to serve as discussants/reactors during
                        the extension conference. Experts from other agencies may also be invited if necessary.

                        8.4.1. External Reactors. Invited external reactors should have the following qualifications:

                               a.  Must  come  from  the  academe,  agencies,  or  industry;  regional,  national,  or
                                   international; public or private; and actively involved in RDE relevant to the subject
                                   matter
                               b.  Must have  at least  three years of experience in the field related  to  the subject
                                   matter

                        8.4.2.  Functions.  Invited  internal  and  external  reactors  shall  perform  the  following
                               responsibilities:

                               a.  Conduct  in-depth  review  of  extension  proposals  or  evaluation  of  extension  on-
                                   going/completed programs/projects based on the approved set of criteria
                               b.  Give suggestions to help improve the proposal or recommend courses of action
                                   necessary based on the results of evaluation of on-going and completed extension
                                   programs/projects
                               c.  Accomplish prescribed review/evaluation forms

                   8.5.  Evaluation Criteria.  The major criteria that shall be used in evaluating the on-going extension
                        programs/projects are the following:



                                                                                                           20]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[a.  Attainment of objectives
                        b.  Significance of findings for the period
                        c.  Adherence to the approved methodology
                        d.  Adherence to the approved budget
                        e.  Timely delivery of outputs
                        f.  Presentation

                        For completed extension programs/projects, the major criteria for evaluation that shall be used
                        are the following:

                        a.  Creativity, originality, and quality of work
                        b.  Significance of findings
                        c.  Manuscript/write-up
                        d.  Presentation

                   8.6.   Awards.  During extension conference, the awards shall include but not limited to the following:

                        a.  Best Extension Project/s (completed and on-going)
                        b.  Best Extension Video/s or Poster/s

                   Section  9.  Request  for  Extending  the  Program/Project.  Requests  for  extension  of  the
               program/project shall only be entertained at least three (3) months before the expected completion
               date. Requests for project extension shall be submitted to the Extension Services and shall be supported
               by the following documents:

                    a.  Request letter duly endorsed by the College Dean/Campus Administrator/Unit Director
                    b.  Latest accomplishment report
                    c.  Latest financial report
                    d.  Revised Work Plan
                    e.  Justification for extension

                   There  shall  be  no  additional  budget  that  shall  be  released  for  program/project  extension.  A
               program/project  proponent  shall  only  be  allowed  once  to  request  for  project  extension.  However,
               another request for extension of the program/project may be entertained for justifiable reasons.

                   Section 10. Project Completion/Termination

                   10.1.  Submission  of  Completion/Terminal  Report.  Not  more  than  thirty  (30)  days  after  the
                        program/project was completed/terminated, an electronic copy of the completion/terminal
                        report, duly endorsed by the  College Dean/Campus Administrator/Unit Director, should be
                        submitted.

                        The  terminal  report  should  be  accompanied  by  financial  report  and  other  supporting
                        documents such as photos, evaluation sheets, IEC materials, Community Needs Assessment,
                        training reports, and other outputs that may show the results of the activities conducted.

                        Undisbursed funds shall be returned to the Cashier and an official receipt shall be properly
                        issued.


                                                                                                           21]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[10.2. Conduct of Terminal Review.   A terminal review is conducted after the completion of an
                        extension  program/project  to  determine  if  the  proposed  objectives  were  met.  A  panel  of
                        evaluators, which is composed of technical experts from within or outside the University shall
                        be invited as evaluators.

                   Section 11. Publication.   Proponent/s with outputs that are publishable should submit at least one
               article (per study) to the CvSU Research Journal or any reputable journal for possible publication. It is the
               responsibility of the proponent to ensure that the Extension Services is furnished a copy of the evidence
               of submission including the copy of the article submitted.

                   Section 12. Intellectual Property.  For output  that is new, novel or an inventive technique, the
               proponent  is  advised  to  seek  assistance  from  Intellectual  Property  Management  Office  (IPMO)  for
               application of IP protection.

                   Section 13. Paper Presentation.  The extension paper may be presented in any regional, national, or
               international extension conference, fora, seminar, or meeting as long as full acknowledgement shall be
               given to the University. Also, the presentation should not prejudice the proprietary/confidential nature
               of the information for the purposes of IP protection.

               Article 5. Awards and Incentives for Conducting Extension Programs/Projects/Activities

                   Section 1. Workload.  Workload points shall be given to a faculty member as incentive for conducting
               extension  programs/projects/activities  based  on  the  guidelines  set  in  the  Unified  Workload  System
               approved by the Board of Regents during its 70th Regular Meeting held on March 24, 2017.   It covers
               the core (e.g., instruction, research and extension) and strategic (e.g., administrative assignments and
               other services) functions of a faculty member (Appendix D. University Workload System).

                   Section 2. Honorarium.  A faculty or staff involved in extension programs/projects is entitled to
               receive honoraria from externally-funded programs/projects provided that it is clearly indicated in the
               approved line-item budget (LIB).

                   No honorarium from the University’s fund is given to the extension worker in accordance   with   DBM
               Budget   Circular   2007-1   Approved   on   April   23, 2007. Furthermore, all extension activities with
               honorarium shall be excluded from the computation of work overload pay of the faculty extensionist.

                   Section 3. Publication Awards.  A monetary and certificate of recognition shall be given to faculty
               and  staff  who  published  extension-related  articles  in  scientific  journals  based  on  the  Guidelines  for
               Granting Incentives for Publication of Faculty and Staff (Appendix E) approved during the 63rd Regular
               Meeting of the CvSU's Board of Regents held on March 19, 2015.

                   Section  4.  Best  Extension  Performing  College/Campus/Unit.  The  objective  of  this  award  is  to
               compensate  and  give  due  recognition  to  the  concerted  efforts  and  exemplary  accomplishments  in
               extension of the different colleges, campuses, and other extension implementing units of the University.

                   The awarding shall be done during the Annual Extension Conference. A special committee shall be
               formed to conduct the selection of the Best Extension Performing College/Campus/Unit. The criteria for




                                                                                                           22]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[evaluation shall be based on indicators of MFO 3, MFO 4, KRA 2, KRA 3 and KRA 4. Other indicators maybe
               included if necessary. The college/campus/unit with the highest points shall be declared as the winner.

                   The winner shall receive Plaque of Recognition.

                   Section 5. Special Awards. To encourage effectiveness and further enhance the delivery of extension
               services, special awards such as Best Extension Coordinator and Best Faculty Extensionist shall also be
               given. A plaque of recognition shall be received by the winners. The award shall be given during the
               Annual Extension Conference.

                   Section 6. Travel Grant.   The University provides travel grant to its faculty members and staff to
               present their extension papers in recognized conference/forum. It is the responsibility of the concerned
               personnel  to  facilitate  the  processing  of  their  request  for  travel  including  the  necessary  travel
               arrangements.


























































                                                                                                           23]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITKSTATEUlflVERSITY
                                           Don Soverino de hu Akn Campus
                                                    Indang. CavitS
                                               (046)4150-010 / (046) 4150-011
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.nh






                        EXCERPT FROM THE MINUTES OF THE ADMINISTRATIVE COUNCIL MEETING
                      HELD ON OCTOBER 12, 2017 AT THE LASAP HALL, ADMINISTRATION BUILDING
                                      CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY, INDANG, CAWTE


                                                RESOLUTION NO. 60-A
                                                   SERIES OF 2017
                                 A resolution endorsing the Revised Manual of Operations to the
                          Board of Regents tor approval.





















                                   , CEO VI


















           .K  v]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Volume 5



                                                    EXTENSION SERVICES




                                                        INTRODUCTION


                              As  mandated,  the  University  shall  “provide  advanced  instruction  and

                       professional training in agriculture, science and technology, education and other related


                       fields, undertake research and extension services, and provide progressive leadership in

                       these areas.”  (Republic Act No. 8468, converting the Don Severino Agricultural College


                       into University Status, to be called Cavite State University).

                              The Republic Act No. 8435, or the Agriculture and Fisheries Modernization Act


                       of 1997 (AFMA) under section 86 stated that: “It is hereby declared the policy of the

                       state  to  promote  science  and  technology,  as  essential  for  national  development  and

                       progress.  The State shall give priority to the utilization of research results through formal


                       and non-formal education, extension and training services.”

                              Extension project or programs are set of activities aimed to transfer knowledge or


                       technology  or  to  provide  services  to  the  community  in  consonance  with  the  programs

                       being  offered  by  the  University.  It  is  being  conducted  as  an  outreach  towards  the


                       improvement of the community’s quality of life (CHED CMO No. 22, s 2008).


                       Article 1. Extension Services Goal, Objectives, Agenda, and Banner Program

                              Section  1.  Goals.    The  Extension  Services  of  Cavite  State  University  (CvSU)


                       shall be geared towards the improvement of the lives of the community especially those

                       that belong to economically and socially disadvantaged sectors through the conduct of]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[2


                       relevant  education  and  training;  farm  and  business  advisory  activities;  demonstration

                       projects; and information, communication and technology services.


                              Section  2.  Objectives.    The  University  shall  provide  excellent  and  socially-

                       responsive extension services to its target clientele.


                              Specifically, it aims to:

                              1.  conduct and/or coordinate relevant training programs as well as appropriate,


                                 efficient and sustainable interdisciplinary extension programs;

                              2.  promote community and social enterprises;


                              3.  coordinate and monitor the extension activities of various colleges and branch

                                 campuses of the University;


                              4.  establish linkages with government and private agencies engaged in extension

                                 and development;

                              5.  coordinate with the Office of the Vice President for Resource Generation and


                                 Production (OVPRGP) in promoting agricultural and other potential income-

                                 generating projects; and


                              6.  promote gender-responsive extension programs and activities.


                              Section 3. University Extension Agenda.  The University shall pursue extension

                       agenda which are responsive to the specific needs of the community brought by present


                       environmental  and  developmental  challenges.  Guided  by  the  local  and  national

                       development thrusts, the University research and extension agenda shall be focused but


                       not limited on the following:

                              1.  Agri-Fisheries  and  Food  Security.    This  thematic  area  emphasizes  on


                                 developing  agriculture  and  food  systems  that  are  economically  viable  and]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[3


                                 sustainable to ensure food security as well as to improve the quality of life of

                                 farmers  and  fisherfolks.  Research  and  extension  activities  on  the  following


                                 commodities shall be given priority: coffee; kaong; rice; corn; root crops; high

                                 value  crops  (banana,  pineapple,  mango,  cacao  and  vegetables);  poultry  and


                                 livestock;  fisheries  and  aquaculture;  urban  agriculture;  and  organic

                                 agriculture.


                              2.  Biodiversity  and  Environmental  Conservation.    This  thematic  area  is

                                 concerned  with  environmental  stewardship  and  equitable  allocation  and


                                 sustainable  use  of  natural  resources.  Emphases  include:  environmental

                                 protection;  biodiversity  assessment  and  monitoring;  cleaner  environment;


                                 climate  change;  risk  reduction  management;  renewable  energy  and  green

                                 technologies; natural resource management; and ecotourism.

                              3.  Smart Engineering, Information and Communication Technology (ICT),


                                 and  Industrial  Competitiveness.    The  term  smart  engineering  covers  the

                                 methods,  processes,  systems  and  tools  for  the  cross-disciplinary,  system-


                                 oriented development of innovative and interconnected products, services and

                                 infrastructures in the field of engineering. Products and process models shall


                                 be  developed  in  which  networking  encompasses  all  stages  of  development,

                                 from interdisciplinary design, to production processes and piloting, right the


                                 way  through  product  usage  and  disposal.  Smart  engineering  is  about  the

                                 integration of appropriate product planning, development, and management to


                                 ensure  the  rapid  market-ready  implementation  of  innovative  product  and

                                 services and industrial competitiveness through digital development process.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[4


                                         The  convergence  of  the  latest  computer  science  and  ICT

                                 developments in the areas of micro-devices, mobile communication, hardware


                                 infrastructures,  internet  and  software  technologies,  image  recognition  and

                                 processing, parallel computing, complex adaptive systems and bioinformatics


                                 shall be given emphasis. Strong focus shall also be given to mathematics and

                                 statistics applications such as industrial and biological modelling, biomedical,


                                 social  and  theoretical  statistics,  computational  mathematics,  discrete  pure

                                 mathematics and physics/engineering.


                              4.  Social  Development  and  Equality.    This  thematic  area  focuses  on

                                 educational,  criminological  and  social  sciences  researches  and  development


                                 initiatives with emphasis on sustainable development, economic development,

                                 gender  and  development,  community  development,  governance,  poverty

                                 alleviation,  social  behavior,  attitude  and  norms,  capacity  building,  peace


                                 process  and  conflict  resolution,  disaster  risk  management  and  social

                                 transitions, pedagogy, special education, ICT and education, among others.


                                          This  area  aims to  create inclusive growth and development,  social

                                 harmony,  and  equal  opportunities  among  the  different  social  groups  and  to


                                 lessen economic divide, inequality and marginalization in the society.

                              5.  Public Health and Welfare.  This area deals with researches on protecting


                                 and  improving  human  health  and  welfare  which  includes  researches  on

                                 diseases  or  conditions  that  may  be  transmitted  to  humans  from  humans  or


                                 animals and vice versa as well as those connected with the environment as a

                                 whole. Disciplines that are also covered are those dealing with epidemiology,]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[5


                                 statistics,  environment,  behavior  and  sociology,  economics,  mental  health,

                                 public policy, public safety, delivery of health services,  occupational  safety


                                 and other related fields.

                              Section  4.  Banner  Program.    The  Ugnayan  2.0  is  the  new  banner  extension


                       program of Cavite State University and is the updated version of the previous Ugnayan

                       Program  which  was  originally  intended  as  a  unified  research  and  extension  program


                       focused on rural development and improving the lives of the community. Ugnayan is a

                       Tagalog word which connotes coordination and cooperation.


                              The new Ugnayan 2.0 will continue the goal of the former extension program to

                       improve  the  lives  of  the  community  and  to  help  in  alleviating  poverty  in  Cavite.  The


                       approach of this program is to establish communication, coordination, cooperation, and

                       collaboration among the University’s colleges and satellite campuses, public and private

                       industries,  and  other  stakeholders  in  providing  necessary  knowledge  and  technical


                       assistance  to  target  communities.  The  program  will  be  anchored  towards  poverty

                       alleviation with specific focus on delivering the matured technologies generated from the


                       researches of the University to the community based on their needs.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[6



                       Article 2. Extension Organization and Management

                              Section  1.  Organizational  Structure.    The  organizational  structure  of  the


                       Extension Services is shown in Figure 1.  The Extension Services is directly under the

                       supervision of the Office of the Vice President for Research and Extension (OVPRE).

                       The  center  has  four  major  divisions:  Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations


                       Division,  Monitoring and Evaluation  Division,  Training  and Courseware Development


                       Division,  and  Technology  Demonstration  and  Promotion  Division.  It  also  oversees  all

                       extension concerns of the different colleges and satellite campuses.

                              Section  2.  Functions  of  the  Extension  Services.    The  Extension  Services


                       performs the third major function of Cavite State University.  It links this educational

                       institution  with  the  community  through  the  conduct  of  non-formal  education  and


                       trainings;  technology  demonstration  and  technology  transfers  to  farmers,  fisherfolks,

                       women  and  children,  persons  with  disabilities  out-of-school  youths,  disadvantaged


                       families  and/or  households,  workers,  migrants  and  other  clients;  and  other  community

                       development activities.

                               The  Extension  Services  performs  overall  coordinative  function  among  the


                       Colleges  and  Campuses’  extension-related  activities.  It  is  tasked  to  perform  the  major

                       extension  activity  of  the  University  and  to  assist  in  the  conduct,  evaluation  and


                       monitoring of the extension activities of the different colleges and satellite campuses.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[7










































                                          Figure 1. Organizational structure of Extension Services]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[8




                              Section 3. Functions of the Major Divisions


                                 a.  Extension  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Division.    The  Extension

                                     Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Division  is  responsible  for  the  overall


                                     monitoring  and  evaluation  of  the  ongoing  extension  projects  of  the

                                     colleges and campuses of the University.


                                 b.  Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division.    The

                                     Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division  is  responsible


                                     for the implementation of activities pertaining to community development.

                                     These  activities  include  Community  Needs  Assessment,  Extension


                                     programs/projects/activities and other outreach activities.

                                 c.  Training  and  Courseware  Development  Division.    The  Training  and

                                     Courseware Development Division plans and conducts training programs


                                     based on the needs of the target communities/clienteles.

                                 d.  Technology  Demonstration  Farm  Division.    The  Technology


                                     Demonstration  Farm  Division  oversees  the  operations  of  the  Techno-

                                     Demo Farm and showcases matured technologies.


                                 e.  Technology  Promotion  Division.  The  Technology  Promotion  Division

                                     validates  and  packages  appropriate  and  matured  technology  for


                                     delivery/transfer.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[9


                              Section 4. Duties and Responsibilities

                                 a.  Director, Extension Services.  The Director of Extension Services shall


                                     perform the following functions:


                                           Prepare and implement the strategic and development plan of the

                                            Extension Services Center;

                                           Coordinate and monitor all the extension programs and activities


                                            of all the colleges and campuses;


                                           Prepare budgetary estimates for all the programs and activities of

                                            the center in coordination with division heads and project/section

                                            in charge;


                                           Design and propose new extension projects/activities/programs;


                                           Make  revisions  on  policies,  rules,  and  regulations  affecting  the

                                            Extension Services Center;

                                           Establish linkages with government and non-government agencies


                                            for the effective implementation of the extension and community

                                            outreach programs of the University;


                                           Prepare and submit yearly performance target and accomplishment

                                            reports of the Extension Services Center;


                                           Sign vouchers and RIVs up to amount approved by the University,

                                            subject to Commission on Audit (COA) rules and regulations; and


                                           Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by

                                            higher authorities.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[10


                                 b.  Head,  Extension  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Division.    The  Head  of

                                     Extension Monitoring and Evaluation Division shall perform the following


                                     duties:


                                           Conduct regular and periodic monitoring and yearly evaluation of

                                            the different extension programs/activities of each college/campus;

                                           Prepare and submit regular M&E reports (monthly, quarterly, and


                                            yearly)


                                           Monitor the conduct of trainings;

                                           Conduct follow-ups and updates on the trainees and adopters;


                                           Prepare tracer studies on the adopters and clienteles;

                                           Conduct impact assessments on extension projects and activities;


                                            and

                                           Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by


                                            higher authorities.

                                 c.  Head, Community Engagement and External Relations Division.  The


                                     Head  of  Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division  shall

                                     perform the following duties:

                                           Oversee  all  the  community  development  projects  including  the


                                            conduct    of    community      needs    assessment,    extension

                                            activities/projects and other outreach activities;


                                           Handle all outside requests for community outreach and extension

                                            services;]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[11


                                           Coordinate  the  extension  activities  of  all  the  colleges  and


                                            campuses;

                                           Provide necessary data and information to other units/divisions of


                                            the Extension Services;

                                           Establish linkages with the target communities;


                                           Establish linkages with government and non-government agencies

                                            for the effective implementation of the extension and community


                                            outreach programs of the University;

                                           Forge a good relationship with all the partner agencies/institutions;


                                           Facilitate  the  collaboration  between  the  University  and  partner

                                            agencies and private entities; and


                                           Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by

                                            higher authorities.


                                 d.  Head, Training and Courseware Development Division.  The Head of

                                     Training  and  Courseware  Development  Division  shall  perform  the


                                     following duties:

                                           Conduct  of  training  needs  assessment  in  the  target

                                            communities/clienteles;


                                           Prepare and submit training proposals for implementation;


                                           Conduct and facilitate planned/approved/requested trainings in the

                                            community;


                                           Prepare  the  training  materials/modules  appropriate  to  target

                                            clientele;]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[12


                                           Package  the  proceedings  of  all  trainings,  seminars,  and  other


                                            activities of the Extension Services;

                                           Submit proceedings or reports of each training/seminar conducted;


                                            and

                                           Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by


                                            higher authorities.

                                 e.  Head,  Technology  Demonstration  Farm  Division.    The  Head  of


                                     Technology  Demonstration  Farm  Division  shall  perform  the  following

                                     duties:

                                           Supervise the day-to-day operations of the Techno-Demo Farm;


                                           Prepare  reports  on  the  operations/management  of  the  Techno-


                                            Demo Farm;

                                           Make  necessary  recommendations  for  the  improvement  of  the

                                            Techno-Demo Farm;


                                           Manage the showcase of farming technologies among the on-site


                                            visitors and clientele;

                                           Coordinate  with  the  Research  Center  to  determine  the  matured

                                            technology and/or product of research experiments; and


                                           Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by


                                            higher authorities.

                                     f. Head, Technology Promotion Division.  The Head of the Technology

                                     Promotion Division shall perform the following duties:


                                           Establish linkages with the target communities;]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[13


                                           Assist  in  the  conduct  of  Community  Needs  Assessment  to


                                            determine    the   appropriate   technology    needed    by   the

                                            community/clientele;


                                           Validate  and  package  appropriate  technology  for  efficient

                                            delivery/transfer;


                                           Prepare reports and make necessary recommendations on possible

                                            technology transfers to be done in the community/clientele;


                                           Spearhead information dissemination activities;

                                           Facilitate technology forum, consultative dialogues, fairs, exhibits,


                                            etc.; and

                                           Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by


                                            higher authorities.

                                     g.  College/Campus  Extension  Coordinators.    The  College/Campus

                                     Extension Coordinator shall perform the following duties:


                                           Initiate the planning, implementation and evaluation of extension


                                            programs/activities in their respective colleges/campuses;

                                           Supervise,  coordinate  and  monitor  the  conduct  of  extension

                                            activities in their adopted communities;


                                           Coordinate  with  the  University  Extension  Services  the  extension


                                            activities of the campus/college;

                                           Prepare  and  submit  progress  and  accomplishment  reports

                                            (monthly,  quarterly  and  annually)  to  the  University  Extension


                                            Services;]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[14


                                           Establish linkages with government and non-government agencies


                                            for the effective implementation of the extension and community

                                            outreach programs of the College/Campus;


                                           Serve  as  a  link  between  the  College/Campus  and  the  University

                                            Extension Services;


                                           Attend the regular meeting of Extension Coordinators;

                                           Represent  the  College/Campus  during  the  Extension  in-house


                                            reviews; and

                                           Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by


                                            higher authorities.

                       Article 3. Extension Services Resources


                              Section 1. Manpower Resources

                              a.  Extension Services Director.  The Extension Services Director must possess

                                 the following qualifications:


                                           Must  have  at  least  a  Master’s  Degree,  preferably  with  Doctoral

                                            units/degree


                                           Must have at least one (1) year of administrative experience

                                           Must have at least one (1) year of experience in extension work


                                           Must hold a permanent position


                                           Must have no administrative or criminal case

                                 b.  Support Staff. The Extension Services support staff should be of different

                                     disciplines related to the thrusts of the University. They shall be selected


                                     using the evaluation system stated in Sections 1 to 5 of Rule VIII (Terms]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[15


                                     and Conditions of Employment) of the University Code. All support staff

                                     shall  be  selected  based  on  the  qualifications  set  by  the  Civil  Service


                                     Commission.

                                 c.  College/Campus  Extension  Coordinators.    The  College/  Campus


                                     Extension Coordinators must possess the following qualifications:

                                           Must have at least a Master’s Degree


                                           Must have at least one (1) year of experience in extension work


                                           Must hold a permanent position

                                           Must have no administrative or criminal case

                              Section 2. Facilities.  The Extension Services houses the Farmers’ Technology


                       Demonstration Farm which serves as a showcase platform of different farming systems

                       and technologies. This aims to assist the farmers/clients/students to have actual exposures


                       and experiences in the operation of a farm or an agro-entrepreneurial project.

                              Section 3. Finance


                              a.  Sources  of  Funds.    Financial  resources  are  generated  through  grants,

                                 donations, bilateral agreements and collaborations with government and non-


                                 government  agencies  private  institutions,  foreign  funding  institutions  and

                                 other agencies and councils.


                                         There are two major classifications of fund sources: the internal and

                                 external  funds.  The  internal  funds  come  from  the  general  appropriation

                                 allocation  (GAA)  of  the  Philippine  government.  The  Center  also  generates


                                 fund from various income generating projects of the University and a portion

                                 of which is allocated for the conduct of the University’s extension activities.]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[16


                                 On the other hand, the  external  funds can come from  government  agencies

                                 such as  Department  of  Agriculture  (DA), Department  of  Interior  and  Local


                                 Government  (DILG),  Department  of  Agriculture  -  Agricultural  Training

                                 Institute (DA-ATI),  Department  of  Agrarian  Reform  (DAR),  Department  of


                                 Social Welfare and Development (DSWD), Local Government Unit (LGUs)

                                 and  others  as  well  as  private  individuals  and  institutions  both  in  the


                                 Philippines and abroad.

                              b.  Handling of Extension Funds.  All funds of Extension Services are handled


                                 by  the  Finance  Management  Office  in  coordination  with  the  Office  of  the

                                 Extension  Director.  Books  of  Accounts  are  kept  by  the  Accounting


                                 Department  which  is  under  the  supervision  of  the  Vice  President  for

                                 Administrative and Support Services (VPASS). Personnel is assigned at the

                                 Accounting  Department  to  handle  documents  of  all  extension  projects  and


                                 activities of the University to expedite processing.

                                         External  grants  are  treated  as  trust  funds.  Funds  are  released  to  the


                                 Accounting  Department  by  project  allotment  whereby  project/study  leaders

                                 handle the processing of papers to release the fund meant for their extension


                                 projects/studies in coordination with the Extension Services Director. Funds

                                 allocated  from  the  income  generating  projects  are  also  handled  by  the


                                 Accounting Department and managed by the Extension Services Director.

                              c.  Management of Extension Services Funds.  Extension Services funds shall


                                 be reported in terms of obligation or liquidation. The Accounting Department

                                 monitors the expenditures in accordance with the items in the budget and sub-]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[17


                                 allotment.  Payrolls,  vouchers,  request  for  supplies  and  materials  and  other

                                 obligation of the projects  shall  be paid through the Accounting Department


                                 with  approval  from  the  Vice  President  for  Administrative  and  Support

                                 Services following the accounting and auditing rules and regulations.


                                         As  with  any  government  agency,  expenditures  incurred  in  the

                                 implementation of research and extension programs in State Universities and


                                 Colleges (SUCs) shall be subjected to auditing procedures prescribed by the

                                 COA.  The  internal  audit  which  is  under  the  supervision  of  the  Office  of


                                 University  President  and  a  representative  from  COA  shall  conduct  the

                                 auditing.



                       Article  4.  Grant  Opportunities,  Submission  of  Proposal,  Implementation,  and


                       Monitoring and Evaluation of Extension Projects

                              Section 1. Extension Grant Opportunities


                                 Section 1.1. CvSU  Extension Grant.   Cavite  State  University  (CvSU) has

                                 trilogy  of  functions  –  instruction,  research,  and  extension.  All  the  three

                                 functions of the University stand in a tripod in order to attain its mission of


                                 educating future leaders, expanding knowledge, and developing technological

                                 innovations and provide services to the community.


                                         Extension is very significant in the promotion of research outputs for

                                 national  development.  Without  extension,  information  and  technologies


                                 developed  and  produced  by  the  University  would  not  be  able  to  reach  its

                                 target beneficiaries.]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[18


                                         Recently,  the  Commission  on  Higher  Education  (CHED)  is

                                 strengthening  the  extension  function  of  the  Higher  Education  Institutions


                                 (HEIs).  In  fact,  the  Commission  has  Grant-In-Aids  (GIA)  for  extension

                                 programs  and  projects.  Aside  from  CHED,  other  institutions  such  as


                                 Department  of  Science  and  Technology  (DOST)  and  Department  of

                                 Agriculture (DA) provide grants for extension.


                                         To  better  reinforce  the  extension  function  of  the  University,  the

                                 creation of the CvSU Extension Grant is proposed. The grant aims to produce


                                 high quality and relevant extension projects for the promotion of community

                                 development.


                                         The  CvSU  Extension  Grant  shall  give  priority  to  extension  projects

                                 which are: aligned with the University Research and Extension Agenda; based

                                 on  the  needs  of  the  community;  utilize  University  research  outputs;


                                 multidisciplinary; and apply appropriate extension approaches, strategies and

                                 methods.


                                     Section 1.1.1. Objectives of the CvSU Extension Grant

                                     1.  To  promote  and  encourage  faculty  and  staff  to  conduct  relevant


                                         extension  activities  and/or  public  service  work  in  line  with

                                         institutional, regional, national, and global thrusts;


                                     2.  To  provide  financial  support  for  extension  projects  that  receive

                                         minimal funds; and


                                     3.  To strengthen the extension function of the University.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[19


                                     Section  1.1.2.  Amount  of  Grant.    A  maximum  of  P200,000.00  grant

                                     money per proponent shall be awarded for a one-year extension project.


                                     Once  all  legal  and  documentary  requirements  have  been  accomplished,

                                     70% of the total amount of grant shall be released to the proponent. The


                                     remaining  balance  shall  only  be  released  after  the  Monitoring  and

                                     Evaluation Division had issued Certificate of Acceptability. It means that


                                     the  project  had  undergone  and  passed  on-site  monitoring,  semi-annual

                                     review, and financial monitoring.


                                            In the case of multi-year projects (with duration of more than one

                                     year), release of grant money shall be on an annual basis and shall depend


                                     on its yearly budgetary requirement. Funds for the succeeding year/s shall

                                     only be released after the Monitoring and Evaluation Division had issued

                                     Certificate of Acceptability.


                                 Section 1.2.  External Grants.  The University Extension Services is tasked

                                 to  prepare  project  proposals  for  external  funding  to  be  submitted  in


                                 accordance  to  the  funding  agency  or  institution’s  research  and  extension

                                 thrusts and priorities and following the agency/institution’s prescribed format.


                                 However,  in  the  absence  of  any  desired  format,  the  CHED’s  format  for

                                 extension  proposal  may  be  used  (Appendix  A.  CHED  NAFES  Proposal


                                 Format).  In  the  event  that  the  funding  agency/institution  requires  a

                                 counterpart funds, the matter shall be first discussed with the Administrative


                                 Council of the University and with consideration of the COA and DBM Rules

                                 and Regulations.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[20


                              Section 2. Evaluation of the Extension Project Proposal

                                 Section  2.1.  Eligibility  of  the  Proponent.    Any  faculty,  non-faculty  or


                                 extension staff (temporary or permanent) is eligible and encouraged to submit

                                 proposals. The extension worker must possess the academic qualifications and


                                 track record of successful implementation of projects.

                                          The  Extension  Services  and/or  Office  of  the  Vice  President  for


                                  Research and Extension may directly solicit proposals from selected faculty

                                  and staff as the need arises.


                                 Section 2.2. Format of the Proposal.  When applying for extension grant, an

                                 extension  project  proposal  must  be  submitted  using  the  prescribed  format


                                 proposals (Appendix B. Form No. 5 Extension Project Proposal Format).

                                         Proposal Format for the extension project consists of eight (8) parts.

                                 The  first  part  is  the  Project  Description  which  contains  the  project’s  basic


                                 information  such  as  the  Project  Title,  Agenda  Classification,  Project

                                 Proponent,  Target  Beneficiaries,  Community  Location,  Period  of


                                 Implementation,  and  Total  Budgetary  Requirement,  Rationale,  Objectives,

                                 Strategies,  Desired  Outcome/Impact,  Organization  and  Staffing,  Plan  of


                                 Activities and Budgetary Requirement.

                                         The  second  part  is  the  Rationale,  followed  by  the  Objectives,


                                 Strategies,  Desired  Outcome/Impact,  Organization  and  Staffing  (Persons

                                 Involved and Responsibility), Plan of Activities and Budgetary Requirement.


                                         The Extension Project Proposal is signed by the person who prepares

                                 the proposal,  recommended by the Director/Dean/Head of the division/unit,]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[21


                                 and approved by the Vice President/President of the agency for the Extension

                                 Services.


                                 Section 2.3. Submission of Proposals.  The Extension Services requires that

                                 proposals be submitted in two (2) copies and electronic copy together with the


                                 Endorsement Letter from the College/Campus Dean or /Unit Head.

                                         All  proposals  together  with  the  necessary  attachments  must  be


                                 submitted to:

                                             The Director
                                             Extension Services Center
                                             Cavite State University
                                             Don Severino delas Alas Campus
                                             Indang, Cavite
                                             Phone: (046) 8620 859


                                         Electronic copy of the proposal and its attachments may be sent via

                                 email at extensionservices@cvsu.edu.ph.


                                         Prior to submission, all proposals should have been pre-evaluated by

                                 the  proponent  using  the  Harmonized  Gender  and  Development  Guidelines


                                 (HGDG) Program/Project Development Evaluation Checklist.

                                 Section 2.1.4. Pre-Screening of Proposals.  All proposals submitted shall be


                                 initially screened by the Monitoring and Evaluation Division of the Extension

                                 Services  to  determine  its  completeness,  conformity  with  the  format,  non-


                                 duplication,  and  alignment  with  the  University  Research  and  Extension

                                 Agenda.


                                         Approved proposals during the pre-screening shall be endorsed to the

                                 Regional  Gender  and  Development  Resource  Center  (RGADRC)  for]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[22


                                 validation  of  points  obtained  by  the  proposal  using  the  HGDG

                                 Program/Project  Development  Evaluation  Checklist.  In  case  of  commodity-


                                 specific extension proposals (i.e. coffee, kaong), proposals should also be pre-

                                 screened by the concerned Commodity RDE Center prior to endorsement to


                                 RGADRC.  Once  proposals  are  validated/pre-screened,  it  shall  be  returned

                                 back to the Extension Services together with comments (if there is any). In


                                 case  of  revision,  one  week  shall  be  given  to  the  proponent  to  revise  the

                                 proposal.


                              Section 3. En Banc Evaluation.  Once the proposal passes the initial screening, it

                       shall  be  presented  to  and  evaluated  by  the  Research  and  Extension  Council.  The


                       following criteria shall be used for evaluation:

                              a.   Contribution of the program/project to regional/national development (30%)

                              b.  Contribution to the advancement of target community/clientele (30%)


                              c.  Quality of information/technology to be promoted/disseminated (20%)

                              d.  Appropriateness of approaches/strategies/methods (20%)


                              Section  4.  Budget  Allocation.    Upon  approval  by  the  Extension  Council,  all

                       extension projects whether funded by the University or by external sources are endorsed


                       by  the  Extension  Services  Director  to  the  University  President  for  final  approval  and

                       budget  allocation  with  the  recommending  approval  of  the  VP  for  Research  and


                       Extension.  Extension projects seeking external fund must conform to the requirements

                       and procedures of the funding agency. The proponents shall be the one responsible for


                       communicating  with  external  funding  agencies  regarding  the  status  of  their  submitted

                       proposals.  Moreover,  the  proponents  are  required  to  submit to  the  Extension  Center  a]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[23


                       copy  of the  approved memorandum  of  agreement,  photocopy of the check voucher or

                       other records of fund transfer.


                              Section 5. Endorsement of Proposal.  Proponents shall be notified of the results

                       of  the  review  whether  their  proposal  passed,  needs  revision  or  rejected.  If  it  needs


                       revision,  the  proponent  shall  be  given  ample  time  to  revise  the  proposal.  Extension

                       proposals which passed the review shall be endorsed by Extension Director to the Vice


                       President for Research and Extension, who shall then endorse it to the President for final

                       approval.


                              The proposals shall also be given attribution to GAD budget. For record purposes,

                       RGADRC,  Concerned  Commodity  R&E  Center  and  MIS  Officer  shall  be  furnished  a


                       copy of the approved proposals. List of approved proposals shall also be presented to the

                       CvSU Administrative Council for confirmation.

                              Section  6.  Processing  of  Funds.    The  Extension  Services  shall  prepare  the


                       contract for signature of the proponent and all authorities concerned.

                              The  Extension  Services  shall  also  facilitate  the  processing  of  the  project  fund.


                       Under the CvSU Extension Grant, the release of funds shall depend on the approved line

                       item budget.


                              Section 7. Program/Project Implementation.  After approval of the proposal for

                       funding, the project proponent/s must attend a pre-implementation meeting to finalize the


                       project timeline and activities and to be aware of their duties and obligations during the

                       period of implementation.


                                 Section 7.1. Pre-Implementation Meeting.  A pre-implementation meeting

                                 shall be conducted prior to the start of implementation of extension projects. It]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[24


                                 aims to fine-tune or finalize the project implementation timelines as well as

                                 the monitoring and evaluation arrangements. During the said meeting, Notice


                                 to Proceed and first tranche of project funds shall be released to the proponent.

                                 Also,  duration  (start  and  end)  of  the  project  shall  also  be  adjusted  (if


                                 necessary) and finalized.

                                         The  Extension  Services  shall  set  the  schedule  and  venue  of  the


                                 meeting. Pre-implementation meeting is usually conducted only once but in

                                 case there are issues or recommendations not threshed out during the meeting,


                                 a follow-up pre-implementation meeting may be agreed upon.

                                         The following are expected to attend the pre-implementation meeting:


                                           Extension Services Director/representative

                                           Extension  M&E  Division  Staff  (shall  serve  as  the  moderator


                                            during the meeting)

                                           Proponent


                                           Extension  Coordinator  of  the  Campus/College  where  the

                                            proponent belongs


                                           Representative from OVPRE

                                           Representative from Administration Office


                                           Representative from Finance Office


                                           Technical expert (identified by the Extension Services) *

                                         *  The  identified  expert  shall  serve  as  one  of  the  evaluators  for  the

                                         whole duration of the project.]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[25


                                         During  the  pre-implementation  meeting,  the  proponent  shall  present

                                 the  general  framework  of  the  project  and  its  strategies  for  implementation


                                 including the work plan and budget summary. The M&E Division staff of the

                                 Extension Services shall discuss the parameters for monitoring and evaluating


                                 the project. Meanwhile, representatives from the Administration and Finance

                                 Offices  shall  present  the  guidelines  for  purchasing  supplies  and  materials,


                                 hiring project staff, among others. All comments and recommendations shall

                                 be documented by the M&E Division. Afterwards, a copy of the highlights of


                                 the meeting shall be distributed to all the attendees of the meeting for their

                                 guidance.


                                 Section 7.2. Hiring/Appointment of Personnel and Professional Services.

                                 Upon  the  approval  of  the  proposal,  the  proponent  or  the  appointed  project

                                 leader is authorized to hire the necessary project staff or expert required to


                                 conduct and complete the deliverables of the project. The hired or appointed

                                 staff  must  be  paid  for  the  services  they  rendered;  provided  that  the  terms,


                                 conditions, and salary rates are strictly in accordance with the approved line

                                 item budget of the project and following the accounting and auditing rules and


                                 regulations of the University.

                                 Section 7.3. Responsibilities of the Program/Project Personnel


                                 a.  Program  Leader.    The  Program  Leader  shall  perform  the  following

                                     functions in the implementation of the program:


                                       Provide overall direction in terms of setting common directions of the

                                         projects under the program;]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[26


                                       Set the work plan of the various projects to establish synchronicity and


                                         coordination between project activities and schedule in order to attain

                                         the objectives of the program;


                                       Represent the program in dealing with collaborating and other external

                                         agencies; and


                                       In cases where the Program Leader is concurrently the Project Leader

                                         of a component project, he must also accomplish the duties expected


                                         of a Project Leader.

                                 b.  Project  Leader.    The  Project  Leader  shall  perform  the  following

                                     functions in the implementation of the program:


                                       Plan, organize and direct the overall conduct of the project;


                                       Spearhead the conduct of extension activities;

                                       Hire  and  recommend  the  appointment  of  the  required  project

                                         personnel;


                                       Recommend  payment  of  salaries  and  compensations  of  project


                                         personnel; and

                                       Prepare  and  submit  progress  reports,  annual  reports,  and  terminal

                                         report


                                 c.  Project Staff/Extension Officer


                                       Assist the Project Leader in planning and managing overall extension

                                         project operations;

                                       Initiate the daily conduct of extension activities;]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[27


                                       Supervise the collection of necessary data and materials related to the


                                         extension activities; and

                                       Assist the Project Leader in preparing progress reports


                                 Section  7.4.  Collaborations.    Established  linkages  and  collaborations  must

                                 have either a Memorandum of Agreement or Memorandum of Understanding

                                 forged      between     the     University     and      the    collaborating


                                 agency/institution/establishment.  The  document  shall  be  duly  signed  by  the

                                 parties involved and shall be notarized by authorized legal authorities.


                                         Terms of reference, responsibilities of each party, contents and other

                                 pertinent  items  shall  be  discussed  between  the  concerned  parties  before


                                 drawing the agreements.

                                 Section 7.5. Conduct of Trainings.  The conduct of trainings and seminars


                                 related to the extension project shall be based on the needs of the community

                                 or stakeholders as per results of the Community Needs Assessment conducted


                                 by the Extension Office. An activity proposal containing the mechanics and

                                 the  budgetary  requirement  shall  be  submitted  to  the  University  President

                                 before the conduct of the training/seminar.  Moreover, training for capability


                                 enhancement of the Extension Coordinators/Staff may also be done subject to

                                 availability  of  funds.  Request  from  other  stakeholders  and  partner


                                 communities and agencies may also be conducted provided that they have sent

                                 letter  of  request  to  the  University  President  who  has  the  sole  authority  to


                                 approve the request.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[28


                              Section  8.  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Extension  Projects.    To  ensure

                       efficient  and  effective  project  implementation,  monitoring  and  evaluation  shall  be


                       conducted  by  the  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Division  with  the  identified  technical

                       expert.


                              a.  Progress Reports.  All project proponents are required to submit two (2) hard

                                 copies  and  electronic  copy  of  their  semi-annual  and  annual  reports  duly


                                 endorsed by the Campus/College Dean or Unit Head.

                              b.  On-site/Field Monitoring.  If necessary, on-site or field monitoring shall be


                                 conducted to  validate the progress  reports submitted by the proponent.  The

                                 schedule shall be set by the Extension M&E Division.


                              c.  Semi-Annual/Annual Review.  Semi-annual review (for one  year projects)

                                 and  annual  review  (for  multi-year  projects)  are  conducted  to  determine  the

                                 continuance or termination of an extension project. The number of reviews to


                                 be  conducted  annually  shall  depend  on  the  number  of  on-going  projects.

                                 Schedule of which shall be set by the Extension Center. Selected members of


                                 Research and Extension Council and/or experts from other institutions shall be

                                 invited as evaluators during the review.


                                         During the review, proponents shall present the progress and plans for

                                 the  continuation  of  implementation  of  the  project.  Evaluators  shall  provide


                                 their  comments/suggestions/  recommendations  on  the  progress  report  and

                                 presentation.  The  M&E  division  shall  document,  integrate/consolidate  the


                                 given comments and suggestions. The same shall provide the proponents copy]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[29


                                 of the review results for their guidance. Once the project passed the review, a

                                 Certificate of Acceptability shall be issued to the proponent.


                                      The  Extension  Services  reserves  the  right  to  discontinue  the  project

                                 anytime  upon  due  consultation  with  the  proponent  and  the  technical  expert


                                 and upon the approval of the President if there is a violation of the contract or

                                 if the soundness of the extension project becomes questionable.


                              Section 9. Annual Extension Agency In-House Review.  One major activity to

                       facilitate the monitoring and evaluation of extension projects is the conduct of the Annual


                       Extension Agency In-house Review.  It involves the evaluation of all extension projects

                       that  are  either  completed  or  ongoing  during  the  particular  year  under  review.  During


                       these reviews, individuals involved in the projects shall present the progress/highlights of

                       their extension projects.  Evaluators consist of members from the Research and Extension

                       Council,  Southern  Tagalog  Agriculture,  Aquatic  and  Resources  Research  and


                       Development Consortium (STAARRDEC), and experts from other HEIs.

                              A.  Goals.  The goals of conducting annual agency in-house review are to:


                                   Establish  an  additional  institutional  mechanism  for  the  monitoring  and

                                     evaluation of the different extension programs/projects/activities (E-PPAs)


                                     of the University;

                                   Increase  faculty  and  staff  participation  in  extension  and  outreach


                                     activities;

                                   Acquire  papers  on  CvSU  extension  services  which  are  acceptable  for


                                     publication on appropriate Journals; and

                                   Improve techniques, strategies and/or approaches in extension]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[30


                              B.  Objectives.  The objectives of conducting annual agency in-house review are

                                 to:


                                   Encourage faculty and staff to write their extension works and outputs;


                                   Present the extension activities of the different colleges and campuses;

                                   Recognize  and  award  commendable  extension  programs,  projects  and


                                     activities;

                                   Document results of extension programs, projects and activities; and


                                   Acquire effective and innovative techniques and/or strategies in extension

                              C.  Schedule.    The  reviews  shall  be  conducted  at  least  twice  a  year  to  select


                                 papers in time for the regional reviews and publication.

                              D.  Evaluation Panel.  The University shall notify STAARRDEC regarding the


                                 upcoming  agency  in-house  review  to  identify  external  evaluators  of  the

                                 extension projects. The evaluators shall be composed of the following:

                                   Experts within the University or experts from other HEIs


                                   Members of the national/regional commodity R&E team/pool of experts


                                   Farmer co-operators

                                   Representatives  from  funding  agencies  (e.g.  PCAARRD,  DA-BAR,


                                     CHED, etc.)

                              E.  Evaluation Criteria.     The major criteria that shall be used in  evaluating


                                 the ongoing extension projects are the following:

                                   Attainment of the objectives


                                   Adherence to the approved methodology or recommendation of more

                                     appropriate methodology]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[31


                                   Adherence to the approved budget


                                   Accomplishments including status of technology generated/verified

                                   Actions taken in response to previous year’s comments


                                     For  completed  extension  projects,  the  major  criteria  for  evaluation  that

                              shall be used are the following:


                                   Creativity, originality, and quality of work

                                   Significance of findings


                                   Manuscript/write-up

                                   Presentation


                              Section 10. Request for Extending Project Extension.  Requests for extension

                       of the project shall only be entertained at least three (3) months before the completion


                       date.  Requests  for  project  extension  shall  be  submitted  to  the  Extension  Services  and

                       shall be supported by the following documents:


                              a.  Request letter duly endorsed by the Campus/College Dean or Unit Head

                              b.  Latest financial report


                              c.  Revised Work Plan

                              d.  Justification for extension

                              There shall be no additional budget that shall be released for project extension. A


                       project proponent shall only be allowed once to request for project extension. However,

                       in extreme and justifiable reasons may be allowed another re-extension.


                              Section 11. Project Completion/Termination

                                     Section 11.1. Submission of Terminal Report.  Not more than thirty (30)


                                 days after the project was completed/terminated, five (5) hard copies of the]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[32


                                 Terminal  Report,  duly  endorsed  by  the  Campus/College  Dean  or  Unit

                                 Head,should be submitted.


                                         The terminal report should be accompanied by supporting documents

                                 such  as  pictures,  evaluation  sheets,  IEC  materials,  Community  Needs


                                 Assessments,  and  other  outputs  that  may  show  the  results  of  the  activities

                                 conducted.


                                         Undisbursed  funds  shall  be  returned  to  the  Cashier  and  an  official

                                 receipt shall be properly issued.


                                 Section  11.2.  Conduct  of  Terminal  Review.    A  Terminal  Review  is

                                 conducted after the completion of an extension program/project to determine


                                 if the proposed objectives were met. A panel of evaluators, which is composed

                                 of technical experts from within or outside the University, shall be invited to

                                 conduct the review.


                              Section  12.  Publication.    Proponents  with  outputs  that  are  publishable  should

                       submit at  least  one article (per study) to  the CvSU Research Journal  or any reputable


                       journal for possible publication. It is the responsibility of the proponent to ensure that the

                       Extension Services is furnished a copy of the evidence of submission including the copy


                       of the article submitted.

                              Section 13. Intellectual Property.  For output that is new, novel or an inventive


                       technique,  the  proponent  is  advised  to  seek  assistance  from  Intellectual  Property

                       Management Office (IPMO) for application of IP protection.


                              Section 14. Paper Presentation.  The extension paper may be presented in any

                       regional,  national,  or  international  extension  conference,  fora,  seminar,  or  meeting  as]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[33


                       long  as  full  acknowledgement  shall  be  given  to  the  University.  Also,  the  presentation

                       should  not  prejudice  the  proprietary/confidential  nature  of  the  information  for  the


                       purposes of IP protection.


                       Article 5. Awards and Incentives for Conducting Extension Activities

                              Section 1. Workload.  A workload points shall be given to a faculty member as


                       incentive for conducting extension projects/activities based on the guidelines set in the


                       Unified  Workload  System  approved  by  the  Board  of  Regents  during  its  70th  Regular

                       Meeting  held  on  March  24,  2017.    It  covers  the  core  (e.g.  instruction,  research  and

                       extension) and strategic (e.g. administrative assignments and other services) functions of


                       a faculty member (Appendix C. University Workload System).

                              Section  2.  Honorarium.    A  faculty  or  staff  involved  in  extension  projects  or


                       activities  is  entitled  to  receive  honoraria  from  externally-funded  projects  or  activities

                       provided that it is clearly indicated in the approved line item budget (LIB), memorandum


                       of understanding/agreement (MOU/MOA) or certificate of compensation.

                              Project  leaders of externally-funded R and E projects  without honorarium  (e.g.

                       institutional development grant; grants in kind; conduct of training, workshop, conference


                       and etc.) shall be entitled to receive honorarium under the indirect cost or admin cost of

                       the project’s approved LIB. The project leader shall receive 30% of the total amount of


                       indirect cost or the amount specified in the LIB.

                              No honorarium  from  the  University’s  fund is  given to  the  extension  worker  in


                       accordance  with  DBM  Budget  Circular  2007-1  Approved  on  April  23,  2007.

                       Furthermore,  all  R  and  E  activities  with  honorarium  shall  be  excluded  from  the


                       computation of work overload pay of the researcher.]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[34


                              Section 3. Publication Awards.  A monetary and certificate of recognition shall

                       be given to faculty and staff who published extension-related articles in scientific journals


                       based  on  the  Guidelines  for  Granting  Incentives  for  Publication  of  Faculty  and  Staff

                       (Appendix  D)  approved  during  the  63rd  Regular  Meeting  of  the  CvSU's  Board  of


                       Regents held on March 19, 2015.

                              Section 4. Best Performing College/Campus.  The objective of this award is to


                       compensate  and  give  due  recognition  to  the  concerted  efforts  and  exemplary

                       accomplishments in research and extension activities of different Colleges and Campuses


                       of the University.

                              The  awarding  shall  be  done  during  the  Annual  R  and  E  Week.  A  special


                       committee composed of the VPRE, VPAA and VP for Planning and Development shall

                       be formed to conduct the selection of the Best Performing College/Campus. Criteria for

                       evaluation shall be based on indicators of MFO 3, MFO 4, KRA 2, KRA 3 and KRA 4.


                       The college/campus with the highest points shall be declared as the winner.

                              A  Certificate  of  Recognition  shall  be  given  to  the  Dean/Campus  Director;


                       College/Campus R and E Coordinator and the College/Campus. A monetary award of not

                       less than P300, 000.00 shall be given to the Best Performing College/Campus to be used


                       for conduct of R and E activities and research capacity building. An additional amount

                       not less than P100,00.00 shall be given if the proposal is focused on coffee and not less


                       than P50,000 if on other focus commodity thrusts of the University.

                              Section  5.  Outstanding  Extensionist  Award.    This  award  recognizes  the


                       exemplary performance of faculty and staff to encourage and to promote excellence in

                       extension services.]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[35


                              Faculty  and  staff  of  the  University  must  satisfy  the  minimum  qualifications  in

                       order to be nominated for the Outstanding Research Award and Outstanding Extension


                       Award.

                              These qualifications are the following:


                                   Permanent or temporary appointment during the period under review

                                   Has at least three years of continuous service immediately preceding the


                                     nomination


                                   Has  not  committed  acts  of  plagiarism,  intellectual  dishonesty  and  other

                                     acts of unprofessionalism

                                   Should  have  at  least  one  funded  extension  project/program  during  the


                                     period under review

                              The  applicant  must  submit  the  prescribed  application  form  together  with  the


                       required supporting documents.

                              Selection of the awardee is based on the following criteria:


                                   Originality (25%) - the extension work should contribute new knowledge

                                     and service to the community


                                   Productivity (20%) - shall consider the amount of resource generated as

                                     principal  investigators.  Only  those  projects  which  have  been


                                     acknowledged by the Extension Services shall be considered.

                                   Paper  presentations  and  publications  (20%)  -  shall  be  based  on  papers


                                     published in scientific journals, monographs, information bulletins, books

                                     and other refereed publications in the last three years and papers presented]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[36


                                     in  national  and  international  conferences  and  unpublished  reports  of

                                     completed projects.


                                   Significance of extension  activity/project  (20%)  - the extension  projects


                                     should  have  significant  impact  to  institutional,  regional  or  national

                                     development.

                                   Recognition  given  to  the  extension  project  (15%)–  this  includes  awards


                                     received  associated  with  the  extension  project  conducted;  citations,  and

                                     other  forms  of  recognition  from  academic  institutions/organizations  or


                                     societies (scientific or learned) given to the extensionist.

                              A  Selection  committee  shall  be  formed  and  recommended  to  the  University


                       President  by  the  OVPRE.  The  College  Dean/Campus  Directors  shall  endorse  one

                       nominee.  A minimum score of 80 is required for a nominee to win the award.


                              A plaque of recognition shall be given to the outstanding researcher. In addition to

                       this, a monetary award of not less than P20, 000.00 shall be given to the awardee. The


                       award shall be given during the annual University Foundation day celebration. A call for

                       nominations,  selection  process  and  amount  prizes  shall  be  announced  by  OVPRE  not

                       later  than  January  15  of  each  year.  Winners  shall  not  be  eligible  for  the  award  for  2


                       consecutive years.

                              Section  6.  Travel  Grant.    The  University  provides  travel  grant  to  its  faculty


                       members and staff to present their research and extension outputs in recognized fora. It is

                       the responsibility of the concerned personnel to facilitate the processing of their request


                       for travel including the necessary travel arrangements.]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[37


                              Travel  request  should  be  submitted  to  the  Office  of  the  Vice  President  for

                       Research and Extension, at least three working days prior to the scheduled travel. In case


                       the travel requires cash advance, R&E personnel are advised to process their requests at

                       least a month before the date of departure.


                              In case the travel requires airfare and/or budget more than P 10,000.00, the letter

                       of  request  approved  by  the  President  should  be  attached.  Please  note  that  budgetary


                       requirement for travel should be stipulated in the letter of request. In the case of travel

                       abroad, the faculty member or staff must also secure Travel Authority from the Human


                       Resource Management Office (HRMO) before the travel.

                              If  the  purpose  of  travel  is  initiated  by  the  office/unit  where  the  faculty/staff


                       belongs,  any  supporting  document  indicating  the  purpose  of  travel  shall  be  attached.

                       Requester with pending travel report shall not be processed.

                              Upon approval of the travel grant, the faculty/staff must submit a Travel Report


                       including  attachments  which  are  applicable  (i.e.  publication,  minutes  of  meeting,

                       accomplished  monitoring  forms,  proceedings,  certificate  of  appearance  and/or


                       participation, attendance sheet, project proposal, etc.) a week after the travel to the Office

                       of the VP for Research and Extension.]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[38



















                                                            Appendix A


                                             CHED NAFES Extension Proposal Format]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[39


                                                   Form A: CHED NAFES Extension Proposal Concept Note

                                                 Office of Planning, Research and Knowledge Management
                                                                           Commission on Higher Education

                                     ___________________________________________________________

                       I. General Information
                       Principal               Name:
                       Investigator:           Institution Affiliation:
                                               Address:
                                               Qualification (degree(s) training experience:
                                               Contact Details:
                       Co-investigator:        Name:
                                               Institution Affiliation:
                                               Address:
                                               Qualification (degree(s) training experience:
                                               Contact Details:
                       Other Investigator:     Name:
                                               Institution Affiliation:
                                               Address:
                                               Qualification (degree(s) training experience:
                                               Contact Details:

                       II. University Research Council/Institutional Research Board
                       Do  you  have  an  existing  University  Research  Council,  URC  (for  Universities)  or
                       Institution Research Board, IRB (for Colleges)?

                       Yes                No
                       If yes, provide the following details:

                       Name of URC/IRB Head:
                       Address:
                       Contact Nos:

                       Project proposal approved by the respective URC/IRB? Yes:               No:

                       III. Proposal Summary
                       Title of Proposal:


                                                 Has this proposal been submitted to another agency for funding?

                                                 Yes:               No:
                       Project Duration]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[40


                       Goals and Objectives      Extension Type:

                                                 Pilot  Testing:                          Technology  Promotion:
                                                 Commercialization:

                                                 Other Types:

                                                 General Objectives:

                                                 Specific Objectives:



                       Stakeholder Demand        Does this build on a previous project?   Yes:               No:
                       and Project Relevance

                       Methodology

                       Mentoring Plan

                       Proposed Budget

                       Beneficiaries of the
                       Extension Project
                       Publication, Patent
                       and Dissemination
                       Plan
                       References




                       Submitted by:                                     Approved by:




                       Principal Investigator                            Head, University Research
                                                           Council/
                                                                         Institutional Research Board



                       Co-Principal Investigator

                       Noted by:



                       Head of Institution]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[41






















                                                            Appendix B

                                                 Extension Project Proposal Format]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[42

                                                 Republic of the Philippines
                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                             Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                       Indang, Cavite
                                                       (046) 8620859
                                             cvsuextensionservices@gmail.com


                                            EXTENSION SERVICES CENTER


                                     EXTENSION PROJECT PROPOSAL FORMAT




               I.  Project Description

                       Project Title:
                       Agenda Classification:
                       Project Proponent:
                       Target Beneficiaries:
                       Community Location:
                       Period of Implementation:
                       Total Budgetary Requirement (P):



               II. Rationale

               III. Objectives


               IV. Strategies

               V. Desired Outcome / Impact

               VI. Organization and Staffing (Persons involved and responsibility)


               VII. Plan of Activities

               VIII. Budgetary Requirement




               Prepared by:                       Approved by:                  Noted by:


               ___________________                ____________________          __________________

               Extension Coordinator               Unit Head                    Dean/Director]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[43























                                                        Appendix C

                                                University Workload System]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[ALIGNMENT OF EXTENSION PROGRAM


                  TO LOCAL, REGIONAL AND NATIONAL


                                  DEVELOPMENT THRUST]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                                                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                                             Tanza Campus

                                                                                    Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

                                                                                                          ☏ (046) 235 – 7997

                                                                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                                                               EXTENSION SERVICES



                                                                         ALIGNMENT OF EXTENSION PROGRAM TO

                                                      LOCAL, REGIONAL AND NATIONAL DEVELOPMENT THRUST



                            EXTENSION                            EXTENSION                            Cavite State                  NEDA Regional                 NEDA Philippine                UN Sustainable

                             PROGRAM                          COMPONENTS                       University Extension               Development Plan               Development Plan                  Development
                                                                                                         Agenda                                                                                          Goals





                       Bagtas ay Aasenso               BAGTAS with CvSU –                           1.  Societal                 Pagbabago-                      Pillar 2: Inequality-         Goal 10: Reduced
                       at Giginhawa kung               Tanza aims to undertake                           Development             Inequality-Reducing             reducing                      Inequality

                       Tayo Ay Sama- sam  the following extension                                        and Equality            Transformation                  transformation
                       with CvSU- Tanza                project components:                                                                                       (Pagbabago)
                       (BAGTAS with                                                                 2.  Public Health            Ensure Ecological

                       CvSU-Tanza)                          1.  Oplan-Karunungan                                                 Integrity, Clean and
                                                            2.  Computer Literacy                        and Welfare             Healthy Environment                                           Goal 3: Good
                                                                 Program                                                                                                                       Health and Well-
                                                            3.  Livelihood Program                  3.  Biodiversity                                                                           Being

                                                            4.  Health and                               and
                                                                 Wellness
                                                                                                         Environmental
                                                                                                         Conservation]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza Campus

 Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

 ☏ (046) 235 – 7997

 www.cvsu.edu.ph


 EXTENSION SERVICES



 ALIGNMENT OF EXTENSION PROGRAM TO

 LOCAL, REGIONAL AND NATIONAL DEVELOPMENT THRUST



 EXTENSION   EXTENSION   Cavite State   NEDA Regional   NEDA Philippine   UN Sustainable

 PROGRAM   COMPONENTS   University Extension   Development Plan   Development Plan   Development
 Agenda                                                                          Goals





 Bagtas ay Aasenso   BAGTAS with CvSU –   1.  Societal   Pagbabago-  Pillar 2: Inequality-  Goal 10: Reduced
 at Giginhawa kung   Tanza aims to undertake   Development   Inequality-Reducing   reducing   Inequality

 Tayo Ay Sama- sam  the following extension   and Equality   Transformation   transformation
 with CvSU- Tanza   project components:      (Pagbabago)
 (BAGTAS with   2.  Public Health   Ensure Ecological

 CvSU-Tanza)   1.  Oplan-Karunungan   Integrity, Clean and
 2.  Computer Literacy   and Welfare   Healthy Environment              Goal 3: Good
 Program                                                                Health and Well-
 3.  Livelihood Program   3.  Biodiversity                              Being

 4.  Health and   and
 Wellness
 Environmental
 Conservation]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[Patuloy na Pag-                 Increasing growth             Goal 1: No Poverty
                                                                                                                                 Unlad -Increasing               potential (Patuloy

                                                                                                                                 Growth Potential                na Pag-Unlad)
                                                                                                                                 Ensure Safety and
                                                                                                                                 Build Resilience







                       Prepared by:





                       RITCH M. BANATE
                       Campus Extension Coordinator





                       Reviewed by:






                       CRIS ALBERT P. CAGIDAS
                       Campus Coordinator





                       Approved by:





                       PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO

                       Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[Patuloy na Pag-                 Increasing growth             Goal 1: No Poverty
          Unlad -Increasing               potential (Patuloy

          Growth Potential                na Pag-Unlad)
          Ensure Safety and
          Build Resilience







 Prepared by:





 RITCH M. BANATE
 Campus Extension Coordinator





 Reviewed by:






 CRIS ALBERT P. CAGIDAS
 Campus Coordinator





 Approved by:





 PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO

 Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[APPROVED BOR AND EXTENSION


                                      PROJECT PROPOSAL]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                         CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY

                                                    Tanza Campus
                                   Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

                                                  ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph



                                         EXTENSION PROJECT PROPOSAL



                   I.     Project Description

                        Title        :      BAGTAS with CvSU-Tanza


                                            (Bagtas ay Aasenso at Giginhawa kung Tayo Ay Sama-sama
                                            with CvSU – Tanza)

                        Location     :      Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

                        Proponent  :        Cavite State University – Tanza Campus

                        Beneficiaries:      Out-of-school  Children  and  Youth,  Brgy.  Officials,  and  non-
                                            working members of the community

                        Project Components:

                               Program 1: Oplan Karunungan
                               Program 2: Computer Literacy Program
                               Program 3: Livelihood Programs for Non-Working Members of the
                               Community
                               Program 4: Health and Wellness


                       Partner Agencies:  Local Government Unit of the Municipality of Tanza, Cavite;
                                            Provincial Cooperative, Livelihood, and Entrepreneurial
                                            Development Office (PCLEDO); Farmers Training Center
                                            (FITS); Companies in Export Processing Zone Authority
                                            (EPZA)


                       Estimated Budget:   Php 610,000

                       Duration      :      5 years


                   II.    Rationale
                              The population explosion in Brgy. Bagtas has led to an initiative to alleviate
                        poverty in the barangay. Brgy. Bagtas, having the most population in Tanza (20,370
                        out of 188,755), has been the site for relocation and reclamation. However, people,
                        who were displaced out of their previous addresses, were relocated in the said barangay]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[without having a regular source of living. Some of them could not find a decent job
                        because they lack the educational and other requirements for the job that they were
                        applying  for.  Others  could  not  start  any  business  because  they  lack  the  skills  in
                        preparing innovative products that could help them earn additional income for their
                        families.

                              Thus, different extension activities are being proposed to increase the quality of
                        life of the citizens in the said barangay. Non-formal education will help out-of-school
                        children to be able to read, write and count. Also, livelihood programs are deemed to
                        strengthen housewives’ skills and at the same time, augment the meager income of
                        their families. In addition, awareness drives concerning health and other GAD-related
                        issues are being proposed to inculcate the importance of appropriate living conditions
                        for every member of the community.

                   III.   Strategies of Implementation

                          A.  Formation of Committee
                                     A committee was formed to study and gather benchmark information
                              on the status, needs, and conditions of selected communities in Tanza, Cavite
                              during the second semester, AY 2014 – 2015. The committee was headed by
                              the  Extension  Coordinator.  Two  faculty  members  from  the  different
                              departments of the campus were selected as members of the committee to
                              ensure that the programs will conform to the mandate of the university. The
                              committee  used  the  following  benchmark  information,  provided  by  Tanza
                              Municipal Planning and Development Office (TMPDO), in order to assess
                              which group of individuals will be the target beneficiaries of the proposal.

                              Table 1. Data of Brgy. Bagtas population 2010 by sex, age, and employment


                                                          Male             Female          Total
                            Brgy. Bagtas Population       12,316           8,054           20,370
                            Age Bracket
                            5 – 9                         1,453            951             2,404
                            10 – 14                       1,299            849             2,148
                            OTHERS                        9,564            6,254           15,818
                            Enrolment Data
                            Pre-School (3 – 6)            1,213            878             2,091
                            Elementary (7 – 12)           1,176            823             1,999
                            Employment Data
                            Employed                      6,908            4,517           11,425
                            Unemployed                    600              393             993
                            Not in the labor force        4,808            3,144           7,952
                            Source: Philippine Statistics Authority and Tanza Municipal Planning and Development Office

                                     The committee used the descriptive design of a study. Data utilized in
                              the  study  mainly  came  from  the  responses  on  the  self-administered  survey
                              questions that were distributed to the residents of Brgy. Bagtas. Residents were
                              selected using simple random sampling.]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[Results revealed that:

                                     •  87.14% of the residents perceived that they lack regular sources of
                                         living  in  the  barangay  because  most  (48.15%)  of  them  lack  the
                                         educational  requirements  and  some  (38.99%)  lack  the  technical
                                         skills to either start a small business or to apply for a regular job;
                                     •  47.06% of the residents believed that these problems and issues may
                                         be  addressed  through  conduct  of  free  seminars/trainings  on
                                         livelihood programs;

                                     •  47.06% of the residents believed that these problems and issues may
                                         be  addressed  through  conduct  of  free  seminars/trainings  on
                                         livelihood programs;

                                     •  47.06% of the residents believed that these problems and issues may
                                         be  addressed  through  conduct  of  free  seminars/trainings  on
                                         livelihood programs;

                          B.  Preparation of Committee

                                     The  proposal  to  conduct  extension  programs  in  the  community  was
                              based upon the respondent’s needs and interests that are consistent with the
                              goals of the campus and that have been identified through surveys.

                                     Some programs relative to the needs and interests of the residents were
                              not  considered  due  to  insufficiencies  on  facilities  and  absence  of  qualified
                              faculty members to handle such programs. This includes recycling of plastic
                              products, water lily bags, and perfume-making which may require raw materials
                              that are unavailable from the community.
                                     While having consultative meetings with the local government of the
                              concerned  barangay,  some  requests  to  the  university  were  raised.  First,  the
                              campus  will  have  to  offer  a  computer  literacy  program  for  their  barangay
                              officials and 4P’s members. This program aims to extend computer literacy to
                              the Brgy. Officials and selected 4P’s members, who, based on observation, lack
                              sufficient skills in computer manipulation and processes. The LGU believes that
                              technical  skills  must  be  manifested  by  their  officials  to  better  serve  their
                              constituents  and  for  those  4P’s  members  for  employment  and  business
                              opportunities.

                                     Also,  the  LGU  requested  that  the  proponents  offer  literacy  skills
                              development among their children. According to them, a number of children
                              were not enrolled in a formal school and parents of these children affirm that
                              they could not send them to formal school due to lack of financial resources,
                              that although education is free in public schools, they could not  provide the
                              requirements that their children must submit.

                                     Another  request  from  the  LGU  is  that  the  proponent  should  give
                              awareness campaigns on different health issues. According to them, the increase
                              in the rate of patients with dengue and AIDS/HIV in the province had been
                              alarming them and the residents. And because the proponent is a GAD advocate,
                              GAD-related issues and concerns were included in this awareness campaign,]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[such as Anti-Violence against Women and their Children (anti-VAWC), sexual
                              harassment among others.


                          C.  Meeting of the Committee
                                     A meeting of the campus Committee on Curriculum and Instruction
                              was conducted on April 10, 2015 to deliberate on the proposed extension
                              programs in the campus.

                                     The following is the decision of the members of the committee:

                                            Total Number of Committee Members          :       15

                                            Total Number of Committee Members
                                            who were present                           :       15

                                            Total Number of Committee Members
                                            who were absent                            :       0

                                            Number of Members in favor
                                                   of the proposal                     :       15

                                            Number of Members not in favor
                                                   of the proposal                     :       0


                                     With  this  result,  the  following  resolutions  were  passed  by  the
                              Committee:

                              Resolution No. 3, s. 2015

                                     “Approving  the  extension  project  proposal  to  alleviate  poverty  in
                              Barangay Bagtas with the following components: (1) Oplan Karunungan; (2)
                              Computer Literacy for Brgy. Officials; (3) Livelihood Programs for the citizens
                              of Brgy. Bagtas; and (4) Health and Wellness; subject to the endorsement of the
                              University  Administrative  Council  and  approval  of  the  University  Board  of
                              Regents.”


                              Resolution No. 4, s. 2015

                                     “Approving the name of the extension project proposal to be BAGTAS
                              with  CvSU-Tanza  (Bagtas  ay  Aasenso  at  Giginhawa  kung  Tayo  Ay

                              Sama-sama with CvSU – Tanza) subject to the endorsement of the University
                              Administrative Council and approval of the University Board of Regents.”


                          D.  Memorandum of Agreement

                                     A Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) will be drafted and signed by
                              different stakeholders involved in the conduct of such extension programs.
                              Stakeholders such as Local Government Unit of the municipality of Tanza,
                              Cavite; Provincial Cooperative, Livelihood, and Entrepreneurial Development]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[Office  (PCLEDO);  Farmers  Training  Center  (FITS);  Companies  in  Export
                              Processing Zone Authority (EPZA); and others.

                          E.  Actual Implementation
                                    All the extension programs under this project will be spearheaded by the
                              campus dean and will be facilitated by faculty members and students in their
                              respective area of specialization. Since this is an extension project, voluntary
                              participation among faculty and students will be encouraged. Additional funds
                              for  the  project  proposal  will  be  sought  through  donations  from  the  Local
                              Government Unit of Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite and other concerned citizens
                              and government and non-government agencies, such as but are not limited to,
                              Provincial Cooperative, Livelihood, and Entrepreneurial Development Office
                              (PCLEDO); Farmers Training Center (FITS); Companies in Export Processing
                              Zone Authority (EPZA); and others.

                             Program 1: Oplan Karunungan

                              1.  All  BSE  students  and  faculty  members  under  the  Teacher  Education
                                 Department are enjoined to take part in this program.
                              2.  The program will be done during Fridays and Saturdays, 7:30 a.m. to 9:30
                                 a.m.at Rm. 102 of the Cavite State University – Tanza Campus.
                              3.  The BSE students and faculty members will have their own schedule on
                                 when to share their knowledge and teaching skills among the out-of-school
                                 youths.
                              4.  For security purposes, each participant will wear name tags during each
                                 session to recognize them as part of the program.
                              5.  On  the  first  day  of  the  session,  each  participant  will  undergo  a  pre-
                                 assessment to determine their basic literacy and numeracy skills.
                              6.  The  officers  will  coordinate  with  the  Barangay  Captain  to  recommend
                                 and/or suggest viable participants of this program.
                              7.  For the first year of implementation, at least 10 out-of-school youths will be
                                 the target participants.
                              8.  Assigned members will see to it that cleanliness and orderliness of the said
                                 classroom will be maintained during the session.
                              9.  The  teachers  and  student-teachers  will  select  three  best  students  to  be
                                 awarded during the Recognition Program.
                              10. Every participant will be awarded a Certificate of Completion upon finishing
                                 the program.
                              11. After  the  program,  each  participant  will  undergo  a  post-assessment  to
                                 determine the effect of the intervention that was conducted.
                              12. Students who have finished the program will be encouraged and supported
                                 to enroll in a formal elementary school.
                              Program 2: Computer Literacy Program

                              1.  All  BSIT  students  and  faculty  members  under  the  Department  of
                                 Information Technology are enjoined to take part in this program.
                              2.  The program will be done during Fridays and Saturdays, 8:30 a.m. to 10:30
                                 a.m. at the Computer Laboratory of the Cavite State University  – Tanza
                                 Campus.
                              3.  The BSIT students and faculty members will have their own schedule on]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[when  to  share  their  knowledge  and  teaching  skills  among  the  barangay
                                 officials.
                              4.  For security purposes, each participant will wear name tags during each
                                 session to recognize them as part of the program.
                              5.  The  officers  will  coordinate  with  the  Barangay  Captain  to  recommend
                                 and/or suggest viable participants of this program.
                              6.  For the first year of implementation, at least 10 selected barangay officials
                                 and  4P’s  members  will  be  taught  basic  computer  skills  during  the  time
                                 allotted.
                              7.  Assigned members will see to it that cleanliness and orderliness of the said
                                 classroom will be maintained during the session.
                              8.  The teachers and student-teachers will select three best participants to be
                                 awarded during the Recognition Program.
                              9.  Every participant will be awarded a Certificate of Completion upon finishing
                                 the program.
                              10. As part of the monitoring and evaluation of the program, each participant
                                 will undergo a pre- and post-test to determine whether they have achieved
                                 the basic skills that are expected of them.

                              Program 3: Computer Literacy Program

                              1.  All  BSBM  and  BSHRM  students  and  faculty  members  under  the
                                 Department of Management are enjoined to take part in this program and
                                 will be the facilitators and overall in-charge.
                              2.  The program will be done during Fridays and Saturdays, 7:30 a.m. to 9:30
                                 a.m. at Function Hall of the Cavite State University – Tanza Campus.
                              3.  The  officers  will  coordinate  with  the  Barangay  Captain  to  recommend
                                 and/or suggest viable participants of this program.
                              4.  Assistance  from  the  Provincial  Cooperative,  Livelihood,  and
                                 Entrepreneurial Development Office (PCLEDO) will be sought in terms of
                                 training of participants.
                              5.  At least 20 housewives will be invited to take part in each session
                              6.  All participants must be residents of Brgy. Bagtas as certified and referred
                                 to by the LGU officials.
                              7.  Participants  with  outstanding  performance  in  selected  activities  will  be
                                 rewarded accordingly. They will be given a small amount of money to start
                                 their own business.
                              8.  Every participant will be awarded a Certificate of Completion upon finishing
                                 the program.
                              9.  As part of the monitoring and evaluation of the program, each participant
                                 will undergo a pre- and post-test to determine whether they have achieved
                                 the basic skills that are expected of them.

                              Program 4: Health and Wellness

                              1.  All students and members of the Sports Club of the campus, and faculty
                                 members are enjoined to take part in this program.
                              2.  The  Aerobics/Zumba  session  will  be  done  every  Wednesday,  starting
                                 January to March 2016 thru the initiative of a competitive professional dance
                                 instructor. Summer Sports Clinic and Sports fest with the community will
                                 be held every weekend starting March to June 2016. Continuous awareness
                                 drive  on  health  issues  will  be  held  every  Friday  and  Saturday,  starting]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[January to March 2016. Awareness drive on GAD-related concerns will be
                                 held every Wednesday, starting January to March 2016.
                              3.  The  officers  will  coordinate  with  the  Barangay  Captain  to  recommend
                                 and/or  suggest  viable  participants  of  this  program.  Also,  they  will  be
                                 requested to lend a venue for the program.
                              4.  At least 20 housewives will be invited to take part in the aerobics/Zumba
                                 session. Outof-school youths will be the target participants in the summer
                                 sports clinic and sports fest with the community. At least 30 residents will
                                 be the target participants in the awareness drive on health and GAD-related
                                 issues.
                              5.  All participants must be residents of Brgy. Bagtas as certified and referred
                                 to by the LGU officials.
                              6.  Participants  with  outstanding  performance  in  selected  activities  will  be
                                 rewarded accordingly, especially  those who  excelled  in  sports and  other
                                 recreational activities.
                              7.  Every participant will be awarded Certificate of Completion upon finishing
                                 the program.
                              8.  As part of the monitoring and evaluation of the program, each participant
                                 will undergo a pre- and post-test to determine whether they have achieved
                                 the basic skills that are expected of them.

                          F.  Monitoring and Evaluation

                                     Each program will undergo three evaluations: before, during, and after
                              conduct of each evaluation. On the first week of each session, each participant
                              will undergo a pre-assessment to determine their current status in the program
                              they were registered to. Evaluation during the conduct of the program will also
                              be done in order to identify problems arising and to immediately resolve these
                              problems.  Post-assessment  will  be  done  in  order  to  determine  if  they  have
                              achieved the basic skills that are expected of them. This will also determine
                              whether the program is successful and has delivered significant impact to the
                              community.

                   IV.    Budgetary Allocation (5 years)


                                        PARTICULARS/PROGRAM                                AMOUNT (PhP)

                         Program 1: Oplan Karunungan                                           60,000.00

                         Program 2: Computer Literacy Program                                  45,000.00

                         Program 3: Livelihood Programs for Non-Working                       300,000.00
                         Members of the Community

                         Program 4: Health and Wellness                                       205,000.00

                                                    TOTAL                                     610,000.00


                   V.     Source Fund

                               The  main  source  of  funds  for  the  project  will  be  the  campus  budget  for]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[extension. The project proponent will solicit additional funding from the Local
                          Government Unit of Tanza and other partner NGO’s and GO’s such as, but not

                          limited to, Provincial Cooperative, Livelihood, and Entrepreneurial Development
                          Office (PCLEDO); Farmers Training Center (FITS); and Companies in Export
                          Processing Zone Authority (EPZA).]]></page><page Index="86"/><page Index="87"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY - TANZA


                               CAMPUS STRATEGIC PLAN


                                                   2017-2022]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN
                                                                                             Cavite State University - Tanza Campus

                                                                                                                2017 – 2022


                                                     PROGRAM/PROJECT/AC                   PERFORMANCE                                IMPLEMENTATION                                 BUDGET REQUIREMENT
                 OBJECTIVES                                    TIVITIES                      INDICATOR              2017  2018  2019  2020  2021  2022                2017        2018        2019        2020        2021       2022


         1. To appreciate the                        Program 1: Oplan                                                                                                  Php         Php         Php         Php       Php
              importance of literacy                     Karunungan                      Significant                                                                 12,000      12,000      12,000      12,000      12,000
              and numeracy among the                                                     increase in the

              participants, thereby                 a)  Remedial                         basic numeracy
              persuading them to enroll                   classes for 4P’s               and literacy skills
              in a formal school.                         members                        of the
                                                                                         participants and

         2. To increase literacy and                b)  Reading/writing                  will enroll in a
              numeracy in the                             literacy and                   formal school.
              barangay.
                                                          numeracy for out-

        3. To immerse future                              of-school children,
           educators in the teaching                      youths and adults
           process, having out-of-
           school youths as their
           students.]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN
 Cavite State University - Tanza Campus

 2017 – 2022


 PROGRAM/PROJECT/AC  PERFORMANCE   IMPLEMENTATION            BUDGET REQUIREMENT
 OBJECTIVES   TIVITIES   INDICATOR   2017  2018  2019  2020  2021  2022   2017   2018   2019   2020   2021   2022


 1. To appreciate the   Program 1: Oplan                        Php   Php   Php     Php       Php
 importance of literacy   Karunungan   Significant   12,000   12,000   12,000     12,000      12,000
 and numeracy among the     increase in the

 participants, thereby   a)  Remedial   basic numeracy
 persuading them to enroll   classes for 4P’s   and literacy skills
 in a formal school.   members   of the
       participants and

 2. To increase literacy and   b)  Reading/writing   will enroll in a
 numeracy in the   literacy and   formal school.
 barangay.
    numeracy for out-

 3. To immerse future   of-school children,
 educators in the teaching   youths and adults
 process, having out-of-
 school youths as their
 students.]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[PROGRAM/PROJECT/AC                   PERFORMANCE                                IMPLEMENTATION                                 BUDGET REQUIREMENT
                 OBJECTIVES                                    TIVITIES                      INDICATOR              2017  2018  2019  2020  2021  2022                2017        2018        2019        2020        2021       2022


         1. To extend computer                        Program 2: Computer                                                                                                          Php         Php         Php       Php

              literacy to the Brgy.                      Literacy Program                  Significant                                                                           9,000       9,000       9,000       9,000
              officials, 4P’s members,                                                     increase
              out-of-school youths and              a)  Lecture/                           in the basic
              adults;                                     Demonstration on                 computer
                                                          Microsoft Office                 literacy

         2. To promote with the                           Applications
              participants the following
              basic skills:                         b)  Lecture/

               •  Word processing                         Demonstration on
                   using MS Words or                      Graphic design and
                   other text editors                     IEC production
               •  Spreadsheet like MS

                   Excel for automated
                   calculations                     c)  Lecture/Demonstrati
               •  Scanning and                            on Basic Computer

                   Printing                               Troubleshooting
               •  Emailing and instant
                   messaging
               •  Scanning and

                   Printing digital
                   documents
               •  Burning CD or DVD


         3. To promote and enhance
              the use of technology
              tools, especially the use
              of MS Office applications

              and their benefits.]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[PROGRAM/PROJECT/AC  PERFORMANCE   IMPLEMENTATION            BUDGET REQUIREMENT
 OBJECTIVES   TIVITIES   INDICATOR   2017  2018  2019  2020  2021  2022   2017   2018   2019   2020   2021   2022


 1. To extend computer   Program 2: Computer                         Php   Php      Php       Php

 literacy to the Brgy.   Literacy Program   Significant   9,000       9,000       9,000       9,000
 officials, 4P’s members,      increase
 out-of-school youths and   a)  Lecture/   in the basic
 adults;   Demonstration on   computer
    Microsoft Office   literacy

 2. To promote with the   Applications
 participants the following
 basic skills:   b)  Lecture/

 •  Word processing   Demonstration on
 using MS Words or   Graphic design and
 other text editors   IEC production
 •  Spreadsheet like MS

 Excel for automated
 calculations   c)  Lecture/Demonstrati
 •  Scanning and   on Basic Computer

 Printing   Troubleshooting
 •  Emailing and instant
 messaging
 •  Scanning and

 Printing digital
 documents
 •  Burning CD or DVD


 3. To promote and enhance
 the use of technology
 tools, especially the use
 of MS Office applications

 and their benefits.]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[PROGRAM/PROJECT/AC                   PERFORMANCE                                IMPLEMENTATION                                 BUDGET REQUIREMENT
                 OBJECTIVES                                    TIVITIES                      INDICATOR              2017  2018  2019  2020  2021  2022                2017        2018        2019        2020        2021       2022


          1. To educate participants                          Program 3:                                                                                               Php         Php         Php         Php       Php

              on how to start a small                  Livelihood Programs                 Number of                                                                 60,000      60,000      60,000      60,000      60,000
              business.                                                                    trainers who
                                                        a)  Training on                    adopt the
          2. To educate participants                         Meat/Food                     technology.
              on how to prepare food                         Processing

              and other innovative                      b)  Training on                    Number of
              products that could help                       Dishwashing                   trainers who
              them generate additional                       Liquid and Fabric             engage in

              income.                                                                      business
                                                             Conditioner                   enterprise.
          3. To share with them some                         Making
              skills in preparing                       c)  Preparation of
              innovative products.                           Delicacies

                                                        d)  Seminar on How
          4. To encourage them to                            to Start a
              start a business based on                      Business
              the products that they                    e)  Seminar on How

              have learned to prepare.                       to Start a Small
                                                             Business

                                                        f)  Lecture/Seminar
                                                             on Product

                                                             Marketing and
                                                             Online Marketing
                                                             Strategies, Basic

                                                             Accounting and
                                                             Bookkeeping and

                                                             Financial
                                                             Documentation]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[PROGRAM/PROJECT/AC  PERFORMANCE   IMPLEMENTATION            BUDGET REQUIREMENT
 OBJECTIVES   TIVITIES   INDICATOR   2017  2018  2019  2020  2021  2022   2017   2018   2019   2020   2021   2022


 1. To educate participants   Program 3:                         Php   Php   Php    Php       Php

 on how to start a small   Livelihood Programs   Number of   60,000   60,000   60,000   60,000   60,000
 business.      trainers who
    a)  Training on   adopt the
 2. To educate participants   Meat/Food   technology.
 on how to prepare food   Processing

 and other innovative   b)  Training on   Number of
 products that could help   Dishwashing   trainers who
 them generate additional   Liquid and Fabric   engage in

 income.   business
    Conditioner   enterprise.
 3. To share with them some   Making
 skills in preparing   c)  Preparation of
 innovative products.   Delicacies

    d)  Seminar on How
 4. To encourage them to   to Start a
 start a business based on   Business
 the products that they   e)  Seminar on How

 have learned to prepare.   to Start a Small
    Business

 f)  Lecture/Seminar
 on Product

 Marketing and
 Online Marketing
 Strategies, Basic

 Accounting and
 Bookkeeping and

 Financial
 Documentation]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[PROGRAM/PROJECT/AC                   PERFORMANCE                                IMPLEMENTATION                                 BUDGET REQUIREMENT
                 OBJECTIVES                                    TIVITIES                      INDICATOR              2017  2018  2019  2020  2021  2022                2017        2018        2019        2020        2021       2022


                                                              Program 4:                                                                                               Php         Php         Php         Php

          1. To inculcate the                          Health and Wellness                 Significant                                                               41,000      41,000      41,000      41,000
              importance of health and                                                     increase in
              wellness among                            a)  Aerobics/ Zumba                the level of
              participants.                                  Session                       awareness of
                                                        b)  Summer Sports                  the

          2. To develop spirit of                            Clinic                        participants
              camaraderie among                         c)  Sports fest with               on the said
              participants through                           the Community                 health issues

              sports and other                                                             and other
              recreational activities.                  d)  Seminar on                     GAD-related
                                                             Proper Hygiene                concerns.
          3. To promote continuous                           and Sanitation
              awareness on different                    e)  Continuous

              health issues and                              Awareness Drive
              concerns                                       on Current Health
                                                             Issues (Rabies,

                                                             Dengue, TB,
                                                             AIDS/HIV) and
                                                             GAD-related

                                                             concerns



                     Prepared by:                                                            Reviewed by:                                                           Approved:








                     DEBBIE ROSE T. BANAG                                                    MILDRED SEBASTIAN                                                      LYNN G. PENALES, PhD

                     Extension Coordinator                                                   Campus Coordinator                                                     Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[PROGRAM/PROJECT/AC  PERFORMANCE   IMPLEMENTATION            BUDGET REQUIREMENT
 OBJECTIVES   TIVITIES   INDICATOR   2017  2018  2019  2020  2021  2022   2017   2018   2019   2020   2021   2022


    Program 4:                                  Php         Php         Php         Php

 1. To inculcate the    Health and Wellness   Significant   41,000   41,000   41,000   41,000
 importance of health and      increase in
 wellness among   a)  Aerobics/ Zumba   the level of
 participants.   Session   awareness of
    b)  Summer Sports   the

 2. To develop spirit of   Clinic   participants
 camaraderie among   c)  Sports fest with   on the said
 participants through   the Community   health issues

 sports and other   and other
 recreational activities.   d)  Seminar on   GAD-related
    Proper Hygiene   concerns.
 3. To promote continuous   and Sanitation
 awareness on different   e)  Continuous

 health issues and   Awareness Drive
 concerns   on Current Health
 Issues (Rabies,

 Dengue, TB,
 AIDS/HIV) and
 GAD-related

 concerns



 Prepared by:                Reviewed by:               Approved:








 DEBBIE ROSE T. BANAG         MILDRED SEBASTIAN            LYNN G. PENALES, PhD

 Extension Coordinator            Campus Coordinator            Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[REFORM: THE PROPOSED CVSU RESEARCH AND

                    EXTENSION FRAMEWORK, ORGANIZATIONAL


                          STRUCTURE, ROAD MAP AND AGENDA]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="103"/><page Index="104"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="108"/><page Index="109"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[REGIONAL DEVELOPMENT PLAN


                                                 2017 - 2022]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[Table of Contents]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[Chapter 4

                 Regional Development Plan


                 2017-2022 Overall


                 Framework]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[Enhancing the social

               fabric








                                                       Enabling and supportive

                                                       economic environment







               Reducing inequality






                                                       Foundations for
                                                       sustainable development












               Increasing
               potential growth]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[AMBISYON NATIN 2040]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="132"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="133"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="134"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="135"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="136"><![CDATA[TRANSFORMING OUR WORLD: THE 2030


                             AGENDA FOR SUSTAINABLE


                                            DEVELOPMENT]]></page><page Index="137"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="138"><![CDATA[TRANSFORMING THE WORLD:



                             THE 2030 AGENDA FOR



                    SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT









                                               A/RES/70/1



























                                        UNITED NATIONS



                                           sustainabledevelopment.un.org]]></page><page Index="139"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="140"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="141"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="142"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="143"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="144"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="145"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="146"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="147"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="148"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="149"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="150"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="151"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="152"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="153"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="154"><![CDATA[Sustainable Development Goals

                 Goal 1: End poverty in all its forms everywhere

                 Goal 2: End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition, and promote sustainable
                 agriculture

                 Goal 3: Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages

                 Goal 4: Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning
                 opportunities for all

                 Goal 5: Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls

                 Goal 6: Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all

                 Goal 7: Ensure access to affordable, reliable, and sustainable economic growth, full, and
                 productive employment and decent work for all

                 Goal 8: Promote sustained, inclusive, and sustainable economic growth, full and productive
                 employment and decent work for all

                 Goal 9: Build resilient infrastructure, promote inclusive and sustainable industrialization and
                 foster innovation

                 Goal 10: Reduce inequality within or among countries

                 Goal 11: Make cities and human settlements inclusive, safe, resilient, and sustainable

                 Goal 12: Ensure sustainable consumption and production patters

                 Goal 13: Take urgent action to combat climate change and its impacts. *


                 Goal 14: Conserve and sustainably use the oceans, seas, and marine resources for sustainable
                 development.


                 Goal 15: Protect, restore, and promote sustainable use of terrestrial ecosystems, sustainably
                 manage forests, combat desertification, and halt and reverse land degradation and halt
                 biodiversity loss.

                 Goal 16: Promote peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable development, provide access to
                 justice for all and build effective, accountable and inclusive institutions at all levels.

                 Goal 17: Strengthen the means of implementation and revitalize the Global Partnership for
                 Sustainable Development

                             _______________

                       *Acknowledging that the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change is the primary
                          international, intergovernmental forum for negotiating the global response to climate change.]]></page><page Index="155"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="156"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="157"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="158"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="159"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="160"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="161"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="162"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="163"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="164"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="165"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="166"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="167"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="168"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="169"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="170"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="171"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="172"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="173"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="174"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="175"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="176"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="177"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>
