<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="157"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.1.           The administration, faculty, students


                         and other stakeholders of the


                         College/Academic Unit of Business



                         and Management Education


                         participate in the planning  and



                         organization of  Extension Program.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Republic of the  Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza,  Cavite
                                                      (046)  235  –  7997
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                 EXTENSION SERVICES


                STAKEHOLDER PARTICIPATION IN THE PLANNING OF EXTENSION PROGRAM


                    The extension programs of CvSU – Tanza Campus is based upon the extension agenda of the
             main campus, which in turn is based on the regional and national development thrust and direction. The
             BAGTAS with CvSU – Tanza program is also based on the result of an extensive community needs
             assessment  conducted  by  the  campus  at  Barangay  Bagtas,  Tanza,  Cavite.  Different  stakeholders
             participated during the formulation of Extension Program.

                               STAKEHOLDERS                                    PARTICIPATION

                 Administration                                  Participate  in  the  planning  and  provide
                                                                 necessary  budget  for  implementation  of
                                                                 extension projects.
                 Campus                                          Prepares     Research      and      Extension
                                                                 Agenda/Programs
                 Department of Management                        Will  initiate  the  “Livelihood  Programs”
                                                                 activities and projects.
                 Department of Information Technology            Will initiate the “Computer Literacy Program”
                                                                 activities and projects.
                 Teacher Education Department                    Will initiate the “Oplan Karunungan” activities
                                                                 and projects.
                 Student Organization of BM and HM units         Would provide assistance in different extension
                                                                 activities    including     planning      and
                                                                 implementation
                 Local Government Unit - Tanza                   Coordinate  with  other  government  agencies
                                                                 and  non-government  organization  for  support
                                                                 and  assistance  to  ensure  the  success  of  the
                                                                 program.
                 Barangay  Chairperson  of  Bagtas,  Tanza,  Participates in the planning process and would
                 Cavite                                          provide venue for different activity.
                 Barangay  Residents  particularly  non-working  Participate  in  different  activities  such  as
                 women,  out-of-school  adults,  youth,  children,  planning,  implementation,  evaluation,  and
                 and 4P’s members.                               monitoring of the program, would serve as the
                                                                 beneficiary of the program.

                    Prepared by:

                    RITCH M. BANATE
                    Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Republic of the  Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza,  Cavite
                                                      (046)  235  –  7997
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                 EXTENSION SERVICES

                                  Planning and Organization of Extension Program


                                                            PERSONS INVOLVED
                    DATE
                                   Administration         Faculty            Students          Stakeholders
               December 10,       Dr. Divinia C.
                    2015          Chavez
                                  (University
                                  President)
                                  Prof. Cristina M.
                                  Signo (Tanza
                                  Campus Dean)
              November 11,        Prof. Cristina M.  Mildred A.
              2015                Signo (Tanza       Sebastian
                                  Campus Dean)
                                  Ma. Soledad        Joyce Erika S.
                                  Lising (Director   Senaris
                                  for Extension
                                  Services) Dr.      Cris Albert P.
                                  Alejandro DC.      Cajigas
                                  Mojica (VP for
                                  Research and
                                  Extension) Dr.
                                  Agnes B.
                                  Nuestro (VP for
                                  Academic
                                  Affairs) Dr.
                                  Divinia C.
                                  Chavez
                                  (University
                                  President)
              October 10,         Prof. Cristina M.  Mildred A.
              2015                Signo              Sebastian
                                                     Joyce Erika S.
                                                     Senaris
                                                     Cris Albert P.
                                                     Cajigas
                                                     Debbie Rose T.
                                                     Banag]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Melona O.
                                                     Igmasine
                                                     Ritch M. Banate
                                                     Charmaine T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     John Carlo
                                                     Lopez
                                                     Armin G.
                                                     Aranas
                                                     Mildred A.
              August 20, 2015                        Sebastian
                                                     Joyce Erika S.
                                                     Senaris
                                                     Cris Albert P.
                                                     Cajigas
                                                     Debbie Rose T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     Melona O.
                                                     Igmasine
                                                     Ritch M. Banate
                                                     Charmaine T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     John Carlo
                                                     Lopez
                                                     Armin G.
                                                     Aranas
                                                     Mildred A.
              May 19, 2015                           Sebastian           FAME Society
                                                     Joyce Erika S.      CSS
                                                     Senaris             CSG
                                                     Cris Albert P.      COPE
                                                     Cajigas
                                                     Debbie Rose T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     Melona O.
                                                     Igmasine
                                                     Ritch M. Banate
                                                     Charmaine T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     John Carlo
                                                     Lopez
                                                     Armin G.
                                                     Aranas
                                                     Prof. Cristina M.
              April 10, 2015      Prof. Cristina M.   Signo
                                  Signo (Tanza       Mildred A.
                                  Campus Dean)
                                                     Sebastian]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Joyce Erika S.
                                                     Senaris
                                                     Cris Albert P.
                                                     Cajigas
                                                     Debbie Rose T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     Melona O.
                                                     Igmasine
                                                     Ritch M. Banate
                                                     Charmaine T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     John Carlo
                                                     Lopez
                                                     Armin G.
                                                     Aranas
                                                     Maria Cristina
                                                     C. Tagle
                                                     Jaemelyn G. Dela
                                                     Cruz
                                                     Kimberly L.
                                                     Cemania
                                                     Lorelie B.
                                                     Baltazar
                                                     Rebekkah Ruth
                                                     S. Labaguis
              January 15,         Prof. Cristina M.   Mildred A.         FAME Society
                                                     Sebastian
              2015                Signo (Tanza       Joyce Erika S.      CSS
                                  Campus Dean)                           CSG
                                                     Senaris
                                                     Cris Albert P.      COPE
                                                     Cajigas
                                                     Debbie Rose T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     Melona O.
                                                     Igmasine
                                                     Ritch M. Banate
                                                     Charmaine T.
                                                     Banag
                                                     John Carlo
                                                     Lopez






                    Prepared by:



                    RITCH M. BANATE
                    Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[PHOTO DOCUMENTATION ON PLANNING AND ORGANIZATION OF EXTENSION
                                                        PROGRAM
























































                    Administration, faculty and staff during the planning and organization of extension program]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Administration, faculty, staff and students during the planning and
                                              organization of extension program]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                 Tanza ǀ Trece  Martires  City ǀ  Gen.  Trias  City Campus

                                           235-7997 ǀ    410-5247 ǀ    437-0693
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                  NARRATIVE REPORT

                         BRGY. BAGTAS GENERAL ASSEMBLY AND CONSULTATIVE MEETING


               Cavite State University – Tanza Campus held its second general assembly and consultative meeting on

        October 5, 2019. The assembly and consultative meeting was held from 8:00 a.m. until 4:00 pm at the covered


        court of Lumina Subdivision where hundreds of Bagtas residents participated.

               The event started out with the words of welcome given by the  Barangay Bagtas Chairperson, Engr.

        Manuel T. Mintu, Jr. Then, he also acknowledged the Sangguniang Barangay Members and Staff as well as the

        faculty members of the campus.

               After that, Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas delivered his message to the residents of Barangay Bagtas about

        the extension programs of the campus. He talked about the various extension programs of the campus. Thus,

        he explained that different extension activities are conducted to increase the quality of life of the citizens in the


        barangay.  Non-formal  education  will  help  out-of-school  children  to  be  able  to  read,  write  and  count.  Also,

        livelihood programs deemed to strengthen housewives skills and at the same time, augment the meager income

        of  their  families.  In  addition,  awareness  drives  concerning  health  and  other  GAD-related  issues  are  also

        conducted to inculcate the importance of appropriate living condition for every member of the community.

               Furthermore, Mr. Ritch M. Banate, the extension coordinator of the campus introduced the upcoming


        activities of the campus per extension programs. It was observed that the residents of the barangay were really

        excited to participate in the various activities. This only means that the residents or stakeholders of the barangay

        were really interested to help the barangay alleviate poverty.

               After the extension coordinator introduced and explained the extension programs of the campus, the

        residents were given the opportunity to raise their concerns regarding the different problems they face within

        their community. One of those is about the growing population in Bagtas as the result of lack of knowledge about

        reproductive health and family planning. As a response, the campus promised to conduct an extension activity


        about reproductive health and family planning in response to their concern. Several questions were raised that

        were really relevant to the formation of various extension activities of the campus.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[The closing remarks of Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian concluded the general assembly and consultative


        meeting. Her message focused on the importance of people’s participation in this kind of event as it is a venue

        for a healthy dialogue where issues and concerns were raised and addressed by the campus. This is also a good

        strategy to better improve the extension programs of the campus.

               A total of 359 participants attended the extension activity. The breakdown of the attendees is as follows:

                           PARTICIPANTS                                           HEAD COUNT


                               Students                                                 132

                           Faculty Members                                              18

                        Campus Administrator                                             1

                        Barangay Chairperson                                             1

                     Barangay Officials/Employees                                       26


                         Barangay Residents                                             181

                                TOTAL                                                   359





        During the extension activity, upcoming activities were presented to the participants. These were presented by

        the following:


        Topic: Livelihood Training Programs
        Speaker: Mr. Ritch M. Banate

        Topic: Oplan-Karunungan
        Speaker: Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian

        Topic: Computer Literacy Program
        Speaker: Ms. Joyce Erika S. Senaris

        Topic: Health and Wellness
        Speaker: Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[EXTENSION ACTIVITY: BRGY. BAGTAS GENERAL ASSEMBLY AND CONSULTATIVE MEETING
                                                Lumina Homes Covered Court


































                   The participants during the Barangay Bagtas Assembly and Consultative Meeting for Extension]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                 Tanza ǀ Trece  Martires  City ǀ  Gen.  Trias  City Campus

                                           235-7997 ǀ    410-5247 ǀ    437-0693
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



                         BRGY. BAGTAS GENERAL ASSEMBLY AND CONSULTATIVE MEETING


               Cavite State University – Tanza Campus held its first general assembly and consultative meeting on

        October 13, 2018. The assembly and consultative meeting was held from 8:00 a.m. until 1:00 pm at the covered

        court of Lumina Subdivision where hundreds of Bagtas residents participated.

               The event started out with the words of welcome given by the Barangay Bagtas Chairperson, Engr.


        Manuel T. Mintu, Jr. Then, he also acknowledged the Sangguniang Barangay Members and Staff as well as the

        faculty members of the campus.

               After that, Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis delivered his message to the residents of Barangay Bagtas about the

        extension programs of the campus. He talked about the various extension programs of the campus. Thus, he

        explained that different extension activities are conducted to increase the quality of life of the citizens in the


        barangay.  Non-formal  education  will  help  out-of-school  children  to  be  able  to  read,  write  and  count.  Also,

        livelihood programs deemed to strengthen housewives skills and at the same time, augment the meager income

        of  their  families.  In  addition,  awareness  drives  concerning  health  and  other  GAD-related  issues  are  also

        conducted to inculcate the importance of appropriate living condition for every member of the community.

               Furthermore, Mr. Ritch M. Banate, the extension coordinator of the campus introduced the upcoming

        activities of the campus per extension programs. It was observed that the residents of the barangay were really

        excited to participate in the various activities. This only means that the residents or stakeholders of the barangay


        were really interested to help the barangay alleviate poverty.

               After the extension coordinator introduced and explained the extension programs of the campus, the

        residents were given the opportunity to raise their concerns regarding the different problems they face within

        their community. One of those is about the growing population in Bagtas as the result of lack of knowledge about

        reproductive health and family planning. As a response, the campus promised to conduct an extension activity

        about reproductive health and family planning in response to their concern. Several questions were raised that


        were really relevant to the formation of various extension activities of the campus.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[The closing remarks of Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian concluded the general assembly and consultative


        meeting. Her message focused on the importance of people’s participation in this kind of event as it is a venue

        for a healthy dialogue where issues and concerns were raised and addressed by the campus. This is also a good

        strategy to better improve the extension programs of the campus.

               A total of 261 participants attended the extension activity. The breakdown of the attendees is as follows:

                           PARTICIPANTS                                           HEAD COUNT


                               Students                                                 87

                           Faculty Members                                              18

                        Campus Administrator                                             1

                        Barangay Chairperson                                             1

                         Barangay Councilors                                             5


                         Barangay Residents                                             149

                                TOTAL                                                   261





        During the extension activity, upcoming activities were presented to the participants. These were presented by

        the following:


        Topic: Livelihood Training Programs
        Speaker: Mr. Ritch M. Banate

        Topic: Oplan-Karunungan
        Speaker: Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian

        Topic: Computer Literacy Program
        Speaker: Ms. Joyce Erika S. Senaris

        Topic: Health and Wellness
        Speaker: Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas

        Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:


        RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
        Extension Coordinator                              Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[EXTENSION ACTIVITY: BRGY. BAGTAS GENERAL ASSEMBLY AND CONSULTATIVE MEETING
                                                Lumina Homes Covered Court
























                                Faculty members together with the barangay officials of Bagtas]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[The participants during the Barangay Bagtas Assembly and Consultative Meeting for Extension]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="132"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="133"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="134"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="135"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="136"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="137"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="138"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="139"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="140"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="141"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="142"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="143"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="144"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="145"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="146"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="147"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="148"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="149"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="150"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="151"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="152"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="153"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="154"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="155"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="156"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="157"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>