<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="81"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.2.            The institution has incentives for:


                        S.2.1.  paper presentation;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Knowledge Management Center (KMC)


                                        Manual and Policies]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[1


                             PROPOSED REVISION ON KMC MANUAL OF OPERATIONS



                                                       VOLUME 6
                                             KNOWLEDGE MANAGEMENT


                   INTRODUCTION

                          The Knowledge Management Center (KMC) is one of the four major units under

                   the Office of the Vice President for Research and Extension (Fig. 1). It was created,

                   by virtue of Board Resolution No. 58, s. 2017 approved on September 15, 2017, to

                   coordinate  with  other  units  in  promoting  research  and  extension  culture  in  the

                   University.



                   ARTICLE 1. Objectives

                   Section 1. General Objective.  The main objective of the Knowledge Management

                   Center  is  to  increase  and  sustain  engagement  in  research  and  innovation  in  the

                   University  through  continuous  improvement  of  the  dissemination  and  utilization  of

                   research  outputs  and  innovations  geared  towards  the  attainment  of  sustainable

                   development goals, and ensuring protection of intellectual property rights.



                   Section 2. Specific Objectives. Specifically, it aims to:

                              1. keep  and  maintain  updated  information  and  facilitate  knowledge

                                exchange through locally and internationally recognized publications;

                              2. manage  and  protect  intellectual  property  rights  of  the  University  in

                                accordance with statutory and regulatory requirements; and


                              3.convert  relevant  information  into  shared  knowledge  essential  to  the

                              development of the organization and its stakeholders.


                   ARTICLE 2. Organization and Management



                   Section 1. Organizational Structure.  The organizational structure of KMC is shown

                   in Figure 1. Under the supervision of the Office of the Vice President for Research and]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[2


                   Extension  (OVPRE),  the  Center,  led  by  the  Director,  has  two  major  divisions:

                   Publication and Communication Division and the Intellectual Property and Technology

                   Business  Management  Division.  KMC  shall  coordinate  all  matters  pertaining  to

                   publication and intellectual property  management to the different colleges/campuses


                   and units of the University.






























                          Figure 1. Organizational structure of the Knowledge Management Center



                   Section 3. Duties and Responsibilities


                   a.  Director,  Knowledge  Management  Center.    The  Director  of  the  Knowledge

                      Management Center shall perform the following functions:

                       •  Supervise the overall planning, strategy formulation, and implementation of

                           knowledge management initiatives;

                       •  Propose  programs/opportunities  for  continuous  knowledge  sharing  among


                           faculty, researchers, staff, and students;

                       •  Give  direction  to  the  plans  and  programs  of  the  Center,  particularly  on

                           promoting knowledge and scholarly productivity;

                       •  Administer  the  funds  allocated  for  patenting  and  activities  related  to  the

                           protection and commercialization of the university IP; and]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[3


                       •  Perform other duties as may be assigned by higher authorities.

                    b.  Head,  Publication  and  Communication  Division  (PCD).    The  Head  of


                        Publication and Communication Division shall perform the following duties:

                        •  Direct the overall operation of the Publication and Communication Unit;

                        •  Oversee the publication of R&E scholarly materials, journals, newsletters,

                            brochures and the like;

                        •  Coordinate with other colleges and universities, linkages and partner


                            institutions on the exchange of publications;

                        •  Lead in the screening of faculty with publication and recommend the same

                            for possible publication incentive/support/awards; and

                        •  Perform other duties related to publications as may be assigned by higher

                            authorities.


                    c.  Research  Assistant  (with  special  designation  as  Science  Communicator

                        Specialist).  To  serve  as  staff  of  the  PCD  Head,  the  Science  Communicator

                        Specialist has the following duties and responsibilities:

                       ⚫     Edit scientific documents such as grant applications, manuscripts, abstracts,

                       book chapters, clinical protocols, and poster presentations

                       ⚫    Copyedit and proofread scientific documents substantially

                       ⚫  Organize workshops on writing, publication strategy and good grantsmanship


                       ⚫  Cater to consultations on grammar, punctuation, style, publication, preparation

                       and revision of documents, responses to reviewers’ comments, etc.

                       ⚫  Communicate  scientific  information  to  the  public  through  multimedia  and

                       infographics;

                       ⚫  Organize  seminars  and  training-workshops  related  to  scientific  information


                       dissemination]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[4


                              Editing services will be on a grant basis only where proceeds will be utilized

                       by the University to hire more Science Communicator Specialists.     The  table

                       below contains the types of scientific editing grants and corresponding fees.


                    TYPE OF SCIENTIFIC EDITING SERVICES                    CORRESPONDING FEE

                                                                                     (PhP)

                    Full manuscript for publication                               25,000.00

                    Abstract only                                                   5000.00


                    Grant applications                                            15,000.00

                    Proofreading/Copyediting (1 transaction only)                 10,000.00

                    Statistical Analysis (1 transaction only)                      15,000.00



                    d. Head, Intellectual Property and Technology Business Management Division


                       (IPTBMD).  The Head of the IPTBMD has the following duties and responsibilities:

                        •  Direct the overall operation of IPTBMD;

                        •  Ensure wide dissemination of ideas and creative works produced at CvSU

                            for the utmost possible public benefit;

                        •  Facilitate the conduct of training and awareness seminar on technology


                            innovations, patents and patent rules and regulations;

                        •  Coordinate with higher authorities on the selection of technical people who

                            will assist in the screening of patentable materials;

                        •  Lead in the selection of research materials and products which can be filed

                            for patenting and copyright;


                        •  Facilitate the filing of applications for intellectual property; and

                        •  Perform other duties related to IP and technology business management as

                            may be assigned by higher authorities.

                    e.  Manager, Innovations and Technology Support Office.  The Manager of the

                       Innovations  and  Technology  Support  Office  has  the  following  duties  and


                       responsibilities:]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[5


                       •  Make deposits on copyright, file and prosecute appropriate IP applications on

                           behalf of the University;


                       •  Communicate with researchers regarding technology or research outputs for

                           IP filing;

                       •  Facilitate  transfer  of  ownership  of  technology  to  CvSU  and  submission  of

                           disclosure of the technology;

                       •  Assign technical staff to do patent search and draft claims;


                       •  Respond  to  formality/  substantive/  subsequent  substantive  examination

                           reports from IPOPHL;

                       •  Facilitate the compliance of requirements for the approval of IP; and

                       •  Provide copy of Certificate of Registration of IP to researchers.

                     f.  Manager, Knowledge and Technology Transfer Office.  The Manager of the


                         Knowledge  and  Technology  Transfer  Office  has  the  following  duties  and

                         responsibilities:

                       •  Facilitate  the  establishment  of  a  network  of  companies  connected  to  the

                           University  utilizing  the    generated  technology  from  researches  and/or

                           university researchers (spin-off) to enhance prospects of further development;


                       •  Facilitate  the  creation  of  new  funding  support  from  sponsored  research  or

                           consulting opportunities;

                       •  Provide  assistance  on  all  areas  related  to  entrepreneurship  and

                           commercialization  of  technology  with  filed  intellectual  property  (IP)  and  IP

                           rights;


                       •  Facilitate net royalty generation for the University and collaborating partners;

                       •  Coordinate with higher authorities on the selection of technical experts who will

                           assist in the screening of patentable materials, technology readiness level and

                           investment readiness level;

                       •  Provide profile of CvSU technology with IP to potential investors;


                       •  Facilitate and submit requirements to DOST for fairness opinion report;]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[6


                       •  Draft licensing agreement for the review and verification of the CvSU President

                           and investor; and


                       •  Keep  records  of  investment  readiness  levels,  negotiations,  and  conduct  of

                           trainings and seminars on technology commercialization.

                   ARTICLE 3. Publications


                   Section 1.  Journals in the University


                   Section 1.1 Cavite State University Journals

                       Section 1.1.1. CvSU Research Journal

                          CvSU Research Journal is the official peer-reviewed journal of Cavite State

                   University published biannually, with occasional special issues. It is a compendium of

                   interdisciplinary research outputs of faculty members, researchers, staff, and students

                   of  the  University,  and  contributors  from  other  public  and  private  agencies  and

                   institutions  engaged  in  the  same  fields  of  specialization  and  discipline  as  the


                   University.

                          Articles  and  manuscripts  are  subject  to  review  by  the  editorial  board  and

                   reviewers who are experts in the specified disciplines. The different types of articles or

                   manuscripts  considered  are:  original  research  papers,  research  notes/short

                   communication, review article, case reports, and methods/methodologies. Research

                   papers  from  CvSU,  with  funding  from  international,  national,  regional,  and  local


                   institutions are given priority for publication.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[7


                          Section 1.1. 2. CvSU-housed International Journals

                          These are specialization or discipline-based journals. Cavite State University

                   shall house other journals that are within its field of specialization or discipline. These

                   journals shall follow the general guidelines in this document but may operate based on


                   their specific protocols in consideration of their peculiarities.

                   Section 1.2. Editors, Staff, and Reviewers

                   Section 1.2.1. Editors

                       A.  Selection

                          The Editorial Board shall be a team of faculty members, and researchers from


                          Cavite State University, and experts from various public and private institutions,

                          selected and recommended by the Head of the Publication and Communication

                          Division, Director of the Knowledge Management Center, and Vice President

                          for Research and Extension, and shall be approved by the University President.

                          It shall be headed by the Editor-in-Chief and shall be composed of Editorial

                          Board, Associate Editor, and Review Editors. Additional editors and an Editorial

                          Board may be designated depending on the needs of the Journal.


                       B.  Duties and Responsibilities

                          The Editor-in-Chief is in-charge of the overall operations of the Journal; mainly

                          responsible for final editing and proofreading of manuscript before publications;

                          and  responsible  in  coordinating  with  the  Head  of  the  Publication  and

                          Communication Division, the Editors, and Journal Staff.


                          Associate  Editors  act  as  managing  editors  and  mainly  responsible  in

                          coordinating with authors and contributors, review editors, editor-in-chief, peer

                          reviewers,  and  Journal  staff;  responsible  for  minor  editing  of  manuscripts

                          before being forwarded to the Editor-in-Chief.

                          Review Editors are in-house experts of the University mainly responsible for

                          technical review of submitted articles. They also act as coordinators between

                          authors and contributors, reviewers, associate editors, and the Editor-in-Chief.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[8


                          They  are  responsible  for  minor  or  light  editing  of  manuscripts  before  being

                          forwarded to the Editor-in-Chief.

                   Section 1.2.2. Journal Staff

                          The Editorial Assistant / Layout Artist / Circulation Staff / Web Developer


                   are  responsible  for  the  management  of  the  online  sites,  and  for  distribution  of  the

                   journals.

                   Section 1.2.3. Reviewers

                          Section 1.2.3.1. Selection and Terms of Reference.  The editor shall prepare

                          a shortlist of prospective referees from selected state and private universities


                          and colleges, as well as other line agencies and have this approved by the

                          University President, upon recommendation of the Director for Knowledge and

                          Management  Center  and  Vice  President  for  Research  and  Extension.  The

                          identified individuals shall then be formally invited to become reviewers for the

                          University Journal.

                                  The peer reviewer group shall consist of experts in different fields of

                           specialization and their functions are as follows:


                            •  Inform editor on receipt of article/manuscript for review;

                            •  Review and critique article/manuscript received. (The number of review

                               requests varies according to submission number.);

                            •  Provide  suggestions  and  comments  for  the  improvement  of  the


                               manuscript  or  article  and  assess  manuscript  quality  according  to

                               established criteria;

                            •  Make recommendation of the manuscript or article as accepted, accepted

                               with minor revision, reconsider after major revision or rejected;

                            •  Return article/manuscript reviewed together with accomplished reviewer's


                               forms within the timeframe set by the Editor; and

                            •  Must maintain anonymity and confidentiality in the review process.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[9


                           Section  1.2.3.2.  Incentives  to  Reviewers.    A  professional  fee  based  on

                           approved rate shall be given to each reviewer for every manuscript reviewed

                           regardless of whether it is accepted or rejected for publication. In addition, the

                           following forms of incentive could be awarded to reviewers to recognize their


                           efforts:

                          Certificate of Recognition and other similar documents that could be used for

                          the regular NBC 461 evaluation or assessment for promotional rankings in their

                          respective institutions

                           •  Invitation to exclusive University events


                           •  Referrals for consultancy work for University client

                   Section 1.3. Submission of Manuscript

                   Section 1.3.1. Types of Paper

                       A.  Full paper - A full-length paper. It may be empirical or conceptual/theoretical. It

                          is also called Original Article, or Research Article. Its main body follows the


                          standard  IMRaD  structure  (Introduction,  Methods,  Results  and  Discussion)

                          plus Conclusions and Recommendations.

                       B.  Research note/Short communication.  A research note/short communication is

                          a description of important current findings or observations made in a limited

                          area  of  investigation  which  aims  to  advance  a  new  idea,  theoretical

                          perspective, or new method.

                       C.  Case Study/Case Report.  A case report is a detailed report, usually in the field


                          of medicine and health science, describing an unusual or novel occurrence.

                          Also called Case Study, it may also apply to other fields such as agriculture,

                          education, social sciences, criminal justice, and others.

                       D.  Review article.   A review article is a narrative paper providing a comprehensive

                          summary of many different articles, or research results on a particular topic


                          coherent to the state of the field, and where it is moving towards.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[10


                       E.  Technical Note/Methodology article. This is an article that presents a novel or

                          improved procedure, method, or test.

                       F.  Letter to the Editor / Correspondence. This is a brief communication to the

                          editors of a journal. It may contain an expert commentary on an article recently


                          published  in  the  journal  which  makes  it  a  post-publication  peer  review.

                          However, it may also be a discussion on a topic of interest to the journal’s

                          readership.

                   Section 1.3.2. Manuscript Format

                           The  manuscript  of  Full  papers,  Research  notes/Short  communication,  and


                   Methodology articles should contain the following: title, author/s, abstract, key words,

                   main  body  in  IMRaD  format,  Conclusion  and  Recommendations  (if  there  is  any),

                   Acknowledgement, and Literature Cited. Case Reports and Review articles will have

                   the same content format except that only Introduction and Discussions are found in

                   the main body. The format found in the style guide of the American Psychological

                   Association (APA) shall be used as reference for the journal. The International System

                   of Units (SI) must be used. Write out numbers one to nine, Arabic numeral is preferred.


                   Only the first word, proper nouns, and acronyms are capitalized.

                       A.  The Title may be written in three different forms: descriptive, declarative, and

                          interrogative. Descriptive title is the traditional type wherein the subject of the

                          article  is  described  but  the  main  conclusion  is  not  shown.  Declarative  title

                          reveals  the  main  results  or  conclusion  of  the  paper.  Interrogative  title  is  a


                          description of the subject of the paper in question form.

                       B.  The name/s of each author, followed by the name and address of the units, or

                          for  external  contributors,  the  institution  where  they  are  affiliated,  should  be

                          indicated.

                       C.  The Abstract must be written in one paragraph, concise and could stand alone.

                          It should provide a brief summary of the research, its general objective, major]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[11


                          methods, significant findings, and implications. A statement of rationale may

                          also be included if needed.

                       D.  The  main  body  text  follows  the  IMRaD  format  plus  Conclusion  and

                          Recommendation (if there is any).


                          The  Introduction  provides  sufficient  but  brief  background  information  and

                          rationale  of  the  paper.  The  basic  components  are:  brief  discussions  or

                          statements of the problem; knowledge gap; and the rationale of the study which

                          may include the hypothesis and the objectives of the study. Relevant literature

                          may be mentioned here to add context.


                          The Methodology should be concise but contains sufficient information about

                          the procedures, materials, animals used (if any), and human participants (if

                          any).  This  section  must  be  arranged  chronologically,  by  succession  of

                          procedures, by priority based on objectives, or in any other logical manner. For

                          researches wherein regulation and ethical evaluation is required, there should

                          be a clear statement about the evaluation process it underwent.

                          Results and Discussion may be written in combination or as separate sections.


                          Results  should  contain  a  summary  and  highlights  of  what  the  data  and

                          observations  show.  Data  should  be  presented  in  the  most  concise  manner

                          using tables,  graphs, or other figures.  Depending on the type of  paper, the

                          objectives of the study, and the methods employed, it should follow a logical

                          flow, and if needed, maybe divided into subheadings. The Discussion should


                          contain an extensive but concise interpretation in relation to the main problem

                          and the objectives of the study. It may be compared or contrasted to previously

                          published works and should focus on the most relevant and significant results.

                          Conclusion  and  Recommendation  (if  there  is  any),  may  be  presented  as  a

                          separate section for emphasis of significant findings or included in the results

                          and discussion as the last paragraph.]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[12


                          Acknowledgments should be limited to persons or institutions with substantial

                          contribution to the work, personally or financially. This section should be briefly

                          stated under separate heading placed immediately before the Literature Cited.

                          Literature  Cited  should  only  include  published  papers  mentioned  in  the


                          manuscript. The latest American Psychological Association (APA) citation style

                          shall be used as pattern.

                          Graphs, tables, and other figures should be meaningful representations of data

                          and  results,  and  should  be  self-explanatory,  able  to  stand  alone.  Titles  of

                          graphs, tables, and other figures should be brief and descriptive.


                          Multimedia content may be accepted as part of the online manuscript. These

                   may include 3D models, demonstration of how design outputs work, microscope views,

                   and others that are better shown in motion. To ensure that this can readily be viewed,

                   it is preferred to be submitted as mp4 with a resolution of 720p to 1080p or as a 350

                   image.



                   Section 1.3.3. Review and Acceptance Process

                           The  primary  mode  of  submission  of  manuscript  is  online.  A  prescribed

                   Submission Form with the following sections will be used: Section 1: information about

                   the authors; Section 2: title of paper, abstract, and the main body, which may vary in

                   content depending on the type of paper; Section 3: Author's attestation that the paper

                   is an original work and has not been submitted, nor published in other journals, books,


                   or  other  literary  works,  and  Co-Authors'  permission  to  apply  for  publication;  and

                   Section 4: Copyright Agreement. Links to the submission platform shall be provided in

                   the Call for Papers, and other announcements in the official online sites of the CvSU

                   Research  Journal  and  Knowledge  Management  Center.  Offline  or  hard  copy

                   submissions shall be accommodated using a printed Submission Form that contains

                   the  abovementioned  sections  and  information.  Three  copies,  one  original  and  two

                   duplicates  may  be  submitted  on  a  document  envelope  with  a  printed  address  as


                   follows:]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[13


                                                       The Editor-in-Chief

                                                       Cavite State University Research Journal

                                                       Cavite State University

                                                       Indang, 4122 Cavite, Philippines




                       A.  Screening. The Journal Staff shall be responsible for initial screening based on

                          the  completeness  of  the  application,  and  result  of  plagiarism  checker.

                          Technical  screening  shall  be  done  by  the  technical  associate  editor  who

                          specializes,  or  is  a practitioner  in the field  or  discipline  the  manuscript  falls


                          under.  The  general  criteria  for  evaluation  will  include:  1)  originality  and

                          innovativeness;  2)  relevance  and  long-term  value;  3)  quality  of  data  and

                          methodologies  applied;  4)  presentation  and  paper  organization;  and  5)

                          soundness of  conclusion.  The topic should also fall within  the scope of the

                          research thematic areas of the university. Depending on the results of review,

                          and  extent  of  revision  needed,  the  editorial  board  shall  either  return  the

                          manuscript  to  the  corresponding  author,  or  forward  it  to  the  external  peer


                          reviewer after two (2) weeks.

                       B.  Review. The same criteria used for technical screening will also be used for the

                          external peer review. The external reviewer shall be given two (2) weeks for

                          this. After being returned, the author(s) may either comply to the suggestions

                          and recommendations of the external peer reviewer, or state an explanation or


                          justification in response to the reviewer’s notes. The Technical Associate Editor

                          and the Editor-in-Chief shall deliberate on the final revisions. If needed, the

                          external reviewer and the authors shall be consulted.

                       C.  Acceptance for Publication. A Notice of Acceptance for Publication shall be

                          sent to the author/corresponding author once a final draft of the manuscript is

                          accepted for publication.



                   Section 1.4. Authorship]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[14


                          This entails important implications in the academic standing, responsibility, and

                   accountability of a researcher, scholar, or writer. It also has a financial implication since

                   they are also given monetary rewards for their work. All of the following criteria should

                   be  met  to  be  recognized  as  a  legitimate  author  of  a  manuscript  submitted:  1)


                   substantial contribution to the conception, innovation, and design of the work, or to the

                   collection, analysis, and interpretation of data; 2) substantial contribution to the drafting

                   and revisions of the paper and other outputs; and 3) accountability in all aspects related

                   to the integrity of the work. The author shall be responsible for communicating and

                   dealing with the Editorial Board and Journal Staff from submission until publication.


                   For multiple authors, the Corresponding Author shall be responsible for this. Faculty

                   members,  researchers,  staff,  and  students  of  the  University,  as  well  as  external

                   contributors  who are experts, specialists, or practitioners in any the same fields of

                   discipline of the University are eligible to submit their papers. Outputs of researches

                   funded by international, national, regional, and local institutions are given priority for

                   publication.



                   Section 2. Miscellaneous Publications

                   Section 2.1. Research and Extension Newsletters

                   Section 2.1.1. REconnections

                            REconnections is the official newsletter (in English) of the Office of the Vice-

                   President  for  Research  and  Extension.  Published  monthly,  it  serves  as  the


                   conglomerate  of  development  issues  and  impending  endeavors  of  the  R&E

                   community. Specifically, it aims to provide an avenue for the information dissemination

                   of the R&E activities, projects, accomplishments, and targets of the University.

                           The members of the Editorial Board shall be selected and recommended by

                   the  Head  of  Publication  and  Communication  Division,  Director  of  the  Knowledge

                   Management Center and the Vice President for Research and Extension, and shall be

                   approved by the University President. It shall be headed by the Editor-in-Chief and


                   shall be composed  of  two Associate Editors, Layout  Artist, Editorial  Assistant, and]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[15


                   Circulation  Manager.  The  Director  for  Knowledge  Management  Center,  the  Vice-

                   President for R & E and the University President shall serve as consultants.

                   The functions and duties of the members of the Editorial Board are as follows:

                   Editor-in-Chief


                       •  Responsible  in  planning,  coordinating  and  final  editing  articles  for  the

                          newsletter.

                       •  Make final decisions on the content of the newsletter for publication.


                       •  Oversee  the  associate  editors,  layout  artist,  and  circulation  manager  and

                          discuss plans, identify problem areas and resolve issues.

                       •  Ensure that the publication is properly laid out and full by conducting a final

                          review before sending the publication to print.

                       •  Confer  and  liaise  with  concerned  authorities  on  issues  arising  from  the


                          published newsletter.

                   Associate Editor

                       •  Assist Editor-in-Chief in the selection and planning of content of the newsletter.

                       •  Edit news articles and check on the authenticity of facts.

                       •  Proofread  articles  to  guarantee  accuracy  and  adherence  to  publication


                          standards.

                   Editorial Assistant

                       •  Support senior editors (Editor-in-Chief and Associate Editors) in all aspects of

                          the publishing process.

                       •  Perform all administrative tasks and clerical duties.


                       •  Keep records on meeting proceedings and notes from the Editor-In-Chief.

                   Circulation Manager

                       •  Oversee the entire distribution process and promotions of the newsletter.

                       •  Coordinate with editorial staff to finalize master copies of the newsletter for

                          distribution.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[16


                       •  Maintain circulation database and create strategies for the timely distribution of

                          the newsletter.


                   Layout Artist

                       •  Responsible for the layout of content and overall physical appearance of the

                          newsletter.

                       •  Prepare templates relevant to the newsletter.

                       •  Assist in the orderliness of the unit's file system.




                        The writers/contributors will come from the different colleges/campuses and units

                   of the University.

                   Section 2.1.2. Ugnayan

                              Published quarterly using Filipino as a medium, this publication focuses on

                   the news and issues about the Extension projects of the different colleges/campuses

                   and units of the University. The writers/ contributors per issue will be the Extension


                   Coordinators of each unit although those who are interested are very much welcome.

                   Having the same duties and responsibilities as that of the REconnections’, Ugnayan

                   editorial board is composed of the Editor-in-Chief, two Associate Editors, Layout Artist,

                   Editorial  Assistant,  and  Circulation  Manager.  The  Director  for  Extension  Services,

                   Director of the Knowledge Management Center, the Vice-President for Research and


                   Extension and the University President shall serve as consultants.






                   Section 2.2. Techno-Guides

                              Techno-guides  are  brochures/  leaflets/ flyers  regarding  a  technology  for


                   dissemination and adoption. Experts will be encouraged to  prepare techno-guides.

                   Priorities will be given to those which concern the University’s commodity thrusts.


                   Section 2.3. Multimedia Publications]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[17


                              This  refers  to  all  non-print  publications  such  as  online  posters  and

                   infographics, videos, animated, interactive graphics, and other similar materials that

                   are produced by faculty, researchers, students, and staff of CvSU.



                   Section 3. Copyright of Publications

                             Cavite State University owns the copyright of all publications including the

                   CvSU Research Journal, the newsletters, techno guides, and multimedia publications.

                   By this, all authors are informed of this upon submission of their articles, and formally

                   signify their agreement to transfer ownership to the University. On the other hand, the


                   CvSU-housed Journals are operated and co-managed with an external entity, usually

                   an  organization  or  society  engaged  in  a  specific  discipline,  and  thus,  are  semi-

                   independent. Publications in these journals are copyrighted to the journal itself.



                   ARTICLE 4. Publishing in External Journals, Applying for Publications Support

                   and Incentive, and Awards and Recognition


                   Section 1. Publishing in External Journals

                   Section 1.1. Papers that Require Authorization of the Knowledge Management

                   Center

                   Section 1.1.1. Criteria for Authorization

                           Papers that require Authorization of the Knowledge Management Center are

                   those that meet any or all of the following criteria:


                       a.  Papers  whose  author/s  is/are  faculty  members,  researchers,  or  students  of

                          Cavite State University, and research was conducted in the university; and/or

                       b.  Research was funded by CvSU; and/or

                       c.  Paper is part of the Thesis or Dissertation of a faculty member or researcher

                          for a degree obtained in another university.

                   Section 1.1.2. Requirements for the Authorization to Publish

                           The  Authority  to  Publish  in  a  CHED  Recognized  peer-reviewed  External


                   Journal, signed by the Head of the Publications and Communication Division, and the]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[18


                   Director of the Knowledge Management Center, shall be issued upon submission of

                   any or all of the following, whichever is/are applicable:

                     a.  For papers whose author(s) is(are) faculty members, researchers, or students

                          of Cavite State University, a Permission to Publish signed by all authors, in the


                          case of multiple authors, and Dean or Head of Unit;

                     b.  For researches funded by CvSU, a Permission to Publish signed by the Director

                          for Research;

                     c.  For  papers  that  are  part  of  a  thesis  or  dissertation  from  other  schools,  a

                          Permission to Publish signed by the advisory committee and the Dean of the


                          Graduate School or someone with equivalent or higher authority.

                   Section 1.2. Assistance for Non-Required Papers

                         Authors who are applying their papers for external publications may voluntarily

                   seek technical assistance from KMC. Technical assistance includes editing to make

                   the paper publication-ready.

                   Section 1.3. Reporting of External Publication Applications

                         All  publications  in  external  journals  are  to  be  reported  to  the  Knowledge


                   Management Center by the college research coordinators collectively.

                   Section 2. Publication Support

                          In  support  of  application  for  publication,  a  researcher  or  author  from  the

                   University is entitled to apply for support in paying the actual amount of publication fee

                   for journal publication, provided that they are one of the authors, they meet the criteria


                   for authors as mentioned in Article 3, Section 1.5 of this document, and they have an

                   Authorization to Publish from KMC, if applicable. Those who have an Authorization to

                   Publish  from  the  Knowledge  Management  Center  may  indicate  that  they  are

                   automatically applying for Publication Support by accomplishing the corresponding box

                   in the said document.

                   Section 3. Publication Incentive]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[19


                         Publication  incentives  shall  be  granted  to  the  faculty,  researchers  and  staff
                   whose papers are published in peer-reviewed journals provided that:

                       a.  the papers  were published in  institutional, regional, national or  international
                          refereed journal accredited by the Commission on Higher Education, and /or
                          updated Scopus list or Clarivate Web of Science -indexed journals;

                       b.  the    research      is    either     internally/externally   funded     or
                          thesis/dissertation/research  requirement  of  faculty  or  staff.  In  case  of

                          thesis/dissertation  and  research  paper  requirement  in  a  course,  the  Cavite
                          State University should be listed as an affiliation of the author; and
                       c.  they have plantilla positions in the University or employed as contractual.


                         The  amount  of  monetary  incentives  shall  be  based  on  the  category  of  the
                   refereed journal relative to its geographical scope, and indexing as shown in Table 1.


                   Table 1 . Publication incentives based on the category of the refereed journal

                                                              INCENTIVE (PhP)

                                     Internally/Externally Funded    Thesis/Dissertation/Research
                    CATEGORY         Researches of the University   Paper Requirement in a Course
                                                                              or Subject

                    Clarivate Web               35,000                          35,000
                     of Science or

                        Scopus
                       indexed

                     International              20,000                          15,000

                       National                 15,000                           7,500


                      Institutional             7,500                            3,750


                          For papers with more than one author, incentives shall be pro-rated according

                   to the degree of participation.  Pro-rated incentive will only apply to the authors of


                   publication from CvSU.]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[20



























                   Section 4. Citation Incentive

                           Similar with publication incentive, the monetary incentive for author citation


                   shall  be  based  on  the  category  of  the  refereed  journal  relative  to  its  geographical

                   scope, and indexing. It will also similarly be prorated. The amount of incentive will be

                   given per number of citations, and may be applied for on a yearly basis. Self-citation

                   is excluded in the incentives.

                   Table 2. Citation incentives based on the category of the refereed journal


                                    Category                              Incentive (PhP)

                       Clarivate Web of Science or Scopus                       2,000
                                     indexed

                                   International                                1,000

                                     National                                    800


                                   Institutional                                 500]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[21


                         For papers with more than one author, incentives shall be pro-rated according to

                   the  degree  of  participation.    Pro-rated  incentive  will  only  apply  to  the  authors  of

                   publication from CvSU.

                   Section 5. Book Chapter Publication Incentive


                          Authors of research outputs that are published as a chapter of  updated Scopus

                   or Clarivate Web of Science – indexed books shall also be given incentives amounting

                   to a PhP 10,000. However, this shall also be prorated based on the following scheme:

















                   Section 6. Recognition and Awards for Publications

                           A  certificate  of  recognition  will  be  awarded  to  researchers  with  successful

                     publications  during  the  Annual  Research  and  Extension  In-House  Review  and

                     Celebration.

                   Article 5.  Paper Presentation in Conferences and Other Fora



                         Section 1. For Student-Led Researches. Thesis or dissertation that were either

                   funded through the Faculty and Students Research Capability Enhancement Fund, the

                   CvSU  Research  Grant  or  other  funding  agencies  must  be  presented  by  students

                   themselves and the students must be the primary authors. Unless expressly agreed

                   upon by the student in writing, the adviser or another member of the thesis panel may

                   present the study on their behalf.

                          Section  2.  For  Faculty  Led  Researches.  Faculty  members  can  present


                   research outputs themselves only if what will be presented are projects or programs of

                   which they are the lead investigators. However, they cannot  present the individual]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[22


                   studies done by their student riders, unless expressly agreed upon by the students in

                   writing as mentioned above.

                          In presenting the project or program, the faculty member should indicate the

                   names of the individual students who took part in the study.


                          Section 3. Funding for Paper Presentation. Priority is given to funded studies

                   local or external that have been presented for funding to the University or external

                   funding agencies and have been presented for evaluation during the Agency In-House

                   Review. The number of presentations to be funded per year would be based on the

                   minimum targets of the University.  These slots will be distributed per college/campus


                   proportional  to  the  number  of  faculty  researchers  and/or  approved  researches.  A

                   faculty member can avail funding for paper presentation only once per year whether it

                   is  in  an  international  or  local  conference  to  give  chance to  other  deserving  faculty

                   members.  Faculty  members  who  opt  to  present  more  papers  should  be  willing  to

                   shoulder all expenses but shall be on official time.

                           For  international  paper  presentation,  the  presenter  will  only  be  given  one

                   opportunity every two years. Amount of fund for an international paper presentation


                   will  be  a  maximum  of  Php  50,000.00  inclusive  of  the  conference  registration  fee,

                   economy  airfare,  hotel  accommodation  and  daily  subsistence  allowance  (DSA).

                   Amount in excess will be shouldered by the faculty member.

                          For local, regional or national paper presentation, a faculty member may

                   present for not more than twice per year. A maximum amount of Php 10,000.00 will


                   be given.

                          Section 4. General Requirements

                   1. Approved Letter of Request

                   2. Notice of Acceptance from the Conference Organizers (Conference should be non-

                   predatory).  Priority  will  be  given  to  conference  that  has  corresponding  journal  for

                   accepted papers (e.g. Elsevier-organized conferences)]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[23


                   3. Accepted  Abstract  showing  the  name  of  the  faculty  member  as  the  Presenting

                   Author and that the institution of the faculty member is CvSU only.



                   4. Publication-ready  paper  following  the  CvSU  Research  Journal  Guidelines  or  the

                   journal of the conference.


                   5. Budgetary estimate showing the airfare (economy class), DSA following government

                   approved guidelines, hotel accommodation (cheapest) and conference fee (preferably

                   early bird rate).



                       Section 5. Screening of Papers for Oral Presentation

                   1.      The  Knowledge  Management  Center  will  determine  the  completeness  of  the

                       submitted  requirements  of  all  requests  for  funding.  Only  those  with  complete

                       submissions will be processed.


                   2.      In  coordination  with  the  Research  Center,  KMC  will  verify  if  the  paper  has

                       undergone proper monitoring and evaluation particularly if it has been presented

                       to the Annual Agency In-House Review.

                   3.   The Center will then check if the slots allotted for the College/Campus/Unit has not

                       yet been used up.

                   4.    The Center will then notify the faculty member of the results of their application


                       not more than three (3) working days from the date of submission of complete

                       requirements.



                   Article 6. Intellectual Property Policy

                            Pursuant  to  the  university’s  mission,  Cavite  State  University  creates,

                   preserves, and disseminates knowledge through instruction, scholarships, research,


                   and extension. Knowledge management may involve faculty, student, staff, and third-

                   party authors and inventors. It often takes the form of intellectual property which can

                   be further developed and/or shared with others, locally, nationally, and globally, for

                   further societal benefit and commercialization.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[24


                          This set of policies seeks to protect the interests of both inventors, creators and

                   CvSU, while also ensuring that the community and society benefit from the fair and full

                   dissemination of knowledge and innovation.

                          This set of policies seeks to provide guidelines that can be consistently applied


                   to facilitate the incubation and/or commercialization of research outputs and to arrive

                   at  reasonable  solutions  to  possible  IP  issues  relating  to  the  conduct  of  research,

                   incubation, and knowledge and technology transfer.

                          Nothing in this policy relieves CvSU of the obligation of adhering to Philippine

                   Law or CvSU contracts, including Research Agreements.


                          Section 1. General Principles

                                 Section  1.1  The  university  resources  should  be  used  for  University

                          purposes and not for personal gain or personal commercial advantage nor for

                          any  other  non-University  purposes.  The  University  subscribes  to  a  policy

                          recognizing the academic practice of treating faculty members as owners of

                          inventions, works and other intellectual creations they generate without the use

                          of  University  and/or  third  party  funding,  and  without  the  use  of  substantial


                          University and/or third party resources, which are not ordinarily available to all

                          faculty for traditional academic purposes which includes teaching, research,

                          and extension work.

                                 Section  1.2.  The  University  encourages  the  faculty’s full  freedom  in

                          research  and  in  the  publication  of  their  results  subject  to  the  adequate


                          performance of their other academic duties.

                                 Section 1.3. The University acknowledges that its efforts to generate

                          income  should  be  weighed  against  its  principal  responsibility  to  provide  a

                          favorable  environment  to  explore  knowledge  for  the  benefit  of  the  public  in

                          general;  and]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[25


                                 Section 1.4. The University accepts that in some cases, the recognition

                          of Intellectual Property (IP) Rights of authors and inventors are effective ways

                          to ensure accountability and accessibility of knowledge and technologies.

                   Section 2. Scope

                          All  affected  university  personnel  and  students  shall  comply  with  this  set  of

                   Policies, as amended from time to time. This Policy is considered part of the conditions

                   of employment, enrollment, or participation in a sponsored research project, and shall

                   be referenced in the Student’s Handbook and University Operations Manual.


                   Section 3. Objectives



                       The Policy reflects the following objectives:


                       1.Promote and support the institution’s research function, provide an institutional


                       mechanism  for  recognition  of  research  output  and  protect  IPR  resources  to

                       encourage and uphold further research;

                       2.  Establish a clear guideline for protecting the interests of its various stakeholders.

                       3. Establish standards for determining the rights and obligations of the university

                             and creators of intellectual property;

                       4. Ensure compliance with applicable laws and regulations; and

                       5. Ensure filing of protections or the IP prior to any publications.



                   Section 4. Other Provisions



                        Section 4.1. Unauthorized actions. Personnel and students may not: (1) sign

                              agreements  or  take  any  action  on  behalf  of  CvSU  unless  they  are

                              authorized  agents  of  CvSU  and  have  the  express  permission  of  the


                              University President or authorized representative; or (2) make unauthorized

                              use  of  CvSU’s  name.  CvSU  will  not  honor  unauthorized  actions  or

                              agreements.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[26


                        Secton 4.2. Acquisition. CvSU may acquire ownership or use of Intellectual

                              Property by assignment, license, gift, or any other legal means. CvSU shall

                              administer such Intellectual Property in accordance with this Policy unless

                              otherwise required by the terms of the acquisition.




                   Section 5. Coverage of IP Policies
                                 Section 5.1    This Policy covers all researches, research contracts,


                        tangible  research  properties  or  outputs  with  or  without  patent  or  copyright

                        protection, whether  for commercial or non-commercial purpose, undertaken by

                        all faculty members, researchers, students, other employees of the University

                        including those on sabbatical leave and on leave with pay, part-time and visiting

                        professors participating in any program, project, contract or research activity in

                        the University using any university resource and including all technology transfer


                        arrangements.


                                 Section 5.2. IP Rights Covered

                                 All types of intellectual property rights (IPRs) enumerated under the IP

                        Code (RA 8293) are covered by this set of IP policies: Copyright and related

                        rights, Patents, Trademarks and service mark, Geographic indications, Industrial


                        designs,  Layout  designs  of  integrated  circuits,    Protection  of  undisclosed

                        information and  New plant variety protection, as provided in Republic Act No.

                        9168



                   Section 6. Ownership and Use

                          Cavite State University shall have the right to reproduce and otherwise use for

                   research and educational purposes any IP, whether owned by CvSU, personnel, or


                   student, created in whole or in part through the use of any Significant Resources. CvSU

                   further reserves the right to pursue multiple forms of legal protection for IP which it

                   owns or for which it claims ownership. Software and other products of the same nature,]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[27


                   may be protected by copyright, patent, trade secret, and trademark. In addition, CvSU

                   shall own all rights in:


                           •  patentable  inventions  and  copyrightable  works  created  by  CvSU

                              Personnel with Significant Use of Resources while on paid leave, including

                              sabbatical.

                           •  IP as stated in written agreements. If CvSU wishes to secure additional

                              rights in any IP, it shall so specify in writing at  the time it provides the

                              Resources.

                              Section 6.1. Responsibilities of Personnel and Students


                                 Section 6.1.1 Assignment.  For Intellectual Property and other works

                        to which CvSU has or had rights of ownership or use under this Policy, creators,

                        personnel,  and  students  shall,  upon  request,  execute  all  appropriate  legal

                        documents, including assignments, and perform such acts designed to assist

                        CvSU or its assignees in proving or benefiting from such rights, all as deemed


                        appropriate by CvSU.

                                 Section 6.1.2. Students. Students may be requested to grant rights or

                        ownership in Student-developed IP to CvSU or others as a condition of access to

                        certain class projects, independent research projects, or other programs at CvSU.

                        Students who choose not to grant rights or ownership in Student-developed IP

                        shall  not  participate  in  these  class  projects,  independent  research  projects,  or

                        other programs, but shall be given the opportunity to participate, without penalty,


                        in alternative projects which do not require the granting of rights or ownership in

                        Student-developed IP.

                                 Section  6.1.3.  Use.    All  personnel  and  students  are responsible  for

                        complying with CvSU policies and guidelines, and all applicable laws regarding

                        Intellectual Property.


                             Section 6.2 Personnel.  Newly employed or newly engaged personnel shall

                          disclose in writing to the director of the Intellectual Property Management Office]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[28


                          any  IP  they  own  or  have  developed,  which  they  plan  to  continue  using,

                          teaching,  or  researching  while  employed  or  engaged  by  CvSU.  The  Vice

                          President  for  Research  and  Extension  shall  determine  the  appropriate

                          ownership of this IP, in consultation with the Office of Legal Affairs. Should it


                          be determined that the Personnel do not own the IP, its use at CvSU may be

                          restricted. Should it be determined that the Personnel own the IP, its use at

                          CvSU shall be consistent with other CvSU policies and procedures, including

                          but not limited to the Individual Conflict of Interest and Commitment Policy.

                                 The decision of the Vice President for Research and Extension may be


                        appealed  to  the  Intellectual  Property  Policy  Committee.  The  decision  of  the

                        Intellectual Property Policy Committee may be appealed to the appropriate office,

                        whose decision shall be final.

                      Section 6.3  Responsibilities of CvSU

                          Section 6.3.1. Use of Resources.  When CvSU authorizes or directs efforts

                          to create a work involving the Significant Use of Resources, it shall enter into a

                          written  agreement  addressing  the  extent  of  use  of  such  Resources,  the


                          schedule for the project (if appropriate), control over the work and its revisions,

                          and ownership of the resulting IP, if any.

                          Section 6.3.2. Revenue Sharing.  CvSU shall remit to inventors their share of

                          Revenue.

                          Section 6.3.3. Dissertations and Theses Publication.  CvSU mandates the


                   publication  of  required  graduate  dissertations  and  theses  in  the  interests  of  open

                   dissemination of research results and scholarship.  Occasionally, a request may be

                   made to the dean of all colleges and campuses to embargo a dissertation or thesis for

                   up to 12 months.  In such cases, the Intellectual Property and Technology Business

                   Management  Division  (IPTBMD)  and  respective  dean  of  college  will  coordinate  a

                   dissertation/thesis content review, in consultation with the thesis advisor, for potential]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[29


                   CvSU patentable material. Patentable material review shall take no longer than 90

                   days from the time a completed set of material is received by the CvSU- IPTBMD.

                          Section  6.3.4.  Externally  Funded  Research.    All  Intellectual  Property

                   developed by personnel performing work sponsored by governmental, commercial,


                   industrial,  or  other  public  or  private  organizations  shall  belong  to  CvSU  unless

                   otherwise specified in a written agreement or applicable state laws and regulations.

                   However, on a case-to-case basis, CvSU may agree to assign ownership or licensing

                   rights  to  the  sponsor,  subject  to  CvSU’s  right  to  reproduce  and  otherwise  use  the

                   Intellectual Property for research and educational purposes. The Vice President for


                   Research and Extension shall approve any such agreement.

                          Section  6.3.5.  Internally  Funded  Research.    All  Intellectual  Property

                   developed  by  personnel  performing  work  under  Internally  Funded  Research  shall

                   belong  to  CvSU.  However,  on  a  case-to-case  basis,  CvSU  may  agree  to  assign

                   ownership or licensing rights, subject to CvSU’s right to reproduce and otherwise use

                   the Intellectual Property for research and educational purposes. The Vice President

                   for Research and Extension shall approve any such agreement in writing.


                   Section 7. Copyright of Works.  As a general rule, copyright of all works shall remain

                   with the author/creator, except in cases of institutional or collaborative works.

                          Section 7.1. Original Work.  Original work shall be owned by the Creator or

                   Personnel unless it:

                                     1. is  subject  to  any  claim  of  ownership  by  another  entity  or


                                     individual. In that case, Original Work shall be owned by the other

                                     entity or individual with the valid claim of ownership.

                                     2. was created with the Significant Use of CvSU Resources. In that

                                     case Original Work shall be owned by CvSU.

                                     3. was  created  in  connection  with  an  Expressed  Assignment  or

                                     commissioning. In that case, Original Work shall be owned by the

                                     entity or individual providing the Expressed Assignment.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[30


                                     4. was created within the Inventor’s Scope of Employment, under

                                     an  internally  or  externally  funded  research  program,  or  other

                                     agreement  which  requires  the  IP  to  be  assigned  to  CvSU  or

                                     Sponsor.


                          Section  7.2.  Institutional  Work.    The  University  shall  have  exclusive

                   ownership over institutional works. Institutional works include:

                          1. works that are supported by a specific allocation of University funds or other

                          resources other than the usual salary and resources made available to every

                          faculty, student or staff;


                          2. works created at the direction and control of the University through its official

                          or designates for the purpose of a specific project or purpose; and

                          3. works whose authorship cannot be attributed to one or a discrete number of

                          authors despite the applications of processes prescribed, namely:

                                            •  the  said  works  is  the  result  of  simultaneous  result  of

                                                simultaneous  or  sequential  contributions  over  time  by


                                                multiple authors;

                                            •  works  created  through  substantial  use  of  University

                                                resources such as libraries, research facilities, buildings,

                                                utilities, equipment, tools, apparatus including services

                                                of  its  employees  working  within  the  scope  of  their

                                                activities not for University purposes but for the personal


                                                gain  or  advantage  of  the  faculty,  research  staff  or

                                                student involved. There is a presumption of substantial

                                                use of University resources if the work has in any way

                                                been done during office hours or within the premises of

                                                the  University  and  is  related  to  unauthorized  outside


                                                teaching or the practice of profession without requisite

                                                permission.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[31


                         Section 7.3. Collaborative Works.  In the absence of any contract, the result of

                   collaborative efforts between the University, an outside institution and the creator/s,

                   the copyright shall be jointly owned by the University, the creator/s and the outside

                   institution.


                   Section 8. Conditions for Lifting Default Ownership.  In case of institutional works

                   and works of joint ownership with the University, the University through its designated

                   officials may waive copyright in favor of the creator if all of the following conditions are

                   met:

                                 •  the waiver would enhance the transfer of technology or improve the


                                     access of the works by the public in general;

                                 •  the waiver does not violate any existing contractual obligations; and

                                 •  the participation of the University in the work is acknowledged by

                                     the creator in all, whether local or international publications of the

                                     work.


                                 •  If the University is unable or has not decided to publish or exhibit

                                     the  works  within  ONE  YEAR  from  its  disclosure,  its  copyright  is

                                     automatically waived IN FAVOR of the creator. The one-year period

                                     may also be waived by the University at the request of the creator if

                                     the  work  is  to  be  published  in  a  reputable  international  or  local


                                     journal  relevant  to  the  academic  discipline  to  which  the  work

                                     belongs.  The  contribution  of  the  University  shall  be  duly

                                     acknowledged in all publications or exhibitions of the work.

                      Section  8.1  Patents.    As  a  general  rule,  rights  to  patents  shall  belong  to  the

                   inventors  except  in  commissioned  inventions  where  the  University  shall  own  all

                   patents.

                         Section 8.1.1 Commissioned Inventions


                                     •  Inventions  that  are  supported  by  a  specific  allocation  of

                                         University funds or other University resources;]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[32


                                     •  Inventions produced at the direction and control of the University

                                         in  pursuit  of  a  specific  project  or  purpose  regardless  of  the


                                         source of funding;

                                     •  Works whose inventorship could not be attributed to one or a

                                         discrete number of inventors despite the application of existing

                                         processes or rules;

                                     •  Those  that  may  be  stipulated  by  contract  as  commissioned


                                         inventions.

                      Section  8.1.2.  Disclosure  and  Assignment.    Creators  of  commissioned

                   inventions should disclose and assign the patent to these works to the University in

                   accordance with existing rules and implementing guidelines as stipulated in the CvSU

                   Manual of Operations.

                       Section  8.1.3.  Inventions  as  a  Result  of  Collaborative  Efforts.    The

                   identification of inventorship, whether sole, primary or joint, shall be determined as


                   follows:

                                     •  by contractual stipulation; and

                                     •  by  applications  of  the  rules  and  standards  of  a  publication

                                        primarily intended by the collaborative effort;

                      Section  8.1.4.  Inventions  Funded  by  Outside  Agencies.    In  the  event  that


                   funding for the research is sourced by the University, entirely or partially, from outside

                   agencies, the University shall negotiate with the funding agency with respect to the

                   ownership of the invention, patent rights and royalty sharing subject to confirmation of

                   the Board of Regents. The agreement shall bind parties including the inventors.

                      Section 8.1.5. Required Assignment of Patent to the University. Regardless of

                   the  source  of  funding,  patents  to  the  following  inventions  shall  be  assigned  to  the


                   University:]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[33


                                      •  those  conceived  or  first  reduced  to  practice  by  employees,

                                          faculty  or  students  in  the  University  in  the  course  of  the


                                          performance of their duties;

                                      •  those created through substantial use of University resources

                                          such  as  libraries,  research  facilities,  buildings,  utilities,

                                          equipment,  tools,  and  apparatus,  including  services  of  its

                                          employees working within the scope of their employment.

                      Section 8.1.6. Waiver by the University of Rights to Patent.  In the absence of

                   contractual  obligation  to  third  parties,  the  University  may  release  patent  rights  to


                   inventors IF ALL of the following conditions are met:

                                     •  the  University  elects  not  to  file  a  patent  application  after  the

                                        disclosure of the invention and the inventor is prepared to do so;

                                     •  the  waiver  would  facilitate  the  transfer  of  technology  or  its

                                        access to the general public; and


                                     •  the  equity  of  the  situation  clearly  indicates  that  such  release

                                        should be given.

                                         Waiver shall be given unless there is a written commitment that

                                 no  further  development  of  the  invention  shall  be  made  involving  the

                                 financial  support  or  resources  of  the  University  and  no  contractual


                                 obligation of the University is violated.

                   Section 9. Trade and Service Marks.  Trade and service marks are distinctive words

                   or graphic symbols long associated with the University (e.g. Laya at Diwa, CvSU seal,

                   etc.) registered by the University with the Intellectual Property Office of the Philippines

                   (IPOPHL).  The  University  shall  own  trade  or  service  marks  relating  to  goods  or

                   services distributed by the University. These include names and symbols used by the


                   University in conjunction with its computer programs or University activities and events.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[34


                   Section  10.  Propriety  Information.    Proprietary  information  includes  information

                   arising  from  University  work.  These  include  processes  which  may  fall  under  the

                   concept of trade secrets.

                   Section 11. Tangible Research Property (TRP).  These are research results which


                   are  in  tangible  form  (i.e.  integrated  circuit  chips,  computer  software,  biological

                   organisms, engineering prototypes, manuals and other publications) which cannot be

                   the  subject  of  any  other  kind  of  Intellectual  Property  protection  are  presumptively

                   considered as owned by the University. All TRPs may not be used by outside parties

                   without the consent of the University.


                   Section 12. Student Thesis/Dissertation

                          1. A student shall own the copyright of his/her thesis/dissertation subject to any

                          agreement with the University or external parties.  The student shall grant to

                          the  University  a  royalty-free  permission  to  reproduce,  publish  and  publicly

                          distribute copies of the thesis, in whatever form, electronic or otherwise

                          2. If  a  thesis/dissertation  contains  information  on  an  invention  that  maybe

                          patentable, the thesis maybe required to be withheld in accordance with the


                          procedures below:

                                     •  The campus/college/department may withhold public access to

                                         the  students’  thesis/dissertation  containing  information  on

                                         patentable invention until such time a patent application is filed

                                         by the Intellectual Property Office of the University (IPOU).


                                     •  The IPOU decides to pursue a patent protection in accordance

                                         with the procedure adopted by the University.

                          3. If the inventors request for the return of the IP under Article 7.2 and wishes

                          to pursue patent protection for the invention themselves, the inventors may

                          request the campus/college/departments to withhold the thesis/dissertation for


                          not more than three (3) months from the date of return of the IP so that the

                          relevant patent application maybe filed.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[35


                   Section  13. IPTBMD  and  ITSO  Services  and  Pricing.   This  section  sets  out  the

                   services provided by the ITSO and charges for them based on the ITSO Franchise

                   Operations Manual of IPOPHL.

                      Section 13.1. ITSO Services.    In  order  to  deliver  the  value  proposition  of


                   affordable  localized  access  to  patent  information,  patent  protection  for  valuable

                   inventions, and guidance and assistance for commercialization of IP to target customer

                   segments, the ITSO will offer the following services:

                              1. Patent  Searching. The ITSO shall conduct  two main types of  patent

                              searches:  a  patentability  search,  which  reviews  prior  art  in  relevant


                              technical field to determine if an invention fulfills the requirements of novelty

                              and inventiveness/ non- obviousness; and an infringement or freedom- to-

                              operate  search  analysis,  which  seeks  to  determine  if  a  particular

                              technology, be it an apparatus, product or process, would likely infringe any

                              patents owned by others.

                              2. Patent  Drafting.  The  ITSO  offers  this  services  to  assist  inventors  to

                              prepare the patent specification by describing the invention and listing the


                              claims prior to filling a patent.

                              3. Patent Filing. The ITSO can assist customers to file a patent application

                              with IPOPHL, which may be a national filing or an international filing under

                              the Patent Cooperation Treaty (PCT).

                              4. Patent  Prosecution.  The  ITSO  may  also  assist  the  customer  in  the


                              patent prosecution by preparing the appropriate response.

                              5. IP  Management  Services.  The  ITSO  may  offer  various  types  of  IP

                              management services to assist its customer including IP commercialization

                              and licensing support.

                              6. IP Skills Training Courses. Part of  the mandate of  each ITSO is to

                              promote the use of patent information and protection of innovation through]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[36


                              patents. It is also a requirement for each ITSO to train at least ten (10)

                              patent drafters annually who actually draft patent through the ITSO.

                     Section 13.2. Pricing Policies and Fee Structures.  The ITSO services pricing

                   below based on the ITSO Franchise Manual is provided as ‘suggested’ retail prices.


                   The prices do not include any applicable taxes and related expenses (e.g. government

                   filing fees).

                                              ITSO Service Fee Schedule

                                                                                       FEE
                                            SERVICE
                                                                                        (P)
                        Patent Search (infringement/FTO)                              15,000
                        Patent Search (patentability and other searches)              10,000
                        Analytic Report
                        Patent Drafting                                               20,000
                        Patent Filing                                                  5,000
                        Response to official action                               5,000 – 10,000
                        IP Management Services                               To be determined by ITSO
                        IP Skills Training Course                            To be determined by ITSO
                        Referral Fee                                         20% of service fee paid of
                                                                                     customer


                   Section 14. Revenue Distribution

                          All Revenues received by CvSU shall be governed by this Policy, and CvSU

                   shall have no financial obligation to any Creator, or designated beneficiary of Creator,

                   with respect to Intellectual Property except in accordance with this Policy.



                     Section 14.1. Distribution of Commercialization Benefits

                                 The University shall share with the Inventor(s)/creator(s) of the IP any


                          net revenue received by the University in the following ratio:

                                    University (60%)            Inventor(s)/creator(s)   (40%)

                          Net revenue is defined as the gross consideration (including all royalties, fees

                   and other benefits) received from the commercialization of the IP less all expenses

                   incurred in the commercialization of that IP. Expenses shall include all patent filing and

                   legal fees, marketing and licensing costs, administrative expenses and fixed overhead

                   costs and any other expenses necessarily incurred for patenting and commercializing


                   the IP.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[37


                          If the University receives shares in a company in exchange for a license or

                   assignment of the IP to the company, the shares the University obtains will be held by

                   the University and the proceeds from the liquidation of the shares shall be distributed

                   to the Investor(s) according to the same ratio as set out in Section 9.1.1. An Inventor


                   may also request to hold his/her portion of the shares in his/her own name, in which

                   case such Inventor shall no longer be entitled to any proceed from the liquidation of

                   the remaining shares by the University.

                          The inventors’ share of net revenue will be distributed equally among any joint

                   inventors unless the university has been previously notified in writing of any different


                   sharing arrangement agreed upon between the joint Inventors.

                          It is the responsibility and obligation of each Inventor to keep the University

                   updated of his/her current contact number and address in order for the University to

                   distribute his/her share of the Net Revenue.

                          The University’s share of the Net Revenue shall be distributed as follows:

                   College/Department                                     (35%)

                   Administrative of IPTBMD and ITSO           (35%)


                   Innovation Fund                                           (30%)

                            Where there are multiple Inventors from different Colleges/Departments, The

                     College’s/Department  share  of  Net  Revenue  will  be  distributed  among  the

                     Colleges/Departments  in  accordance  with  the  number  of  inventors  from  each

                     College/Department.


                          The University shall distribute to the Inventor(s) proportion of the Net Revenue

                   due to them in such manner and such times the University shall, in its sole and absolute

                   discretion, deem fit.

                          The University shall assign to the author(s), inventor(s), or creator(s) 100% of

                   the first two hundred thousand pesos of the royalty received by the University from

                   commercialization of the intellectual property. This amount may be adjusted on a yearly]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[38


                   basis,  taking  into  account  factors  such  as  inflation  rate.  In  excess  of  this  amount,

                   provisions of Section 9.1 shall apply.


                    Section 15. Use and Management of Income

                          Section 15.1.   Use of Income Derived from IPs and IPRs



                          All income generated from commercialization  of  IPs and/or IPRs from  R&D

                   funded by public funds shall be constituted as a revolving fund for use of the University,

                   deposited  in  an  authorized  government  deposit  bank  subject  to  accounting  and

                   auditing rules and regulations.



                          1.    Provided,  that  said  income  shall  be  used  only  to  defray  IPTBMD/ITSO

                          operations such intellectual property management costs and expenses and to


                          fund  research  and  development  with  potential  IPs,  science  and  technology

                          capability building, and technology transfer activities.



                          2.  Provided, further, that no amount of said income shall be used for payment

                          of salaries and other allowances.]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Research Manual

                            from CvSU Manual of Operations]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           261
                   Workload Credits

                                 The  workload  credits  that  shall  be  given  to  the  faculty
                          researchers differ depending on the responsibility of researcher by
                          scope of research whether it is a program, project or study.  Credits
                          are  also  given  for  researchers  that  are  in-charge  of  laboratories,
                          research  management  operation  units,  non-degree  training
                          activities and other tasks.


                   Research  and  Extension  (R&E)  Workload  System  for  Faculty
                   Members

                        This  set  of  guidelines  coheres  with  the  Faculty  Teaching  Workload
                   System  of  the  University  and  applies  to  R&E  workloads  of  the  faculty
                   members.

                          Definition of Terms:


                         Program is composed of at least two interrelated or complementing
                          projects aimed to accomplish predetermined goals within a specific
                          time frame.
                         Project      is    composed        of    at     least     two     interrelated
                          studies/activities/components aimed to accomplish predetermined
                          objectives within a specific timeframe.
                         Study  is  the  basic  or  applied  experiments  or  survey  designed  to
                          provide  solutions/answers  to  research  problems/topics  that  are
                          within the University thrusts.
                         Activity is a specific extension activity conducted within a specific
                          period that is within the thrusts of the University.
                         R & D Activities and their Corresponding Credit Units


                   A.  Research /Extension Activity Program

                       Nature        of  Proposal          Proposal      On-going            Completed
                       Activity          Endorsed/         Approved
                                         Submitted                       (Institutionally
                                                                         funded)
                          Program               7              10               12                 20
                           leader
                           Project              5               8               10                 10
                           Leader
                       Study Leader             3               6                 8                 6


                          *Training  activity  shall  not  be  part  of  the  program/  project  and
                          study activity for which workload is claimed.  The training lasts for
                          at  least  three  days,  otherwise,  the  credit  unit  earned  shall  be
                          prorated.




                                                                                                      261]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           262
                    B.  Conduct of Non-Degree Short Term Training Coordinator/Chair,
                          Training

                          Management  Group  (TMG)  –  --------three  (3)  credit  units  per
                          training


                          Member, TMG ------------------------ two (2) credit units/training

                          Resource speaker -------------------- Local = 2 credit units
                                                                     National/regional  =  3  credit
                   units
                                                                            International = 5 credit units
                            Facilitator/moderator/discussant  -----------------------  one  (1)
                            credit
                            unit/training

                   C.  Publications


                          Section coordinator (with function under the Office of the Director)
                                                                                           --fifteen (15) credit units


                          For College Research Journal

                          Editor-in-chief ------------------------------ eight (8) credit units/issue

                          Associate and Managing Editor ---------- six (6) credit units

                          Editorial staff --------------------------------three (3) credit units/issue

                          Writer/contributor --------------------------two (2) credit units/paper


                          Subject      Matter      Specialist/Reader----------three         [3]    credit
                          units/issue


                          For Ugnayan

                          Editor in chief-------------------------------------six (6) points / issue


                          Associate  and  Managing  Editors------------four  (4)  credit  units/
                          issue

                          Member/contributors ----------------------------two (2) points / issue


                          Newsletter

                          Editor------------------------two (2) points but not to exceed 6 points


                          Associate  Editor-----------1.5  points  per  issue  but  not  to  exceed  5
                          points

                                                                                                      262]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           263
                          Contributors-----------------1 point but not to exceed 2 points

                   D.  Paper presentation


                          1.  Oral Presentation


                                 a. National and International (in the Philippines)  -- 3 credit
                                         units


                                 b. International (outside of the Philippines) ------------5 credit
                                         units

                          2.  Poster presentation


                                 a. National and International (in the Philippines) --- 1 credit
                                              unit

                                 b.  International  (outside  of  the  Philippines)  ------------2.5
                                         credit units

                   E. Other Tasks


                          1.  Unit In-charge ------------------------------------ ten (10)
                                                                                                    credit units
                          2.  RDE Research Council ---------------------------two credit
                                                                                                    units per meeting
                          3.  Regional Consortium Director
                              (STARRDEC) ------------------------------------- twenty (20)
                                                                                                    credit units
                          4.  Representative to STARRDEC/
                               Similar organization –--------------------------- five (5)
                                                                                                    credit units
                          5.   Division Chiefs ----------------------------------- fifteen (15)
                          6.   Leader/Chair, National/Regional R&E Network Team - four (4)
                                                                             credit       units       per
                              semester


                   III.   Mechanics of Implementation


                       1.  The  workload  system  applies  to  all  faculty  members  who  are
                          involved in R & E activities either full-time or part-time.


                       2. For purposes of workload credit, the assigned task external to the
                          university  shall  be  covered  by  a  Memorandum  of  Agreement
                          between the University and the partner Agency or a Special Order
                          from the office of the University President.


                       3.  A faculty member shall have a minimum of 18 credit units in R &
                          E to be classified full-time researcher/extensions.

                                                                                                      263]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           264
                       4.  A full-time faculty member shall be entitled to workload credit in R
                          & E only if he/she has satisfied the minimum workload of 18 credit
                          units in teaching and R & E work.


                       5.  A program leader who is a project leader and a study leader in the
                          same program shall only be credited once whichever has the higher
                          credit units.

                       6. Overload pay shall be given to faculty researchers whose total credit
                          units is beyond 25 units

                       7.  Faculty  member  with  external  activity  to  R&E  and  has  received
                          honorarium for such activity shall not be given credit units


                       8.  All claims for credit units shall be supported by proper documents.

                       9. Credit units as researcher/extensions shall only be claimed for the
                          period specified in the program/project study activity as approved.

                       10.  Workload  accreditation  of  other  R&E  activities  not  covered  by
                            these  guidelines  shall  be  referred  to  the  Office  of  the  Vice
                            President  for  Research  &  Extension  for  consideration  upon  the
                            approval of the President.

                       11. The rate of overload pay or honorarium is similar to those on full
                            time    teaching.

                       12. The funds for the overload shall come from the R & E allocation or
                            from other sources which the University deems appropriate.


                          Honorarium

                                 Honorarium is a form of remuneration granted to researchers
                          for services rendered beyond the minimum/regular workload.  It is
                          a  form  of  incentive  granted  for  the  services  of  officials/employees
                          on special assignment.   For this purpose, a special assignment is
                          an  undertaking  by  an  individual  or  a  composite  group  of
                          officials/employees,  which  is  beyond  their  regular  and  primary
                          functions.


















                                                                                                      264]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           265
                          Types of Honoraria

                                 Those  paid  to  a  government  official  or  employee  or  private
                          individual who is requested to speak, lecture, or act as a resource
                          person in seminars, workshops, conferences,  symposia, trainings,
                          or classroom sessions (AMMRO, Book I as cited by UPLB Research
                          Manual, 2002)

                                 Those paid to a government official or employee by another
                          office in which he/she is on detail or special assignment provided
                          that  if  he/she  is  already  collecting  similar  compensation  or
                          allowance for the same service or period for which payment is being
                          claimed he/she may only choose to collect whichever is higher but
                          in  no  case  shall  he/she  receive  both  (UPLB  Research  Manual,
                          2002)

                                 Those  paid  to  a  government  official/employee  or  private
                          individual  for  his  membership  in  or  special  assignment  to
                          committees or special projects.

                                 Those  paid  to  a  government  official  or  employee  or  private
                          individual     who     is   involved     in    the    conceptualization       of
                          projects/programs;  implementation  of  research  and  development
                          activities; coordination of R & D activities; or rendition of advisory;
                          administrative,       and/or       management         functions      in     the
                          implementation of R & D (UPLB Research Manual, 2002).

                          Monitoring and evaluation


                          Research Projects


                                 The  research  projects  are  monitored  in  two  ways:  (1)  the
                          financial and (2) the technical aspects.


                                 The  accounting  department  of  the  University  monitors  and
                          audits  the  financial  status  of  the  research  funds.  However,  the
                          Special  Budget  Officer  of  the  Research  Center  records  every
                          disbursement  for  each  research  project/unit  and  annotates  the
                          Purchase Request Forms to indicate availability of funds and from
                          which funds the purchases are to be credited.

                                 The  Office  of  the  Director  of  Research  serves  as  the
                          monitoring  and  coordinating  arm  for  all  researches  in  the
                          University.    Although  research  activities  are  independently
                          undertaken  by  the  different  colleges,  faculty  researchers  are  still
                          required  to  submit  quarterly  progress  reports  on  their  research
                          projects/studies.  The researchers submit their progress reports to
                          their  respective  Deans  concerned,  which  in  turn  endorses  the
                          progress  reports  to  the  Office  of  the  Director.  This  enables  the

                                                                                                      265]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           266
                          Research  Center  to  keep  track  of  ongoing  projects  for  monitoring
                          and evaluation as well as workload compensation purposes.

                              The technical reports are submitted by the project proponent to
                          the Monitoring and Evaluation Unit of the Research Center.   The
                          numbers of copies are stated below:

                                Copies  of  Progress  Report  to  be  forwarded  to  the  funding
                                 agency
                                Copies of the Annual Report to be used in annual agency in-
                                 house review
                                Copies  of  the  Terminal  Report  to  be  submitted  two  months
                                 after the termination or completion of the project.


                          Annual Local Agency In-House Review

                                 One major activity to facilitate the monitoring and evaluation
                          purposes  is  the  holding  of  the  Annual  Local  Agency  In-house
                          Review.  It involves the evaluation of all researches that are either
                          completed  or  ongoing  during  the  particular  year  under  review.
                          During these reviews, researchers present the progress/highlights
                          of  their  researches.    The  panel  of  reviewers  consists  of  members
                          from  STARRDEC,  SUC’s  and  PCARRD.    The  guidelines  for  the
                          conduct of Annual Local Agency In-House Review of the Research
                          Center are based from the implementing guidelines set by PCARRD
                          for all SUC’s conducting the review.

                          The  major  criteria  that  shall  be  used  in  evaluation  the  ongoing
                                 projects are:


                                   Attainment of the objectives.
                                   Adherence to the approved methodology.
                                   Adherence to the approved budget.
                                   Accomplishments,          including      status    of    technology
                                     generated/verified.
                                   Actions taken in response to previous year’s comments.


                                 1.      Scope  and  Scheme  of  Agency  In-House  Reviews
                          (AIHR’s)

                                       a.   Completed, ongoing and new (those initiated within
                                            the  year)  R&D  projects  (i.e.  TG,  TA,  and  extension
                                            projects)  regardless  of  sources  of  funds  will  be
                                            presented.    All  completed  researches  of  faculty
                                            scholars  and  theses/dissertations  funded  by  the
                                            University shall likewise be reported during the in-
                                            house reviews.




                                                                                                      266]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           267
                                       b.   Sessions  shall  be  conducted  by  sector  (i.e.,  crops,
                                            environment,  livestock,  farm  resources,  forestry,
                                            and socio-economics) or integrated, if feasible.


                                       c.   Reports  shall  be  by  program/project/study  basis,
                                            but  related  projects  shall  be  reported  in  the  same
                                            session.

                                       d.   Agriculture       and     natural      resources       (ANR)
                                            programs/projects/studies  should  be  presented
                                            separately.

                                 2.      Objectives


                                       a.        To  evaluate  completed  and  ongoing  R&D  projects
                                            particularly  with  regards  to  the  attainment  of
                                            objectives  and  adherence  to  the approved  program
                                            of activities.

                                       b.    To  review  initial  activities  of  new  projects  giving
                                            emphasis  on  the  research  methods/procedures  to
                                            check/verify if the objectives were attained.

                                       c.   To     identify    problems       met     during      project
                                            implementation and recommend specific courses of
                                            action, i.e. continuation, extension, modification of
                                            planned  activities  and  methodology,  suspension,
                                            termination,      etc.,    in    accordance      with     the
                                            recommendation of the evaluation panel.


                                       d.  To  identify  technologies  generated  requiring  field
                                            testing, verification and piloting.

                                       e.   To  identify      research  results/technologies  for
                                            presentation  during  the  Regional  Symposium  on
                                            R&D       Highlights       (RSRDH),       and      potential
                                            technologies for technology assessment.


                                       f.   To identify significant results/information for policy
                                            formulation  and  development  planning  of  the
                                            University, Consortium and PCARRD.


                                       g.    To classify status of technologies.

                                       h.    To identify new researchable areas.








                                                                                                      267]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           268
                                 3.      Schedule

                                         a.     The reviews shall be conducted between July to
                                                September  to  select  papers  in  time  for  the
                                                regional reviews.


                                 4.      Evaluation Panel

                                         The  University  shall  notify  the  STARRDEC  and
                                 PCARRD regarding the upcoming agency in-house review to
                                 identify  external  evaluators  of  the  projects.  The  following
                                 shall comprise the panel of evaluators:


                                         a.     Experts  within  and  nearby  regions  shall  be
                                                tapped as evaluators.

                                         b.     Members  of  the  National/regional  Commodity
                                                R&D Teams/Experts’ Pool.

                                         c.     Farmer cooperators (Magsasaka Siyentista).


                                         d.     PCARRD,  DA-BAR  and  DENR-ERDB  senior
                                                technical staff

                                         e.     Participants:  Researchers, extensions


                                         f.     Duties  and  Responsibilities  Agency  Conducting
                                                the In-House Review


                                                a)    Facilitate  the  smooth  conduct  of  the  review
                              by:

                                                   o  Creating  committees  to  work  on  the
                                                       different aspects of the review;
                                                   o  Making       arrangements        for    necessary
                                                       logistics;
                                                   o  Providing  the  researchers  about  the
                                                       mechanics of the paper presentation;
                                                   o  Providing the list of programs/projects for
                                                       review  to  the  consortium  at  least  one
                                                       month before the review schedule. All R&D
                                                       programs/projects implemented regardless
                                                       of  funding  source  shall  be  included  for
                                                       evaluation;
                                                   o  Inviting      evaluators      to     assist     the
                                                       consortium evaluators not later one month
                                                       before the review schedule;




                                                                                                      268]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           269
                                                   o  Notifying  the  concerned  researchers  at
                                                       least  two  months  before  the  review
                                                       schedule;
                                                   o  Inviting Budget/Finance Officer and COA;
                                                   o  Notifying  the  concerned  researchers  at
                                                       least  two  months  before  the  review
                                                       schedule;
                                                   o  Reproducing         the      necessary       forms
                                                       (NARRDS  Form  No.  1/No.2)  for  use  of
                                                       researchers  and  for  preparing  outputs  of
                                                       the  review  (NARRDS  Form  Nos.  5  and  6).
                                                       (Appendix 4, 5, 6 and 7 respectively);
                                                   o  Accomplishing NARRDS Form No. 4 (Items
                                                       A-I)    for   distribution      to    evaluators;
                                                       (Appendix 8)
                                                   o  Convening  the  evaluation  panel  and
                                                       secretariat before the review to discuss the
                                                       evaluation  policies/guidelines,  and  after
                                                       the     review     to    discuss      the    final
                                                       action/recommendation  (e.g.  to  continue,
                                                       terminate,  etc.)/  synthesize  the  output;
                                                       and
                                                   o  Preparing/consolidating  the  output  for
                                                       submission to the consortium (AIHR Form
                                                       Nos.  1  and  2)  (Appendix  9  and  10,
                                                       respectively);

                                               b.   Ensures the utility of the review by:


                                                   o  Informing the concerned researchers of the
                                                       comments  and  recommendations  to  be
                                                       complied  within  their  respective  projects;
                                                       and
                                                   o  Monitoring  compliance  of  the  researchers
                                                       to the evaluators’ recommendations.

                              7. Expected Outputs


                                   Specific  courses  of  action  for  each  project,  i.e.  for
                                     continuation,  extension,  expansion,  modification  of  plan
                                     of  activities  and  methodology,  suspension,  termination,
                                     etc.;
                                   Technologies  requiring  field  testing,  verification  and
                                     piloting;
                                   Best paper and posters;
                                   Papers for possible presentation during the RSRDH;
                                   Potential technologies and information for dissemination;
                                   Significant research  results/information for the PCARRD
                                     publication “R&D Highlights”;
                                                                                                      269]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           270
                                   New researchable areas;
                                   Suggested solutions/recommendation to problems met.

                                8.   Research Reports


                          Research reports are to be submitted on a quarterly basis.

                           Awards and Recognition


                                 Awards,  in  line  with  the  University  Merit  System,  are
                          available  for  Faculty  Researchers  and  other  Research  personnel.
                          These are:


                                 a. Monetary Award

                                         Cash award in accordance with scales decided by the
                                 University  may  be  granted  for  accomplishments  that  result
                                 in  monetary  savings  and  tangible  benefits.  The  amount  of
                                 cash award shall be determined on the basis of its estimated
                                 or total value or benefits and in accordance with the scales
                                 established by the University.


                   Undergraduate and Graduate Thesis Support

                          Objective:


                                 To  strengthen  students’  research  capabilities  by  providing
                          Graduate and undergraduate theses financial assistance


                          Criteria for Application


                                 Graduate and undergraduate students of the university with
                          approved thesis/dissertation outline can apply for thesis support.


                          Guidelines for Availment

                                 The  thesis  should  be  in  line  with  the  existing  research
                          thrusts/ priorities of R and E.


                                 In  case  the  thesis  is  not  in  line  with  the  existing  research
                          thrusts of R and E, the following criteria will be considered:


                                Importance  to  national  development  considering  its  social,
                                 economic and environmental impact
                                Originality (done by the students themselves)
                                Urgency in terms of the college’ needs.






                                                                                                      270]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           271
                          Faculty  and  Students  Research  Capability  Enhancement
                          Program (FSRCEP)

                                 A  program  designed  to  support  the  conduct  of  research
                          undergone  by  faculty  members  of  the  University  and  senior
                          students presently enrolled in the University.

                                 Students  can  be  junior  researchers  and  can  be  involved  as
                          part  of  an  approved  R  and  E  programs/  projects.  A  copy  of  the
                          approved proposal must be on file with the in Charge of the Faculty
                          and  Students  Research  Capability  Enhancement  Program
                          (FSRCEP)  Financial  or  material  support  is  granted  if  funds  are
                          available.


                                 a.1 Requirements:

                                       Proposed  research  should  be  in  conformity  with  the
                                         research thrusts/agenda of the University;
                                       Properly endorsed by the College Deans;
                                       Should  be  included  in  the  list  of  research  titles
                                         approved by their respective College;
                                       In  accordance  with  the  prescribed  format  of  the
                                         University  and  the  DA-BAR  for  students  and  faculty,
                                         respectively;
                                       Defined budgetary requirement of the proposed study;


                                     Maximum  allowable  fund  to  be  allocated  to  approved
                                 programs/      projects/studies  would  be  P25,000.00  for
                                 studies  having  budgetary  requirements  of  P50,000.00.  On
                                 the  other  hand,  50%  of  the  total  cost  shall  be  allocated  to
                                 studies with budgetary requirements lower than P50,000.00

                              a.2. Publication


                                       Research  results  shall  be  submitted  to  the  CvSU
                                         Research  Journal’s  Editorial  Committee  as  technical
                                         paper for publication.
                                       Students’  thesis  shall  have  the  student  as  the  main
                                         author


                             a.3. Intellectual Property Rights

                                   Patented product shall be treated as a joint ownership of
                                     the author and the University.
                                   If  commercialized,  student  and  the  faculty  adviser  are
                                     eligible  to  acquire  an  equal  share  from  70%  of  the
                                     royalties and the remaining 30% to the University.




                                                                                                      271]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           272
                             a.4.  Workload Credit


                                   A  faculty  researcher  who  exceeds  the  minimum
                                     requirement  for  teaching  shall  be  entitled  to  a  research
                                     overload pay with the corresponding credit points earned
                                     for the semester.

                          The  College  Research,  Development  and  Extension  (RDE)
                   Coordinator in consultation with the department chairpersons selects the
                   entries for their corresponding colleges.

                              The thesis proposals are then submitted to the Research Center
                          on or before the following schedules:


                            September  to  November  –  Theses  to  be  conducted  during  the
                              second semester
                            June  to  August  -  Theses  to  be  conducted  during  the      first
                              semester
                            Submitted  proposals  are  then  referred  to  minimum  of  3
                              members of the RDE Council.
                            The members of the RDE Council finally review and recommend
                              to the University President, approval of the theses to be funded.
                            With  an  initial  budget  of  Php  1M  in  one  year,  at  least  20  per
                              cent shall be allocated for graduate theses and 80 per cent shall
                              be allocated for undergraduate theses.
                            A total of 5 graduate students and 34 undergraduate students
                              which are on the stage of conducting their theses could avail of
                              the financial support. In case where not all the budget allotted
                              to graduate students was awarded, the remaining balance shall
                              be allocated to undergraduate theses.
                            Each undergraduate student is entitled to a theses support in
                              the form of supplies and materials with a minimum amount of
                              Php  25,000.00.  Graduate  students  will  be  granted  a  thesis
                              support with a minimum amount of Php 30,000.00.
                            Upon  approval,  a  notarized  memorandum  of  agreement  duly
                              signed  by  the  student,  thesis  adviser,  Dean  of  the  college
                              concerned,  Director  for  research,  VP  for  Academic  Affairs  and
                              VP for RDE.
                            After  the  completion  of  the  research,  students  are  required  to
                              submit  two  copies  of  the  manuscript  to  the  Research  Center,
                              and together with the Adviser/ Senior Researcher, present the
                              results of the study during the Annual Agency In House Review,
                              and  publish  them  in  refutable  and  /or  refereed  journal.
                              Likewise, the student must submit to the RDE, one copy of the
                              financial  report  including  the  Official  Receipts  of  materials
                              purchased.






                                                                                                      272]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           273




































































                     Figure 3: Flowchart for the implementation of Faculty and   Students
                               Research Capability Enhancement Program (FSRCEP)














                                                                                                      273]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           274
                                         MEMORANDUM OF AGREEMENT

                          KNOW ALL MEN BY THESE PRESENTS:


                                 This  MEMORANDUM  OF  AGREEMENT  made  and  executed
                          by  and  between  CAVITE  STATE  UNIVERSITY,  a  government
                          educational  institution  created  and  existing  pursuant  to  the
                          provisions  of  R.  A.  8468,  with  principal  office  at  its  represented
                          herein by its president, DR. DIVINIA C. CHAVEZ, herein referred to
                          as  the  UNIVERSITY  and  ____________________________________,  of
                          legal      age,       single      ,      and       residing                  at
                          __________________________________,hereafter  referred  to  as  the
                          FACULTY          AND       STUDENTS           RESEARCH           CAPABILITY
                          ENHANCEMENT PROGRAM GRANTEE ,

                                                       W I T N E S S E T H


                                 WHEREAS,  the  GRANTEE    is  a  graduate/undergraduate
                          student  of  the  CAVITE  STATE  UNIVERSITY  with  an  approved
                          thesis/dissertation  outline,  has  applied  for  and  found  to  be
                          qualified  as  grantee  of  the  Faculty  and  Students  Research
                          Capability  Enhancement  Program  (FSRCEP)  this  First/Second
                          Semester, 200__-20___.

                                 WHEREAS,  the  thesis  outline  of  the  GRANTEE  has  been
                          selected by the College RDE  Coordinator in consultation with the
                          department  chairpersons,  and  referred  to  the  members  of  the
                          RECETS Council who then recommend to the university president
                          for its approval.


                                 NOW, THEREFORE, for and in consideration of the foregoing
                          premises, the Parties hereby agree as follows:

                          1.  In  consideration  for  the  thesis/dissertation  support  in  the
                          amount of Php________________ granted to _________________ by the
                          UNIVERSITY,    the  GRANTEE  hereby  binds  herself  to  comply
                          strictly with the terms and conditions thereof.


                          2. After the completion of the research, that is within 5 months to a
                          maximum of one year, two copies of the final manuscript must be
                          submitted  to  the  Research  Center;  results  of  the  study  must  be
                          presented  during  the  Annual  Agency  In-House  Review,  and
                          research  results  must  be  presented  during  the  Agency  In-House
                          Review  and  published  in  refutable  and  or  refereed  journal.    The
                          GRANTEE  must  submit  two  copies  of  the  manuscript  to  the
                          Research Center and one copy of the financial report including the
                          Official Receipt of materials purchased.




                                                                                                      274]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           275
                          3. The PARTIES agree that the obligations of the GRANTEE, under
                          this contract are binding, and that in any event of any violation by
                          the  GRANTEE,  the  UNIVERSITY  may  require  the  GRANTEE’S
                          performance at the UNIVERSITY’s discretion.


                          4. The PARTIES, likewise agree that any and all actions to enforce
                          the provisions of this MOA will be filed with the court of competent
                          jurisdiction within the province of Cavite.


                                 IN  WITNESS  WHEREOF,  the  PARTIES  have  signed  this
                          Contract  at  the  Municipality  of  Indang,  Province  of  Cavite,  this
                          ______ day of _______________, 20___.


                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY                    ______________________________

                                                                                    Grantee


                          By:

                          DIVINIA C. CHAVEZ


                                President

                          _______________________                    ________________________


                                    Adviser                              RDE Coordinator

                                                  ___________________________


                                                     Dean


                   Signed in the presence of:



                   ____________________________               ___________________________


                           VP-RECETS                          VP-Academic Affairs
















                                                                                                      275]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           276
                          Search for Best Graduate and Undergraduate Theses

                          Objectives:


                                 The main objective of the search is to encourage students to
                          develop outstanding thesis/dissertation by giving incentive to their
                          work.

                          Specifically, it aims to:


                                 Select  one  outstanding  thesis  each  for  science  and  non-
                          science  courses  in  the  undergraduate  level  and  one  each  for  MS
                          and PhD; and


                                 Provide  certificate  of  recognition  and  cash  awards  to
                          students with outstanding thesis/dissertation.


                          Mechanics of Implementation

                          Who May Join?


                                 Theses  of  all  graduating  undergraduate  /graduate  students
                          can  be  considered  for  the  best  thesis  award.    These  include  all
                          science  and  non-science  undergraduate  theses/dissertations
                          theses  and  all  MS  theses  and  PhD  dissertations.  However,  those
                          which are part of any ongoing government funded researches are
                          not eligible in the search.

                          Selection is done sequentially in three levels, namely:


                          Department Level

                                 Every  department  screens  students’  theses  /dissertations
                          during the final defense. For the undergraduate level, the selection
                          committee,  composed  of  the  chairman  and  the  members  of  the
                          faculty, selects an outstanding thesis for the department.


                                 For  the  graduate  level,  members  of  the  advisory  committee
                          recommend  potential  candidates  to  the  department  where  the
                          student  belongs.  The  selection  committee  composed  of  the
                          chairman  and  the  faculty  members  then  selects  one  outstanding
                          thesis/dissertation for the department.


                                 Theses selected for each department in both undergraduate
                          and  graduate  levels  are  submitted  to  the  head  of  the  college
                          screening  committee  and  Office  of  the  Graduate  School,
                          respectively.



                                                                                                      276]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           277
                          College/Graduate Level

                                 From  all  nominees  in  each  department,  the  selection
                          committee  composed  of  the  dean,  department  chairpersons  and
                          college     research       coordinator       selects     one      outstanding
                          undergraduate thesis for the college.

                                 For the graduate level, the selection committee, composed of
                          the  dean,  secretary  and  chairpersons,  selects  the  best  MS  thesis
                          and PhD dissertation for each graduate degree program.

                          Final Selection Level


                                 The best thesis for each college and graduate programs are
                          then submitted to the director for research for final screening.

                                 All nominees from each college are evaluated by a screening
                          committee composed of the RDE Council and the college research
                          coordinators.

                          Requirements for Participation


                                 The  following  are  submitted  to  the  chairman  of  the  final
                          screening committee not later than three working days before the
                          meeting  of  the  University  Academic  Council  to  approve  the
                          candidates for graduation:

                                 One  copy  of  the  final  manuscript,  and  five  copies  of  the
                          abstract and the summary, conclusions and recommendation


                          Criteria for Selection

                                 The  student  theses  shall  be  divided  into  six  divisions,
                          namely:  Agricultural  Bio  Resources,  Humanities  and  Social
                          Sciences,  Biomedical  and  Life  Sciences,  Engineering  and
                          Nanotechnology, and secondary school Divisions























                                                                                                      277]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           278
                   The following are the criteria for the selection of the best thesis award.

                                                                                                      Weight (%)


                          Originality                                                      30
                          (Student’s original proposal)
                          Organization                                                     30
                          (Validity of approach and reliability of results)
                          Relevance/Significance (potential contribution to
                          countryside development considering its social,
                          economic and ecological impacts)                                     40

                                 A  cut-off  point  of  85  percentile  for  secondary  and
                          undergraduate  levels  and  90  percentile  for  graduate  level  for  the
                          above  criteria  will  be  maintained  during  the  final  selection.  The
                          candidates receiving the highest point which is equal or above the
                          cut-off points are considered winners.


                          Incentives

                                 All  nominees  for  the  best  thesis  are  given  a  certificate  of
                          recognition.

                                 During the university recognition program, the best thesis is
                          awarded the following:


                                   Certificate of Recognition
                                   Cash Award:  Php 5,000 for doctoral

                                                       Php 4,000 for masteral


                                                       Php 3,000 for undergraduate

                                                       Php  2,000 for secondary


                                 The cash awards can be sourced out by tapping sponsors or
                          through the income generating unit of the university.


                                 The  abstracts  of  selected  best  theses  are  immediately
                          published in the R and D Highlights. The full papers are published
                          in the CvSU Research Journal.

                          Trainings/Seminars for Students

                                 Departmental  or  college-based  research/extension  paper
                          presentation can be done for information dissemination.






                                                                                                      278]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[Paper Presentations]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                          List of Faculty Research Presentations

                       Title of Research
                      Presented/ Activity       Name of Faculty        Date/Venue         Participation
                            Attended
                                                                     June 29-30, 2022
                         th
                        5  Division Basic        Ms. Jonane J.       SDO Marinduque           Paper
                      Education Research             Saguid          Conference Hall,       Presenter
                             Summit                                   Malusak, Boac,
                                                                        Marinduque
                      Mathematical Model
                      Equation: Predictor of
                         Success in the
                     Licensure Examination
                        for Teachers for                              January 21-22,
                    Mathematics Program of     Engr. Ma. Cristina          2022               Paper
                     Cavite State University     C. Tagle, LPT         via Microsoft        Presenter
                                                                          Teams
                                        th
                       Tanza Campus (4
                      DLSAU International
                        Multidisciplinary
                     Research Conference)
                        BSE Mathematics
                    Program Performance of
                    Cavite State University –
                      Tanza Campus in the      Engr. Ma. Cristina    December 8 – 10,         Paper
                     Licensure Examination       C. Tagle, LPT             2021             Presenter
                     for Teachers Basis for
                       LET Math Equation
                             Model
                    Narrative Experiences of
                            Student
                     Leaders among Public
                          High Schools         Ms. Jhollie Anne D.  March 13-14, 2021         Paper
                      in Trece Martires City,      Lopez, LPT        Philippine Normal      Presenter
                      Cavite (International                              University
                       Graduate Teacher
                    Education Summit 2021)
                         Gender-based
                      Differentiation among        Mildred A.
                       Public Elementary           Sebastian*
                       Teachers in Cavite       Ritch M. Banate,       December 17,           *Paper
                         (5  Gender and            Melona O.               2020             Presenter
                           th
                     Development Research           Igmasine
                          Conference)
                    Achievement Motivation,
                      Locus of Control and      Engr. Estelita A.      November 18,           Paper
                        Study Habits ‘as              Villa                2019             Presenter
                          Predictors of]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[Mathematics
                         Achievement of
                       Freshman College
                      Students (T3 Inhouse
                            Review)


                   Prepared by:


                   MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                   Research Coordinator



                   Certified Correct:


                   GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                       CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                  Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                        Indang, Cavite
                                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph

                         OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH AND EXTENSION

                                               RESEARCH CENTER

               April 22, 2021


               PROF. MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Faculty Researcher
               Tanza Campus
               This University


               Dear Prof. Saquin:

               The Research Center will conduct a Research Proposal Presentation on April 27, 2021 via
               Cisco Webex.

               In  this  regard,  may  we  invite  you  to  present  your  research  proposal  entitled  “Workplace
               Performance of CvSU-Tanza Graduates: Inputs to Curriculum Development”.

               During the presentation, only a maximum of 10 slides  will be allowed to  include Rationale,
               Objectives, Summary of Methodology, Expected Outputs (6Ps), Workplan and LIB. Ten (10)
               minutes will be allotted for presentation and ten (10) minutes for question and answer.

               Kindly  submit  your  PowerPoint  Presentation  to  cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph  on  or  before
               April 26, 2021. Mechanics of presentation, program of activities and Cisco Webex link shall be
               sent to all not later than April 23, 2021.

               Should you have any queries, please contact us thru mobile number 09069453267.

               Thank you


               Sincerely,



               KHAY B. ARANDIA
               Head, Monitoring and Evaluation Division



               Noted:



               MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
               Director]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                       CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                  Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                        Indang, Cavite
                                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph

                         OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH AND EXTENSION

                                               RESEARCH CENTER

               April 22, 2021


               PROF. MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
               Faculty Researcher
               Tanza Campus
               This University


               Dear Prof. Sebastian:

               The Research Center will conduct a Research Proposal Presentation on April 27, 2021 via
               Cisco Webex.

               In  this  regard, may  we  invite  you  to  present  your  research  proposal  entitled  “Assessment
               Strategies in the New Normal: Inputs to Curriculum Design”.

               During the presentation, only a maximum of 10 slides  will be allowed to  include Rationale,
               Objectives, Summary of Methodology, Expected Outputs (6Ps), Workplan and LIB. Ten (10)
               minutes will be allotted for presentation and ten (10) minutes for question and answer.

               Kindly  submit  your  PowerPoint  Presentation  to  cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph  on  or  before
               April 26, 2021. Mechanics of presentation, program of activities and Cisco Webex link shall be
               sent to all not later than April 23, 2021.

               Should you have any queries, please contact us thru mobile number 09069453267.

               Thank you


               Sincerely,



               KHAY B. ARANDIA
               Head, Monitoring and Evaluation Division



               Noted:



               MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
               Director]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                          List of Faculty Research Presentations

                       Title of Research
                      Presented/ Activity       Name of Faculty        Date/Venue         Participation
                            Attended
                                                                     June 29-30, 2022
                         th
                        5  Division Basic        Ms. Jonane J.       SDO Marinduque           Paper
                      Education Research             Saguid          Conference Hall,       Presenter
                             Summit                                   Malusak, Boac,
                                                                        Marinduque
                      Mathematical Model
                      Equation: Predictor of
                         Success in the
                     Licensure Examination
                        for Teachers for                              January 21-22,
                    Mathematics Program of     Engr. Ma. Cristina          2022               Paper
                     Cavite State University     C. Tagle, LPT         via Microsoft        Presenter
                                                                          Teams
                                        th
                       Tanza Campus (4
                      DLSAU International
                        Multidisciplinary
                     Research Conference)
                        BSE Mathematics
                    Program Performance of
                    Cavite State University –
                      Tanza Campus in the      Engr. Ma. Cristina    December 8 – 10,         Paper
                     Licensure Examination       C. Tagle, LPT             2021             Presenter
                     for Teachers Basis for
                       LET Math Equation
                             Model
                    Narrative Experiences of
                            Student
                     Leaders among Public
                          High Schools         Ms. Jhollie Anne D.  March 13-14, 2021         Paper
                      in Trece Martires City,      Lopez, LPT        Philippine Normal      Presenter
                      Cavite (International                              University
                       Graduate Teacher
                    Education Summit 2021)
                         Gender-based
                      Differentiation among        Mildred A.
                       Public Elementary           Sebastian*
                       Teachers in Cavite       Ritch M. Banate,       December 17,           *Paper
                         (5  Gender and            Melona O.               2020             Presenter
                           th
                     Development Research           Igmasine
                          Conference)
                    Achievement Motivation,
                      Locus of Control and      Engr. Estelita A.      November 18,           Paper
                        Study Habits ‘as              Villa                2019             Presenter
                          Predictors of]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[Mathematics
                         Achievement of
                       Freshman College
                      Students (T3 Inhouse
                            Review)


                   Prepared by:


                   MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                   Research Coordinator



                   Certified Correct:


                   GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>