<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="129"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.7.            Independent work and performance are


                        encouraged and monitored in the


                        following:

                        I.7.5.  thesis and]]></page><page Index="2"/><page Index="3"><![CDATA[THE ELEMENTS OF DIFFICULTIES IN USING PREPOSITIONS: BASIS FOR A
                    PROPOSED ACTION PLAN AT TANZA NATIONAL COMPREHENSIVE HIGH
                                                         SCHOOL



















                                               Undergraduate Research Paper
                                                 Submitted to the Faculty of
                                               Teacher Education Department
                                          Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                       Tanza, Cavite
















                                                     In partial fulfillment
                                             of the requirements for the Degree
                                              Bachelor of Secondary Education
                                                      (Major in English)




















                                                   JOANNA LEI P. LAPIG
                                                   ARIEL D. LOMUNTAD
                                                         April 2022]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[BIOGRAPHICAL DATA



                       Joanna Lei P. Lapig was born in Sta. Maria, Bulacan, on Ferbruary 23, 2000. She was

               the eldest and only daughter among the four children of Mr. Francisco D. Lapig, Jr. and Ms. Lea


               R. Peralta . She is currently residing at Block 61 Lot 5 Phase 2 Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza

               Cavite Philippines.


                       She finished her primary education at Matias B. Salvador Memorial Elementary School,

               Siling Bata, Pandi, Bulacan. Her Junior High education was completed in Virginia Ramirez Cruz

               High School, Siling Bata, Pandi, Bulacan and she graduated her Senior High in Immaculate

               Conception Polytechnic, Sta. Maria, Bulacan. She was a member and elected as PRO in

               Anglicists Guild (2018-2019), and a member and a PRO in Torch Interfaith Club (2019-2020)


               and a member of Circle of Potential Educators (COPE).















































                                                                 ii]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[BIOGRAPHICAL DATA



                       Ariel D. Lomuntad Ariel D. Lomuntad was born in San Policarpo, Eastern Samar, on

               24th of October, 1995. He was the youngest among the seven children of Mr. Arsenio V.


               Lomuntad and Mrs. Elisa D. Lomuntad. He is currently residing at Block 6 Lot 30 Phase 1

               Workersville, MM St. Bunga Tanza Cavite Philippines.


                       He completed his secondary education at Tanza National Comprehensive High School

               and presently completing his bachelor degree at Cavite State University Tanza campus. He is

               taking Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English. His ultimate goal in life is to help

               people understand the value of education.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[ACKNOWLEDGEMENT


                       The researchers would like to extend their warmest and deepest gratitude to the

               following people who generously and patiently helped in completing this study:

                       To their Alma Mater, Cavite State University-Tanza Campus, for molding them into

               excellence in the field of research and education,


                       To Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, research adviser as well as technical adviser, for her

               patience, guidance, advice, and reliable suggestions in correcting and improving this research

               study;

                       To their classmates, fourth-year Bachelor of Secondary Education - major in English, for

               their motivation and pieces of advice toward the betterment and success of the study;


                       To their loving family, who have always been their inspiration and source of unlimited

               strength to go on with life's challenges;


                       And above all, to Almighty God, for all the blessings he showers upon us. He became

               the source of their hope, strength, patience, wisdom, and uncountable blessings. With Him,

               everything is possible. Hence, thank God for helping the researchers to make this research

               study possible.

































                                                                 iv]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Abstract


                       Prepositions are regarded as one of the most difficult parts of speeches for students to

               master (Harmer, 2007). As one of the English grammar elements, prepositions are seen as


               challenging for English students, especially those learning it as a second language (L2).

               According to Arjan, A., Abdullah, N. H., & Roslim, N. (2013) many studies have been

               undertaken on this subject, yet it remains a difficult and unsolved issue. In this case, the

               researchers will conduct action research to determine the difficulties in using prepositions, which

               will serve as the foundation for a proposed action plan to discover and meet the following goals:

               Determine the various ways of teaching prepositions received by participants; Develop a


               research-based learning plan that will serve as a tool and foundation for the proposed action

               plan. This research project is focused on a prestigious high school in Tanza, Cavite. Tanza

               National Comprehensive High School is the name of the school, which caters to both Junior and

               Senior High School students. The researchers chose JHS students as the primary target,

               resulting in study participants. The researchers will explain the findings of this study and provide

               key recommendations as to the basis for an action plan for the mentioned institution, among


               other things, using the approach they have devised.

































                                                                 v]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENTS




                                                                                                   Page

                      BIOGRAPHICAL DATA ……………………………………………….                                           ii

                      ACKNOWLEDGEMENT ………………………………………………                                             iv

                      ABSTRACT………………………………………………………………                                                v

                      TABLE OF CONTENTS………………………………………………………….                                       vi

                      LIST OF TABLES………………………………………………………….                                          viii


                      LIST OF APPENDICES……………………………………………………                                         ix

                      INTRODUCTION…………………………………………………………..                                            1

                      Objectives of the Study …………………………………………………..                                   2

                      Significance of the Study …………………………………………………                                   3

                      Time and Place of the Study ……………………………………………                                   3

                      Scope and Limitations of the Study ………………………………………                              3

                      Definition of Terms ………………………………………………………                                       4


                      REVIEW OF RELATED LITERATURE…………………………………                                       5

                      METHODOLOGY…………………………………………………………..                                            13

                      Research Design ………………………………………………………….                                        13

                      Participants of the Study ………………………………………………….                                 13

                      Sampling Technique ……………………………………………………                                        13


                      Data Gathering Procedure ………………………………………………                                    14

                      Data Analysis …………………………………………………………                                           14

                      RESULTS AND DISCUSSION…………………………………………                                         15

                      Pre-Test…………………………………………………………………..                                            16

                      Post-Test…………………………………………………………………                                             18







                                                                 vi]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[SUMMARY, CONCLUSIONS, AND RECOMMENDATIONS…………                                  22

                      Summary ………………………………………………………………….                                             22

                      Conclusions ………………………………………………………………                                           23

                      Recommendations ………………………………………………………..                                        23


                      REFERENCES………………………………………………………………                                             24

                      APPENDICES………………………………………………………………                                             25


































































                                                                vii]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[LIST OF TABLES




                     Table                                                                       Page

                        1     Table 1.1. Grade and Section of Participants                        15


                        2     Table 1.2. Age of Participants                                      15


                        3     Table 2.1. Preposition of Time                                      16


                        4     Table 2.2. Preposition of Place                                     16


                        5     Table 2.3. Preposition of Direction                                 17



                              Table 3.1. Preposition of Direction                                 18


                              Table 3.2. Preposition of Direction                                 18


                              Table 3.3. Preposition of Direction                                 19












































                                                                viii]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[LIST OF APPENDICES






                      Table                                                                      Page

                        1      Figure 2.1. Overall Average Score of Pre-test                      15


                        2      Result of Post-test                                                15


                        3      Table 3.1. Preposition of Time                                     16


                        4      Table 3.2. Preposition of Place                                    16


                        5      Table 3.3. Preposition of Direction                                17


                        6      Figure 3.1. Overall Average Score of Post-test                     21




















































                                                                  ix]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[DIFFICULTIES IN USING PREPOSITIONS: BASIS FOR A PROPOSED ACTION

                           PLAN AT TANZA NATIONAL COMPREHENSIVE HIGH SCHOOL



                                                    Lapig, Joanna Lei P.
                                                    Lomuntad, Ariel D.








               An undergraduate Case Study submitted to the Faculty of Teacher Education Department,
               Cavite State University – Tanza Campus in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the course

               BSEE 31 – Language and Education Research Contribution No. ________________________.
               Prepared under the supervision of Mildred A. Sebastian










                                                      INTRODUCTION


               Background of the Study


                       In general, teaching English in the Philippines is difficult. Many students can

               comprehend the language, but the majority of them struggle to effectively communicate their

               views through the use of prepositions in writing and verbally. The issue is a lack of both a


               sufficient stock of prepositions and writing inventiveness. Nonetheless, it is a difficult

               assignment for teachers to effectively teach English so that students can become autonomous

               learners and gain much from the teachers' unique teaching strategies.


                       According to Mukundan & Norwati (2009), prepositions are always thought to be the

               most important aspects of teaching English, especially when it comes to teaching speech and

               writing abilities.








                                                              1]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[A preposition is a word that expresses a relationship between two elements, one of

               which is represented by the prepositional complement of several sorts of relational meaning

               (Quirk et al., 2009). Time, place, direction, and varying degrees of mental and emotional states

               are all part of these interactions. According to studies, the preposition is one of the most difficult


               categories for students to learn in English (Ravina, 2008). Prepositions, on the other hand, are

               one of the most underappreciated aspects of grammar. Others believe they are only employed

               to introduce prepositional phrases such as from the top, in the room, or with the mother;

               however, they serve various roles. One preposition, for example, can introduce time, place, or

               other words. Confusion emerges as a result of the numerous uses of prepositions, which leads

               to inaccuracies in their application. English native speakers rarely make grammatical errors,

               although they do make typical English faults that demonstrate how difficult the English language


               can be (Swick, 2005).


                       In line with this study, the researchers aim to determine the challenges that English

               language learners experience when utilizing prepositions in writing and speaking, examine the

               source and effect of the typical preposition teaching technique, and provide research-based

               action plans for improving teaching and learning environments. This will be possible with the

               participation of the students from Tanza National Comprehensive High School.







               Objectives of the Study


               The present study aims to shed new light based on the following objectives:


                   1. Identify the difficulties faced by English language learners in using English prepositions

                       while writing and speaking;

                   2. Analyze the cause and effect of the traditional teaching method of the preposition; and







                                                              2]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[3. Propose research-based action plans for the betterment of teaching and learning

                       prepositions.






               Significance of the Study


                       The researchers believe that this study will not only yield data that will be helpful to them,


               more so to the following groups of people:


               English Teachers. The relevance of the study will be of significant help to English teachers

               who will devote more time, attention, and practice to prepositions. This study is intended to aid

               English teachers in determining a student's capacity to comprehend prepositional principles.

               They are also required to be aware of the students' prepositional errors and for the teacher to

               pay attention to them. They can foresee a student's issues and assist them in solving the


               problem so that the end outcome is better.


               Students. After reading the findings of this study, students are aware of their prepositional

               errors. Students should be able to avoid making the same mistakes in the future when writing

               and speaking.


               Future Researchers. The ideas presented may be used as reference data in conducting new


               research or in testing the validity of other related findings. This study will also serve as a cross-

               reference that will give them background or an overview regarding the difficulties encountered

               by students in using prepositions.


               Time and Place of the Study


                       The study was conducted for four months at Tanza National Comprehensive High

               School. It is in San Agustin, Tanza, Cavite. The research started from January 2021 to April

               2022.




                                                              3]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Scope and Delimitation of the Study


                       This study will focus on the difficulties in using prepositions as the basis for a proposed

               action plan at Tanza National Comprehensive High School. The participants will be limited to

               one hundred (100) Junior High School students of TNCHS. The participants will be selected

               based on their availability. The period covered in thesis writing is from January 2021 to April


               2022.


               Definition of Terms


                       For clarification, the important terms used in this study have been defined. The following

               terms are:


                   1. Preposition. A word or group of words is used before a noun, pronoun, or noun phrase

                       to show direction, time, place, location, spatial relationships, or introduce an object.


                   2. L2. A person’s second language, or L2, is a language that is not the native language.

                   3. Inevitable. Incapable of being avoided or evaded an inevitable outcome.

                   4. Peculiar. Characteristic of only one person, group, or thing. A characteristic or quality

                       that is distinctive of a particular person or place.

                   5. Pedagogy. The study of teaching methods, including the aims of education and how


                       such goals may be achieved.

                   6. Polysemy. Is the capacity for a sign to have multiple related meanings.

                   7. Monosyllabic words. Words with only one syllable.

                   8. Semantics. The study of reference, meaning, or truth.

                   9. Perplexed. Completely baffled

                   10. Participatory Action Research. It is an approach to action research emphasizing

                       participation and action by members of communities affected by that research. It seeks


                       to understand the world by trying to change it, collaboratively and following reflection.




                                                              4]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[11. Pre-assessments. Tests that evaluate students’ knowledge before instruction begins.

                   12. Post-assessment. Allow the instructor and learners to assess their understanding of the

                       content covered.

                   13. EFL. English as a Foreign Language is learning English in a non-English speaking


                       country.

                   14. Diagnostic test. An examination to identify an individual’s specific areas of weakness

                       and strength.

                   15. Comprehensive. Covering completely or broadly



























































                                                              5]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[REVIEW OF RELATED LITERATURE







                       The task of preposition error detection has received a considerable amount of attention

               in recent years because selecting an appropriate preposition poses a particularly difficult

               challenge to learners of English as a second language (ESL). Hence, according to Martin Scott

               (2010), getting errors and finding difficulties in this subject are considered inevitable.

               Furthermore, this part of the research paper will conventionally show, using multiple and various


               related literature studied by researchers – the difficulties and common challenges encountered

               by learners of the English language. Especially, the L2 or those who speak English as a second

               language. Through sample research-based data, it can serve as a conclusion that the difficulty

               in using correct prepositions is common among learners of English. Here, the researchers

               provided a definition and elaborate on the following terms: difficulty, preposition, and concept of

               a preposition, to conceptualize correctly.


               2.1 Definitions of Preposition



                       A preposition is generally known as part of the speech in which it is used to show a

               relationship between a noun, pronoun, two things, or more. Yates (1999) stated that the word

               “preposition” has a straightforward definition: “a word placed before a noun or abstract.”


                       In a study of the definitions of a preposition, Sinclair (1991) claimed that a preposition is

               a word that reveals the possibility of saying more about a thing or an action. Prepositions help







                                                              6]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[us to indicate the place or the location of the action, someone or something, where it is coming

               from, or the direction where the action is moving.


                       Another study from Chalker (1984) explains that preposition means “place before”. This

               means preposition usually goes to a word, another word or words, specifically goes through a

               noun or a noun phrase. Most prepositions are usually single words, hence there are still


               students who are suffering from confusion on the use of prepositions.


                       In another study from a book (Lindstromberg, Seth, 1947), a preposition is a word that

               expresses a relationship between two elements, one of which is represented by the

               prepositional complement of several sorts of relational meaning (Quirk et al, 1985). Time, place,

               direction, and varying degrees of mental and emotional states are all part of these interactions.

               According to studies, the preposition is one of the most difficult and important aspects of


               teaching English. Prepositions can be an issue for Arabic learners of English, according to

               research (Thahir, 1987). The fact that Arabic prepositions are less in number than English

               prepositions makes it more difficult for Arab English learners to acquire English preposition

               usage.


                       Prepositions are generally divided into three groups, according to Lindstromberg (1998):

               prepositions of place, direction (or motion or movement), and time. Because of the peculiarity of


               the situation, these prepositions present a difficulty to both learners and teachers of English.

               The students struggle with the right use of prepositions in phrases, and as a result, they get into

               difficulty. Aside from that, each of these prepositions has a variety of meanings and applications,

               making the learning process equally challenging.


               2.2 Difficulty with the use of the prepositions


                       Prepositions are well-known yet difficult for students to understand especially their


               concepts, therefore many English Language Learners are having difficulty in mastering



                                                              7]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[prepositions due to the total number of them in the English language. The study of (Elglaibi

               Ahmed Mohammed, 2019) examines the reason behind the difficulty of students in using the

               preposition in the English language, the researcher has revealed that prepositional errors of

               students are from the substitution, omission, and addition account for the majority of syntactic


               errors. In the existing study (Elglaibi Ahmed Mohammed, 2019), the researchers are made to

               understand the difficulties faced by the students and create an action plan that will cater to the

               student’s difficulties in using the preposition in a sentence, and evaluate alternative methods.


                       In our present study, we consider the research of (Elglaibi Ahmed Mohammed, 2019) in

               creating an action plan to determine what pedagogical methods are most effective for students

               to cater to what makes learning prepositions so difficult for them.


                       Another study by (Koffi 2010) explains, that two things affect the learners in


               understanding the concept of a preposition. First, prepositions are typically polysemous. The

               majority of prepositions in English have numerous meanings depending on the context, which is

               known as polysemy. As a result, students frequently become confused while trying to figure out

               what propositional meanings are and how to apply them correctly. Second, as (Koffi 2010)

               pointed out, because prepositions often contain few syllables, they might be difficult to


               recognize, especially in spoken speech. Many monosyllabic English prepositions, such as on,

               for, or to, are monosyllabic. As a result, language learners may find it difficult to distinguish

               prepositions in fast, genuine speech. Furthermore, the employment of prepositions in context

               differs substantially between languages, resulting in negative syntactic transfer.


                       The research of both (Elglaibi Ahmed Mohammed, 2019) and (Koffi 2010) proves that

               there is still a need in our study to create an action plan that can help learners to understand the

               concept of a preposition.









                                                              8]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Another study (Reef, 2000) observed the errors in the use of place prepositions and

               attempted to find out whether such errors were tied to poor teaching or the interference of the

               first language. The researcher undertook this study to find the level of competence among

               students in the use of the four types of prepositions namely, position/destination, relative,


               passage, and orientation.


                       The results revealed that students could not differentiate the four types of prepositions

               and they faced more difficulties in using the prepositions of position/ destination than the other

               types. The inability of the students to distinguish the semantic content of these prepositions and

               poor teaching methods employed by teachers are the major reasons for the errors.


                       Another study by Kim (2001) looked into how Malay Upper Secondary pupils misused

               English prepositions in their written work. The purpose of the study was to figure out what


               causes prepositional errors and why they happen. The researcher looked at nine different

               notions, including time, place, and location prepositions. To gather information, these children

               were given a diagnostic test. They had to compose an essay and fill in the blanks of a cloze text

               and phrases with the correct prepositions as part of the test.


                       The study's findings revealed that students made several mistakes while employing the

               prepositions of place, time, and direction as a result of incorrect selections. According to the


               study, the technique of teaching English prepositions could be crucial in facilitating preposition

               learning.


               2.2.1 Difficulty with the use of prepositions of time.


                       According to (Yangon University of Foreign Languages Research Journal 2020) An

               Analysis of Students’ Difficulties in Using Preposition of Time in the Russian Language.

               Learning Russian as a foreign language must be familiar with grammatical concepts such as


               cases, tenses, nouns, verbs, adjectives, adverbs, pronouns, prepositions, conjunctions, and so



                                                              9]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[on. Students can talk, write, and create sentences once they have mastered grammar. A

               preposition is one of the most crucial components of grammar that we study in school. A

               preposition is a group of words that show the relationship between a noun or a noun substitute

               and another word in a phrase. Preposition, on the other hand, is a word that indicates the


               relationship between nouns or pronouns and other words in a phrase. Prepositions in Russian

               come in a variety of forms. This study focuses solely on the usage of prepositions of time

               expression, which is an issue for many students, and it identifies the students' difficulties with

               prepositions of time expression. The researcher will try to figure out what is causing the

               problems with time expression in Russian and what the actual causes and difficulties are. This

               paper aims to investigate the difficulties in using time expression of the Russian language

               encountered by Third Year Russian specialization students at Yangon University of Foreign


               Languages. The findings of the data analysis revealed that there are many difficulties

               encountered by the Third-year level students while using the preposition of time expression. The

               findings of this study revealed several issues and errors made by third-year students during an

               exam. The majority of pupils struggle with employing prepositions of time, and the interference

               of the mother tongue might lead to errors. As a result, teachers should provide pupils with


               extensive preposition exercises. Students should pay particular attention to Russian

               prepositions of time expression. To assist pupils to improve in the domain of prepositions, a

               teacher should use efficient teaching strategies.


                       According to Abdelrazig Abdelghani Mahil Ibrahim (2018) to The Difficulties Encounter

               (ESP) Students in Using English Prepositions of Time. English prepositions are difficult for any

               EFL learner because he/she usually relates them to his/her own mother tongue prepositional

               system. The difficulty is also caused by the difference in number, meaning, and usage of the


               prepositions in the mother tongue and the EFL. In learning English prepositions, Arab students

               try to relate them to the smaller number of Arabic ones and the Arabic prepositional system.




                                                             10]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Although Arabic and English prepositions have some characteristics in common, they differ in

               both number and usage. Finally, since the preposition “at”, “in” and “on” are among the

               prepositions that are commonly employed by English language speakers, the teachers can

               tackle preposition problems by the following strategies: Asking students to detect the pattern in


               their own to be able to learn and recognize the typical prepositional uses better. Encouraging

               students to find out the different grammatical rules by themselves to develop their sensitivity to

               the language, and the role of the students in this issue that they should stay away from turning

               to the mother tongue when answering prepositions exercises.


               2.2.2 Difficulty in the use of prepositions of place


                       Students frequently make mistakes when studying English. As a result, it becomes a

               very good input and will be valuable for this research since it will assist the researcher in


               resolving the challenges that students in junior high school will have while utilizing the

               prepositions of place.


                       The preposition of place is a word that refers to a location where something or someone

               is found (Frank, n.d.). Language learners, particularly junior high school students, may make

               mistakes while utilizing prepositions of place. It occurs most likely because language learners

               do not yet fully comprehend the preposition of place.



                       Writing is challenging for the students, especially when employing prepositions of place.

               Descriptive text is one of the genres taught in junior high school. A text genre is a written or

               spoken form of communication. Each of these text types has a different function and is written in

               a different style or format.


                       A factual description, according to Anderson (2003), describes a specific person,

               location, or thing. In other words, the composition elaborates on a specific person, location, or







                                                             11]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[thing. Descriptive text is a text that describes the characteristics of an item, animal, or person.

               Its goal is to describe and reveal a certain object, person, or location.


               2.2.3 Difficulty in the use of prepositions of direction


                       As stated clearly in this study, prepositions have been significantly a major factor in why


               many students of the English language find the matter difficult and almost impossible to master.

               The researchers have made that concept very clear in this study so far. One of the types of

               prepositions is the preposition of direction that in this scheme seems to be out of topic most of

               the time compared to prepositions of time and place. The researchers have looked into a couple

               of published studies from the year 2015 until the present. The chosen studies circulate on the

               difficulties of using prepositions of direction by English students. A few students may be

               perplexed as to whether prepositions should be used in particular circumstances. In other words,


               they may be unable to differentiate between the right usage of each preposition of direction

               because each has a different application and meaning in phrases. According to (Drs. Suprapto,

               2015) the students attempted to mix knowledge from their respective languages. They are

               learning the Indonesian language as well as a second language (English). The researchers

               intend to test this conclusion since the participants involved are students of English language


               who speak Filipino as their first language. People have different concepts of error, but to have a

               standard definition of it, Corder defines errors as performance failure (as cited in Castro, 2001).

               Also, they can be the result of faulty, controversial, or unconventional usage of grammatical

               elements (Nordquist, 2018). The researchers have added data results of pre-assessment and

               post-assessment comprising the errors made by participants of the study. An interpretation was

               calculated and defined found in the next chapter of this study. According to (Elkhadiri and

               Khouya, 2019) University of South Korea, the study’s findings proved that Moroccan students


               experienced extreme difficulty with the use of the English locative, as they made many mistakes

               in their attempts to place the five targeted prepositions in the correct places.



                                                             12]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[The researchers have made the context very clear that prepositions of direction give a

               difficult time to English students globally. Through this study, the researchers claimed some

               truths from the existing and prior studies and contrast some of those too. Given that the setting

               of the study is primarily in the researcher’s location.








































































                                                             13]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[METHODOLOGY






                       This section presents the research design, sampling procedure, data collection

               procedure, and data analysis that were employed to achieve the objectives of the present study.


               Locale of the Study



                       This study will be conducted at Tanza National Comprehensive High School located at

               Daang Amaya 2, Tanza, Cavite. The researchers will focus their study on the Grade 8 and 10

               Junior High School students of the said institution. The researchers perceived that TNCHS will

               be a reliable source of study since it is one of the well-established and pioneer institutions in the

               Province of Cavite.



               Research Design


                       This study will employ the use of action research style to determine the difficulties in

               using prepositions and become the basis for a proposed action plan, among the 100

               participants from Grade 8 and 10 students of Tanza National Comprehensive High School.

               Action research - which is also known as Participatory Action Research (PAR), community-

               based study, cooperative inquiry, action science, and action learning – is an approach


               commonly used for improving conditions and practices in a range of healthcare environments

               (Lingard et al., 2008; Whitehead et al., 2003). This study is a mix of quantitative and qualitative

               research in which the result of an examination is analyzed through statistical data and will be

               interpreted based on their scores.


               Sampling Procedure


                        Since the study falls under the qualitative method, the researchers will employ non-

               probability sampling. To be precise, this study will use convenience sampling. According to




                                                             14]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[PHAST (2020), it is the easiest method of sampling because participants are selected based on

               availability and willingness to take part in answering the survey questionnaire or other

               techniques. Since the study is intended to ascertain the difficulties of using prepositions and

               getting the basis for a proposed action plan, the researchers chose to do the research with the


               available participants, especially during this time of the pandemic.


               Data Collection Procedure


                       The researchers will develop a self-administered focus group student recorded interview

               with five open-ended questions about teaching and learning preposition and survey

               questionnaires, the survey questionnaire will be in form of pre-test and post-test focus on

               prepositions of time, place, and direction. The pre-test and post-test examinations will be

               reviewed and validated by the research advisor, Professor Mildred Sebastian. Once done, the


               researchers will request for letter of approval from the university administration or Dean’s office,

               for the official distribution of the survey through Google Form which can be answered online and

               submitted the same way. This ensures that no physical contact will be made between the

               researchers and participants. The result of the submitted questionnaires will be tabulated and

               the data collected will be analyzed and interpreted through the use of the most appropriate


               statistical procedures.










               Data Analysis


                       The data that will be gathered will be arranged in the qualitative method to interpret and

               determine the various ways of teaching prepositions received by the participants and develop a

               research-based learning plan that will be a tool and basis for the proposed action plan. The






                                                             15]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[statistical treatment that the researchers will use is simple statistics in the form of averages and

               percentages to analyze and provide interpretation to the gathered data.














































































                                                             16]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[RESULTS AND DISCUSSION






                       This chapter presented the findings of the data as a result of the survey conducted. It

               also presented pertinent information regarding the problem of the study.


               Demographic Profile of Participants



               Table 1.1. Grade and Section of Participants


                     Grade and Section                       N                          Percentage

               Grade 8 – Integrity                           17                             17%

               Grade 10 – Freedom                             9                              9%

               Grade 10 – Ametrine                           15                             15%


               Grade 10 – Einstein                           19                             19%

               Grade 10 – Onyx                               16                             16%

               Grade 10 – Jade                               17                             17%


               Grade 10 – Albite                              7                              7%


                       The participants in this study are from Tanza National Comprehensive High School who

               are Grade 8 and 10 Junior High School students from the following sections respectively:

               Integrity, Einstein, Jade, Onyx, Ametrine, Freedom, and Albite. The highest number of


               participants is from Grade 10 – Einstein since it is the pioneer section of the grade level.


               Table 1.2. Age of Participants


                            Age                              N                          Percentage

                             13                               7                              7%

                             14                               8                              8%






                                                             17]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[15                              45                             45%

                             16                              31                             31%

                             17                               9                              9%



                       As shown in the table, the majority of participants are 15 years old follow by 16 years old

               since many of them are Grade 10 students.


               Result of Pre-test



               Table 2.1. Preposition of Time


                               Questions                         No. of Correct             Percentage

               We get up in the morning.                               88                      88%

               We go to bed at night.                                  94                      94%


               It's always hot in summer.                              45                      45%

               The movie starts at two in the afternoon.               75                      75%

               Autumn begins in September.                             45                      45%

               They were married in 1990.                              62                      62%

               Joe arrived after me.                                   89                      89%


               It has not rained at all for two weeks.                 73                      73%

               Breakfast is served at seven o'clock.                   94                      94%

               Kevin and Joe have been in the same class               98                      98%
               since first grade
                         Average No. of Correct Answers                            76.3






               Table 2.2. Preposition of Place


                                   Questions                          No. of Correct          Percentage

               Sign your name on the dotted line.                            65                  65%




                                                             18]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[When we flew under the clouds, we could see the               62                  62%
               earth's surface.
               Can I sit beside you at the movie theatre?                    96                  96%

               The kids are playing in the backyard.                         40                  40%


               Your glasses are right in front of you.                       85                  85%

               You can pick up your keys at the front desk.                  51                  51%

               Let's meet at the front door.                                 79                  79%

               There's a helicopter hovering over our house.                 73                  73%


               Didn't you park your car next to mine?                        93                  93%

               Please stay behind the police caution tape.                   90                  90%

                                Average No. of Correct Answer                         73.4





               Table 2.3. Preposition of Direction



                                  Questions                          No. of Correct          Percentage

               The bank is next to the police station.                     92                    92%

               The church is at the corner lot.                            44                    44%

               The store is across from the movie theatre.                 80                    80%

               The school is below the post office.                        40                    40%


               The train station is at the central avenue.                 45                    45%

               The drugstore is behind the movie theatre.                  33                    33%

               The school is in front of the train station.                85                    85%

               The church is around the second street                      43                    43%


               The store is beside the police station                      80                    80%

               The drugstore is in between of post office and              91                    91%
               movie theatre.
                              Average No. of Correct Answers                         63.3





                                                             19]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Figure 2.1. Overall Average Score of Pre-test


























                                       Total Average Score:                       21.05/30



                       The researchers conduct a pre-test examination among selected 100 participants from

               Grade 8 and 10 Junior High School students of Tanza National Comprehensive High School.

               This examination was given to the participants without any lecture or discussion from the

               instructor regarding the topic which is the preposition. From the obtained results of the pre-test,

               the Grade 8 and 10 students at Tanza National Comprehensive High School had encountered


               difficulty in using prepositions. According to Lorincz (2012), English language learners find

               prepositions difficult to acquire due to their huge quantity and varied nature. According to their

               research on learners' linguistic output, substitution, addition, and omission are the most

               common syntactic errors.


               Result of Post-test


               Table 3.1. Preposition of Time



                               Questions                         No. of Correct             Percentage

               We get up in the morning.                               97                      97%

               We go to bed at night.                                  94                      94%




                                                             20]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[It's always hot in summer.                              95                      95%

               The movie starts at two in the afternoon.               95                      95%

               Autumn begins in September.                             95                      95%


               They were married in 1990.                              92                      92%

               Joe arrived after me.                                   99                      99%

               It has not rained at all for two weeks.                 93                      93%

               Breakfast is served at seven o'clock.                   94                      94%


               Kevin and Joe have been in the same class               98                      98%
               since first grade
                         Average No. of Correct Answers                            95.2





               Table 3.2. Preposition of Place


                                   Questions                          No. of Correct          Percentage


               Sign your name on the dotted line.                            95                  95%

               When we flew under the clouds, we could see the               92                  92%
               earth's surface.
               Can I sit beside you at the movie theatre?                    96                  96%

               The kids are playing in the backyard.                         90                  90%

               Your glasses are right in front of you.                       95                  95%


               You can pick up your keys at the front desk.                  91                  91%

               Let's meet at the front door.                                 99                  99%

               There's a helicopter hovering over our house.                 93                  93%

               Didn't you park your car next to mine?                        93                  93%


               Please stay behind the police caution tape.                   98                  98%

                                Average No. of Correct Answer                         94.2








                                                             21]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Table 3.3. Preposition of Direction


                                  Questions                          No. of Correct          Percentage

               The bank is next to the police station.                     98                    98%


               The church is at the corner lot.                            96                    96%

               The store is across the movie theatre.                      97                    97%

               The school is below the post office.                        94                    94%

               The train station is at the central avenue.                 95                    95%

               The drugstore is behind the movie theatre.                  93                    93%


               The school is in front of the train station.                95                    95%

               The church is around the second street                      92                    92%

               The store is beside the police station                      92                    92%

               The drugstore is in between of post office and              98                    98%
               movie theatre.
                              Average No. of Correct Answers                          95






               Figure 3.1. Overall Average Score of Post-test









                       40
                       30

                       20
                       10








                                       Total Average Score:                       27.2/30






                                                             22]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[After a week of pre-test, the researchers conduct a lecture about the proper usage of

               prepositions with a series of activities that will help the students master it. Then, after two weeks

               of discussion and activities, the students took the post-test examination to assess whether they

               learn from past activities. As the result has shown, the students learned from the discussion and


               activities. From the previous result of 21.05, the students’ total average score increases to 27.2.




































































                                                             23]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[SUMMARY, CONCLUSIONS, AND RECOMMENDATIONS






                       This chapter presents the summary and conclusions drawn from the findings and the

               corresponding recommendations.


               Summary



                       The purpose of this study is to determine the challenges that students from Tanza

               National Comprehensive High School experience when utilizing prepositions in writing and

               speaking, examine the source and effect of the typical preposition teaching technique, and

               provide research-based action plans for improving teaching and learning environments. Based

               on the related studies, students are having a hard time using the prepositions both written and

               oral.



                       In a study of the definitions of a preposition, Sinclair (1991) claimed that a preposition is

               a word that reveals the possibility of saying more about a thing or an action. Prepositions help

               us to indicate the place or the location of the action, someone or something, where it is coming

               from, or the direction where the action is moving.


                       Tables 1.1 and 1.2 show the demographic profile of respondents regarding their grade,


               section, and age. The participants are from Tanza National Comprehensive High School who

               are selected Grade 8 and 10 of sections Integrity (17), Freedom (9), Ametrine (15), Einstein (19),

               Onyx (16), Jade (17), and Albite (7). Their age ranges from 13 to 17 years old but the majority of

               them are 15 years old.


                       Tables 2.1, 2.2, and 2.3 are the result of the pre-test per part. Part I of the pre-test which

               is the preposition of time got a 76.3 average number of correct answers. Part II which is the

               preposition of place has a 73.4 average number of correct answers, while Part III which is the





                                                             24]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[preposition of direction got a 63.3 average number of correct answers. The students

               encountered difficulty in using the preposition of direction. The overall average score of the pre-

               test is 21.05/30.


                       On the other hand, the result of the post-test is successful with the use of lesson

               exemplar and a new method of teaching that was conducted for two weeks. The preposition of


               place got 95.2; the preposition of direction got 94.2, and the preposition of direction has an

               average of 95. The overall average score of the post-test is 27.2/30. Hence, the study was

               possible with the help of students and faculties of TNCHS.


               Conclusions


               Based on the results of the study, the researchers conclude the following:


                   1. When it comes to the usage of prepositions of direction, students make more mistakes.


                   2. More time should be spent by teachers teaching prepositions and how to employ them in

                       various situations and contexts.

                   3. Teachers and students need to adopt new ways of learning with the use of technology to

                       familiarize themselves and have access to more prepositional words.

                   4. The presence of a detailed and comprehensive lesson exemplar as a guide for teaching


                       is important for a better understanding of the usage of prepositions.

                   5. Students learn quickly when the teacher is making their discussion engaging and fun

                       through a series of activities.


               Recommendations


               The following recommendations were made for a better understanding of prepositions for

               students:


                   1. Lesson Exemplar





                                                             25]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[It is recommended for teachers to have a detailed and comprehensive lesson exemplar

               as an action plan to help and guide the students to understand the proper usage of prepositions

               and be aware of the common grammatical errors. Through this, the students can easily catch up

               with the lessons since they are guided accordingly. As the pillar of knowledge, learning is


               engaging when an instructor has a flow to follow.


                   2. New method of teaching


                       Since we are in the 21    st  century, technological advancement is inevitable. Our

               environment is adapting to the changes we are facing due to advancements. The pandemic

               leaves us no choice but to learn using the Internet. There are many words and phrases with

               prepositions that we are not familiar with due to limited access. Technology makes our lives

               easier and learning a new method of teaching is significant in this era since everyone is


               adjusting to what this will offer. Fun and engaging discussion are possible since the cyber world

               is offering us a lot of opportunities to learn.









































                                                             26]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[References:


               Anderson, M. (2003). Text Types in English. Australia: Macmillan Education. P.26


               Frank, M. (n.d.). Modern English a Practical Reference Guide, (New Jersey: Prentice-Hall).

               P.165


               Lodge Jason M., Kennedy Gregor, Lockyer Lori, Arguel Amael, Pachman Mariya. (2018).


                       Understanding Difficulties and Resulting Confusion in Learning: An Integrative Review.

                       Frontiers of Education, 3(2018).

                       https://www.researchgate.net/publication/260695699_Learning_Difficulties

               Definition of Preposition. (2000). Oxford Learner’s Dictionary. Retrieved 2022, from

                       https://www.oxfordlearnersdictionaries.com/definition/english/preposition


               Ahmad, Nasir And Bukhari, Maqud And Hussain, Shafqat. (2011). Error Analysis: Learning

                       Articles and Prepositions among Secondary School Students in Pakistan.

                       Interdisciplinary Journal of Contemporary Research In Business. Institute of

                       Interdisciplinary Business Research. UK, 2.

                       https://www.researchgate.net/publication/216315339_Error_Analysis_Learning_Articles_

                       and_Prepositions_among_Secondary_School_Students_in_Pakistan

               Mukundan, J., & Norwati R. (2009). Textbook Representation of Prepositions. English Language


                       Teaching, 2(4), 13 – 34.


               Quirk, R., Greenbaum, S., Leech G, & Svartvik, J. (2009). A comprehensive grammar of the

                       English Language. London: Longman.


               Ravina, M.C. (2008). An assessment of transitional language competence – A study of the

                       Interaction of selected learners/learning variables.


               Swick, E. (2005). Practice makes perfect: English pronouns and prepositions. New York:


               McGraw Hill.


                                                             24]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[DIFFICULTIES IN USING PREPOSITIONS: BASIS FOR A PROPOSED ACTION PLAN

                                                          Pre-test


               Name:
               Grade & Section:                                                          SCORE:
               Age:



               Multiple Choice: Choose the letter of the correct answer.




                                               Part I. Preposition of Time


                   1. We get up _ the morning.                     a. On
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. From
                   2. We go to bed _ night.                        a. On
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. From
                   3. It’s always hot _ summer.                    a. On
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. From
                   4. The movie starts at two _ the                a. In
                       afternoon.                                  b. On
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. Over
                   5. Autumn begins _ September.                   a. Since
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. On
                                                                   d. At
                   6. They were married _ 1990.                    a. From
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. On
                   7. Joe arrived _ me.                            a. By
                                                                   b. Under
                                                                   c. After
                                                                   d. From
                   8. It has not rained at all _ two weeks.        a. For
                                                                   b. Since
                                                                   c. Before
                                                                   d. After


                                                             25]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[9. Breakfast is served _ seven o’clock.         a. At
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. For
                                                                   d. Since
                   10.Kevin and Joe have been in the               a. Since
                       same class _ first grade.                   b. For
                                                                   c. On
                                                                   d. At



                                               Part II. Preposition of Place

                   11.Sign your name _ the dotted line.            a. After
                                                                   b. Beyond
                                                                   c. On
                   12.When we flew _ the clouds, we                a. Over
                       could see the Earth’s surface.              b. In
                                                                   c. Under
                   13.Can I sit _ you at the movie                 a. Beside
                       theater?                                    b. Inside
                                                                   c. Around
                   14.The     kids   are   playing    _   the      a. In
                       backyard.                                   b. From
                                                                   c. At
                   15.Your glasses are right _ you.                a. In front of you
                                                                   b. From
                                                                   c. Over
                   16.You can pick up your keys _ the              a. Over
                       front desk.                                 b. In
                                                                   c. At
                   17.Let’s meet _ the front door.                 a. In
                                                                   b. On
                                                                   c. At
                   18.There’s a helicopter hovering _ our          a. At
                       house.                                      b. Over
                                                                   c. Under
                   19.Didn’t you park your car _ mine?             a. Next to
                                                                   b. Over
                                                                   c. From
                   20.Please stay _ the police caution             a. Behind
                       tape.                                       b. Over
                                                                   c. Next


                                            Part III. Preposition of Direction






                                                             26]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Direction Map
                   21.The blank is _ the police station.           a. Behind
                                                                   b. Over
                                                                   c. Next to
                                                                   d. Under
                   22.The church is _ the corner lot.              a. In
                                                                   b. At
                                                                   c. From
                                                                   d. On
                   23.The store is _ the movie theater.            a. In
                                                                   b. At
                                                                   c. Across
                                                                   d. Below
                   24.The school is _ the post office.             a. Above
                                                                   b. Below
                                                                   c. Across
                                                                   d. Around
                   25.The train station is _ the central           a. At
                       avenue.                                     b. In
                                                                   c. On
                                                                   d. From
                   26.The drugstore is _ the movie                 a. At
                       theater.                                    b. Behind
                                                                   c. Around
                                                                   d. From
                   27.The school is _ the train station.           a. At
                                                                   b. In front of
                                                                   c. Around
                                                                   d. Behind
                   28.The church is _ the second street.           a. Around
                                                                   b. Across
                                                                   c. Since
                                                                   d. Behind
                   29.The store is _ the police station.           a. Around
                                                                   b. Across
                                                                   c. Beside


                                                             27]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[d. Behind
                   30.The drugstore is _ of post office and        a. Around
                       movie theater.                              b. Across
                                                                   c. In between
                                                                   d. Behind




               DIFFICULTIES IN USING PREPOSITIONS: BASIS FOR A PROPOSED ACTION PLAN


                                                         Post-test

               Name:
               Grade & Section:                                                          SCORE:
               Age:


               Multiple Choice: Choose the letter of the correct answer.





                                               Part I. Preposition of Time

                   1. We get up _ the morning.                     a. On
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. From
                   2. We go to bed _ night.                        a. On
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. From
                   e. It’s always hot _ summer.                    a. On
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. From
                   e. The movie starts at two _ the                a. In
                       afternoon.                                  b. On
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. Over
                   e. Autumn begins _ September.                   a. Since
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. On
                                                                   d. At
                   e. They were married _ 1990.                    a. From
                                                                   b. In
                                                                   c. At
                                                                   d. On



                                                             28]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[e. Joe arrived _ me.                            e. By
                                                                   f. Under
                                                                   g. After
                                                                   h. From
                   f. It has not rained at all _ two weeks.        e. For
                                                                   f. Since
                                                                   g. Before
                                                                   h. After
                   g. Breakfast is served _ seven o’clock.         e. At
                                                                   f. In
                                                                   g. For
                                                                   h. Since
                   h. Kevin and Joe have been in the               e. Since
                       same class _ first grade.                   f. For
                                                                   g. On
                                                                   h. At



                                               Part II. Preposition of Place

                   i.  Sign your name _ the dotted line.           d. After
                                                                   e. Beyond
                                                                   f. On
                   j.  When we flew _ the clouds, we               d. Over
                       could see the Earth’s surface.              e. In
                                                                   f. Under
                   k. Can I sit _ you at the movie                 d. Beside
                       theater?                                    e. Inside
                                                                   f. Around
                   l.  The    kids   are   playing    _   the      d. In
                       backyard.                                   e. From
                                                                   f. At
                   m. Your glasses are right _ you.                d. In front of you
                                                                   e. From
                                                                   f. Over
                   n. You can pick up your keys _ the              d. Over
                       front desk.                                 e. In
                                                                   f. On
                   o. Let’s meet _ the front door.                 d. In
                                                                   e. On
                                                                   f. At
                   p. There’s a helicopter hovering _ our          d. At
                       house.                                      e. Over
                                                                   f. Under
                   q. Didn’t you park your car _ mine?             d. Next to
                                                                   e. Over



                                                             29]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[f. From
                   r. Please stay _ the police caution             d. Behind
                       tape.                                       e. Over
                                                                   f. Next



                                            Part III. Preposition of Direction



















                                                      Direction Map
                   s. The blank is _ the police station.           e. Behind
                                                                   f. Over
                                                                   g. Next to
                                                                   h. Under
                   t. The church is _ the corner lot.              e. In
                                                                   f. At
                                                                   g. From
                                                                   h. On
                   u. The store is _ the movie theater.            e. In
                                                                   f. At
                                                                   g. Across
                                                                   h. Below
                   v. The school is _ the post office.             e. Above
                                                                   f. Below
                                                                   g. Across
                                                                   h. Around
                   w. The train station is _ the central           e. At
                       avenue.                                     f. In
                                                                   g. On
                                                                   h. From
                   x. The drugstore is _ the movie                 a. At
                       theater.                                    b. Behind
                                                                   c. Around
                                                                   d. From
                   e. The school is _ the train station.           a. At
                                                                   b. In front of
                                                                   c. Around


                                                             30]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[d. Behind
                   e. The church is _ the second street.           a. Around
                                                                   b. Across
                                                                   c. Since
                                                                   d. Behind
                   e. The store is _ the police station.           a. Around
                                                                   b. Across
                                                                   c. Beside
                                                                   d. Behind
                   e. The drugstore is _ of post office and        a. Around
                       movie theater.                              b. Across
                                                                   c. In between
                                                                   d. Behind




























































                                                             31]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[ON THE USE OF CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY LEARNING MANAGEMENT
                                  SYSTEM:  CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY – TANZA CAMPUS
                                     STUDENTS AND FACULTY MEMBERS PERCEPTION











                                                   Undergraduate Research
                                                Submitted to the Faculty of the
                                                Teacher Education Department
                                            Cavite State University -Tanza Campus
                                                         Tanza, Cavite










                                                      In partial fulfillment
                                              of the requirements for the degree
                                               Bachelor of Secondary Education
                                                     major in Mathematics











                                                       RONNIE C. DAEF
                                                    ROMEO P. NORBE JR.
                                                  MA. WOODELYN P. REYES
                                                           June 2022]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                     CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                            Tanza Campus
                                             Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                           (046) 414 – 3979
                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                Teacher Education Department (TED)


                               Author   RONNIE C. DAEF
                                        ROMEO P. NORBE JR.
                                        MA. WOODELYN P. REYES


                               Title    ON  THE  USE  OF  CAVITE  STATE  UNIVERSITY  LEARNING
                                        MANAGEMENT  SYSTEM:    CAVITE  STATE  UNIVERSITY  –
                                        TANZA  CAMPUS  STUDENTS  AND  FACULTY  MEMBERS
                                        PERCEPTION


                                                            A P R O V E D:





                        MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN             _______  MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                 _______

                        Research Adviser                   Date     Research Coordinator                 Date

                        MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN             _______  GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto                _______

                        Department Chair                   Date     Campus Administrator                 Date]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[BIBLIOGRAPHICAL DATA



                              Ronnie Cuyos Daef was born at Brgy. Acacia, Silang of the province of Cavite

                       on October 2, 1992. He is the eldest son among the five children of Mrs. Concepcion


                       C. Daef and Mr. Ronaldo B. Daef. He resides at Blk. 32, Lot 9, Brgy. Acacia, Silang,

                       Cavite.

                            He  finished  his  primary  education  at  Bulihan  Sites  and  Services  Project

                       Elementary School, now known as Bulihan Sites and Services Elementary School in

                       2005  and  pursued  his  secondary  education  at  Bulihan  National  High  School  and


                       graduated in 2009.

                            In 2012, he enrolled at the Cavite State University – Tanza Campus (CvSU-TC)

                       under the program Associate in Computer Technology and graduated with award in

                       April 2014.

                            In June 2014, he was employed as a Teacher by Maranatha Christian Academy

                       – GMA Campus where he was able to teach students from Kinder 1 & 2 and Grades 1

                       – 5. He handled Computer, Mathematics, Science, and English subjects. He stayed in


                       the said school for one period only and got his job as Customer Service Representative

                       (CSR) in iQor, Philippines – Dasmariñas City afterwards. After some months of working

                       as a CSR, he was hired as an IT Administrator at Walid Al Baker Trading, Est in Doha,

                       Qatar where he stayed for 1 year and 3 months. He got back in the Philippines in

                       September 2016 where he continued working in a call center facility.


                            He went back to studying in 2018 and took up Bachelor of Secondary Education

                       major in Mathematics in the same university, in that year, he tried becoming a working

                       student, but due to lack of rest, he was forced to give up studying and gave his focus

                       on working. In 2020, during the surge of pandemic, he grabbed the opportunity to go

                       back to the university. He anticipates graduating in the March 2022.








                                                                i]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[BIBLIOGRAPHICAL DATA



                              Romeo  Prado  Norbe  Jr.  was  born  on  December  31,  1997,  at  Bago  City

                       Negros Occidental. He is currently residing at Block 14, Lot 31, Phase 3B Carissa


                       Home, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite. He is the third among the five children of Mr. Romeo M.

                       Norbe and Mrs. Anabelle P. Norbe.

                              He finished his elementary education at Alicia M. Espinos Elementary School

                       at Maria, Elena, Barangay Dulao, Bago City in 2012. He spent his secondary education

                       at  Ramon  Torres  Dulao  National  High  School,  Barangay  Dulao,  Bago  City,  and


                       graduated in 2018.

                              In June 2018, he took up the program Bachelor of Secondary Education Major

                       in Mathematics at Cavite State University Tanza Campus. At present, he is a 4th-year

                       student and hopefully wishes to finish his degree this coming August 2022.

















































                                                                ii]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[BIBLIOGRAPHICAL DATA



                              Ma.  Woodelyn  P.  Reyes  was  born  on  June  9,  1998,  in  Dasmarinas  City,

                       Cavite. She is the second child and eldest daughter of Mr. Woody P. Reyes and Mrs.


                       Margie P. Reyes. She is currently residing at Block 7, Lot 10, Section 19, Phase 2,

                       Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite.

                              From 2005 until 2008, she studied her first to fourth grade at Dr. Jose P. Rizal

                       Elementary School in Dasmarinas Cavite. In 2009, she then transferred to Leyte and

                       finished her remaining primary education in 2010. In that same year, she moved back


                       to Cavite. From 2010 to 2014, she spent her secondary education and graduated with

                       honor at Tanza National Trade School—ANNEX, located in Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite.

                       In that same year, she took a two-year computer programming course at Datacom

                       Institute of Computer Technology in Rosario Cavite and graduated in 2016.

                              In 2017, she landed her first job in Silang, Cavite, and filed her resignation in

                       August 2018. In that same year, she took up a Bachelor of Secondary Education major

                       in Mathematics at Cavite State University Tanza Campus.


                              She is hoping to obtain a degree in 2022.



































                                                               iii]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[ACKNOWLEDGEMENT



                              The  researchers  would  like  to  express  their  inmost  gratitude  and  sincere

                       appreciation to the following who contributed on their own way to finish this study:


                              Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, chairperson of Teacher Education Department and

                       Research  adviser,  for  her  invaluable  dedication  in  supervising  the  researchers  to

                       accomplish the study;

                              Prof. Joyce B. Senaris, IT Department Chairperson, for her valuable assistance

                       towards the improvement of the research questionnaire;


                              Ms. Gerry Mae T. Silvero, instructor, for her valuable assistance towards the

                       improvement of the research questionnaire;

                              All fourth year BSE – Mathematics students, for the friendship, support, and

                       kindness;

                              To the respondents, for answering all the questions honestly, which served as

                       an aid in gathering the necessary information towards the completion of this study; and

                              To Almighty God, for guiding the researchers throughout the study.





                                                                                RONNIE C. DAEF
                                                                              ROMEO P. NORBE JR.
                                                                           MA. WOODELYN P. REYES

























                                                               iv]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[PERSONAL ACKNOWLEDGEMENT



                            Ronnie C. Daef would like to express his heartfelt gratitude appreciation and

                       gratefulness to the following who helped him in some way while he is undergoing his


                       research study:

                            The  Almighty  God,  for  the  guidance,  love,  and  joy  He  has  always  given  the

                       researcher every day of his life;

                            His parents, Mrs. Concepcion C. Daef and Mr. Ronaldo B. Daef, for the advice,

                       love, care and patience during his study and existence;


                            His brothers, Ronniel, Ronito, Ronaldo Jr. and Ronnel Jhon, who stand as his

                       motivation in pursuing his tertiary education;

                            Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, the Teacher Education Department Chairperson and

                       research adviser, for the advises and guidance she gave to the researcher, for the joy,

                       laughter and friendship they had shared, also for inspiring him to finish his study and

                       guiding him in all way of his life;

                            Ms. Noemi Perida, the campus registrar, for making sure that all the researcher’s


                       pending subjects will be included in his enrolled subjects;

                            Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas (deceased), the researcher’s friend, mentor, mother,

                       and teacher, for the love he gave to the researcher, for the laughter and tears they

                       have shared, also for the support he gave to the researcher when he was still alive;

                            Ms. Jessica Avon Quezada, Mr. Ricky Pimentel, Ms. Angelica Solares-Añasco,


                       and  Mama  Rolz  Regalado,  for  the  long-term  friendship  they  had  shared  and  for

                       pushing him to pursue his education;

                            IGG. Michael T. Ocava, RSW, Punong Barangay of Barangay Narra III, Silang,

                       Cavite, for being his mentor and role-model leader, for being there to the researcher

                       through ups and downs and for never leaving the researcher behind despite of the time

                       constrains;





                                                                v]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[IGG.  Mark  “Phem”  Perido,  Barangay  Councilor  of  Barangay  Yakal,  Silang,

                       Cavite, for becoming his comfort whenever he feels weak, for always being there to

                       inspire him and give him life advises;

                            Mr.  Benjamin  Cruz,  Ms.  Adhel  Romero,  Ms.  Mabelle  Murillo,  Mr.  Romeo


                       Coligado, Ms. Lharbel Coligado, Ms. Regina Coligado and Mr. Jonathan Azucena, for

                       the inspiration they always impart to the researcher and checking on him despite of

                       their busy schedule;

                            Ms.  Leona  Grace  Lyn  A.  Abbariao,  Barangay  Treasurer,  and  Ms.  Faith  D.

                       Espera, Barangay Secretary of Barangay Narra III, Silang, Cavite, for the kindness


                       they had showed to the researcher and for becoming his audience whenever he needs

                       to practice his presentation;

                            Ms.  Mary  Jane  Balote  and  Ms.  Maricel  Blanca,  Violence  Against  Women’s

                       Officers of Barangay Narra III, Silang, Cavite, for being his friend and a mother outside

                       home, for taking care of the researcher throughout his study journey, also for always

                       thinking of his welfare;

                            The faculty and staff of the Cavite State University  – Tanza Campus, for the


                       laughter, knowledge, advice, and guidance they have shared with the researcher on

                       his entire study journey;

                            His classmates from all the year levels in the Teacher Education Department,

                       especially his research partners, Ms. Woodelyn Reyes and Mr. Romeo Norbe; and

                            Those whom the researcher was not able to mention, but in some way helped


                       the research in completing his research successfully



                                                                                     RONNIE C. DAEF













                                                               vi]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[PERSONAL ACKNOWLEDGEMENT



                            Romeo  P.  Norbe  Jr.  would  like  to  express  his  inmost  gratitude  and  sincere

                       appreciation to the following who helped me during research study:


                              Mr.  Romeo  M.  Norbe  and  Mrs.  Anabelle  P.  Norbe,  his  parents,  for  their

                       guidance, motivation and financial, and moral support that helped him face each day

                       with a big smile;

                              Prof.  Mildred A. Sebastian for her advice and effort just to make this study

                       more knowledgeable;


                              All  my  classmates,  for  their  physical  and  emotional  support,  and

                       encouragement to keep going;

                              My friends, for cheering his up during my research study; and

                              Almighty God, for giving her strength, knowledge, faith, and wisdom to finish

                       my  practice  teacher  properly  and  for  relieving  my  personal  problem  and  stress

                       encountered while conducting the research.




                                                                                ROMEO P. NORBE JR.




































                                                               vii]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[PERSONAL ACKNOWLEDGEMENT



                            Ma.  Woodelyn  P.  Reyes  would  like  to  express  her  deepest  gratitude  and

                       appreciation to the following who helped her all throughout the research journey:


                              To  Almighty  God,  Jesus  Christ,  for  the  courage,  knowledge,  wisdom,  and

                       strength while conducting the research;

                              To  Mrs.  Margie  and  Mr.  Woody  Reyes,  her  parents,  who  always  been  her

                       priority and serves as her inspiration to keep going, for their love and support;

                              To  Hazel  Andrea  Reyes,  her  only  and  beloved  sister,  for  being  incredibly


                       supportive;

                              To Ms. Josephine Dichoso and Ms. Joyce, her closest classmate and friend,

                       for their moral support that motivates her to fight every challenge that comes her way;

                       and

                            To Mr. Michael Macaraig, for his love, understanding, and support morally and

                       financially.




                                                                         MA. WOODELYN P. REYES



































                                                               viii]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[ABSTRACT

                       DAEF,  RONNIE  C,  NORBE,  ROMEO  JR.  P.  and  REYES,  MA.  WOODELYN  P.
                       On the Use of Cavite State University Learning Management System:  Cavite
                       State University  – Tanza Campus Students and Faculty Members Perception.
                       Undergraduate Research. Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics.
                       Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus,  Tanza  Cavite.  June  2022.
                       Adviser: Mildred A. Sebastian


                              The study was conducted from August 2020 to June 2022 in Bagtas, Tanza,


                       Cavite to determine the perceptions of faculty and students on the use of Cavite State

                       University Learning Management System in teaching and learning. It specifically aimed

                       to: (1) determine the perceptions of CvSU - TC students and faculty members towards

                       the use of CvSU – LMS; (2) determine if there are differences on perception of students

                       on the use of the CvSU - LMS in learning in terms of age, sex, program, academic

                       level, commonly used gadget, and type of internet connection; (3) determine if there


                       are differences on perception of faculty members on the use of the CvSU - LMS in their

                       teaching  according  to  age,  sex,  department,  experience,  educational  attainment,

                       commonly used gadget, and type of internet connection; and (4) identify the significant

                       difference between the overall perception of CvSU - TC students and faculty members

                       towards their use of CvSU - LMS.

                              The descriptive analytical approach was used to determine CvSU TC students'


                       and faculty's perceptions of the CvSU LMS.The researchers collected data using two

                       different instruments: one for students to determine their perception of the CvSU LMS

                       in  learning  and  one  for  faculty  to  determine  their  perception  of  the  CvSU  LMS  in

                       teaching.It was distributed using Google Forms and stratified random sampling was

                       used to identify samples for each group. The sample included 14 faculty members and

                       181  students.  Calculation  means,  standard  deviations,  T-test,  and  ANOVA  were

                       calculated.


                              The  study  revealed  that  the  perception  of  Cavite  State  University  Tanza

                       Campus  faculty  members  and  students  towards  the  use  the  university  Learning



                                                               ix]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Management System in teaching and learning were positive. The results also showed

                       statistically significant differences in the perception of students in terms of age, sex,

                       program,  and  type  of  internet  connection;  and  no  significant  differences  in  the

                       perception of faculty in terms of all variables.


                              Moreover, the study revealed that there are significant difference between the

                       overall perception of CvSU - TC students and faculty members towards their use of

                       CvSU – LMS in terms of the systems’ objectives, attributes, and advantages.

                            In  light  of  these  findings,  the  researchers  recommended  the  need  for  more

                       research  on  the challenges  and  difficulties  experienced  by  university  students  and


                       faculty members while utilizing the software Learning Management System in learning

                       and teaching, as well as solutions to such problems. The need for technical assistance

                       to answer questions that may arise when using the Learning Management System and

                       to benefit from all the capabilities provided by Learning Management System software.















































                                                                x]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENT





                        BIOGRAPHICAL DATA ……………………………………………….................                         i

                        ACKNOWLEDGEMENT ………………………………………………................                            iv

                        ABSTRACT ……………………………………………………………..................                            ix

                        LIST OF FIGURES ……………………………………………….........................                  xiii

                        LIST OF TABLES ………………………………………………..........................                  xv

                        LIST OF APPENDICES ……………………………………………….................                       xvi


                        INTRODUCTION ……………………………………………………….................                           1

                             Statement of the Problem ………………………………………..............                   2

                             Objective of the Study …………………………………………................                  3

                             Significance of the Study ………………………………………...............                 4

                             Time and Place of the Study …………………………………................                5

                             Scope and Limitations of the Study ………………………….................           5


                             Definition of Terms …………………………….………………................                   6

                             Conceptual Framework …………………………………………..............                      7

                        REVIEW OF RELATED LITERATURE ………………………………...............                      8

                        METHOLOGY …………………………….……………….…..…………..............                           14

                             Research Design ………….……………….…..………………................                   14

                             Sources of Data …………………………………………………..............                       14


                             Participants of the Study ………………………………………...............                14

                             Sampling Technique ……………………………………………...............                     15

                             Data to be gathered ……………………………………………................                   15

                             Statistical Treatment of Data ……………………………………..............              16

                             Validation of Research Instruments                                      17

                             Reliability of the Research Instruments ………………………................       17






                                                               xi]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[RESULTS AND DISCUSSION ……………….……………….…..……….…..…                             18

                        SUMMARY, CONCLUSION AND RECOMMENDATIONS ……………………                             53

                             Summary …….……………….…..……….…..……….…………………..                               53

                             Conclusions ….……………….…..……….…..……….…………………..                            54


                             Recommendations ….……………….…..……….…..……….…………..                           55

                        REFERENCES ….……………….…..……….…..……….……………………….                                 56

                        APPENDICES ….……………….…..……….…..……….………………………...                               58


































































                                                               xii]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[LIST OF TABLES


                        Table                                                                      Page

                         1      Cronbach’s Alpha of the questionnaire                                17

                         2      Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Objective                       26

                         3      Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Functions                       27

                         4      Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Attributes                      28


                         5      Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Accessibility                   29

                         6      Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Advantages                      30

                         7      Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Objective                       31

                         8      Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Functions                       32

                         9      Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Attributes                      33

                         10     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Accessibility                   34

                         11     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Advantages                      35


                         12     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Age Mean Value                  36

                         13     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Age (ANOVA)                     36

                         14     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Sex (T-Test)                    37

                         15     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Program Mean Value              38

                         16     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Program (ANOVA)                 38


                         17     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Year Level Mean Value           39

                         18     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Year Level (ANOVA)              39

                         19     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Commonly Used Gadget            40

                                Mean Value

                         20     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Commonly Used Gadget            40

                                (ANOVA)

                         21     Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Type of Internet                41


                                Connection (T-Test)





                                                               xiii]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[LIST OF TABLES


                        Table                                                                      Page

                         22     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Age Mean Value                  42

                         23     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Age (ANOVA)                     42

                         24     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Sex (T-Test)                    43

                         25     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Department Mean Value           44


                         26     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Department (ANOVA)              44

                         27     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Educational Attainment          45

                                Mean Value

                         28     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Educational Attainment          45

                                (ANOVA)


                         29     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Years of Teaching               46

                                Experience Mean Value

                         30     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Years of Teaching               47

                                Experience (ANOVA)

                         31     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Commonly Used Gadget            48

                                Mean Value

                         32     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Commonly Used Gadget            48


                                Mean Value

                         33     Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Type of Internet                49

                                Connection (T-Test)

                         34     Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Objective          50

                         35     Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Function           51

                         36     Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Attributes         51

                         37     Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Accessibility      52


                         38     Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Advantages         52





                                                               xiv]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[LIST OF FIGURES



                        Figure                                                                     Page

                          1      Conceptual framework of the study                                   7


                          2      Distribution of respondents based on student’s age group            18

                          3      Distribution of respondents based on student’s sex                  19

                          4      Distribution of respondents based on student’s program              19

                          5      Distribution of respondents based on student’s year level           20

                          6      Distribution of respondents based on student’s commonly used        20

                                 gadgets

                          7      Distribution of respondents based on student’s type of internet     21


                                 connection

                          8      Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s age                  22

                          9      Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s sex                  22

                          10     Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s department           23

                          11     Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s age                  23


                          12     Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s years of teaching    24

                                 experience

                          13     Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s commonly used        25

                                 gadgets

                          14     Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s type of internet     25

                                 connection



















                                                               xv]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[LIST OF APPENDICES

                        Appendix                                                                   Page

                            1       Research instrument for Students Respondents                     59

                            2       Research instrument for Faculty Respondents                      62


                            3       Letter of Request to Campus Dean                                 65







































































                                                               xvi]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[ON THE USE OF CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY LEARNING MANAGEMENT
                                  SYSTEM:  CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY – TANZA CAMPUS
                                     STUDENTS AND FACULTY MEMBERS PERCEPTION



                                                        Ronnie C. Daef
                                                      Romeo Jr. P. Norbe
                                                    Ma. Woodelyn P. Reyes




                        An undergraduate thesis submitted to the faculty of the Teacher Education Department,
                        Cavite State University – Tanza Campus, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite in partial fulfillment of the
                        requirements for the degree of Bachelor of Secondary Education (major in Mathematics)
                        with  Contribution  No.  ________________.  Prepared  under  the  supervision  of  Prof.
                        Mildred Arellano-Sebastian.


                                                        INTRODUCTION

                              The COVID-19 pandemic, which began in December 2019, severely impacted

                       the operations of educational institutions in the Philippines and around the world. It has

                       evolved into a global health crisis that affects everyone, regardless of age, gender, or

                       social  status.  The  world  suddenly  stopped,  and  the  economy  collapsed  as  all

                       businesses had no other choice but to temporarily cease their operations. To stop the


                       spread of the said virus, most countries closed schools, colleges, and universities. The

                       crisis  created  a  dilemma  for the  government  not  only  in  the  health  but  also  in the

                       education sectors.

                              The Philippine government has temporarily suspended classes at all levels as

                       a precautionary measure against the aforementioned virus. However, learning cannot

                       be  cancelled.  The  government  had  to  find  a  way  to  continue  education  amidst  a


                       pandemic, and a shift to online learning is one of the alternatives that has created a

                       hot debate in the country. In this sort of learning, both the learner and the instructor or

                       provider of knowledge are not physically present in the typical classroom setting. E-

                       learning management is a useful platform for remote teaching and learning. A learning

                       management system (LMS) is a piece of software or web-based technology that is

                       used to organize, implement, and evaluate a specific learning process. It is used for]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[2


                       eLearning activities and, in its most typical form, consists of two elements: a server

                       that  provides  basic  operations  and  a  user  interface  that  instructors,  students,  and

                       administrators control (Brush 2019). Moreover, An LMS manages the distribution of

                       learning materials, administration, management, and information. All of this is done to


                       achieve one basic goal: to meet learning objectives (Tamm 2021). To adapt to the new

                       normal, Cavite State University (CvSU) migrated from a traditional classroom set up to

                       a flexible learning set up for the academic year 2020–2021. The pandemic also forces

                       the state university to create its own learning management system that will be used by

                       the entire university organization.




                       Statement of the Problem

                            Generally, the research aims to determine the perception of Cavite Statement

                       University – Tanza Campus (CvSU - TC) students and faculty members on the use of

                       Cavite State University - Learning Management System (CvSU - LMS).

                            Specifically, the study aimed to answer the following questions:

                       ●  What are the perceptions of CvSU - TC students and faculty members towards the


                          use of CvSU - LMS?

                       ●  Is the perception of students differing about the use of the CvSU - LMS in learning

                          in terms of age, sex, program, academic level, commonly used gadget, and type

                          of internet connection?

                       ●  Is the perception of faculty members differing about the use of the CvSU - LMS in


                          their  teaching  according  to  age,  sex,  department,  experience,  educational

                          attainment, commonly used gadget, and type of internet connection?

                       ●  Is  there  a  significant  difference  between  the  overall  perception  of  CvSU  -  TC

                          students and faculty members towards their use of CvSU - LMS?]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[3


                       Objectives of the Study

                              The purpose of this study is to investigate the perception of CvSU - TC students

                       and faculty members on the use of CvSU - LMS.

                            Specifically, it aimed to:


                              ●  determine the  perceptions of CvSU - TC students and faculty members

                                 towards the use of CvSU – LMS;

                              ●  determine if there are differences on perception of students on the use of

                                 the CvSU - LMS in learning in terms of age, sex, program, academic level,

                                 commonly used gadget, and type of internet connection;


                              ●  determine if there are differences on perception of faculty members on the

                                 use of the CvSU - LMS in their teaching according to age, sex, department,

                                 experience, educational attainment, commonly used gadget, and type of

                                 internet connection; and

                              ●  identify the significant difference between the overall perception of CvSU -

                                 TC students and faculty members towards their use of CvSU - LMS.]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[4


                       Significance of the Study

                              The researchers would like the following to benefit from this study:

                              Students. Through this study, students will be able to determine the perception

                       of the entirety of the student population's perception of the use of CvSU-LMS. Through


                       this study, students can manage their own expectations, considering the perception of

                       the other students, and will be able to adapt easily to the system. In addition, this will

                       help the students determine the factors affecting the usability of the students that they

                       might encounter in the future.

                              Faculty. Through this study, faculty members will be able to understand the

                       perception of the general faculty population regarding the use of CvSU-LMS. As a


                       result,  faculty  members  will  be  able  to  regulate  their  own  expectations  while

                       considering the perceptions of their co-teachers and will be able to readily adapt to the

                       system  as  a  result.  Furthermore,  this  research  will  help  the faculty  members in

                       determining  the  factors  that  influence  teaching usability  that  they  may  face  in  the

                       future.

                              Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus.  Through  this  study,  the


                       administration will be able to determine if the use of CvSU-LMS is effective and efficient

                       for  both the  students  and  the faculty  members. In  addition,  this  study  will  suggest

                       improvements  and  expose  gray  areas  of  the  system  to  provide  a  better  quality  of

                       teaching and learning through LMS. This will also help the administration to provide

                       proper and guided training on the use of CvSU-LMS to the incoming faculty members.

                              Future Researchers. Through this study, future researchers will be able to

                       determine the perception of the pilot users of the CvSU-LMS for both the students and


                       the  faculty  members.  It  will  guide  future  researchers  accordingly  to  suggest

                       improvements if deemed necessary for its better usability. It can also serve as the

                       basis of future research as a reference.]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[5


                       Time and Place of the Study

                              This study was conceptualized in August 2020 during the surge of COVID-19

                       pandemic and the data gathering was conducted from October 2021 to March 2022

                       among faculty and students of CvSU - TC. Interpretation and finalization were done


                       from April – May 2022.



                       Scope and Limitations

                              This study focused on the perception of the students and faculty members on

                       the use of the CvSU - LMS of the CvSU - TC. Further, it focused on the variables that

                       might affect the usability of the CvSU - LMS particularly age, gender, sex, program,

                       academic  level,  commonly  used  gadget,  and  type  of  internet  connection  for  the


                       students, and age, sex, department, experience, educational attainment, commonly

                       used gadget, and type of internet connection for the faculty members. The results were

                       gathered from the responses of the students and faculty members of CvSU - TC during

                       the Second Semester of the Academic Year 2021 - 2022.]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[6


                       Definition of Terms

                              The following terms were theoretically and operationally defined in the study:

                              Database refers to a structured collection of information or data that is often

                       stored digitally in a computer network. A database management system is usually in


                       charge of controlling and managing it.

                              Instructional Resources refers to a wide range of resources in any medium

                       that impact student's learning and instructor's instruction.

                              Learning Management System (LMS) refers to a computer program or web-

                       based technology which can be used to organize, execute, and evaluate a learning

                       process. The LMS is a technology for eLearning that consists of two parts: a server

                       that executes the fundamental functions and a user interface that is administered by


                       teachers, students, and administration.

                              Moodle refers to a learning platform that allows educators, administrators, and

                       learners to develop customized learning experiences using a single robust, safe, and

                       integrated system.

                              Pedagogy refers to the method on how teachers teach, in both theory and in


                       practice.

                              Plagiarism Checker refers to an online tool that help educators to check for

                       plagiarism in students' work. It scans and compares files against the submitted files

                       online.]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[7


                       Conceptual Framework

                            This section presents the conceptual framework of the perception of the students

                       and faculty members of the CvSU-TC on the use of the CvSU-LMS.



































                                           Figure 1. Conceptual framework of the study]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[8


                                             REVIEW OF RELATED LITERATURE



                            There is much related literature in learning management systems that can be

                       obtained  in  a  variety  of resources,  including  websites  and  published journals.  This


                       literature review aims to evaluate the available literature relating to the use of learning

                       management systems that could aid in identifying the perspective of faculty members

                       and students towards the use of it. The literature review starts with conceptualizing the

                       learning  management  system,  how  it  is  perceived  as  well  as  defined  by  different

                       persons, followed by the discussions on the system objectives, functions, attributes,


                       accessibility, the advantages and disadvantages.



                       Learning Management System

                            Learning Management System  or  LMS  is  a  web-based  software  package  for

                       planning,  implementing,  and  evaluating  learning,  as  well  as  facilitating  student

                       engagement, providing feedback, and managing students' activities. One of the most

                       essential  features  of  a  learning  management  system  is  the  capacity  to  optimize


                       learning quality and develop an interactive learning system. (Mohd Kasim, N. et al.

                       2016)

                            According to Trayek, Fuad., et.al. (2013), a learning management system or LMS

                       is  a  software  application  that  allows  users  or  learning  managers  to  disseminate

                       information from systematic planning using a pedagogical approach that is suited for


                       the situation. It allows users to collaborate and share information through the internet.

                            Ippakayala, V.K., et al. (2017), introduced a learning management system that

                       provides a centralized control mechanism for course content. A secure approach for

                       recording lectures is a significant aspect of this application. Brown and Johnson (2007)

                       consider LMS to be a vehicle for training, evaluation, and tracking results, while Al-

                       Khalifa (2010) considers LMS to be a platform for students to complete tasks quickly,

                       uploading  various  types  of  files  into  its  environment,  allowing  users  to  access]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[9


                       information at any time and from any location, and allowing users to communicate

                       electronically with other students in the course and the tutor.



                       System Objectives


                            Qafie  LMS  –  Blog  stated  an  eight  (8)  objectives  of  a  Learning  Management

                       System, which are the following: (1) to provide access to a resource pool; (2)  to get

                       rid of the old roadblocks; (3) to improve the efficiency of learning; (4) to seamlessly

                       incorporate technology; (5) to grant the ability to access information at any time; (6) to

                       save a significant amount of time, energy, and money; (7) to tailor the learning sessions


                       to the needs of the students; and (8) to make the assessment and feedback procedure

                       as simple as possible. In addition, the purpose is for students to be able to complete

                       their courses and contribute information from the comfort of their own home or school.

                       (Pirani, Z. and Sasikumar, M. 2014)



                       System Functions

                            Alshorman,  B.  A.  &  Bawahen,  A.  K.  (2018) found  that  learning  management


                       systems  have  a  wide  range  of  functions,  making  them  an  effective  and  efficient

                       instrument in tertiary education. The following are the functions of an LMS, according

                       to them: (1) provides an interaction tool, such as announcements, timetables, tasks,

                       estimations, user guides, and address books. (2) Content presentation, which they

                       define as the fundamental goal of the educational materials distribution system, which


                       is to make instructional resources available to students, and (3) Communication, which

                       is divided into three categories: sending and receiving mails, discussion board, and

                       virtual classroom.]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[10


                       System Attributes

                            Positive  attributes  of  a  Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  include  user-

                       friendliness, adaptability, openness, and others, according to Mohd Kasim, N. et al.,

                       (2016).


                            Alshorman, B. A. & Bawahen, A. K. (2018) reviewed the attributes of LMS from

                       the research of several researchers as follows:

                       ●  Easy access: Users can communicate with the information included in this code by

                          simply connecting to the Internet at any time and from any location.

                       ●  Provides feedback: The system keeps the users updated on the course, students,


                          results, and other related to the teaching and learning.

                       ●  Follow-up: The availability of a statistical file of all given activities allows the teacher

                          to track students' use of the software and delivery of assignments.

                       ●  Skills development: The system stimulates many skills for learners such as good

                          time management and other ICT-related skills.

                       ●  Learners' diversities are taken into consideration: The system offers a variety of


                          material delivery choices, including audio, video, animation, pictures, games, and

                          others, all of which work to account for individual variations among students and

                          their varying intelligence quotients.



                       System Advantages

                            According to the findings of a study conducted by Nayak, M., and Suesaowaluk,


                       P. (2007), learning management systems provides learners with an interactive and

                       authentic environment, allowing them to actively search for solutions and construct

                       their  own  knowledge  rather  than  receiving  standard  explanation,  and  increases

                       learners' enthusiasm to study and encourages greater cooperation among them. Al

                       handhali, et al. (2020) added that management, instructors, and students save time by

                       having online access to their accounts, allowing them to work from anywhere in the

                       globe.]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[11


                       System Disadvantages

                            Nayak, M., and Suesaowaluk, P. (2007) found that LMS increases the possibility

                       of copyright infringements; the quality of learning is also compromised; LMS are prone

                       to viruses and hacking; and the training time is significantly reduced, which also stated


                       by Pantazis, C. (2002) that eLearning has an impact on an industry's training practices.

                       On the other hand, Al handhali et al. (2020) states that LMS do not support a wide

                       range of teaching methods or give resources for particular pedagogical activities, such

                       as audio discussion boards.



                       System Accessibility

                            LMS is an effective and efficient tool for learning. Accessibility is an aspect of


                       LMS that should not be overlooked and forgotten (Tovutilms.com). Accessibility issues

                       are crucial that can make or break a learning management system (Vilamis.com). All

                       users should have access to LMS regardless of their physical and learning ability,

                       ethnicity or digital skills Chen, W. et al. (2013).

                            The following factors, according to Pappas, C., and Zaharias, P. (2018), makes


                       an LMS inaccessible:

                       1.  Complicated Logins – Users cannot access the LMS without a well-designed login

                          interface. Furthermore, complicated login procedures discourage users to use the

                          platform and access the data they require. (Pappas and Zaharias, P., 2018).

                       2.  Inability to change user preferences – Within an organization, users of LMS has

                          different roles. An instructor may require a deeper level of subject immersion than

                          a student, whereas an administrator or developer may demand back-end access,


                          which could possibly disrupt the LMS if tampered with by users who aren't familiar

                            with it. If a Learning Management System is unable to construct these access

                            divisions, data security could be endangered.  (Pappas and Zaharias, P., 2018).

                       3.  Confusing navigation controls – The ability to move freely and easily between LMS

                          pages is referred to as navigation. It should be simple to use, with controls that are]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[12


                          all the same, and it should be simple to transition from one screen to the next

                          according to Roque et al. (2004). However, users' accessibility may be hampered

                          by complicated or inconsistent navigation and complex system design, Pappas and

                          Zaharias, P. (2018).


                       4.  No built-in communication tools – A learning management system’s effectiveness

                          hinges  on  effective  communication.  Without  clear  communication  between

                          teachers and students, an online learning program may not be able to transfer the

                          skills and information to students (Williams, 2018). Furthermore, the LMS should

                          provide effective communication channels (e.g., email access and chat functions)


                          because there is no way to evaluate performance, provide comments, or escalate

                          issues inside the LMS without it, (Pappas and Zaharias, P., 2018).

                       5.  Transfer, update, or merging of data are too complex – Uploading files, producing

                          documents, and updating data should all be simple and intuitive on the LMS. To

                          reduce the drop-off rate, data input scenarios must be seamless and functional.

                          Learners  and  teachers have the tendency to stop  using the  LMS  if they  find  it

                          difficult to use it. (Pappas and Zaharias, P., 2018).


                       6.  Lack of LMS support resources – LMS support services come in a variety of forms.

                          Chat  bots,  pop-up  assistants,  forums,  contact  forms,  and  help  buttons  are  all

                          features of a good LMS that users can use if they have technical difficulties while

                          using it, (Pappas and Zaharias, P., 2018).

                       7.  Users are unable to access the platform on any device – Every user of a LMS


                          should have the same access to the system, either those who use a mobile phone

                          or tablet to access it. A responsive LMS should allow you to access the system at

                          any time, from any location and device as it should be automatically modifying the

                          content  to  meet  the  device’s  screen  and  resolution  of  the  users,  (Pappas  and

                          Zaharias, P., 2018)]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[13


                       Synthesis of the Related Literature and Studies

                            The above-mentioned literature and studies helped the researchers to have a

                       better understanding of the learning management system, how it is conceptualized and

                       defined in numerous studies.


                            With  the  aid  of  those  literatures,  the  researchers  were  able  to  identify  and

                       determine the objectives, functions, attributes, advantages and disadvantages, and

                       accessibility  of  a  learning  management  system.  It  also  helps  the  researcher  in

                       developing a survey questionnaire that will be employed in data gathering.]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[14


                                                       METHODOLOGY



                              This chapter presents the research design and the sampling techniques that

                       were used in selecting the participants for the study. This also describes the data to


                       be gathered that were used for the study. It also reveals the sources of the data and

                       the statistical treatment of the data



                       Research Design

                            The study used descriptive research design. This design was used to determine


                       the  perception  of  students  and  faculty  members  on  different  uses  of  Cavite  State

                       University Learning Management System. In line with that, descriptive research was

                       being adapted as it focuses on the "what" of the research rather than the "why" of it,

                       thus, it is much appropriate to be utilized because the proponents’ aims to get the

                       perception of the students and faculties and make an analysis out of it based on the

                       variables.




                       Sources of Data

                            The data which was utilized in this study came from the responses of all faculty

                       members across all departments and 320 bonafide students at Cavite State University

                       – Tanza Campus and was administered through Google Form.




                       Participants of the Study

                              Participants of the study were faculty members and bonafide students of CvSU

                       – Tanza Campus. Faculty member participants consist of 36 across all departments.

                       On the other hand, the student participants numbered a total of 284 students, which

                       comprises 71 students from BS in Business Management; 43 students from BS in

                       Hospitality Management; 73 students from BS in Information Technology; 25 students

                       from BS in Psychology, 22 students from BS in Tourism Management, 25 students]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[15


                       from  BSE  major  in  Mathematics,  15  students  from  BSE  major  in  English,  and  10

                       students from Bachelor of Elementary Education.



                       Sampling Technique


                            The study population encompasses multiple diverse groups, Cochran Formula

                       was  utilized  to  develop a  sample  size  and  Probability  Stratified  Random  Sampling

                       method was employed to identify the number of participants for each group (Faculty

                       member and Students). Stratified random sampling is a type of probability sampling in

                       which  a  researcher  divides  data  into  various  sub-groups  (strata)  sharing  common


                       characteristics (Acharya, A. S, et al. 2013). The abovementioned sampling approach

                       ensures and guarantees that the number of participants for each group (strata) was

                       calculated in a methodical manner.



                       Data to be gathered

                              The data in this study consisted of the perception of the CvSU-TC students and

                       faculty  members.  A  two-set  of  questionnaires  was  provided  to  determine  the


                       perception of the CvSU-TC students and faculty members. The questionnaire was a

                       combination  of  researcher-made  and  adapted  questionnaire  and  was  constructed

                       based  on  the  functionalities  available  to  the  CvSU-LMS  which  are  objectives,

                       attributes, functions, advantages, and accessibility. Each questionnaire has two parts

                       for  both  the  students  and  the  faculty  members;  the  first  part  for  the  student's


                       questionnaire  was  their  demographical  information  including  age,  sex,  program,

                       academic level, commonly used gadget, type of internet connection and the frequency

                       of their CvSU-LMS usage, while the first part for the faculty's questionnaire was their

                       age, sex, department, experience, educational attainment, commonly used gadget,

                       type of internet connection and the frequency of their CvSU-LMS usage. The second

                       part for both student and faculty members' questionnaire include their perception on

                       the use of the CvSU - LMS.]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[16




                       Statistical Treatment of Data

                            Prior to actual data gathering, the developed questionnaire was administered to

                       thirty (30) respondents, who were not included in the study, to determine its internal


                       consistency  before  it  was  administered  to  the  target  participants.  The  researchers

                       administered  the  questionnaire  to  students  from  other  satellite  campuses  that  had

                       already  used  the  CvSU  LMS.  Cronbach's  Alpha  was  used to  describe  the  internal

                       consistency of the entire questionnaire.




                       Validation of Research Instruments

                            The researchers sent the initial instruments with validation rating scale to three

                       (3) experts from different fields of expertise through email to assess its validity. One is

                       from  the  Department  of  Information  Technology,  one  from  the  Department  of

                       Management and one from the Teacher Education Department. The total of items of

                       initial instruments for both faculty members and students were 32. Minor revisions of

                       grammar and terminologies undergone, ending the instrument for faculty with 31 items


                       while the instrument for students remains with 32 items.]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[17


                       Reliability of the Research Instruments

                              Before  the  implementation  of  the  data  gathering,  the  questionnaire  was

                       administered to 30 respondents, who are not included in the study, to determine its

                       internal  consistency  before  it  was  administered  to  the  target  participants.  It  was


                       administered  through  Google  Form  and  computed  using  the  IBM  SPSS  Statistics

                       version 28. Results were presented below.

                              Table  1  presents  the  internal  consistency  using  Cronbach's  Alpha.  The

                       minimum acceptable requirement of Cronbach’s Alpha should be greater than or equal

                       to 0.70. The Cronbach’s Alpha result of the 32 questions is more than 0.70; therefore,


                       the questionnaires reached the basic threshold for reliability and have an acceptable

                       internal consistency.



                       Table 1. Cronbach’s Alpha of the questionnaire

                                                      Cronbach’s Alpha Based
                            Cronbach’s Alpha                                               N of items
                                                       on Standardized Items

                                   0.974                        0.974                          32]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[18


                                                  RESULT AND DISCUSSION

                            This chapter presents the findings of the data as a result of the survey being

                       conducted.

                       CvSU – Tanza Campus Students’ Profile


                            There are 181 students who were able to answer the survey questionnaire and

                       has turn-over rate of 63.73% out of the 284 targets set to conduct the survey.  Below

                       shows the respondents according to their age, sex, program, year level, commonly

                       used gadget, and type of internet connection:



                                                       3%  3% 1%
                                              12%











                                                                               81%



                                                 18-22  23-27  28-32   33-37  43-60

                                Figure 2. Distribution of respondents based on student’s age group




                              According to figure 2, most of the respondents are from the age group 18 – 22

                       and covers 81% of all the respondents. The age groups 23 – 27, 28 – 32, 33 – 37, and

                       43 – 60 was able to cover the 12%, 3%, 3%, and 1% of the respondents, respectively.]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[19





                                                 27%










                                                                                      73%



                                                              Male   Female

                                   Figure 3. Distribution of respondents based on student’s sex




                            Figure 3 shows that most of the respondents are male students who has turn-

                       over rate of 73% while the female students have a turn-over rate of 27%.


                                                        10%           5%

                                             11%
                                                                                       25%
                                        6%




                                        6%

                                                                                        11%


                                                       26%



                                Bachelor of Elementary Education     Bachelor of Science in Business Management
                                Bachelor of Science in Hospitality Management  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                Bachelor of Science in Psychology    Bachelor of Science in Tourism Management
                                Bachelor of Secondary Education - English  Bachelor of Secondary Education - Mathematics

                                Figure 4. Distribution of respondents based on student’s program



                              Figure  4  shows  that  most  of  the  repospondents  are  from  the  Bachelor  of

                       Science  in  Information  Technology  program  which  has  a  turn-over  rate  of  26%

                       ,followed by Bachelor of Science in Business Management that has a turnover rate of

                       25%. It was then followed by the Bachelor of Science in Hospitality Management and]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[20


                       Bachelor  of  Secondary  Education  –  English  which  has  both  11%,  Bachelor  of

                       Secondary Education – Mathematics that has 10%, Bachelor of Science in Tourism

                       Management and Bachelor of Science in Psychology that both has 6% and Bachelor

                       of Elementary Education that has 5%.






                                                    14%

                                                                                     38%




                                      23%






                                                             25%


                                            First Year  Second Year  Third Year  Fourth Year

                                Figure 5. Distribution of respondents based on student’s year level




                            Figure 5 shows that most of the repospondents are from the First Year which

                       has a total of 38% respondents. It was followed by Second Year level with 25% rate,

                       Third Year level which has 23% rate and Fourth Year level which has 14% rate.




                                                           5%   1%          16%















                                                     78%

                                             Laptop   Mobile Phone  Personal Computer  Tablet

                         Figure 6. Distribution of respondents based on student’s commonly used gadgets]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[21


                            Figure 6 shows that most of the respondents are using of Mobile Phone with 78%

                       usage rate. It was then followed by Laptop which has 16%, Personal Computer which

                       has 5% and Tablet which has 1% usage rate.





                                                                                      30%










                                         70%






                                                              Data  Wired

                        Figure 7. Distribution of respondents based on student’s type of internet connection




                            Figure 7 presents the distribution of the respondents based on the type of their

                       internet connection. Most of the respondents were using wired connection which has

                       70% usage rate while data connection has 30% usage rate.




                       CvSU – Tanza Campus Faculty’s Profile

                              There  are  14  faculty  members  who  were  able  to  answer  the  survey

                       questionnaire and has turn-over rate of 38.89% out of the 36 targets set to conduct the

                       survey.  Below shows the respondents according to their age, sex, department, highest

                       educational attainment, years of teaching experience, commonly used gadgets, and

                       type of internet connection.]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[22




                                                     14%


                                        14%







                                                                                       72%





                                                         22 - 32  33 - 43  44 - 60

                                   Figure 8. Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s age




                            Figure 8 presents that most of the faculty participants are from the age group 22

                       - 32 and has 72% of the total respondents. Age groups 33 - 43 and 44 - 60 has both

                       14% of respondents.









                                                                                      36%








                                    64%




                                                              Male   Female

                                   Figure 9. Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s sex



                            Figure 9 presents that the majority of the of the faculty respondents are female

                       with a 64% while male faculty respondents with 36%.]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[23





                                                                                21%


                                   43%



                                                                                           7%







                                                                              29%




                                       Department of Arts and Sciences  Department of Management
                                       Information Technology Department  Teacher Education Department

                               Figure 10. Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s department





                              Figure 10 present that most of the participants are from the Teacher Education

                       Department  with  43%r  response  rate.  It  was  followed  by  Information  Technology

                       Department with 29%, Department of Arts and Sciences with 21% and Department of


                       Management with 7% response rate.






                                                  14%
                                                                                    29%











                                     43%                                                14%








                                  Bachelor's Degree  Graduate Degree  Master units earner  PhD Unit earner

                                   Figure 11. Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s age]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[24




                            Figure 11 represent that most of the respondents are master’s unit earners with

                       43%  response  rate.    This  has  been  followed  by  faculty  respondents  who  has  a

                       bachelor’s degree with 29% response rate, and master’s degree holder and PhD unit


                       earners with 14% response rate for both.


                                                    14%



                                                                                          43%








                                         43%






                                              1 year to 3 years  6 years or more  Less than a year

                            Figure 12. Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s years of teaching

                                                           experience



                            Figure 12 present that most of the respondents is from the group 1 year to 3

                       years and 6 years or more with 43% response rate for each followed by the less than


                       a year of teaching experience group with 14% response rate.]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[25



                                                     11%




                                    25%






                                                                                          64%








                                                Laptop   Mobile Phone  Personal Computer

                        Figure 13. Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s commonly used gadgets



                            Figure 13 present that most of the faculty respondents are using laptop with 64%

                       response rate. This is followed by Mobile Phone users with 25% response rate and

                       Personal Computer with 11% response rate.





                                                                                   28%











                                      72%







                                                            Data   Wired

                       Figure 14. Distribution of respondents based on faculty’s type of internet connection



                            Figure 14 presents the distribution of the faculty respondents based on the type

                       of their internet connection. Most of the faculty respondents were using wired type of

                       internet connection which has 72% rate while 28% usage rate.]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[26


                        Table 2. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Objective
                                                     SYSTEM OBJECTIVE
                                                      Weighted Mean (    ̅ )         Interpretation
                        1.     The CvSU LMS
                        provides additional                  4.1602                    Very Good
                        learning resources related
                        to courses.
                        2.     The CvSU LMS
                        provides greater                     4.0442                    Very Good
                        information.
                        3.     The CvSU LMS
                        helps me learn at the                4.1050                    Very Good
                        comfort of my home.
                        4.     The CvSU LMS is
                        accessible in different              4.4530                    Excellent
                        platforms.
                        5.     The CvSU LMS can
                        be accessed at all times.            3.8398                    Very Good
                        6.     The CvSU LMS
                        helps me develop self-               4.0718                    Very Good
                        learning.
                        7.     The CvSU LMS
                        allows me to receive
                        direct feedback from my              3.9945                    Very Good
                        quizzes, activities and
                        exams.
                               OVERALL                       4.0955                   Very Good


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Objective

                            Table 2 presents the responses of the students on their perception of the use of

                       the CvSU LMS based on the system objective. Results show that the weighted mean


                       ranges  from  3.8398  to  4.4530.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item

                       number 4 with an excellent remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at

                       item  number  5  with  a  very  good  remark.  The  calculated  mean  was  4.0955,  which

                       means that the student's perception towards the use of CvSU LMS in terms of system

                       objectives is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[27


                        Table 3. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Functions
                                                     SYSTEM FUNCTIONS
                                                      Weighted Mean (    ̅ )         Interpretation
                        1.     The CvSU LMS
                        provides interaction tools
                        such as announcements,               4.2320                    Excellent
                        timetables, calendar and
                        user guide.
                        2.     The CVSU LMS’s
                        content and resources
                        are available to all                 4.3039                    Excellent
                        students enrolled to a
                        specific course.
                        3.      The CvSU LMS has
                        comment sections where
                        students can receive
                        direct feedback from the             4.0552                    Very Good
                        instructor and ask them
                        questions at the same
                        time.
                               OVERALL                       4.1970                   Very Good


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Function

                            Table 3 presents the responses of the students on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU  LMS  based  on the  system  functions.  Results  show that  the  weighted mean

                       ranges  from  4.0552  to  4.3039.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item

                       number 2 with an excellent remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at

                       item number 3 with a very good remark. The calculated mean was 4.1970 which means


                       that  the  student's  perception  towards  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS  in  terms  of  system

                       functions is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[28


                        Table 4. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Attributes
                                                    SYSTEM ATTRIBUTES
                                                      Weighted Mean (    ̅ )         Interpretation
                        1.     The CvSU LMS can
                        be integrated in other               4.2873                    Excellent
                        LMS like Moodle.
                        2.     The CvSU LMS
                        provides notification for
                        new uploaded learning                3.7901                    Very Good
                        materials before it is
                        explained.
                        3.     The CvSU LMS
                        provides notification on             3.7238                    Very Good
                        activities I haven’t
                        submitted yet.
                        4.     The CvSU LMS
                        provides notification on             3.8674                    Very Good
                        activities on due.
                        5.     The CvSU LMS
                        provides additional skills           3.9337                    Very Good
                        related to ICT.
                        6.      The CvSU-LMS can
                        be tailored to fit my                3.9282                    Very Good
                        learning styles.
                               OVERALL                       3.9218                   Very Good


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Attributes

                            Table 4 presents the responses of the students on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU LMS based on the system attributes. Results show that the weighted mean

                       ranges  from  3.7238  to  4.2873.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item


                       number 1 with an excellent remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at

                       item number 3 with a very good remark. The calculated mean was 3.9218 which means

                       that  the  student's  perception  towards  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS  in  terms  of  system

                       attributes is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[29


                        Table 5. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Accessibility
                                                   SYSTEM ACCESSIBILITY
                                                      Weighted Mean (    ̅ )         Interpretation
                        1.     The CvSU LMS has
                        an easy and well-design              4.0166                    Very Good
                        log-in interface.
                        2.     The CvSU LMS
                        provides access that suits           4.0110                    Very Good
                        to my needs.
                        3.     The CvSU LMS
                        menus (buttons) are                  4.0773                    Very Good
                        easily recognized
                        4.      The CvSU LMS has
                        a built-in communication             4.0000                    Very Good
                        tool to facilitate
                        knowledge sharing.
                        5.     The CvSU-LMS lets
                        me easily upload my                  4.1934                    Very Good
                        activities.
                        6.     The CvSU LMS has
                        an assigned contact
                        person for any technical             3.8453                    Very Good
                        issues that might be
                        encountered.
                        7.     The CvSU LMS can
                        be accessed in different
                        devices such as Mobile               4.0166                    Very Good
                        Phone, Tablet, Laptop,
                        etc.
                               OVERALL                       4.0229                   Very Good


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Accessibility

                            Table 5 presents the responses of the students on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU LMS based on the system accessibility. Results show that the weighted mean

                       ranges  from  3.8453  to  4.1934.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item


                       number 5 with a very good remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at

                       item number 6 with a very good remark as well. The calculated mean was 4.0229 which

                       means that the student's perception towards the use of CvSU LMS in terms of system

                       accessibility is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[30


                        Table 6. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Advantages
                                                    SYSTEM ADVANTAGES
                                                       Weighted Mean (    ̅ )        Interpretation
                        1.     The CvSU LMS
                        software increases                    3.8950                   Very Good
                        interaction between teacher
                        and learner.
                        2.     The CvSU LMS
                        makes me feel in control of           3.9613                   Very Good
                        my learning.
                        3.     The CvSU LMS
                        increases my enthusiasm               3.8729                   Very Good
                        in learning.
                        4.     The CvSU LMS saves
                        my time in terms of                   3.9227                   Very Good
                        learning.
                        5.     The CvSU LMS has a
                        built-in plagiarism checker.          3.5801                   Very Good
                        6.     The CvSU LMS
                        increases the quality of my           3.9006                   Very Good
                        teaching.
                        7.     The CvSU LMS’s
                        documents and credentials             4.1602                   Very Good
                        are secured in its database.
                        8.     The CvSU LMS allows
                        me to submit documents in
                        different formats with no             3.7072                   Very Good
                        limit in file size.
                        9.     The CvSU LMS’s
                        assessments such as
                        quizzes have no time                  3.5359                   Very Good
                        restriction and the allowed
                        attempts to answer are
                        unlimited.
                                OVERALL                       3.8373                  Very Good


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Advantages

                            Table 6 presents the responses of the students on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU LMS based on the system advantages. Results show that the weighted mean

                       ranges  from  3.5359  to  4.1602.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item


                       number 7 with a very good remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at

                       item number 9 with a very good remark as well. The calculated mean was 4.0229 which

                       means that the student's perception towards the use of CvSU LMS in terms of system

                       advantages is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[31


                        Table 7. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Objective
                                                     SYSTEM OBJECTIVE
                                                      Weighted Mean (    ̅ )         Interpretation
                        1.  The CvSU LMS can
                           be accessed at all                3.7857                    Very Good
                           times.
                        2.  The CvSU LMS is
                           accessible in different           4.0000                    Very Good
                           platforms.
                        3.  The CvSU LMS helps
                           my students develop               3.7143                    Very Good
                           self-learning.
                        4.  The CvSU LMS
                           makes it easier to
                           assess and give
                           feedback in quizzes,              3.5714                    Very Good
                           outputs, exams and
                           as such.
                        5.  The CvSU LMS helps
                           me teach virtually in
                           the comfort of my                 3.6429                    Very Good
                           home.
                                 OVERALL                     3.7429                   Very Good


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Objective

                            Table 7 presents the responses of the faculty on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU  LMS  based  on  the  system  objective.  Results  show  that  the  weighted  mean

                       ranges  from  3.5714  to  4.000.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item

                       number 4 with a very good remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at


                       item number 2 with a very good remark as well. The calculated mean was 3.7429 which

                       means that the faculty’s perception towards the use of CvSU LMS in terms of system

                       objective is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[32


                        Table 8. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Functions
                                                     SYSTEM FUNCTIONS
                                                      Weighted Mean (    ̅ )         Interpretation
                        1.  The CvSU LMS
                           provides interaction
                           tools such as
                           announcements,                    3.7857                    Very Good
                           timetables, calendar
                           and user guide.
                        2.  The CVSU LMS’s
                           content and resources
                           are available to all              4.2143                    Excellent
                           students enrolled to a
                           specific course.
                        3.  The CvSU LMS has
                           comments section.                 4.2143                    Excellent
                                 OVERALL                     4.0714                   Very Good


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Functions


                            Table 8 presents the responses of the faculty on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU  LMS  based  on the  system  functions.  Results  show that  the  weighted mean

                       ranges from 3.7857 to 4.2143. The highest weighted mean was observed at items

                       number  2  and  3  with  an  excellent  remark,  while  the  lowest  weighted  mean  was

                       observed at item number 1 with a very good remark. The calculated mean was 4.0714

                       which means that the faculty’s perception towards the use of CvSU LMS in terms of

                       system functions is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[33


                        Table 9. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Attributes
                                                    SYSTEM ATTRIBUTES
                                                      Weighted Mean (    ̅ )         Interpretation
                        1.  The CvSU LMS can
                           be integrated in other            4.0000                    Very Good
                           LMS (e.g., Moodle).
                        2.  The CvSU LMS
                           provide notification
                           every time students               3.7857                    Very Good
                           submit a task or
                           activity.
                        3.  The CvSU LMS
                           provides notification             3.9286                    Very Good
                           about the status of the
                           activities.
                        4.  The CvSU LMS
                           provide additional                4.2857                    Excellent
                           skills related to ICT.
                        5.  The CvSU LMS can
                           be tailored to fit my
                           student’s learning                3.5000                    Very Good
                           style.
                                 OVERALL                     3.9000                   Very Good


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Attributes

                            Table 9 presents the responses of the faculty on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU LMS based on the system attributes. Results show that the weighted mean

                       ranges  from  3.5000  to  4.2857.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item

                       number 4 with an excellent remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at


                       item number 5 with a very good remark. The calculated mean was 3.9000 which means

                       that the faculty’s perception towards the use of CvSU LMS in terms of system attributes

                       is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[34


                        Table 10. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Accessibility
                                                   SYSTEM ACCESSIBILITY
                                                      Weighted Mean (     ̅)         Interpretation
                        1.  The CvSU-LMS has
                           an easy and well-                 3.9286                    Very Good
                           design log-in
                           interface.
                        2.  The CvSU-LMS
                           provides access that              3.7857                    Very Good
                           suits to my needs.
                        3.  The CvSU-LMS
                           menus (buttons) are               3.7143                    Very Good
                           easily recognized
                        4.  The CvSU-LMS has a
                           built-in
                           communication tool to             3.5000                    Very Good
                           facilitate knowledge
                           sharing.
                        5.  The CvSU-LMS lets
                           me easily upload my               4.0000                    Very Good
                           modules.
                        6.  The CvSU LMS has
                           an assigned contact
                           person for any                    3.9286                    Very Good
                           technical issues that
                           might be
                           encountered.
                        7.  The CvSU LMS can
                           be accessed in
                           different devices such            4.0714                    Very Good
                           as Mobile Phone,
                           Tablet, Laptop, etc.
                                 OVERALL                     3.8469                   Very Good


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Accessibility

                            Table 10 presents the responses of the faculty on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU LMS based on the system accessibility. Results show that the weighted mean

                       ranges  from  3.5000  to  4.0714.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item

                       number 7 with a very good remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at


                       item number 4 with a very good remark as well. The calculated mean was 3.8469 which

                       means that the faculty’s perception towards the use of CvSU LMS in terms of system

                       accessibility is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[35


                        Table 11. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Advantages
                                                    SYSTEM ADVANTAGES
                                                                           Weighted       Interpretation
                                                                           Mean (    ̅ )
                        1.  The CvSU LMS software increases                  3.5714         Very Good
                           interaction between teacher and learner.
                        2.  The CvSU LMS makes me feel in control of         3.7143         Very Good
                           my pedagogy.
                        3.  The CvSU LMS increases my enthusiasm in
                           teaching.                                         3.7857         Very Good
                        4.  The CvSU LMS saves my time in terms of           3.6429         Very Good
                           teaching.
                        5.  The CvSU LMS have available system
                           generated quizzes related to my teaching          3.4286         Very Good
                           courses.
                        6.  The CvSU LMS generates progress reports
                           for students based on the results of their        3.6429         Very Good
                           activities, quizzes, and examinations.
                        7.  The CvSU LMS has a built-in plagiarism           3.0000            Good
                           checker.
                        8.  The CvSU LMS increases the quality of my         3.6429         Very Good
                           teaching.
                        9.  The CvSU LMS’s documents and
                           credentials are secured in its database.          3.8571         Very Good
                        10. The CvSU LMS allows me to upload
                           instructional resources in a variety of file      4.1429         Very Good
                           formats. (e.g., in PDF, docx, pptx, etc.)
                        11. The CvSU LMS allows me to modify the
                           time limit and number of allowed attempts         3.7857         Very Good
                           for my quizzes, activities and examination.
                                            OVERALL                          3.6559         Very Good



                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS Advantages

                            Table 11 presents the responses of the faculty on their perception on the use of

                       CvSU LMS based on the system advantages. Results show that the weighted mean

                       ranges  from  3.0000  to  4.1429.  The  highest  weighted  mean  was  observed  at  item

                       number 10 with a very good remark, while the lowest weighted mean was observed at

                       item number 7 with a good remark. The calculated mean was 3.6559 which means


                       that  the  faculty’s  perception  towards  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS  in  terms  of  system

                       advantages is very good and positive.]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[36


                       Table 12. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Age Mean Value

                         Age Mean      Objective  Functions  Attributes  Accessibility  Advantages

                           18 - 22       4.0169      4.1806       3.8671        3.9769         3.8087

                           23 - 27       4.2473      4.1673       3.9923        4.1286         3.9186

                           28 - 32       4.6917      4.2767       4.3350        4.5000         4.0183

                           33 - 37       4.5000      4.5000       4.5833        4.5550         4.1300

                           38 - 42       4.6400      4.1700       4.5833        2.7500         3.0000

                           43 and        5.0000      5.0000       5.0000        5.0000         5.0000
                           above

                         OVERALL         4.0956      4.1972       3.9219        4.0239         3.8373



                        Table 13. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Age (ANOVA)
                                                               Sum of             Mean
                         Uses of LMS            Group                      df                F      Sig.
                                                               Squares           Square
                                         Between Groups         5.9220      5     1.184
                          Objectives     Within Groups         87.6150     175     .501    2.366  0.042
                                                Total          93.5370     180
                                         Between Groups         1.2930      5      .259
                          Functions      Within Groups         101.8660  175       .582    0.444  0.817
                                                Total          103.1590  180
                                         Between Groups         6.0420      5     1.208
                          Attributes     Within Groups         118.1880  175       .675    1.789  0.117
                                                Total          124.2300  180
                                         Between Groups         7.8110      5     1.562
                         Accessibility   Within Groups         99.1210     175     .566    2.758  0.020
                                                Total          106.9320  180
                                         Between Groups         3.7280      5      .746
                         Advantages      Within Groups         111.8760  175       .639    1.166  0.328
                                                Total          115.6040  180


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Age

                            Table 13 presents the perception of the students on the use of CvSU LMS in

                       terms  of  their  age  using  ANOVA.  According  to  the  results,  there  is  a  significant

                       difference among the different age groups on objective (F = 2.366, p = 0.042) and

                       accessibility (F = 2.758, p = 0.020). Table 12 shows that the students from the age


                       group 43 and above (5.00) have a better perception among the other age groups for]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[37


                       both objective and accessibility. The functions have a t-value 0.444 with p-value > 5%,

                       attributes have a t-value 1.789 with p-value > 5%, and advantages have t-value 1.166

                       with p-value > 5%, therefore, it can be concluded that there is no significant difference

                       between the students’ perception according to age on the use of the CvSU LMS in


                       terms of functions, attributes, and advantages but have significant difference in terms

                       of objectives and accessibility.



                        Table 14. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Sex (T-Test)

                         Uses of LMS       Group       Mean       Std. Dev      t- value   Significance

                                            Male      4.1750       0.67110
                          Objective                                              2.502         0.013
                                          Female      3.8756       0.81118

                                            Male      4.2959       0.69858
                          Functions                                              2.983         0.003
                                          Female      3.9237       0.84874
                                            Male      3.9939       0.79738
                          Attributes                                             1.955         0.052
                                          Female      3.7225       0.89568
                                            Male      4.0992       0.71402
                         Accessibility                                           2.210         0.028
                                          Female      3.8154       0.88481
                                            Male      3.8953       0.73022
                         Advantages                                              1.629         0.100
                                          Female      3.6765       0.96238


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Sex

                              Table 14 presents the perception of the students on the use of CvSU LMS

                       according  to  their  sex  using  T-Test.  According  to  the results, there  is  a  significant

                       difference among male and female on objective (t = 2.502, p = 0.013), functions (t =


                       2.983, p = 0.003) and accessibility (t = 2.210, p = 0.028), The male group (4.20, 4.30,

                       4.10, 3.90) has a higher perception among female group (3.90, 3.90, 3.80, 3.70) in

                       terms of objective, functions, accessibility, and advantages, respectively. The results

                       also show the t-value of attributes is 1.955 while the advantages is 1.629 with p-value

                       > 5%, therefore, it can be concluded that there is no significant difference between the

                       male and female’s perception on the use of the CvSU LMS in terms of attributes and

                       advantages.]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[38


                        Table 15. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Program Mean Value
                         Program     Objective    Functions  Attributes  Accessibility  Advantages
                          Mean
                           BEE         4.3800       4.3311       3.9067         4.2422         3.8889

                          BSBM         4.3915       4.3917       4.0800         4.1878         4.1378
                          BSHM         3.8150       3.7170       3.7585         3.8425         3.7270
                           BSIT        3.8911       4.0068       3.7945         3.8683         3.7423
                           BSP         3.8570       4.1670       4.0010         4.1670         3.9560

                          BSTM         4.0118       4.1209       3.7736         3.7891         3.5555
                          BSEE         3.9855       4.4675       3.8590         3.9585         3.5560
                          BSEM         4.3489       4.4267       4.1567         4.2406         3.8583

                        OVERALL        4.0956       4.1972       3.9219         4.0239         3.8373


                        Table 16. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Program (ANOVA)
                                                              Sum of             Mean
                        Uses of LMS           Group                       df                F      Sig.
                                                             Squares            Square
                                       Between Groups          10.34      7      1.477
                           Objective   Within Groups           83.20     173     0.481    3.072    0.004

                                       Total                   93.54     180
                                       Between Groups          10.70      7      1.529

                           Functions   Within Groups           92.46     173     0.534    2.860    0.008

                                       Total                  103.16     180
                                       Between Groups           3.82      7      0.546
                           Attributes   Within Groups         120.41     173     0.696    0.785    0.601

                                       Total                  124.23     180
                                       Between Groups           5.20      7      0.743
                        Accessibility  Within Groups          101.73     173     0.588    1.264    0.271


                                       Total                  106.93     180
                                       Between Groups           7.18      7      1.026
                        Advantages  Within Groups             108.43     173     0.627    1.636    0.128

                                       Total                  115.60     180


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Program

                            Table  16  presents  the  perception  of  the  students  on  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS

                       according to their program using ANOVA. According to the results, there is a significant


                       difference among programs on objective (t = 3.072, p = 0.004) and functions (t = 2.860,

                       p = 0.008). Table 15 shows that the BSBM program (4.39) has a higher perception

                       among other programs according to objective while the BSE-E program (4.47) has a

                       higher perception among other programs according to functions. The attributes have]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[39


                       a t-value 0.785 with p-value > 5%, accessibility have a t-value of 1.264 with p-value >

                       5%, and advantages have a t-value of 1.636 with p-value > 5%, therefore, it can be

                       concluded  that  there  is  no  significant  differences  among  the  students’  perception

                       across programs on the use of the CvSU LMS in terms of attributes, accessibility, and


                       advantages, respectively.



                        Table 17. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Year Level Mean Value

                          Year Level      Objective    Function    Attribute  Accessibilit   Advantage
                             Mean             s            s           s            y             s

                           First Year       4.1923      4.2475      4.0161       4.0894        3.9127
                         Second Year        3.9804      4.1624      3.8000       3.9744        3.7780
                          Third Year        4.0002      4.1198      3.8421       3.9207        3.7248
                          Fourth Year       4.2900      4.3300      4.0000       4.5000        4.2200
                          OVERALL           4.0956      4.1972      3.9219       4.0239        3.8373



                        Table 18. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Year Level (ANOVA)
                                                               Sum of            Mean
                        Uses of LMS           Group                       df                  F     Sig.
                                                              Squares           Square
                                       Between Groups            1.89     3       0.63
                         Objective     Within Groups            91.65    177      0.52     1.214  0.306
                                               Total            93.54    180
                                       Between Groups            0.56     3       0.19
                         Functions     Within Groups           102.60    177      0.58     0.322  0.810
                                               Total           103.16    180
                                       Between Groups            1.77     3       0.59
                         Attributes    Within Groups           122.46    177      0.69     0.852  0.467
                                               Total           124.23    180
                                       Between Groups            1.18     3       0.39
                        Accessibility  Within Groups           105.75    177      0.60     0.660  0.578

                                               Total           106.93    180
                                       Between Groups            1.37     3       0.46
                        Advantages  Within Groups              114.24    177      0.65     0.705  0.550
                                               Total           115.60    180


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Year Level

                            Table  18  presents  the  perception  of  the  students  on  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS

                       according to their year level using ANOVA. According to the results, the objective have

                       a t-value 1.215 with p-value > 5%,  functions have a t-value of 0.322 with p-value >]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[40


                       5%, attributes have a t-value 0.852 with p-value > 5%, accessibility have a t-value

                       0.660 with p-value > 5% and advantages have a t-value of 0.705 with p-value > 5%,

                       therefore, it can be concluded that there is no significant differences among students’

                       perception  across  year  level  on  the  use  of  the  CvSU  LMS  in  terms  of  objective,


                       functions, attributes, accessibility and advantages, respectively.



                        Table 19. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Commonly Used Gadget Mean
                        Value
                                          Objective   Function    Attribute   Accessibilit   Advantage
                         Gadget Mean
                                              s           s           s             y             s
                            Laptop         4.1257       4.2177      3.9433       4.0626        3.8848
                         Mobile Phone      3.9948       4.1838      3.8917       3.9600        3.6786
                           Personal
                           Computer        3.9430       3.8660      3.6830       3.6830        3.6010
                            Tablet         4.2900       5.0000      4.1700       3.8300        4.1100


                          OVERALL          4.0956       4.1972      3.9219       4.0239        3.8373


                        Table 20. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Commonly Used Gadget
                        (ANOVA)
                                                               Sum of             Mean
                        Uses of LMS            Group                       df                 F     Sig.
                                                              Squares            Square
                                       Between Groups            .693      3      0.231
                         Objective     Within Groups           92.844     177     0.525    0.441  0.724

                                               Total           93.537     180
                                       Between Groups           1.806      3      0.602
                         Functions     Within Groups           101.353    177     0.573    1.051  0.371

                                               Total           103.159    180
                                       Between Groups            .723      3      0.241
                         Attributes    Within Groups           123.507    177     0.698    0.346  0.792

                                               Total           124.230    180
                                       Between Groups           1.530      3      0.510
                        Accessibility  Within Groups           105.402    177     0.595    0.856  0.465

                                               Total           106.932    180
                                       Between Groups           1.680      3      0.560
                        Advantages  Within Groups              113.924    177     0.644    0.870  0.458

                                               Total           115.604    180]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[41


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Commonly Used

                       Gadget

                              Table 20 presents the perception of the students on the use of CvSU LMS

                       according to their commonly used gadgets using ANOVA. According to the results, the


                       objective have a t-value 0.441 with p-value > 5%,  functions have a t-value of 1.051

                       with p-value > 5%, attributes have a t-value 0.346 with p-value > 5%, accessibility have

                       a t-value 0.856 with p-value > 5% and advantages have a t-value of 0.870 with p-value

                       > 5%, therefore, it can be concluded that there is no significant differences among

                       students’ perception across the commonly used gadgets on the use of the CvSU LMS


                       in terms of objective, functions, attributes, accessibility and advantages, respectively.



                        Table 21. Student’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Type of Internet Connection (T-
                        Test)

                         Uses of LMS       Group       Mean       Std. Dev      t- value   Significance

                                            Data      3.9050       0.73033
                          Objective                                              -2.348        0.010
                                           Wired      4.1766       0.70414
                                            Data      4.0370       0.88941
                          Functions                                              -2.013        0.023
                                           Wired      4.3150       0.83286
                                            Data      4.1667       0.88488
                          Attributes                                             -1.453        0.074
                                           Wired      4.3622       0.80346
                                            Data      3.9815       0.99983
                         Accessibility                                           -0.666        0.253
                                           Wired      4.0866       0.95969
                                            Data      4.0617       0.78619
                         Advantages                                              -1.577        0.058
                                           Wired      4.2548       0.73994


                       Student’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to the Type of Internet

                       Connection

                              Table 21 presents the perception of the students on the use of CvSU LMS

                       according to their type of internet connection using T-Test. According to the results,


                       there is a significant difference among data and wired internet connection on objective

                       (t = -2.348, p = 0.010) and functions (t = -2.013, p = 0.023). The students have a higher

                       perception on the use of CvSU LMS using wired internet connection (4.18, 4.32) than]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[42


                       using the data as internet connection (3.90, 4.04) in terms of objective and functions,

                       respectively. The attributes have a t-value -1.453 with p-value > 5%, accessibility have

                       a t-value -0.666 with p-value > 5%, and advantages have a t-value -1.577 with p-value

                       >  5%,  therefore,  it  can  be  concluded  that  there  is  no  significant  difference  among


                       students’ perception across the type of internet connection on the use of the CvSU

                       LMS in terms of attributes, accessibility, and advantages, respectively.



                        Table 22. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Age Mean Value

                        Age Mean  Objectives  Functions  Attributes  Accessibility  Advantages

                         22 – 32        3.76         4.135        3.98          3.899           3.82


                         33 – 43         4.2         4.335         3.6          4.285           3.59

                          44 and
                          above          3.2          3.5          3.8           3.14           2.91

                        OVERALL        3.7429       4.0729         3.9          3.8457         3.6571



                        Table 23. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Age (ANOVA)
                                                           Sum of              Mean
                        Uses of LMS        Group                        df                   F      Sig.
                                                          Squares             Square
                                       Between
                                       Groups               1.01        2       0.51
                         Objective                                                        0.6400  0.547
                                       Within Groups        8.70        11      0.79
                                            Total           9.71        13
                                       Between
                                       Groups               0.83        2       0.42
                         Functions                                                        0.4800  0.634
                                       Within Groups        9.64        11      0.88
                                            Total           10.48       13
                                       Between
                                       Groups               0.26        2       0.13
                         Attributes                                                       0.1900  0.829
                                       Within Groups        7.64        11      0.69
                                            Total           7.90        13
                                       Between              1.41        2       0.71
                                       Groups
                        Accessibility                                                     0.8700  0.447
                                       Within Groups        8.95        11      0.81
                                            Total           10.36       13
                                       Between              1.39        2       0.70
                                       Groups
                        Advantages                                                        1.2800  0.315
                                       Within Groups        5.96        11      0.54
                                            Total           7.35        13]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[43


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Age

                            Table 23 presents the perception of the faculty on the use of CvSU LMS in terms

                       of  their  age  using  ANOVA.  According  to  the  results,  objectives  have  a  F-value  of

                       0.6400 with p-value > 5%, functions have F-value 0.4800 with p-value > 5%, attributes


                       have F-value 0.1900 with p-value > 5%, accessibility have F-value 0.8700 with p-value

                       > 5% and advantages have  F-value 1.2800 with p-value >5%, therefore, it can be

                       concluded  that there  is no  significant  difference  among faculty’s  perception  across

                       ages  on  the  use  of  the  CvSU  LMS  in  terms  of  objective,  functions,  attributes,

                       accessibility and advantages.




                        Table 24. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Sex (T-Test)

                         Uses of LMS        Group        Mean       Std. Dev     t- value   Significance

                                             Male        3.7200     1.06395
                           Objective                                             -0.071        0.945
                                            Female       3.7556      .80485
                                             Male        4.0020      .91196
                           Functions                                             -0.212        0.836
                                            Female       4.1122      .94281
                                             Male        4.2800      .67231
                           Attributes                                             1.410        0.184
                                            Female       3.6889      .78811
                                             Male        4.1420      .77651
                         Accessibility                                            0.920        0.376
                                            Female       3.6811      .95292
                                             Male        4.0020      .90378
                          Advantages                                              1.315        0.213
                                            Female       3.4656      .62798



                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Sex

                              Table  24  presents  the  perception  of  the  faculty  on  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS

                       according  to  their  sex  using  T-Test.  According  to  the  results,  objective,  functions,

                       attributes, accessibility, and advantages has t-value of -0.071 with p-value > 5%, t-

                       value of -0.212 with p-value > 5%, t-value of 1.410 with p-value > 5%, t-value of 0.920

                       with p-value > 5% and t-value of 1.315 with p-value > 5%, respectively. Therefore, it

                       can be concluded that there is no significant difference among faculty’s perception]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[44


                       across  sex  on  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS  in  terms  of  objective,  functions,  attributes,

                       accessibility, and advantages.



                        Table 25. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Department Mean Value
                        Departmen      Objective    Function     Attribute   Accessibilit    Advantage
                          t Mean           s            s            s             y              s

                            DAS         3.0667       3.4467       4.0000        3.6667         3.4567
                            DM          4.0000       3.6700       3.8000        3.7100         3.9100
                            ITD         3.9500       4.0850       3.6000        3.7850         3.7050
                            TED         3.9000       4.4450       4.0667        3.9983         3.6833

                         OVERALL        3.7429       4.0729       3.900         3.8457         3.6571



                        Table 26. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Department (ANOVA)
                                                         Sum of               Mean
                        Uses of LMS        Group                      df                    F      Sig.
                                                         Squares             Square
                                       Between
                                       Groups             1.758        3      0.586
                          Objective    Within             7.957       10      0.796      0.7360    .0554
                                       Groups
                                           Total          9.714       13
                                       Between
                                       Groups             2.170        3      0.723
                          Functions    Within             8.307       10      0.831      0.8710    0.488
                                       Groups
                                           Total          10.477      13
                                       Between             .567        3      0.189
                                       Groups
                          Attributes   Within             7.333       10      0.733      0.2580    0.854
                                       Groups
                                           Total          7.900       13
                                       Between             .269        3      0.090
                                       Groups
                        Accessibility   Within                                           0.0890    0.965
                                       Groups             10.090      10      1.009
                                           Total          10.359      13
                                       Between
                                       Groups              .198        3      0.066
                         Advantages    Within                                            0.0920    0.963
                                       Groups             7.149       10      0.715
                                           Total          7.347       13]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[45


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Department

                            Table 26 presents the perception of the faculty on the use of CvSU LMS in terms

                       of their department using ANOVA. According to the results, objectives have a F-value

                       of  0.7360  with  p-value  >  5%,  functions  have  F-value  0.8710  with  p-value  >  5%,


                       attributes have F-value 0.2580 with p-value > 5%, accessibility have F-value 0.0890

                       with p-value > 5% and advantages have F-value 0.0920 with p-value > 5%, therefore,

                       it can be concluded that there is no significant difference among faculty’s perception

                       across  departments  on the  use  of the  CvSU  LMS  in  terms  of  objective,  functions,

                       attributes, accessibility and advantages.




                        Table 27. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Educational Attainment Mean
                        Value
                        Educational
                         Attainment    Objectives   Functions    Attributes   Accessibility   Advantages
                           Mean
                         Bachelor's      3.8500      3.8350       3.8500        3.7850         3.8200
                          Degree
                        Master unit’s
                           earner        3.7000      4.3350       4.0667        3.9750         3.8200
                         Graduate
                          Degree         3.7000      3.3350       3.8000        3.9250         3.3200
                          PhD Unit       3.7000      4.5000       3.6000        3.5000         3.1800
                           earner
                         OVERALL         3.7429      4.0729       3.9000        3.8457         3.6571



                        Table 28. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Educational Attainment
                        (ANOVA)
                        Uses of           Group          Sum of       df     Mean         F     Sig.
                        LMS                              Squares            Square
                                       Between            0.064        3     0.021
                                       Groups
                          Objective    Within             9.650       10     0.965      0.022  0.995
                                       Groups
                                           Total          9.714       13
                                       Between            2.092        3     0.697
                                       Groups
                         Functions     Within             8.385       10     0.838      0.832  0.506
                                       Groups
                                           Total          10.477      13]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[46


                                       Between            0.377        3     0.126
                                       Groups
                          Attributes   Within             7.523       10     0.752      0.167  0.916
                                       Groups
                                           Total          7.900       13
                                       Between            0.367        3     0.122
                                       Groups
                        Accessibility  Within             9.992       10     0.999      0.122  0.945
                                       Groups
                                           Total          10.359      13
                                       Between            0.948        3     0.316
                                       Groups
                        Advantages     Within             6.399       10     0.640      0.494  0.695
                                       Groups
                                           Total          7.347       13


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Educational
                       Attainment

                            Table 28 presents the perception of the faculty on the use of CvSU LMS in terms

                       of their educational attainment using ANOVA. According to the results, objectives have

                       a F-value of 0.022 with p-value > 5%, functions have F-value 0.832 with p-value > 5%,

                       attributes have F-value 0.167 with p-value > 5%, accessibility have F-value 0.122 with

                       p-value > 5% and advantages have F-value 0.695 with p-value > 5%, therefore, it can

                       be  concluded  that  there  is  no  significant  difference  among  faculty’s  perception


                       according to their educational attainment on the use of the CvSU LMS in terms of

                       objective, functions, attributes, accessibility and advantages.



                        Table 29. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Years of Teaching Experience
                        Mean Value
                        Educational
                         Attainment    Objectives   Functions    Attributes   Accessibility   Advantages
                           Mean
                        Less than a
                            year            -           -            -             -              -
                         1 year to 3     3.3300      3.7800       3.6700        3.4800         3.4400
                           years
                         6 years or      4.0500      4.2900       4.0800        4.1200         3.8200
                           more

                         OVERALL         3.7400      4.0700       3.9000        3.8500         3.6600]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[47


                        Table 30. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Years of Teaching Experience
                        (ANOVA)
                                                           Sum of              Mean
                        Uses of LMS         Group                       df                  F      Sig.
                                                           Squares            Square
                                        Between             1.761       1      1.761
                                        Groups
                          Objective                                                       2.657  0.129
                                        Within Groups       7.953       12     0.663
                                             Total          9.714       13
                                        Between             0.901       1      0.901
                                        Groups
                          Functions                                                       1.128  0.309
                                        Within Groups       9.576       12     0.798
                                             Total          10.477      13
                                        Between             0.572       1      0.572
                                        Groups
                          Attributes                                                      0.936  0.352
                                        Within Groups       7.328       12     0.611
                                             Total          7.900       13
                                        Between             1.443       1      1.443
                                        Groups
                         Accessibility                                                    1.942  0.189
                                        Within Groups       8.916       12     0.743
                                             Total          10.359      13
                                        Between             0.488       1      0.488
                                        Groups
                         Advantages                                                       0.853  0.374
                                        Within Groups       6.860       12     0.572
                                             Total          7.347       13


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Years of Teaching


                       Experience

                            Table 30 presents the perception of the faculty on the use of CvSU LMS in terms

                       of their years of teaching experience using ANOVA. According to the results, objectives

                       have an F-value of 2.657 with p-value > 5%, functions have F-value 1.128 with p-value

                       >  5%,  attributes  have  F-value  0.936  with  p-value  >  5%,  accessibility  have  F-value

                       1.942  with  p-value  >  5%  and  advantages  have  F-value  0.853  with  p-value  >  5%,

                       therefore, it can be concluded that there is no significant difference among faculty’s


                       perception according to their educational attainment on the use of the CvSU LMS in

                       terms of objective, functions, attributes, accessibility and advantages.]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[48


                        Table 31. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Commonly Used Gadget Mean
                        Value
                        Educational
                         Attainment    Objectives   Functions    Attributes   Accessibility   Advantages
                           Mean
                                                     3.9529
                           Laptop        3.4857                   3.6571        3.4671         3.4557

                           Mobile        3.4000      2.6700       3.4000        3.1400         2.6400
                           Phone
                          Personal       4.1000      4.4467       4.2667        4.4050         4.0617
                         Computer
                         OVERALL         3.7429      4.0729       3.9000        3.8457         3.6571



                        Table 32. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Commonly Used Gadget Mean
                        Value
                                                           Sum of              Mean
                        Uses of LMS        Group                        df                  F      Sig.
                                                          Squares             Square
                                        Between             1.346       2      0.673
                                        Groups
                          Objective     Within              8.369       11     0.761      0.884  0.440
                                        Groups
                                            Total           9.714       13
                                        Between             2.907       2      1.454
                                        Groups
                          Functions     Within              7.570       11     0.688      2.112  0.167
                                        Groups
                                            Total          10.477       13
                                        Between             1.470       2      0.735
                                        Groups
                          Attributes    Within              6.430       11     0.585      1.257  0.322
                                        Groups
                                            Total           7.900       13
                                        Between             3.378       2      1.689
                                        Groups
                         Accessibility   Within             6.981       11     0.635      2.661  0.114
                                        Groups
                                            Total          10.359       13
                                        Between             2.300       2      1.150
                                        Groups
                         Advantages     Within              5.047       11     0.459      2.507  0.1270
                                        Groups
                                            Total           7.347       13]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[49


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to Commonly Used
                       Gadget

                            Table 32 presents the perception of the faculty on the use of CvSU LMS in terms

                       of their commonly used gadget using ANOVA. According to the results, objectives have

                       a F-value of 0.884 with p-value > 5%, functions have F-value 2.112 with p-value > 5%,

                       attributes have F-value 0.167 with p-value > 5%, accessibility have F-value 2.661 with


                       p-value > 5% and advantages have F-value 2.507 with p-value > 5%, therefore, it can

                       be  concluded  that  there  is  no  significant  difference  among  faculty’s  perception

                       according to their commonly used gadget on the use of the CvSU LMS in terms of

                       objective, functions, attributes, accessibility and advantages.



                        Table 33. Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Type of Internet Connection (T-
                        Test)

                         Uses of LMS       Group       Mean       Std. Dev      t- value   Significance

                                            Data      3.0000
                          Objective                                              -0.884        0.394
                                           Wired      3.8000       0.87178
                                            Data      4.3300
                          Functions                                              0.287         0.779
                                           Wired      4.0531       0.93120
                                            Data      4.2000
                          Attributes                                             0.386         0.706
                                           Wired      3.8769       0.80638
                                            Data      3.1400
                         Accessibility                                           -0.809        0.434
                                           Wired      3.9000       0.90475
                                            Data      3.1800
                         Advantages                                              -0.644        0.532
                                           Wired      3.6938       0.76930]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[50


                       Faculty’s Perception on the use of CvSU LMS According to the Type of Internet

                       Connection

                              Table  33  presents  the  perception  of  the  faculty  on  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS

                       according to their type of internet connection using T-Test. According to the results,


                       faculties  have  a  higher  perception  on  the  use  of  CvSU  LMS  using  wired  internet

                       connection than using the data as internet connection. The result also shows that there

                       is no significant difference among data and wired internet connection on objective (t =

                       -0.884, p = 0.394), functions (t = 0.287, p = 0.779), attributes (t = 0.386, p = 0.706),

                       accessibility  (t  =  -0.809,  p  =  0.434),  and  advantages  (t  =  -0.644,  p  =  0.532).  The


                       objective, functions, attributes, accessibility, and disadvantages have all p-value > 5%,

                       therefore, it can be concluded that there is no significant difference among faculty’s

                       perception on the type of internet connection across all uses of the CvSU LMS.






                        Table 34. Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Objective

                          Uses of LMS        Group        Mean       Std. Dev    t- value  Significance


                                            Students     4.0956      0.72087
                           Objective                                              1.738        0.042
                                             Faculty     3.7429      0.86444




                              Table 34 presents the perception of both students and faculty on the use of

                       CvSU LMS in terms of the system objective. The mean value for students is 4.0956

                       while the faculty has a mean value of 3.7429. Based on the t-value 1.738 with p-value

                       < 5%, it can be concluded that there is significant difference between the two group's

                       perception on CvSU LMS objective and that students (4.10) have higher perception

                       than the faculty (3.74).]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[51



                        Table 35. Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Function
                          Uses of LMS        Group        Mean       Std. Dev    t- value  Significance


                                            Students     4.2320      0.85717
                            Function                                              0.667        0.253
                                             Faculty     4.0729      0.89773



                              Table 35 presents the perception of both students and faculty on the use of

                       CvSU LMS in terms of the system functions. The student group has a mean value of

                       4.2320 while the faculty group has a mean value of 4.0729. On the t-value 0.667 with

                       p-value > 5%, we can say that there is no significant value between the two group's

                       perceptions on the use of the CvSU LMS functions.






                        Table 36. Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Attributes


                          Uses of LMS        Group        Mean       Std. Dev    t- value  Significance


                                            Students     4.3039      0.83095
                           Attributes                                             1.759        0.040
                                             Faculty      3.900      0.77955



                              Table 36 presents the perception of the students and faculty on the use of

                       CvSU LMS in terms of the system attributes. Mean value for students is 4.3039 while

                       the faculty has a mean value of 3.900. Based on the t-value 1.759 with p-value < 5%,


                       we can conclude that there is a significant difference between the students and the

                       faculty’s perception on CvSU LMS attributes and that students (4.30) have a higher

                       perception than the faculty (3.90).]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[52


                        Table 37. Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Accessibility


                          Uses of LMS        Group        Mean       Std. Dev    t- value  Significance

                                            Students     4.0552      0.97024
                         Accessibility                                            0.783        0.217
                                             Faculty     3.8457      0.89267



                              Table 37 presents the perception of both students and faculty on the use of

                       CvSU LMS in terms of the system functions. The student group has a mean value of

                       4.0552 while the faculty group has a mean value of 3. 8457. On the t-value 0.783 with


                       p-value > 5%, it can be concluded that there is no significant value between the two

                       group's perceptions on the use of the CvSU LMS accessibility.




                        Table 38. Students and Faculty’s Perception on the CvSU LMS Advantages


                          Uses of LMS        Group        Mean       Std. Dev    t- value  Significance


                                            Students     4.1972      0.75704
                          Advantages                                              2.573        0.005
                                             Faculty     3.6571      0.75177



                              Table 38 presents the perception of the students and faculty on the use of

                       CvSU LMS in terms of the system advantages. The mean value for students is 4.1972


                       while the faculty mean value is 3.6571. Based on the t-value 2.573 with p-value < 5%,

                       we can conclude that there is a significant difference between the students and the

                       faculty’s perception on CvSU LMS attributes and that students (4.20) have a higher

                       perception compared to the faculty (3.70).]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[53


                                        SUMMARY, CONCLUSION AND RECOMMENDATIONS



                              This chapter presents the summary of the study, the conclusion drawn, and the

                       recommendations  made  regarding  to  the  perceptions  of  CvSU  Tanza  Campus

                       students  and  faculty  on the  uses  of  Cavite  State  University  Learning  Management

                       System.



                       Summary

                              The study was conducted to determine the perception of both students and


                       faculty  of  Cavite  State  University  Tanza  Campus  on  the  uses  of  the  university’s

                       learning management system.  It specifically aimed to: (1) determine the perceptions

                       of CvSU - TC students and faculty members towards the use of CvSU – LMS; (2)

                       determine if there are differences on perception of students on the use of the CvSU -

                       LMS in learning in terms of age, sex, program, academic level, commonly used gadget,

                       and type of internet connection; (3) determine if there are differences on perception of


                       faculty members on the use of the CvSU - LMS in their teaching according to age, sex,

                       department, experience, educational attainment, commonly used gadget, and type of

                       internet  connection;  and  (4)  identify  the  significant  difference  between  the  overall

                       perception of CvSU - TC students and faculty members towards their use of CvSU -

                       LMS.

                              The descriptive analytical approach was used to determine the perception of


                       CvSU TC Students and Faculty on the use of CvSU LMS. The data were collected

                       using two different instruments constructed by the researchers; (1) is for the students

                       to  determine  their  perception  on  CvSU  LMS  in  learning;  and  (2)  is  for  faculty  to

                       determine their perception on CvSU LMS in teaching. The data were gathered in  from

                       181 students across all programs in CvSU TC and 14 faculty members, respectively.

                              As a result, majority of the respondents from the two groups ages from 18 to

                       32 and were female. Furthermore, majority of the respondents from two groups used]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[54


                       wired  type  of  internet  connection,  and most  students  used  mobile  phones  as their

                       device in accessing the software, and laptop to faculty, respectively.

                              The  results  shows  that both  students  and faculty  members  have  a  positive

                       perception towards the use of CvSU LMS. However, the results also showed that there


                       is a statistically significant differences in the perception of students in terms of age,

                       sex, program, and type of internet connection; and no significant differences in the

                       perception of faculty in terms of all variables.

                              Moreover,  there are significant difference between the overall perception of

                       CvSU - TC students and faculty members towards their use of CvSU – LMS in terms


                       of the systems’ objectives, attributes, and advantages.



                       Conclusion

                            After the series of analyzing the results, the following conclusions were drawn:

                       ◼  Both faculty and students have positive perception towards the use of CvSU LMS


                          in teaching and learning.

                       ◼  Students’  perception  on  CvSU  LMS  in  the  accessibility  in  different  platforms,

                          resources available to the students, integration of the CvSU LMS to other LMS,

                          easy uploading of activities and security of their documents and credentials in all

                          variables received a higher perception rate while availability of the CvSU LMS,

                          comment section on where the students can receive feedback from the instructors,

                          notification of pending activities, technical personnel, and time restriction in taking


                          the quiz received a low perception rate.

                       ◼  Faculty’s perception on CvSU LMS in the assessment and providing feedback,

                          availability  of  the  resources  for  the  students,  providing  additional  ICT  skills,

                          accessibility  of  the  CvSU  using  any  platform,  and  uploading  of  instructional

                          resources  in  a  variety  of  file  formats  received  a  higher  perception  rate  while


                          accessibility  in  different  platforms,  availability  of  interaction  tool  such  as

                          announcement board, adapting student’s learning style, built-in communication in]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[55


                          knowledge-sharing  facilitating,  and  built-in  plagiarism  checker  received  a  low

                          perception rate.

                       ◼  Students’ perception on the use of CvSU LMS do not change regardless of their

                          year  level  and  commonly  used  gadget,  however,  there  are  changes  in  the


                          perception  of  the  students  in  terms  of  age  (objective  and  accessibility),  sex

                          (objective, functions, and accessibility), program (objective and functions) and type

                          of internet connection (objective and functions).

                       ◼  Faculty’s perception on the use of CvSU LMS do not change regardless of their

                          age,  sex,  department,  highest  educational  attainment,  years  of  teaching


                          experience, commonly used gadget, and type of internet connection.

                       ◼  Students’  and  Faculty’s  perception  changes  according  to  the  CvSU  LMS’s

                          objective, attributes, and advantages where students have a higher perception rate

                          compared to faculty.



                       Recommendations

                            In the light of the results of the study, the following recommendations are hereby


                       made:

                       ◼  The  need  for  more  research  on  the  challenges  and  difficulties  experienced  by

                          university  students  and  faculty  members  while  utilizing  the  software  Learning

                          Management  System  in  learning  and  teaching,  as  well  as  solutions  to  such

                          problems;


                       ◼  The required technical assistance is required to discover answers to problems that

                          may arise when using the Learning Management System and to benefit from all

                          the capabilities provided by Learning Management System software.

                       ◼  Developers  of  the  CvSU  LMS  should  consult  the  faculty  members  on  which

                          functionalities of the LMS they wanted to incorporate for better user experience.

                       ◼  Developers of the CvSU LMS should also ask the students on the functionalities

                          that they might find useful in their learning to maximize the full potential of the LMS.]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[56


                                                         REFERENCES



                       Acharya, A. S., Prakash, A., Saxena, P., & Nigam, A. (2013). Sampling: Why and

                              how of it. Indian Journal of Medical Specialties, 4(2), 330-333.


                       Al-Khalifa, H. S. (2010). E-learning in Saudi Arabia. In U. Demiray (Ed.). E-learning

                              practices (Vol. 2). Eskisehir-Turkey: Anadolu University

                       Alblassi, R. (2016). Trends faculty members at the University of Hail towards the use

                              of  learning  management  system  –  Learning  Management  System,  Saudi

                              Journal of Arab Studies in Education and Psychology. 69, 103-120.


                       Aljarrah, Abdelmuhdi. (2011). University of Jordan Students’ Attitudes Towards the

                              use of the Learning Management System as a learning tool. Dirasat Journal,

                              educational sciences. 38(4). 1293 – 1304.

                       Alshorman, B. A. & Bawahen, A. K. (2018). Attitudes of Faculty Members and

                              Students towards the Use of the Learning Management System in Teaching

                              and Learning. Turkish Online Journal of Educational Technology - TOJET, v17

                              n3         p1-15          July         2018.         Retrieved         from


                              http://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/EJ1184192.pdf

                       Brown, A., & Johnson, J. (2007). Five Advantages of Using a Learning Management

                              System. Microburst learning

                       Importance and Objectives of a Learning Management System. (2021). Retrieved

                              from Importance and objectives of a learning management system | Easy LMS


                              (easy-lms.com)

                       Ippakayala, V.K. & El-Ocla, H. (2017). OLMS: Online learning management system

                              for e-    learning. World Journal on Educational Technology: Current Issues.

                              9(3), 130-138

                       Mohd Kasim, N. N., Kasim, N. N. M., & Khalid, F. (2016). Choosing the Right]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[57


                              Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  for  the  Higher  Education  Institution

                              Context: A Systematic Review. International Journal of Emerging Technologies

                              in Learning (IJET), 11(06), 55. https://doi.org/10.3991/IJET.V11I06.5644

                       Nayak, M. K., & Suesaowaluk, P. (2007, November). Advantages and disadvantages


                              of  eLearning  management  system.  In Fourth  International  Conference  on

                              eLearning for Knowledge-Based Society (pp. 1-7).

                       Pappas, Christian & Panagiotis, Zaharias (2018, May 18). 7 LMS Accessibility Issues

                              That Prompt Organizations to Replace Their Current Systems. Retrieved from

                              7  LMS  Accessibility  Issues  That  Prompt  Organizations  To  Replace  Their


                              Current Systems (elearningindustry.com)

                       Pirani, Zainab & Mukundan, Sasikumar. (2014). Accessibility Issues in Learning

                              Management Systems for Learning Disabled: A Survey. 10.1007/978-3-319-

                              01778-5_26.

                       Roque, G., Chamovitz, I., Araujo, J., Gouvea, M., Cardoso, R., Azambuja, S., &
                               Moura, S. (2004). Aspectos relevantes para o desenvolvimento de ambientes

                              educacionais  para  a  web In:  Proccedings  of  CISCI,  3rd  Conferência
                              Iberoamericana en Sistemas, Cibernética e Informática. Miami, United States.

                       Trayek, Fuad & HASSAN, Sharifah. (2013). Attitude towards the use of learning

                              management system among university students: A case study. Turkish Online

                              Journal of Distance   Education. 14. 91-103.)

                       Williams, D. (2018). 3 LMS Features to Promote Communication Between

                              Instructors  and  Learners.  Retrieved  from  https://www.topyx.com/lms-blog/3-


                              lms-features-that-promote-communication-with-learners

                       What is an LMS? The Basics of Learning Management Systems. (2019, March 25).

                              Retrieved  from  What  is  a  Learning  Management  System  (LMS)?  |  eThink

                              (ethinkeducation.com)

                       8 Objectives of a Learning Management System in imparting education. (2018, May

                              8). Retrieved from 8 Objectives of a Learning Management System in Imparting

                              education | Qafie LMS – Blog (wordpress.com)]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[58




























                                                         APPENDICES]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[59


                       Appendix 1. Research instrument for students’ respondents]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[60


                       Appendix 1. Continued]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[61


                       Appendix 1. Continued]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[62


                       Appendix 2. Research instrument for faculty’s respondents]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[63


                       Appendix 2. Continued]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[64


                       Appendix 2. Continued]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[65


                       Appendix 3. Letter of Request]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[66


                       Appendix 4. Letter of Request]]></page></pages></Search>
