<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="16"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.4.            The Dean, the faculty and the


                        administration work together for the


                        improvement of the College of Teacher

                        Education, particularly in:


                        I.4.7.   preparing guidelines in the


                                       proper use and maintenance of

                                       facilities, equipment, supplies


                                       and materials, etc.]]></page><page Index="2"/><page Index="3"><![CDATA[GUIDE IN THE USE OF LIBRARY]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Fine                                             Library Collections and Services
                                                                                                                                 Republic of the Philippines
           1. Overdue materials are subject to fine:       A. Reader’s Services                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                                                             Don Severino de las Alas Campus
             (Students)                                      1.  General Circulation Section – houses books used as
                                                                textbooks  and  references  in  the  different  program        Indang, Cavite, Philippines
               General Circulation Books – P5.00/day per book   offerings.                                                      (046) 4150-010 / (046) 4150-013 loc 250
               Reserved books – P5.00/day per book                                                                               www. cvsu.edu.ph
               Room Use Only books – P50.00/day per book    2.  Filipiniana  Section  –  houses  books  and  other
                                                                materials on various subjects about the Philippines or
              (Faculty)                                         any topic related to the Philippines regardless of author
                                                                or format.
               General Circulation Books – P10.00/day per book                                                           Library
               Reserved books – P10.00/day per book         3.  Serials/Periodicals  Section-  houses  all  local  and
               Room Use Only Books – P50.00/day per book       foreign journals, magazines, newspapers, etc.

           2. Saturdays, Sundays and holidays are counted in the   4.  Thesis  Section-  houses  theses  and  dissertations
             charging of fines                                  submitted by CvSU students and employees.

           3.  Borrowers  with  overdue  books  or  with  standing   5.  Reference Section – houses reference books for quick
             obligation to the library shall not be allowed to borrow   consultation purposes on specific topics of information
             additional  materials  unless  previous  accounts  have   like  dictionaries,  encyclopedias,  atlases,  handbooks,
             been settled.                                      almanacs,  directories,  bibliographies  and  current
                                                                sources like yearbooks and annuals.
          Note: All fees/fines collected shall be part of the University
             Trust Fund (Library).                         B. Technical Services

          Security Control                                   1.  Acquisition Section – handles selection, ordering and
                                                                procurement of books, subscription of periodicals and
             Bags, briefcases, umbrellas, large envelopes, folders   other materials.
             not  needed  for  study  should  be  deposited  at  the
             baggage counter desk (control desk).            2.  Cataloging  Section  –  prepares  the  bibliographical
                                                                description, classification, and mechanical processing
          Library Discipline                                    of the materials.

             SILENCE shall be observed in the library at all times.   C. Photocopying
                                                              The LDML provides photocopying jobs.                           User
             A  student  caught/accused  of  marking,  mutilating,
             destroying books and other library materials shall be   Other Services
             sanctioned according to the provisions stipulated in the
             student handbook.                             A. Online Public Access Catalog (OPAC)
                                                                                                                           Guide
             Readers are reminded that the library is primarily for      Access to the collections of the library can be done
             serious study and research.                     by  using  the  online  catalog.  The  Online  Public  Access
                                                             Catalog computers are not intended for e-mail or Internet
             Eating,  loud  talking,  entertaining  visitors  and   searching. Students are requested to use the computers at
             unnecessary  noise  which  may  be  caused  by  cell   the Internet Section for sending e-mails and searching the
             phones  within  the  library  premises  are  strictly   Web.

             prohibited.                                                                                                 LADISLAO N. DIWA
                                                           B. Athena Web Server
             Courtesy must be practiced especially when borrowing                                                     MEMORIAL LIBRARY
             or returning books or other library materials.       This allows patrons to search for materials available      2020 Edition
                                                             in the library collections. With Athena Web Server, patrons
                                                             may view information about their fine balances, items on
                                                             loan  and  items  on  reserve.  Everyone  now  has  the
                                                             convenience of being able to search the library collections
                                                             remotely.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Fine   Library Collections and Services
                                            Republic of the Philippines
 1. Overdue materials are subject to fine:   A. Reader’s Services     CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
 (Students)   1.  General Circulation Section – houses books used as
    textbooks  and  references  in  the  different  program   Indang, Cavite, Philippines
   General Circulation Books – P5.00/day per book   offerings.           (046) 4150-010 / (046) 4150-013 loc 250
   Reserved books – P5.00/day per book       www. cvsu.edu.ph
   Room Use Only books – P50.00/day per book   2.  Filipiniana  Section  –  houses  books  and  other
    materials on various subjects about the Philippines or
 (Faculty)   any topic related to the Philippines regardless of author
    or format.
   General Circulation Books – P10.00/day per book      Library
   Reserved books – P10.00/day per book   3.  Serials/Periodicals  Section-  houses  all  local  and
   Room Use Only Books – P50.00/day per book   foreign journals, magazines, newspapers, etc.

 2. Saturdays, Sundays and holidays are counted in the   4.  Thesis  Section-  houses  theses  and  dissertations
 charging of fines   submitted by CvSU students and employees.

 3.  Borrowers  with  overdue  books  or  with  standing   5.  Reference Section – houses reference books for quick
 obligation to the library shall not be allowed to borrow   consultation purposes on specific topics of information
 additional  materials  unless  previous  accounts  have   like  dictionaries,  encyclopedias,  atlases,  handbooks,
 been settled.   almanacs,  directories,  bibliographies  and  current
      sources like yearbooks and annuals.
 Note: All fees/fines collected shall be part of the University
 Trust Fund (Library).   B. Technical Services

 Security Control   1.  Acquisition Section – handles selection, ordering and
    procurement of books, subscription of periodicals and
   Bags, briefcases, umbrellas, large envelopes, folders   other materials.
 not  needed  for  study  should  be  deposited  at  the
 baggage counter desk (control desk).   2.  Cataloging  Section  –  prepares  the  bibliographical
    description, classification, and mechanical processing
 Library Discipline   of the materials.

   SILENCE shall be observed in the library at all times.   C. Photocopying
     The LDML provides photocopying jobs.   User
   A  student  caught/accused  of  marking,  mutilating,
 destroying books and other library materials shall be   Other Services
 sanctioned according to the provisions stipulated in the
 student handbook.   A. Online Public Access Catalog (OPAC)
                                       Guide
   Readers are reminded that the library is primarily for      Access to the collections of the library can be done
 serious study and research.   by  using  the  online  catalog.  The  Online  Public  Access
    Catalog computers are not intended for e-mail or Internet
   Eating,  loud  talking,  entertaining  visitors  and   searching. Students are requested to use the computers at
 unnecessary  noise  which  may  be  caused  by  cell   the Internet Section for sending e-mails and searching the
 phones  within  the  library  premises  are  strictly   Web.

 prohibited.                        LADISLAO N. DIWA
    B. Athena Web Server
   Courtesy must be practiced especially when borrowing      MEMORIAL LIBRARY
 or returning books or other library materials.      This allows patrons to search for materials available   2020 Edition
    in the library collections. With Athena Web Server, patrons
    may view information about their fine balances, items on
    loan  and  items  on  reserve.  Everyone  now  has  the
    convenience of being able to search the library collections
    remotely.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[GUIDE TO CvSU- MAIN CAMPUS LIBRARY
          LDML Vision                                        Current Awareness                                      Borrowing Rights and Responsibilities

                 Library that will be recognized for its  excellent   Bulletin boards are available for announcements.   CvSU graduate students may borrow a maximum
              service  as  its  contribution  to  the  development  of                                             of  five  (5)  books  (circulation)  and  undergraduate
              globally competitive and morally upright individuals.   Library Users                                students a maximum of three (3) books (circulation) at
                                                                                                                   a time
          LDML Mission                                           Regular  Users    -  all  bonafide  students,  staff  and
                                                                  faculty members of CvSU Main Campus             Hours of Service
                 Ladislao N. Diwa Memorial Library shall provide      Extended  Users  –  all  bonafide  students,  staff  and
              excellent, equitable and relevant library services and   faculty  members  of  external  CvSU  Campuses  and         Regular Semester
              resources in support with the University’s mission.   alumni : I.D. is required  (library resources for Room
                                                                                                                            Day                     Time
          LDML Goals                                             Use Only)                                               Monday-Saturday         7 a.m. – 6 p.m.
                                                                  Visitors  –  users  who  have  referral  letters  from
                                                                  librarians  or  heads  of  offices  where  they  are                         (No Noon Break)
                 To  support  the  University  in its main  thrust  of   enrolled/employed other than CvSU
              field of expertise by providing adequate, updated and                                                                     Summer
              relevant  collection  of  research  and  reference
              materials  to  its  clientele  composed  of  students,   LIBRARY RULES AND REGULATIONS                        Day                     Time
              faculty and other researchers in the community.                                                             Monday-Saturday         8 a.m. – 5 p.m.
                                                                                                                                                        (No Noon Break)
          LDML Objectives                                  General Rules
                                                                1.  Students  are  required  to  wear  their  valid  I.D  and
              The University Library aims to:                     official uniform when entering the library except on   Borrowing Schedules
                                                                  Wednesdays and Saturdays. The library shall exempt
              a.  Establish a collection that will be at par with other   students who belong to colleges that hold activities   Circulation Book:      7 a.m. – 6 p.m.
                 modern libraries not only in the region but also   upon  presentation  of  request  letter  signed  by  the
                 at national and international levels;                                                            Photocopying Room Use Book:   8 a.m. – 11 a.m.
                                                                  College Dean.                                                               1 p.m. – 5 p.m.

              b.  Encourage maximum utilization of its collection   2.  Student’s ID is required as access to the library. This
                 by making it readily available and accessible to   card  is  non-transferrable.  Mispresentation  by   Reserved Book:        4 p.m. – 8 a.m.
                 users; and
                                                                  showing someone else’s ID is an offense. Students
                                                                  caught doing such act may be deprived of their library
              c.  Coordinate  with  all  colleges  and  campuses  in   privileges for a period of two weeks.      Photocopying
                 the  selection  and  acquisition  of  materials
                 needed to supplement research and instruction.                                                         Photocopying of theses and dissertations is strictly
                                                              3.  A  sticker  will  be  issued  to  all  students  upon   prohibited.
                                                                  presentation  of  their  Registration  Form  (RF)  and

          Brief History of the University Library                 school ID for old students, temporary school ID for      Photocopying time for Room Use Only books is for
                                                                  new students. Validation of registration will be done
                                                                  every  semester  to  keep  our  database  of  patrons   one (1) hour only. In excess of one hour, a borrower
                 In 1980, the University Library was established   updated.                                              will be charged an overdue fine of ₱50.00.
              as  a  two-storey  building  with  a  collection  of  2,946
              volumes consisting of 1,196 titles which were turned   4.  Referral  letter  is  issued  to  faculty  and  students  of   Lost Books
              over  from  the  old  high  school  library.  The  library   CvSU who wish to do research in other libraries with
              opened its door to users in November 1980.          a fee of ₱5.00 per referral letter.                   A  lost  book must be  replaced  immediately in  the
                                                                                                                         concerned  section  where  the  book  was  charged
                   On July  14,  1997,  the University Library  was                                                      out.
              named Ladislao N. Diwa Memorial Library (LDML) in   5.  Other non-CvSU clientele is allowed to use the library
                                                                  every Thursdays only upon presentation of a valid ID
              recognition of the various contributions of Ladislao N.   from  their  respective  institutions/offices  where  they      It must be replaced with the same title or subject but
              Diwa and his heirs to the library. In 2005, the library   are  enrolled/employed  together  with  a  referral  and   of recent edition.
              was transferred to a new five-storey building.      payment of ₱30.00 as library fee.

                 In 2011, the LDML upgraded its services with the
              Online  Public  Access  Catalogues  (OPAC)  and  the   6.  Readers are reminded that the library is primarily for
                                                                  serious study and research.
              utilization of 18 computer units for online search.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[GUIDE TO CvSU- MAIN CAMPUS LIBRARY
 LDML Vision     Current Awareness     Borrowing Rights and Responsibilities

 Library that will be recognized for its  excellent   Bulletin boards are available for announcements.   CvSU graduate students may borrow a maximum
 service  as  its  contribution  to  the  development  of      of  five  (5)  books  (circulation)  and  undergraduate
 globally competitive and morally upright individuals.   Library Users   students a maximum of three (3) books (circulation) at
                               a time
 LDML Mission      Regular  Users    -  all  bonafide  students,  staff  and
    faculty members of CvSU Main Campus   Hours of Service
 Ladislao N. Diwa Memorial Library shall provide      Extended  Users  –  all  bonafide  students,  staff  and
 excellent, equitable and relevant library services and   faculty  members  of  external  CvSU  Campuses  and      Regular Semester
 resources in support with the University’s mission.   alumni : I.D. is required  (library resources for Room
                                        Day                     Time
 LDML Goals       Use Only)          Monday-Saturday         7 a.m. – 6 p.m.
 Visitors  –  users  who  have  referral  letters  from
    librarians  or  heads  of  offices  where  they  are                (No Noon Break)
 To  support  the  University  in its main  thrust  of   enrolled/employed other than CvSU
 field of expertise by providing adequate, updated and              Summer
 relevant  collection  of  research  and  reference
 materials  to  its  clientele  composed  of  students,   LIBRARY RULES AND REGULATIONS   Day             Time
 faculty and other researchers in the community.           Monday-Saturday         8 a.m. – 5 p.m.
                                                                    (No Noon Break)
 LDML Objectives   General Rules
      1.  Students  are  required  to  wear  their  valid  I.D  and
 The University Library aims to:   official uniform when entering the library except on   Borrowing Schedules
    Wednesdays and Saturdays. The library shall exempt
 a.  Establish a collection that will be at par with other   students who belong to colleges that hold activities   Circulation Book:      7 a.m. – 6 p.m.
 modern libraries not only in the region but also   upon  presentation  of  request  letter  signed  by  the
 at national and international levels;   Photocopying Room Use Book:   8 a.m. – 11 a.m.
    College Dean.                                         1 p.m. – 5 p.m.

 b.  Encourage maximum utilization of its collection   2.  Student’s ID is required as access to the library. This
 by making it readily available and accessible to   card  is  non-transferrable.  Mispresentation  by   Reserved Book:      4 p.m. – 8 a.m.
 users; and
    showing someone else’s ID is an offense. Students
 caught doing such act may be deprived of their library
 c.  Coordinate  with  all  colleges  and  campuses  in   privileges for a period of two weeks.   Photocopying
 the  selection  and  acquisition  of  materials
 needed to supplement research and instruction.      Photocopying of theses and dissertations is strictly
    3.  A  sticker  will  be  issued  to  all  students  upon   prohibited.
 presentation  of  their  Registration  Form  (RF)  and

 Brief History of the University Library   school ID for old students, temporary school ID for      Photocopying time for Room Use Only books is for
 new students. Validation of registration will be done
    every  semester  to  keep  our  database  of  patrons   one (1) hour only. In excess of one hour, a borrower
 In 1980, the University Library was established   updated.   will be charged an overdue fine of ₱50.00.
 as  a  two-storey  building  with  a  collection  of  2,946
 volumes consisting of 1,196 titles which were turned   4.  Referral  letter  is  issued  to  faculty  and  students  of   Lost Books
 over  from  the  old  high  school  library.  The  library   CvSU who wish to do research in other libraries with
 opened its door to users in November 1980.    a fee of ₱5.00 per referral letter.      A  lost  book must be  replaced  immediately in  the
                                     concerned  section  where  the  book  was  charged
   On July  14,  1997,  the University Library  was   out.
 named Ladislao N. Diwa Memorial Library (LDML) in   5.  Other non-CvSU clientele is allowed to use the library
 every Thursdays only upon presentation of a valid ID
 recognition of the various contributions of Ladislao N.   from  their  respective  institutions/offices  where  they      It must be replaced with the same title or subject but
 Diwa and his heirs to the library. In 2005, the library   are  enrolled/employed  together  with  a  referral  and   of recent edition.
 was transferred to a new five-storey building.    payment of ₱30.00 as library fee.

 In 2011, the LDML upgraded its services with the
 Online  Public  Access  Catalogues  (OPAC)  and  the   6.  Readers are reminded that the library is primarily for
 serious study and research.
 utilization of 18 computer units for online search.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[GUIDELINES IN THE USE OF
                                                                                               COMPUTER LABORATORY]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Laboratory Guidelines Posted in the Computer

                                                       Laboratory]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[USING A FIRE EXTINGUISHER



                                                                         P  A  S  S




        Pull the pin at the top of the extinguisher. The pin releases a locking

        mechanism and will allow you to discharge the extinguishers.



        Aim at the base of the fire, not flames. This is important – in order to put out

        the fire, you must extinguish the fuel.


        Squeeze the lever slowly. This will release the extinguishing agent in the


        extinguisher. If the handle is released, the discharged will stop.


        Sweep from side to side. Using a sweeping motion, move the fire


        extinguisher back and forth until the fire is completely out. Operate the

        extinguisher from a safe distance, several feet away, and then move towards


        the fire once it starts to diminish. Be sure to read the instructions on your fire

        extinguisher – different fire extinguishers recommended operating them from

        different distances.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[USING A FIRE EXTINGUISHER



 P  A  S  S




 Pull the pin at the top of the extinguisher. The pin releases a locking

 mechanism and will allow you to discharge the extinguishers.



 Aim at the base of the fire, not flames. This is important – in order to put out

 the fire, you must extinguish the fuel.


 Squeeze the lever slowly. This will release the extinguishing agent in the


 extinguisher. If the handle is released, the discharged will stop.


 Sweep from side to side. Using a sweeping motion, move the fire


 extinguisher back and forth until the fire is completely out. Operate the

 extinguisher from a safe distance, several feet away, and then move towards


 the fire once it starts to diminish. Be sure to read the instructions on your fire

 extinguisher – different fire extinguishers recommended operating them from

 different distances.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>
