<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="24"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.6.            The following basic services are


                        available:


                        S.6.3.  Institutional Student Programs

                                       and Services;


                                        S.6.3.12. Social and Community


                                                         Involvement Programs;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[23


                              5.1.1.  Plans, implements, attends and evaluates cultural programs and
                                       activities
                              5.1.2.  Develops non-formal cultural education programs
                              5.1.3.  Supervises the operation and activities of all cultural groups and
                                       organizations
                              5.1.4.  Acts  as  overall  adviser  to  the  different  artistic  and  cultural
                                       groups
                              5.1.5.  Acts as property custodian for culture and arts
                              5.1.6.  Evaluates seminars and workshops conducted
                              5.1.7.  Prepares financial plans and fund utilization reports
                              5.1.8.  Evaluates  and  recommends  hiring  of  coaches  and  trainers  of
                                       performing arts group
                       5.2.   The CA Coordinator shall be assisted by a Council of Advisers for Culture
                              and  Arts  which  shall  be  composed  of  advisers,  trainors/coaches  and
                              events coordinators.
                       5.3.   Source of Funds
                                     All budgetary and financial requirements of the Culture and Arts
                              Program shall be coming from  Student Funds collected by the Central
                              Student Government and specifically allotted to Culture and Arts
                              Program according to its approved financial plan.


               Section  6. NSTP and Community Involvement
                       6.1.   Organization.
                              6.1.1.  The  CvSU  NSTP  shall  be  implemented by  the  Office  of  Student
                                       Affairs (OSA) Main Campus in coordination with the University,
                                       College,  and  Campus  Registrars.  While  the  Dean  for  Student
                                       Affairs  is  the  over  all  Program  Coordinator,  all  NSTP  student
                                       records shall be handled by the University Registrar’s Office for
                                       the  main  campus    and  the  campus  registrars,  in  the  case  of
                                       students in the branch campuses.
                              6.1.2.  College  Registrar’s  in  the  main  campus  shall  assist  the
                                       University  registrar  in  keeping  track  of  records  of  students
                                       taking the CvSU NSTP in their respective colleges.
                              6.1.3.  College and campus registrars shall submit the list of students
                                       in  CvSU  NSTP  to  the  Dean  for  Student  Affairs  for  purposes  of
                                       monitoring and evaluation.
                              6.1.4.  The  NSTP  to  be  conducted  in  branch  campuses  shall  be
                                       coordinated  with  the  OSA.  They  may  designate  their  own
                                       respective NSTP component coordinators.
                              6.1.5.  The  conduct  of  the  ROTC  component  shall  be  taken  care  of  by
                                       the  DND  under  their  own  guidelines.  In  addition  to  the  ROTC,
                                       the  University  main  campus  shall  also  offer  the  Civic  Welfare
                                       Training  Services.(CWTS)  and  Literacy  Training  Services  (LTS)
                                       components. The branch campuses may opt for any of the three
                                       components. In cases where the component selected by students
                                       is  not  being  offered,  he/she  may  cross  register  in  other




               Excerpts from OSAS Manual (Page 23-27)]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[24


                                       campuses  with  the  written  permission  from  their  respective
                                       campus  registrars.  Students  taking  the  NSTP  component  in
                                       another campus shall be governed by the CvSU NSTP guidelines.
                              6.1.6.  In the main campus, students taking the Civic Welfare Training
                                       Services (CWTS) Component shall be under the responsibility of
                                       the college deans who shall create a pool of teachers or trainers
                                       for  their  respective  students.  The  fielding  or  practicum  of
                                       students  in  connection  with  CWTS  shall  be,  as  much  as
                                       possible,  within  the  requirements  of  the  extension  services
                                       component  of  the  main  campus  University  Project  UGNAYAN:
                                       A  Unified  Research  and  Extension  of  the  Academic  Affairs
                                       Unit of the University.     Any CWS in the main campus that is
                                       outside  the  domain  of  or  not  related  to  the  conduct  of  Project
                                       UGNAYAN  shall  require  the  approval  of  the  Vice  President  for
                                       Academic Affairs
                              6.1.7.  The LTS shall be implemented by the College of Education which
                                       has the expertise in the suggested curriculum content of the said
                                       component.
                              6.1.8.  The  practicum  of  students  in  the  CvSU  NSTP  shall  not  be
                                       credited toward another course.
                       6.2.   Who are Required/ Not Required To Undergo the NSTP?
                              6.2.1.  All  incoming  freshmen  students  of  the  University,  male  or
                                       female,     under  the  degree  programs  and at  least  2 year non
                                       degree  programs  shall  be  required  to  undergo  any  of  the  three
                                       components of the NSTP  for two semesters. The NSTP shall be
                                       credited  for  three  3  units  per  semester  to  be  conducted  for  at
                                       least 54 hours, but not exceeding 90 hours. A total of six credit
                                       units NSTP shall be required for graduation.
                              6.2.2.  All male students of the University regardless of their year level,
                                       who have not taken the ROTC shall be required to complete any
                                       of the components of the NSTP.
                              6.2.3.  It  is  understood  from  the  intent  of  the  RA  9163  that  female
                                       students may also opt to take the ROTC NSTP component.
                              6.2.4.  Male students who have not taken the ROTC shall be required to
                                       complete  any  component  of  the  NSTP  as  requirement  for
                                       graduation.
                              6.2.5.  Male  students  who  have  completed  the  Expanded  ROTC  (E-
                                       ROTC)  /  National  Service  Program  (NSP)  are  deemed  to  have
                                       complied with       NSTP requirement.
                              6.2.6.  The ROTC Training Service in the main campus shall be offered
                                       for at least 350 students opting for this component. Students in
                                       branch  campuses  desiring  to  take  the  ROTC  Training  Service
                                       may take the ROTC in the main campus offered every Saturday
                                       or  they  may  take  the  ROTC  in  the  nearby  public  or  private
                                       University  offering  the  ROTC  component,  provided  they  first
                                       secure written permission from the university/campus registrar.






               Excerpts from OSAS Manual (Page 23-27)]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[25


                                       Branch campuses may offer the ROTC              component  if  the
                                       number of students satisfy the 350 requirement.
                              6.2.7.  The existing arrangement between the CvSU and the DND shall
                                       be  continued  in  the  implementation  of  the  ROTC.  The  existing
                                       Department  of  Military  Science  and  Tactics  Office  in  the  main
                                       campus shall continue in operation.

                       6.3.   Budget
                              6.3.1.  CvSU students taking the CvSU NSTP shall be charged uniform
                                       basic tuition equivalent to 50 percent of what is currently being
                                       charged per unit in the main campus. This is equivalent to PhP
                                       68.50  per  semester  or  50  percent  of  PhP  137.00  per  unit.  The
                                       total  NSTP  cost  per  student  per  semester  is  equivalent  to  PhP
                                       205.50 The amount shall be collected by the respective cashiers
                                       in the main campus and in the branch campuses. The collection
                                       shall be deposited on special NSTP trust funds. Such funds shall
                                       be used for the maintenance and operation of the NSTP and also
                                       for honoraria of university faculty and employees involved in the
                                       CvSU NSTP.
                              6.3.2.  The honoraria rates for faculty involved in the CvSU NSTP shall
                                       follow the provisions of NCC 75, “Prescribing the Guidelines and
                                       Procedures for Granting of Honoraria  to Government  Officials
                                       and Employees”. For this purpose, Section 6.2 of NCC 75  shall
                                       be followed as follows:
                                       Team Leader / Coordinator                  –   P 1,600.00 per month
                                       Technical Staff / Team Member              –     1,200.00 per month
                                       Administrative Staff                       –       800.00 per month

                                       The  granting  of  honoraria  shall  be  performance  –  based.  The
                                       CvSU  NSTP  personnel  to  receive  honoraria  should  have  prior
                                       authority or designation from the University President.

                              6.3.3.  The Dean for Student Affairs shall prepare the financial plan for
                                       the   CvSU NSTP.

                       6.4.   Curriculum
                              6.4.1.  The curriculum for the ROTC component shall follow the regular
                                       curriculum designed by the DND for the purpose.
                              6.4.2.  The suggested curriculum content for the CWS and the LTS per
                                       CHED Memo to CHEDRO Redirectors dated 25 April 2002 shall
                                       form the basis for the conduct of CWTS/LTS components of the
                                       CvSU NSTP.
                              6.4.3.  Guidelines in the Conduct of CWTS/LTS Components
                                       6.4.3.1.  There  shall  be  one  common  curriculum  content  for
                                                 NSTP – CWTS /LTS for all campuses.
                                       6.4.3.2.  Pool of trainers for specific area shall be:


                                       Area                                                 Trainer
                                       Orientation (RA 9163)                            –   c/o OSA





               Excerpts from OSAS Manual (Page 23-27)]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[26


                                       Self- Awareness and Values Development           –   c/o OSA
                                       Basic Leadership Training                        –   c/o CEMDS
                                       Disaster Preparedness                            –   Red Cross /ARESCOM
                                       Environment Resource Management                  –   c/o CAFENR
                                       Education, Moral of the Citizenry                –   c/o CEd
                                       Recreation and Safety                            –   c/o CSPEAR
                                       Safety and Health                                –   c/o CSPEAR
                                       Community Need Assessment                        –   c/o CEMDS



                                       6.4.3.3.  Grading System/ Submission of Grades

                                              Trainers  shall  give  numerical  grades  for  each  student  at
                                       the end of their training session following the grading system of
                                       the  University.  The  grading  sheet  shall  be  submitted  to  the
                                       college  registrar  concerned  not  later  than  one  week  after  the
                                       session.
                                              Grade  of  students  shall  be  computed  based  on  the
                                       average grade given by the trainers in proportion to the number
                                       of hours the topic is handled. To wit:

                                                        Total Contact                         Weighted
                                           Trainer                             Grade
                                                            Hours                               Grade
                                              1                9                1.0              9.0
                                              2                9                1.25            16.07
                                              3                6                1.0              6.0
                                              4                9                2.0              18.0
                                              5                9                2.0              18.0
                                              6                9                1.0              9.0
                                              7                12               3.0              36.0
                                              8                9                1.0              9.0
                                              9                9                2.0              24.0
                                           TOTAL               84                              135.07


                                                                   135.07
                                                                =   =     = 1.607 =   .     
                                                                     84

                                              The College or Campus Registrar shall submit the grading
                                       sheet to the Office of the University Registrar.




                              6.4.4.  Community Immersion:
                                       6.4.4.1. After identifying the needs of the community, the college
                                                shall:
                                       6.4.4.2. Identify the project
                                       6.4.4.3. Identify the barangay where to conduct the project




               Excerpts from OSAS Manual (Page 23-27)]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[27


                                       6.4.4.4. Identify the faculty members to be designated as project
                                                coordinators
                              6.4.5.  Term of reference of project coordinators:
                                       6.4.5.1. plan and implement the project /program
                                       6.4.5.2. coordinate with the barangay /GOs/NGO
                                       6.4.5.3. supervise students at work
                                       6.4.5.4. give grades to students
                                       6.4.5.5. submit  project  report  to  the  NSTP  coordinator  through
                                                the dean
                              6.4.6.   NSTP as required course for graduation:
                                       6.4.6.1. Students  shall  enroll  the  course  during  their  first  and
                                                second year in college
                                       6.4.6.2. No  students  shall  be  allowed  to  enroll  in  third  year
                                                without passing / completing the NSTP.
                       6.5.   Effectivity
                              The  implementation  of  the  CvSU  NSTP  per  R.A.  9163  started  the  First
                       Semester of the School Year 2002-2003.
                              The Office of Student Affairs shall issue an immediate announcement for
                       students to enlist in any NSTP option. They will be charged Php 205.50 to be
                       paid at the Cashier’s Office in the main and branch campuses. Students who
                       were  unable  to  pay  the  required  tuition  fee  shall  not  be  allowed  to  take  the
                       CvSU NSTP.


                       6.6.   Schedule of Implementation

                              a)  Announcement of implementation and orientation            June 30-July 15
                              b)  Collection of fees                                        July 15 to 29
                              c)  Designation of personnel for CvSU NSTP                    July 15
                              d)  Finalization of CvSU  NSTP curricula and syllabi          July 26
                              e)  Start of NSTP classes                                     August 1




                       Section 7.  Services for students with special needs

                              Services for Student s with Special needs and persons with
                       disabilities – programs and activities designed to provide equal opportunities to
                       persons with disabilities

                          1.  Provisions  for  life  skills  training  such  as  cconflict  management,
                              counselling, testing referrals
                          2.  Submission of list of students with disabilities detailing the intervention
                              programs to CHEDRO









               Excerpts from OSAS Manual (Page 23-27)]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Implementing Guidelines for NSTP



                    from CvSU Manual of Operations


                                          (Pages 173-178)]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES


                            Approved Continuity Plan



                           for Social and Community



                               Involvement Programs


                                               2021-2022]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>