<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="150"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.3.            Quality instruction is assured through


                        the following strategies;


                        I.3.3.  conducting competency

                                       assessment;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Student Competencies are assessed

                                 by conducting the following


                                      assessment strategies:]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[A  s s e s s  m  e n  t   o f   S k i l l s   o n
                                        Assessment of Skills on

                                Demonstration Teaching and/or

                                   Student Teaching Internship]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[32]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[33]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[34]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[35]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[36]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[37]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[38]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[39]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[40]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[41]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[42]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[43]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[44]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[45]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[46]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[47


                                                      GUIDE QUESTIONS



                       What does the Teacher need to think about before beginning?

                          1.  Why am I teaching this lesson?


                                 •  Required curriculum?

                                 •  Student interest in topic?

                                 •  My interest in topic?


                          2.  What do I hope to accomplish?

                                 •  Skill to be developed?

                                 •  Concepts to be discussed for understanding?

                                 •  Product to be produced?

                          3.  Who are the students?


                                 •  Range of abilities?

                                 •  Range of ages?

                                 •  Ethnic diversity and varying cultures?

                          4.  What is the time frame for teaching this lesson?


                                 •  Part of a unit?

                                 •  One period or block schedule?

                                 •  Isolated lesson?

                          5.  How will I begin the lesson to capture student attention?


                                 •  Story or anecdote?

                                 •  Relevance to their lives?

                                 •  Props or visual displays?

                          6.  Will I need other resources to teach this lesson?

                                 •  Audio visual or technology?


                                 •  Student hand-outs?

                                 •  Manipulative or visual displays?]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[48


                          7.  How will students spend their time during the lesson?

                                 •  Small group discussions? Individual? Large group?


                                 •  Hands on activity or experiment?

                                 •  Taking notes or observing?

                          8.  How will this lesson be assessed?

                                 •  Formal? Quiz or test?

                                 •  Informal? Observation of learning?


                                 •  Open-ended question? Written? Verbal?

                          9.  How will I close the lesson or close the class period?

                                 •  Review and summary?

                                 •  Collecting papers and giving assignments?


                                 •  Allowing time for homework or question?

                          10. Will there be homework or enrichment activities offered?

                                 •  How will I collect later? Is it required or extra?

                                 •  Will it count? What is the cooperating teacher’s policy?


                                 •  How will I grade it?

                          11. How will I know if I succeeded in teaching the lesson?

                                 •  Self-assessment?

                                 •  Response of students?

                                 •  Cooperating teacher impart?


                          12. How will the next lesson relate or build on this one?]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[49]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[50]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[51]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[52]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[53]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[54]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[55]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[56]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[57]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[58]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[59]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[60]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[61


                                                     CASE STUDY SHEET


                        Name:__________________________  School:__________________________

                        Date of Birth:___________________       Date:____________________________

                        Parents: _______________________        Siblings:_________________________

                        Referral Source:
                        __________________________________________________________________

                        Reasons for referral (specific problem including observable symptoms):
                        __________________________________________________________________


                        Family Background (family relationship, home environments, socio-economic
                        status):
                        __________________________________________________________________
                        Physical History (disabilities, speech defects, vision, height, weight:

                        __________________________________________________________________
                        School history:
                               ____________________________________________________________
                               ____________________________________________________________
                        Test Data:
                                      Achievement, including reading level:
                                      ______________________________________________________
                                      Aptitude, including mental ability:
                                      ______________________________________________________
                                      Personality and social adjustment (general behavior patterns):

                                      ______________________________________________________
                                      Vocational interest:

                                      ______________________________________________________

                        Interest, hobbies, and experiences:
                                      ______________________________________________________

                        Plan (vocational or educational):
                                      ______________________________________________________

                        General appraisal, interpretation, and hypotheses:
                                      ______________________________________________________
                        Recommendations:
                        __________________________________________________________________
                        __________________________________________________________________
                              Source:
                                     Shertzer and Stone. (1981).  Fundamentals of Guidance.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Ms. Aubrey Cedillo, BSE English student teacher, while conducting her demonstration teaching
                             at Tanza National Trade School – Bagtas Annex (October 18, 2022)




































                 Ms. Cristina Pilande, BSE Mathematics student teacher, while conducting her demonstration
                         teaching at Tanza National Trade School – Bagtas Annex (October 12, 2022)]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on
                                        A  s s e s s  m  e n  t   o f   S k i l l s   o n

                                               Lesson Planning]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[CvSU Vision                      Republic of the Philippines              CvSU Mission
                                                                                        Cavite State University shall
               The       premier               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY              provide excellent, equitable and
            university  in  historic                   Tanza Campus                 relevant educational opportunities
            Cavite  recognized  for                                                 in  the  arts,  science  and
            excellence  in   the                   Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite            technology  through  quality
            development of globally                   (046) 414-3979               instruction and relevant research
            competitive and morally                  www.cvsu.edu.ph                and development activities.
            upright individuals.                                                        It shall produce professional,
                                                                                    skilled  and  morally  upright
                                                                                    individuals  for    global
                                                                                    competitiveness.


                                            Semi-Detailed Lesson Plan



               I. LEARNING OBJECTIVES
                At the end of the discussion, the students will be able to:
                    1. Differentiate verbal from nonverbal communication,
                    2. Identify the different types of nonverbal communication, and;

                    3. Communicate effectively by using proper verbal and nonverbal cues.


               II. SUBJECT MATTER
               Lesson: Verbal and Nonverbal Communication
               Reference: Flores, R. S. (2016). Oral Communication in Context. Rex Bookstore.
               Materials: laptop, projector, PowerPoint presentation, and printed instructional
               materials



               III. PRIMING
               A. Preliminaries
                       Greetings
                       Prayer

                       Attendance
               B. Motivational Activity | Previous Lesson Recall - Process of Communication
                       The class will be grouped into three. Each group will think of a scenario where process of
                        communication is taking place. They can choose representatives to portray the scenario in
                        front. The rest of the students will identify the elements of the process of communication in
                        the scenarios given.


               IV. ANALYSIS

               1. What did you learn from the previous lesson?
               2. How is it important to be an effective communicator?


               V. ABSTRACTION
                       From the student’s different viewpoints, the teacher will explain how important it is to know
                        the elements of communication and everything you say and do means something.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Oftentimes, misunderstanding occurs when the message perceived is different from the
                        intended message. To prevent such, we will talk about verbal and nonverbal cues.
                       Differentiate verbal from nonverbal communication.
                              VERBAL COMMUNICATION - means sharing things by means of

                                                       words, whether spoken or written.
                              NONVERBAL COMMUNICATION - is communication without
                                                      words,only visual cues.
                       Introduction of different types of verbal communication: oral and written
                       Introduction of different types of nonverbal communication:
                       a. Facial expressions – The principal source of feedback.
                       b. Eye contact – The most expressive element in face-to-face communication.

                       c. Body movements & posture – The way you stand and hold your body also
                                     sends messages.
                       d. Gestures – The movement that you make with a part of your body,
                       especially your hands.
                       e. Haptics – also known as “touching”.
                       f. Proxemics – refers to the amount of space that individuals naturally

                       maintain between each other which communicates meanings.
                       g. Voice – The way in which a message is spoken is as important as what is
                       said.


               VI. APPLICATION
                       The class will be divided into four groups. Each group will be required to have a short
                        scenario to be performed in front. Of course, before coming up with the performance,there

                        must be a script. The script should contain verbal and nonverbal cues. For example: “Girl:
                        Yes! (nodding)”
                       It is up to the group leaders how they will divide the tasks. As long as all of the members will
                        participate, a script will be produced, and a short role play will be performed. The rubrics will
                        be given by the teacher.



               VII. GENERALIZATION
                       To make sure that the lesson is learned, the teacher will call students to answer and
                        complete these statements:
                                                  “I have learned that…”
                          “Knowing verbal and nonverbal communication is important because…”


                VIII. ASSESSMENT

               The class will be divided into four groups. Each assigned leader will pick a random task (see below).
               Each group will be given 10 minutes to prepare before presenting their output in front of their
               classmates. The rubrics will be given by the teacher.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Tasks (Draw lots):
               1. Create a jingle about the importance of verbal and non-verbal cues.
               2. Create a short skit about misunderstandings when the message perceived is different from the

               intended message.
               3. Present a speech choir about the importance of verbal and non-verbal cues.
               4. Craft a slogan about verbal and non-verbal communication and explain your concept in front of the
               class.


               IX. ASSIGNMENT

                   Do an advanced reading on “Effective Communication Skills” and prepare for a graded recitation.




               Prepared by:                                                        Checked by:


               Marie Russel Daquila Martin                                                Ivory Mojica, LPT
                        Student                                                               Instructor]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[MODEL LESSON PLAN

               Name: Vanessa H. Rosas


               Section: Bsem 3-1

               Subject: Mathematics

               Topic: Solids

               Reference: Mathematics Learner’s Module 7




               General Objective: Student will:

               1. Know the terms vertices, faces and edges

               2. Understand the relation between vertices, faces and edges

               3. Build the Euler's relationship

               4. Apply the Euler's relationship to solve the problems

               Approach: Contructivist (5e Model)


               Method: Activity Base

               TLM: Different type of solids like cube, regular tetrahedron and A4 shits.



               TIME     STEPS       TEACHERS ACTIVITIES                STUDENTS ACTIVITIES        TLM


               20 min   Engage      Make five groups of students and   Identifies how many        Cubiod
                                    distribute cuboids, cubes, regular   vertices, faces and edges.
                                    tetrahedrons, and A4 shits. Then                              Cube
                                    students ask to find out how many   Find a connection among
                                    vertices, faces, and edges they have   the faces, edges       Regular
                                                                                                  tetrahedron
                                    and whether there is a connection   andvertices.
                                    between the faces, edges, and      Complete the work with     A4 shits
                                    vertices. Then they compare with   teacher and peer help.
                                    other groups and come to a
                                    conclusion.

               5 min    Explore     Helps student to complete the task.   Note down their         A4 shits
                                                                       observation.
                                    Ask students to exchange their
                                                                       Find how many vertices,]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[objects and do the same thing again.  faces and edges and find a
                                                                       connection among the
                                                                       faces, edges and vertices.




               10 min   Explain     Listen to students' findings from   Each student group
                                    each group and ask them to explain   representative explains
                                    whether there is a relation between   and justifies their findings
                                    c and d. Also provides explanation   to the teacher as needed.
                                    and justification where ever needed.


               20 min   Elaborate   Relates c/d to π. Introduce the c   Take the diameter as
                                    formulae c = πd.                   d=7cm, and use the
                                                                       formulae c = πd.
                                    Find the circumference of a circle
                                    with the diameter of 7cm.

               5 min    Evaluate    Students work evaluated.           Solves problem on it.



               Home Assignment:

               1. Find the circumference of the circle which has the radius 3.5cm.


               2. If the circumference is 220cm find the diameter of that circle.



               Closure/Reflection:]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[MODEL LESSON PLAN

               Name of the School: Tanza National Trade School                                 Name of teacher: Maria Angela A. Capuz

               Class: VII                                                                      Subject: Mathematics

               Average age: 13+ yrs                                                            Unit :


               No. of students: 40                                                             Topic : Law of Exponent

               Duration: 50 mins                                                               Name of the book : Mathematics – Grade 7 Teacher’s Guide

               Date: 01/12/2021                                                                Publisher : Department of Education




               Concept Mapping:










                     (n times)                              product of a power                    law for zero exponent
                                                                                                   0
                      n
                     a = a • a • a • a • a.…                a • a = a m+n                         a = 1
                                                                 m
                                                             n
                                                                                quotient of a power                      law for negative exponent
                                           power of powers                       a n                                     a n
                                             n m
                                           (a ) = a nm                           a m  = a n-m                             a m    = a n-m]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[MODEL LESSON PLAN

 Name of the School: Tanza National Trade School  Name of teacher: Maria Angela A. Capuz

 Class: VII  Subject: Mathematics

 Average age: 13+ yrs  Unit :


 No. of students: 40  Topic : Law of Exponent

 Duration: 50 mins  Name of the book : Mathematics – Grade 7 Teacher’s Guide

 Date: 01/12/2021  Publisher : Department of Education




 Concept Mapping:










 (n times)  product of a power  law for zero exponent
               0
 n
 a = a • a • a • a • a.…  a • a = a m+n  a = 1
 m
 n
 quotient of a power                law for negative exponent
 power of powers  a n                a n
 n m
 (a ) = a nm  a m  = a n-m            a m    = a n-m]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[General Objective: Student will:

               1. Know the term Exponent.

                                              n
               2. Understand the meaning of a where n is a positive integer.
               3. Apply the law of exponents to solve problems.


               4. Analyze word problems to the answer from a given conditions.

               5. Evaluate among law of exponent.

               Approach: Constructivist (5E Model)

               Method: Demonstration cum Explanation, Problem Solving

               Technique: Activity based

               TLM:Power Point Presentation]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[General Objective: Student will:

 1. Know the term Exponent.

 n
 2. Understand the meaning of a where n is a positive integer.
 3. Apply the law of exponents to solve problems.


 4. Analyze word problems to the answer from a given conditions.

 5. Evaluate among law of exponent.

 Approach: Constructivist (5E Model)

 Method: Demonstration cum Explanation, Problem Solving

 Technique: Activity based

 TLM:Power Point Presentation]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[TIME         STEPS                   TEACHERS ACTIVITIES                          STUDENTS ACTIVITIES                      TLM

                                           The teacher will flash a fill in the box activity on

                                           the google meet. The activity will direct students They think and construct their own    Activity will flash on


                                           to fill the boxes with correct letters to complete the understanding about exponent.     Google    meet    using

               5 min         Engage        word. The letters consist of problems related to                                         Power             Point

                                           the law of exponent.                                                                     Presentation

                                           ACTIVITY                                           Students will complete the activity.

                                           T 3x3 =                                            .

                                               1
                                           O 8 =
                                           X 2*2*2*2*2*2*2 =
                                           E (5)(5)(5) =

                                                2
                                           N 10 =
                                           E 1 =
                                               0
                                           P 6*6*6*6*6 =

                                           N 4x4x4x4x4x4 =




                                            15   128   7776   8   4096    1    100    9]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[TIME  STEPS  TEACHERS ACTIVITIES  STUDENTS ACTIVITIES   TLM

 The teacher will flash a fill in the box activity on

 the google meet. The activity will direct students They think and construct their own  Activity will flash on


 to fill the boxes with correct letters to complete the understanding about exponent.  Google  meet  using

 5 min  Engage  word. The letters consist of problems related to  Power  Point

 the law of exponent.                           Presentation

 ACTIVITY  Students will complete the activity.

 T 3x3 =  .

 1
 O 8 =
 X 2*2*2*2*2*2*2 =
 E (5)(5)(5) =

 2
 N 10 =
 E 1 =
 0
 P 6*6*6*6*6 =

 N 4x4x4x4x4x4 =




 15  128  7776  8  4096  1  100  9]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Findings:

               6 min           Explore     Guides student to complete the task.                E   X    P    O   N    E   N    T

                                                                                               15  128 7776  8  4096  1   100  9

                                           Listens to the explanation of the students about Students explain of their findings in

                                           their findings, ask students to justify where ever each letter and justifies where ever

                                           necessary and give feedback. Also, provides necessary.

               10 min          Explain     explanation and justification where ever needed

                                           about the lesson connected to the activity.


                                           Introduces the other law of exponent and solve

                                           problem. Then, students are asked to elaborate Students justify their observation,

                                           on:                                                learns new concepts, definition of

               20 min                                                                         terms,  other   law  of   exponents

                             Elaborate                                                        and solves problems.






                                           1. Did you notice something?


                                           2. What can you conclude about



                                           3. What will you do with a, n and m?]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Findings:

 6 min  Explore  Guides student to complete the task.  E  X  P  O  N  E  N  T

           15  128 7776  8  4096  1   100  9

 Listens to the explanation of the students about Students explain of their findings in

 their findings, ask students to justify where ever each letter and justifies where ever

 necessary and give feedback. Also, provides necessary.

 10 min  Explain  explanation and justification where ever needed

 about the lesson connected to the activity.


 Introduces the other law of exponent and solve

 problem. Then, students are asked to elaborate Students justify their observation,

 on:      learns new concepts, definition of

 20 min   terms,  other   law  of   exponents

 Elaborate  and solves problems.






 1. Did you notice something?


 2. What can you conclude about



 3. What will you do with a, n and m?]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[6 min          Evaluate     Students’ responses and answers are checked.




               Home Assignment:Create a graphic organizer of the law of exponent using canva, ppt or any editing application. Show your creativity and enjoy.


               Closure/Reflection:]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[6 min  Evaluate  Students’ responses and answers are checked.




 Home Assignment:Create a graphic organizer of the law of exponent using canva, ppt or any editing application. Show your creativity and enjoy.


 Closure/Reflection:]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on
                                        A  s s e s s  m  e n  t   o f   S k i l l s   o n

                                          Writing Test Items and

                                          Table of Specifications]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[____7. An example of a gas is _____.

                       A.  A rock
                       B.  A Pencil
                       C.  A chocolate Syrup
                       D.  Helium

               ____8. What happens to a gas when the temperature decreases?
                       A.  It expands.
                       B.  It rises.
                       C.  It condenses.
                       D.  It became less dense.

               ____9. A juice is an example of _____.

                       A.  Gas
                       B.  Liquid
                       C.  Mixture
                       D.  Solid

               ____10. What is mass?
                       A.  The amount of space that an object takes up.
                       B.  The amount of matter in a solid, liquid, or gas.
                       C.  The material through which an electrical charge can pass.
                       D.  None of the above.]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[EDUC75 Module 6 Output 1

               Create a 30-item Table of Specifications based on a topic of your choice. You may use the DepEd Curriculum guides accessible
               through this link:  https://www.deped.gov.ph/k-to-12/about/k-to-12-basic-education-curriculum/ for your reference.
               Deadline for submission is on December 3, 2021, via CVSU LMS.



               Name: , Arniel C. Silvano

               Year/Section: BEE 2-1
               Date Submitted: November 23, 2021


                    Grade 1 Second    No.                                   Placement of Items                                         No. of    Item
                       Quarter        of                                                                                         %     items   Number
                       Learning      Days
                    Competencies             Remembering      Understanding     Applying   Analyzing    Creating   Evaluating
                   Illustrates
                   addition as
                   “putting together
                   or combining or     3                                           6                                             20      6      13-18
                   joining sets”


                   Visualizes and
                   adds two one
                   digit numbers
                   with sums up to     2           1                1                                                   2        13      4      19-22
                   18 using the                                                                                                 13.33
                   order and zero
                   properties of
                   addition.

                   Adds two one-
                   digit numbers       2                                                       2           2                     13      4        1-4
                   using appropriate                                                                                            13.33
                   mental]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[EDUC75 Module 6 Output 1

 Create a 30-item Table of Specifications based on a topic of your choice. You may use the DepEd Curriculum guides accessible
 through this link:  https://www.deped.gov.ph/k-to-12/about/k-to-12-basic-education-curriculum/ for your reference.
 Deadline for submission is on December 3, 2021, via CVSU LMS.



 Name: , Arniel C. Silvano

 Year/Section: BEE 2-1
 Date Submitted: November 23, 2021


 Grade 1 Second   No.   Placement of Items         No. of    Item
 Quarter   of                                %     items   Number
 Learning   Days
 Competencies   Remembering   Understanding   Applying   Analyzing   Creating   Evaluating
 Illustrates
 addition as
 “putting together
 or combining or   3    6                    20      6      13-18
 joining sets”


 Visualizes and
 adds two one
 digit numbers
 with sums up to   2   1   1       2         13      4      19-22
 18 using the                               13.33
 order and zero
 properties of
 addition.

 Adds two one-
 digit numbers   2   2   2                   13      4       1-4
 using appropriate                          13.33
 mental]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[techniques e.g.
                   adding doubles
                   and/or near-
                   doubles.

                   Visualizes and
                   adds three one-
                   digit numbers
                   using the           4           4                4                                                            27      8       5-12
                   grouping property                                                                                            26.66
                   of addition

                   Visualizes and
                   adds two to three
                   one-digit
                   numbers             4           2                2                                                   4        27      8      23-30
                   horizontally and                                                                                             26.66
                   vertically.


                                      15           7                7              6           2           2            6        100     30
                                     Days]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[techniques e.g.
 adding doubles
 and/or near-
 doubles.

 Visualizes and
 adds three one-
 digit numbers
 using the   4   4   4                       27      8       5-12
 grouping property                          26.66
 of addition

 Visualizes and
 adds two to three
 one-digit
 numbers   4   2   2               4         27      8      23-30
 horizontally and                           26.66
 vertically.


    15   7   7   6   2   2         6        100     30
    Days]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on

                                      Proving and Conjecturing]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[Ronnie Cuyos Daef
               BSEM 3-1


                                                         OBA 9 (6)


                                     PROVING                                      REASONING
               1.




               We are going to use the principle of Mathematical     We  use         to  prove  that          is
               Induction to prove the statement. We are going to     true  using  the  Principle  of  Mathematical
               prove that                                            Induction by assuming that      .




               Let:

                                                                     By assuming that      , we will use it to

               Then:                                                 substitute  to  our  statement         to
                                                                     make the statement true.




                               this statement is true

               Now, let’s make


                                                                     Since we  were able  to find that  if
               Then:                                                 makes  our  statement  true,  then  we

                                                                     assign                       so  we  can
                                                                     formulate  to  cases  to  make  the  original
                                                                     statement being true.
               And let’s make:



               Then:





               Now let’s us make this cases:

               Case 1:



                           where m is a positive integer]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Case 1 shows that n=1 is true.

               Case 2:                                               So, by the using of the PMI it proved that
                                                                     2n>n  is  true.  Therefore  n<2n  for  all
                                                                     positive integers n is also true.



                                     or simply



               Case 2 shows that           is true when
               is also true                                          By  stating  the  2  cases,  we  now

                                                                     concluded  that  the  statement          is
                                                                      true for all positive integers n.


               2. Prove that the sum of two odd integers is even.


                                                                     In here, we first substitute even and odd
                                                                     numbers  using  the  notation
               Let’s assume that we are going to add two odd         and
               integers







                                        or                           By adding to odd numbers, we arrive to
                                                                                .






               Let:
                                                                     We are now then going to assign
                                                                                    since if we add any two






                                                                     integers and constant, we will also get an
               So we have:                                           integer.



               By arriving to this, we were able to prove that any   Arriving to     denotes that any integers

               integers multiplied by 2 is an even number, as such,  that we are going to multiply to 2 is an
               the sum of which is always even.                      even number since their sum is even.]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on

                                                    Story Telling]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[The Most Important Question









                 The Kingdom
                                                                      Once upon a time there was a
                 of the Prince

                                                                      prince who always want what’s
                                                                       best for his Kingdom. He get
                                                                       this being perfectionist to his

                                                                      late Mother Queen. He always
                                                                        looking for an answer to his
                                                                      exceptional question. One day,
                                                                      a bright and unusual question

                                                                     came to his mind but he did not
                                                                          know the answer. So he
                                                                        decided to give a reward to

                                                                      those who will answer his one

                                                                          important question. The
                                                                        question is what is the right
                                                                       thing to do and when was the

                                                                                  right time?]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[But then again others
                                                                       said there were some
                                                                      things which could not
                                                                       wait to be laid before,
          After hearing the announcement of the Prince, the gre  at    but about which one
          men of every kingdom came to give their answers. They        had at once to decide

         answered the question differently. The first man replied that   whether to undertake
          to know the right time to take an action, you must plan it       them or not.

         ahead of time, one must draw up in advance, and must live
         strictly according to it. Only thus, said he, could everyth  ing
            be done at its proper time and the right thing to do as

           well.  Others declared that it was impossible to decide                                 In order to decide
           beforehand the right time for every action; but that, not                                that, one must

          letting oneself be absorbed in idle pastimes, one should                                 know beforehand

          always attend to all that was going on, and then do what                                what was going to
                                                                                                   happen. It is only
        was most needful. Some, again, said that however attentive                                  magicians who

        the Prince might be to what was going on, it was impossible                                 know that; and,
           for one man to decide correctly the right time for every                               therefore, in order

          action and the right decision to make, but that he should                                to know the right

          have a council of wise men, who would help him to fix the                                 time for every
                         proper time for everything                                                action, the prince

                                                                                                     must consult
                                                                                                      magicians






                                                                           The Prince was not satisfied with
                                                                            the answers of the learned and

                                                                           intelligent men. He did not agree
                                                                              with any of those incredible
                                                                           answers. But still he is not giving

                                                                           up that someone will answer this
                                                                             very important question. One
                                                                           day a little boy came to him and
                                                                           told him that he has an old friend

                                                                             in the forest who is witty and
                                                                               wise and he knows all the
                                                                             answers to all questions. His

                                                                            Majesty did not waste time and
                                                                             he hurriedly went to the forest
                                                                             together with his guard but he
                                                                           left his guards at the opening of

                                                                             the forest so that the old man
                                                                              would not be frightened and
                                                                                  answer his question.]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[When the Prince reached the hut of the old wise man he saw the latter fixing something on his fence. He
          went pounding and pounding and he noticed that the old man was exhausted and tired as a horse carrying a
           bunch of load. When the old man noticed the Prince, he greeted him and gave respect and asked him what

           he can do for the Prince and what made him go to that forest. The Prince replied” a little boy recommended
          a witty and wise man who answers all the questions.” The old wise smiled and continued his repair. What is

          that most important question that made you decide to go into this peculiar and freaky forest? The Prince saw
               the weakness of the man so he took the hammer   to the latter and he continued pounding and said.


            It came to my mind that to be the
          best Prince, what was the right thing
           to do and when was the right time?

















             The old wise man answered in figurative words “you are now

           doing the right thing at the right time, you have been answered.”

          The Prince furrowed his brow and was confused. He said, what do
           you mean and how was it answered while you were not? The old,

                        weak, frail, wise man smiled and replied,





                                                                                         The moment you decided to help

                                                                                          me without hesitation that you
                                                                                          might be get dirty and the fact

                                                                                         that you are a Prince doing this
                                                                                         kind of thing is the right decision
                                                                                        and thing to do, and the right time
                                                                                        was the time you decided to help.
                                                                                           Being a Prince, the will and
                                                                                         enthusiasm to help regardless of
                                                                                         the status and ability to pay back
               The Prince left the                                                        with no hesitation and regrets
                                                                                         and the sacrifices are the “most
             forest very happy and                                                       right thing” in this world and from
             ordered his council to                                                      the moment you decided to help
                                                                                        was the “most right time”. You will
             make the old man one                                                           be the best Prince in your
                                                                                                   Kingdom.
               of his advisers.]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[Prepared by:

                                                  Cedillo, Aubrey


                                                Gambala, Haydee


                                                 Zabala, Romulo

                                                      BSEE 2-1




                                                   Presented to:


                                             Mr. Audreyson Borilla

                                 BSEE 32 – Children and Adolescent



                                                      Literature]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on

                                   Presentation and Reporting]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[DEVELOPMENT OF CHILDREN’S



                                     LITERATURE AND ADOLESCENT]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[(Ancient Greece and Rome)


                                                    Oral         literature        was        the       principal
                                                      entertainment for most people during this

                                                      period.
                                                    Purpose            of      storytelling           was        for

                                                      entertainment,  comfort,  instruction  for


                                                      young  in  living  and  to  pass  on  their
                                                      religious and cultural heritage.
                                                    Kept ancient stories alive.
                                                    Children  and  adults  shared  a  common

                                                      literature.
                                                    No distinction between adult and children

                                                      literature.

                                                    GREEK STORIES (500 BCE):


                                               -Trojan  War  (from  Homer’s  Iliad),  Travels  of
                                               Odysseus (from Homer’s Odyssey, Jason and
                                               the  Golden  Fleece  and  adventures  of
                                               Hercules.


                                               -  Aesop’s  Fables:  animal  tale  with  moral  to
                                               instruct  children  and  cultural  and  personal

                                               values.]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[ ROMAN STORIES (100 CE)

                                              -Tales  of  Virgil’s  Aeneid,  (Stories  of  Aeneas,
                                              Trojan  hero  credited  for  founding  the  Roman


                                              race.
                                              -Tales  of  Ovid’s  Metamorphose,  (tales  of  gods,

                                              goddesses, heroes, and heroines of the classical
                                              world.


                                                   MODERN  RETELLING  OF  GREEKS  AND
                                                     ROMAN STORIES

                                              -Most famous are Padraic Colum’s, The Children

                                              of Homers, The Golden Fleece, etc.

                                              -Bulfinch’s Mythology (Thomas Bulfinch)


                                               age of Fables, stories of gods and heroes.]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[(Between the fall of Rome and


                                                           The Rise of the Renaissance)


                                                   Roman  Catholic  Church  dominated  the
                                                     social  and  political  scene;  responsible  for

                                                     what education there was.



                                                   Religious Tales

                                              -Biblical  stories  were  very  popular;  the  lives  of

                                              saints  were  used  to  set  example  for  young
                                              people in didactic purpose.


                                                   Romantic Tales

                                              -Secular stories (Medieval  Romances) were also
                                              popular  such  as  King  Arthur  and  his  knights  in

                                              the  round  table,  The  epic  describing  the heroes
                                              Roland etc.]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[ Children’s version for these tales

                                                  -Rosemary Sutcliff’s Dragon Slayer- a retelling

                                                       of Beowulf and her King Arthur stories:

                                                  “Sword and Circle”, “Light beyond the forest”,

                                                                      “Road to Camlann”
                                                   -Bulfinch’s Mythology (By Thomas Bulfinch)


                                                       Beowulf; Children’s Bible stories, God’s
                                                                      Stories for Children.]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[(A time for a Rebirth of the ideals of ancient

                                                                     Greece and Rome)


                                                    The rise of Education books.


                                                    During this period printing press were


                                                      invented which made it possible to make
                                                      multiple copies of books, invented by

                                                      Johannes Gutenberg.

                                               -during the early Renaissance most books for

                                               children were textbooks or educational books.
                                               “Books of courtesy” giving lesson in proper
                                               behavior for young gentlemen.


                                               -Woman’s did not yet merit their own books.

                                                     -Orbis Sensualism Pictus by John

                                                       Comenius (1658)
                                                       -The first children’s picture book.
                                                          st
                                                       -1  appeared in German/Latin Version
                                                       (1658)
                                                          nd
                                                       -2  as an English/Latin Version (1659)]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[ Two specific influence needs of the child.
                                                     -Spiritual Development

                                                     -Intellectual Development


                                                   New England Primer

                                                     - The most famous early school books,


                                                         first appearing around 1690. It introduced
                                                         young puritan children to the alphabet
                                                         through rhymes, reading material, and all
                                                         religious intent.

                                                   Chapbooks
                                                     - Small and cheaply made books
                                                         containing fairy tales and other secular

                                                         books.

                                              -Thought’s concerning Education, famous essay
                                              written by John Locke, He believed every child

                                              had equal capabilities to learn and adult had the
                                              responsibility to provide proper education.


                                                   Children continue to adopt certain adult
                                                     works of literature.
                                                   Some famous work were retold and

                                                     rewritten from time to time in various
                                                     versions for children.]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[ Publishing of Children’s books

                                                        -began notably  by John Newberry (1713-
                                                        1778)

                                                        -books  were  largely  collections  of  story

                                                        and  poems  with  Crude  woodblock

                                                        illustrations.

                                                      A Little Pretty Pocket Book (1744)
                                                        -One  of  the  first  published  children’s

                                                        books  to  entertain  children  and  teach
                                                        them.
                                                      Rousseau and Moral Tale
                                                        -Rise of Moralistic tales

                                                        -express  his  ideas  in  education  and
                                                        emphasize  the  importance  of  moral
                                                        development.

                                                        -Rousseau  followers  wrote  didactic  and
                                                        moralistic books to teach children.
                                                        Most writers were woman]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[ Folktales  from  old  tradition  revived
                                                       during this time.

                                                     Tales of Mother Goose

                                                       -retold  and  published  by  the  Frenchman
                                                       Charles Parrault (1697)

                                                       -usually retold for moral purpose.

                                                     Tales from the Arabian Nights
                                                       -published  by  Elizabeth  Newberry  (1791)
                                                       first  children  edition  of  the  Middle

                                                       Eastern tales.
                                                     Han’s  Christian  Anderson’s  Fairy  Tales
                                                       (1835,  Denmark)  considered  the  first
                                                       book containing modern fairy tales.]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[ During        the  reign  of  Queen  Victoria  (1837-
                                                     1901)
                                                     -Children’s literature first blossomed




                                                   Rise of Modern Fantasy
                                                     -Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland (1865) by
                                                     Lewis Carroll (England)
                                                     Beginning a new era in Children’s literature.


                                                     -The Adventures of Pinocchio (1883) by Carlo
                                                     Collodi’s (Italy)

                                                     Most famous puppet story.

                                                     -The Wonderful Wizard of Oz (1900) by Frank
                                                     Baum (U.S)

                                                     The  first  classic  U.S  modern  fantasy  for
                                                     children’s.]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[-The  Tale  of  Peter  Rabbit  (1901)  by
                                                          Beatrix Potter.
                                                          Early         important           modern            picture

                                                          storybook in English.

                                                        Rise of Realistic Stories


                                                          -Little  Woman  (1868)  by  Louisa  May
                                                          Alcott (U.S).
                                                          Early  family  story  of  great  popularity

                                                          (girl’s story)

                                                          -Treasure Island (1881) by Robert Louis

                                                          Stevenson (England).
                                                          Famous classic adventures story (Boy’s
                                                          story)]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[ Children’s  literature  began  to  flourish  on  a
                                                   variety of fronts.

                                                Theme is focused on children themselves.

                                                Fantasy stories and realistic fiction has been

                                                   popular.



                                               - Winnie the Pooh (1926) by A.A. Milne (U.K).
                                                   Early classic personified by toy animal story.


                                               - Little  house  in the  big wood (1932) by  Laura
                                                   Ingalls Wilder (U.S).
                                                   Classic historical fiction based in the authors’

                                                   childhood.

                                                Popularity  of  the  publication  of  picture
                                                   storybooks.

                                                Popularity  of  fantasy  stories  and  series
                                                   books.]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[- The  lion,  the  witch,  and  the  wardrobe


                                                        (1950) and sequels by C.S Lewis.
                                                        Early classic quest adventure for children



                                                     - Charlotte’s Web (1952) by E. B. White.
                                                        Classic U.S animal fantasy



                                                             Rise of new realism (After world war
                                                               II)
                                                             A  variety  of  cultures  presented  in

                                                               Children’s books
                                                             Emergence  of  awards  for  children’s
                                                               books         (the       earliest       one        was
                                                               Newberry Medal in 1922. U.S)

                                                             Study  of  children’s  literature  began
                                                                                                        th
                                                               in the last quarter of the 20  century.]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[SEVERINO, FIDEL JR. A.                                                          BEE-2-1

               MODULE 5                                                                        OUTPUT 1
               Instruction: Create a 10-item multiple choice test for a specific elementary level subject.

               Subject: Science 5

               Topic: Matter
               Direction: Choose the letter of the correct answer and write it on the blank provided at the left side of the
               paper before each number.

               ____ 1. What is the state of matter with a definite volume, but no fixed shape?

                       A.  Solid
                       B.  Matter
                       C.  Liquid
                       D.  Gas

               ____ 2. The process by which a liquid changes to a gas is called _____.
                       A.  Condensation
                       B.  Evaporation
                       C.  Precipitation
                       D.  Transpiration

               ____3. The molecules in a liquid are?

                       A.  Closer together than in a solid and further apart that in gas.
                       B.  Are spaced the same as in solids and gases.
                       C.  Closer than in gases but further apart in solids.
                       D.  None of the above.

               ____4. What are the states of matter that has definite size shape and weight?
                       A.  Gas
                       B.  Solid
                       C.  Matter
                       D.  Liquid

               ____5. What is volume?

                       A.  The amount of space that an object takes up.
                       B.  The amount of matter in a solid, liquid, or gas.
                       C.  The material through which an electrical charge can pass.
                       D.  A strong resistor that can stop most electrical charges.

               ____6. A pencil is a _____.
                       A.  Liquid
                       B.  Solid
                       C.  Plasma
                       D.  Gas]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on
                                        A  s s e s s  m  e n  t   o f   S k i l l s   o n

                               Data Organizing and Presentation]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[Classes f           CM        LCB       UCB        <cf       >cf       rf (%)
            30-38             8        34      29.5       38.5         8        50        16
            39-47            10        43      38.5       47.5        18        42        20
            48-56             5        52      47.5       56.5        23        32        10
            57-65             7        61      56.5       65.5        30        27        14
            66-74             5        70      65.5       74.5        35        20        10
            75-83             7        79      74.5       83.5        42        15        14
            84-92             8        88      83.5       92.5        50         8        16
            n = 50





                                           BSEM Class

            12

            10
                                                                                  30-38
             8                                                                    39-47
                                                                                  48-56
             6
                                                                                  57-65
             4                                                                    66-74
                                                                                  75-83
             2
                                                                                  84-92
             0
                                              f




                                              BSEM Class

                    12

                    10

                     8
                   Frequency  6                                                         f



                     4

                     2

                     0
                         30-38   39-47    48-56   57-65   66-74   75-83    84-92]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[Ariel Gabiana                                                                   BSEM 26
                 BSEM 2-1

                 Problem Set no. 2

                 I. Qualitative Variables


                 1. Based on the pie chart below, which was made from a sample of 800 students, construct a
                 frequency table of college majors.


                 College majors  Frequency  rf (%)
                 Psychology        384       48%
                 Biology           320       40%
                 Chemistry          64       8%
                 Physics            32       4%


                 2. Given the following data, construct a pie chart and a bar chart. Which do you think is
                 the more appropriate or useful way to display the data?


                     Favorite   Frequency
                   Movie Genre
                     Comedy         14
                      Horror        9
                    Romance         8
                      Action        12
                                                                           Favorite Movie Genre
                                                                    16
                              Favorite Movie Genre
                                                                    14
                                                                    12
                                                                    10
                                                                     8
                                                                     6
                                                                     4
                                                                     2
                                                                     0
                           Comedy   Horror  Romance  Action              Comedy  Horror  Romance  Action


                 For me, the more useful one was bar chart as we only need to show the frequency of the movie genre and
                 makes it easy to compare it to other.]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[II. Quantitative Variables

                 A test was administered to an BSEM class of 50 students resulted in the following scores.


                   Classes     f         CM        LCB      UCB      <cf       >cf     rf(%)
                   30-38       8         34       29.5      38.5      8        50       16
                   39-47      10         43       38.5      47.5      18       42       20
                   48-56       5         52       47.5      56.5      23       32       10
                   57-65       7         61       56.5      65.5      30       27       14
                   66-74       5         70       65.5      74.5      35       20       10
                   75-83       7         79       74.5      83.5      42       15       14
                   84-92       8         88       83.5      92.5      50       8        16


                        12

                        10


                         8

                         6

                         4


                         2

                         0
                              30-38   39-47    48-56   57-65    66-74   75-83    84-92




                                              Frequency Polygon
                         12

                         10

                         8

                         6

                         4
                         2

                         0
                              30-38   39-47    48-56   57-65    66-74   75-83    84-92]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on
                                        A  s s e s s  m  e n  t   o f   S k i l l s   o n

                                                   Book Review]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[Jan Eric C. Rin                                                             janeric.rin@cvsu.edu.ph

               BSEE-31                                                                                    201810096




               A. Title of the Piece: Magnificence




               B. Genre: General Fiction




               C. Introduction

                                       The story of Magnificence by Estrella Alfon took place at the house of the two
               children. The characters of the story are primarily Vicente the bus conductor, the mother, Oscar

               the little boy and the little girl. The story started with a man named Vicente coming to the house
               of  the  two  children  to  tutor  them  with  their  school  works.  The  family,  especially  the  mother

               trusted Vicente whole-heartedly for they think that the man was always so gentle, so kind, and
               there was nothing to fear with when he is around. When Vicente came earlier than usual one
               evening,  the  children  immediately  put  their  lesson  down  sharing  stories  to  him  about  his

               classmates being envy with the pencils he gave them. The children wanted Vicente to buy them
               more pencils. Then, Oscar was asked by Vicente to get a glass of water. Vicente held the little
               girl up lightly in his arms and held her to sit down on his lap. The little girl felt uncomfortable and

               kept squirming. Vicente’s face was wet with sweat and his eyes looked strange. The girl jumped
               away from Vicente. The mother saw what has happened. He slapped Vicente and threw him out
               of the house.




               D. Significant examples

                                                 The  story  is  a  fictional  story  because  it  is  product  of  the  author’s
               imagination.  The  story  reflects  most  of  the  people  in  our  society.  Vicente  used  pencils  to
               stimulate the little kids and earn their trust and also used the pencils so that they will be excited

               to see him again. The story shows how some people, especially today in times of poverty, will
               really do everything for them to be able to live. Pencils those times where sensational for kids

               that’s why it is the material used to catch the attention of the kids.]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[Vicente’s showed his “persona” during the neighbourhood association meeting. He was able to

               reach out and gain the trust of the children and their mother by showing his social personality.
               This is too please the children with his attitude. He, like earlier, even used pencils to catch the
               attention  of  the  children.  He  promises  to  give  them  pencils  so  that  they  will  look  forward  in

               seeing him. It is shown in the story that he promised an extra pencil to the little girl because
               she’s very smart but actually it was not really the reason. She did this so that the girl will really
               be happy and be able to induce envy in her classmates.



               E. Conclusion

                              “Magnificence” is a great piece of work written by Estrella Alfon. This literary work can
               have different meaning depending on what kind of approach was used. In this paper, formalistic

               and psychoanalytical criticism were applied. Using the formalistic approach, the students look
               into the details of the text itself including the characters, the setting, the point of view, the figures
               of  speech,  the plot and  others.  Through  this,  the students  found  out  that  Magnificence  is an

               adjective  used  to  describe  the  mother’s  character  and  upon  reading  the  story  the  students
               conclude that it can represent universality since the mother’s name was unknown this literally
               means  that  Magnificence.  It  is  used  not  only  to  describe  the  mother  in  the  story  but  all  the

               mothers  in  the  world.It  was  also  observed  that  the  setting  of  the  story  is  actually  in  their
               household  meaning  it  can  happen  anywhere  and  anytime.  Using  psychoanalytical  approach,
               different symbolisms were identified to represent different meanings. Like how pencil was used

               to represent a phallic symbol that symbolizes the male’s reproductive organ. Every color of the
               pencil  that  Vicente  gave  to  the  children  represents  meanings—red  for  power,  sexuality,  and

               passion, yellow for intelligence and consciousness and white for purity and innocence. Using all
               the symbolisms and interpreting those, students concluded that the girl was a victim of sexual
               molestation. Hence, “Magnificence” is a literary piece that tackles about what truly a mother is

               and how magnificent they are in terms of showing their motherly love and protectiveness. Also,
               the generalizations of the violence in the world as it can happen anywhere and anytime.]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on
                                        A  s s e s s  m  e n  t   o f   S k i l l s   o n

                                 Module Making and Designing]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[BSEM 24

                                     Plane and Solid Geometry



                 THREE-DIMENTIONAL FIGURES













                                                      Prepared by
                                                RONNIE CUYOS DAEF
                                                       BSEM 3-1
                                                       June 2021






                                                      Checked by
                                            Ms. MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                                            BSEM 40, Assistant Professor]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[Copyright disclaimer:
               Borrowed materials and contents found on this module are owned by their respective
               copyright holders. The author does not represent nor claim ownership over them.]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[Three-Dimensional


                                           Figures






               Learning Intended Outcomes

               At the end of the lesson, the learners are expected to:

                     Identify 3D objects
                     Define 3 Dimensional
                     Classify items according to different types of 3D objects
                     Know how to find surface are and volume of a 3D object.
                   

               How can we consider that an object is a Three-Dimensional Figure?

               You can classify three-dimensional figures based on
               information  about  their  faces,  bases,  edges,  and
               vertices.  Three-dimensional  figures  include  prisms
               and  pyramids,  as  well  as  figures  with  curved
               surfaces.


                                  A prism is a three-dimensional figure with two parallel, congruent bases.
                                  The bases, which are also two of the faces, can be any polygon. The
                                  other faces are rectangles. A prism is named according to the shape of
                                  its bases.



                                  A pyramid is a three-dimensional figure with only one base. The base
                                  can be any polygon. The other faces are triangles. A pyramid is named
                                  according to the shape of its base.




                  Vocabulary
                     Cone: A three-dimensional object that has a circular base and one vertex.
                     Cube: A three-dimensional object that has six equal-sized square faces and
                      eight vertices.
                     Cylinder:  A  three-dimensional  object  with  two  circular  bases  and  a  curved
                      side.
                     Rectangular Prism: A three-dimensional object with six rectangular faces.
                     Sphere: A round three-dimensional object, like a ball.]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[Chapter

                                                Prism and Pyramids

                      1



               Triangular Prism

               A triangular prism is a polyhedron, (three-dimensional shape)
               made up of two triangular bases and three rectangular sides. Like
               other Prisms, the two bases here are parallel and congruent to
               each other. It has 5 faces, 6 vertices and 9 edges in total.


               Triangular Prism is a pentahedron and has nine distinct nets. The edges and vertices of
               the bases are joined with each other via three rectangular sides.

               The  sides  of  triangular  prism,  which  are
               rectangular  in  shape  are  joint  with  each  other   Facts
               side  by  side.  All  cross-sections  parallel  to  the     Number of faces = 5
               base  faces  are  the  same  as  a  triangle.  A        Number of edges = 9
               triangular  pyramid  has  four  triangular  bases       Number of vertices = 6
               unlike  the  triangular  prism,  joined  with  each     Shape of the base = Triangular
               other and all are congruent to each other.              Shape of Sides = Rectangular
                                                                       Surface  Area  =  2(Area  of
               In geometry, a triangular prism is a type of prism       triangular  bases)+Perimeter  of
               with three sides and two bases. The sides are of         base x Height of prism
               rectangle shape and bases are of triangle shape.        Volume = Area of base x Height
               Altogether, it has five faces, nine vertices and six     of Prism
               edges.
               The sides and bases of the triangular prism are congruent or else oblique. The edges of the
               prism join the corresponding sides.  The two bases of this prism are equilateral triangles and
               edges of these triangles are parallel to each other. See the below figure to understand the
               structure
















                                              Dissected Triangular Prism]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[Properties
               Let us discuss some of the properties of the triangular prism.

                     It  has  a  total  of  9  edges,  5  faces,  and  6  vertices  (which  are  joined  by  the
                       rectangular faces).
                     It has two triangular bases and three rectangular sides.
                     If the triangular bases are equilateral and the other faces are squares, instead
                       of a rectangle, then the triangular prism is said to be semi regular.


               Volume
               The volume of a triangular prism is equal to the product of the triangular base area
               and the height of the prism.

                       Formula:





                                    Where b is the base length, h is the height of the triangle
                                        and l is the length between the triangular bases.


                       Example:

                              Find the volume of the triangular prism with base is 5 cm, height is 10
                       cm, and length is 15 cm.


                       Given:






                       Solution:]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[Surface Area
               Surface area of triangular prism is equal to the sum of the lateral surface area and
               twice the base area of the triangular prism. It is measured in square units.

                       Formula:



                             Where A is the area of the triangular bases, P is the perimeter of the bases
                                               and H is the height of the prism.
                       Now,





                       If a, b and c are the sides of the triangular bases, then



                       Therefore,


                                                                      (        )   (         )


                       or


                                                                    (     (         ) )

                       Where b and h is the base and height of the bases, respectively and H is the height of the prism.



                       Example:

                              If  the  height  of  the  prism  is  4cm  and  the  length  of  the  side  of  the
                       equilateral triangular base is 6cm. Then find the area of the prism with base is
                       5 cm, height is 10 cm, and length is 15 cm.


                       Given:






                               As the base is an equilateral triangle, therefore all its sides will be equal.
                               Hence,]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[Solution:

                                                                    (     (         ) )

                                   (             (               )   )


                                   (       (    )   )

                                   (            )








               Right Triangular Prism

               A  right  triangular  prism  has  its  three  rectangular  sides  congruent.  Also,  the  two
               triangular bases are parallel and congruent to each other. The rectangular or lateral
               faces are perpendicular to the triangular bases.


               Triangular Prism Net
               If we open each face of the triangular prism, we will get the net. The net of this prism
               comprises three rectangles and two triangles. In the below figure you can see the
               nine distinct nets.












                         Exercise
               Find the volume and surface area of a triangular prism with a right-angled triangle
               base, if length of the prism base legs are 7.2 cm and 4.7 cm and height of a prism is
               24 cm.]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[Rectangular Prism

               A rectangular prism is a three-dimensional shape. It has
               six faces,  and all  the  faces  of  the  prism  are  rectangles.
               Both  the  bases  of  a  rectangular  prism  must  be  a
               rectangle. Also, the other lateral faces will be rectangles.
               It is also called a cuboid.

               A rectangular prism is a polyhedron with two congruent and parallel bases. It is also
               a cuboid. It has six faces, and all the faces are in a rectangle shape and have twelve
               edges. Because of its cross-section along the length, it is said to be a prism. Similar
               to triangle, square and pentagonal prism, it also has its surface area. The surface
               area of the prism is the area of its net. In this article, let us discuss the definition,
               types, surface area, and volume of a rectangular prism in detail.


               Properties
               Let us discuss some of the properties of the rectangular prism.

                     It has 6 rectangular faces, 12 edges and 8 vertices.
                     Opposite faces are in rectangle shape
                     It has a rectangular cross-section
                     It looks exactly like a cuboid


               Types
               Rectangular prism can be classified into two different types. They are:

                   1.  Right Rectangular Prism
                   2.  Oblique Rectangular Prism


               Right Rectangular Prism
               A  prism  with  rectangular  bases  is  called  a  rectangular  prism.  A  right  rectangular
               prism  is  a  prism  that  has  six  faces  that  are  rectangles,  and  all  angles  are  right
               angles.

                     Vertices of a rectangular prism = 8
                     Edges of a rectangular prism = 12
                     Faces of a rectangular prism= 6 (including bases)


                                              Oblique Rectangular Prism
                                              An oblique prism is a prism in which the bases are not
                                              perpendicular to each other. A rectangular prism with
                                              bases that are not aligned one directly above the other
                                              is an oblique rectangular prism.]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[Volume
               The  volume  of  a  rectangular  prism  is  a  measurement  of  the  occupied  units  of  a
               rectangular prism. The volume of a rectangular prism is represented by cubic units. It
               is also defined as the number of units used to fill a rectangular prism.


                       Formula:





                                     Where l is the length, w is the width and h is the height.



                       Example:

                              Find the volume of a rectangular prism whose length, width, and height
                       are 8cm, 6cm, and 4cm, respectively.


                       Given:






                       Solution:]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[Surface Area
               The surface area of a rectangular prism is the measure of how much exposed area a
               prism  has.  Surface  area  is  expressed  in  square  units.  The  surface  area  of  a
               rectangular prism is the sum of the lateral surface area and twice the base area of
               the rectangular prism.

                       Formula:

                                                                             (         )

                       To get the Lateral Surface Area, we need to follow the formula:



                       Where P is the perimeter of a base and h is the height of the prism,

                       To get the P or the Perimeter of the rectangular prism we need to follow the formula:

                                                           (     )

                       Therefore, the surface area of a rectangular prism formula is given as:


                                                           (            )


                                     Where l is the length, w is the width, and h is the height.


                       Example:

                              Find the area of a rectangular prism whose length, width, and height
                       are 8cm, 6cm, and 4cm, respectively.


                       Given:






                       Solution:

                                                              (            )

                                    ((         )   (         )   (         ))




                                    (                   )


                                    (      )]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[Rectangular Prism Net
               The net of any prism is the surface area of it. It shows when we open the prism in a
               plane;  then  all  its  sides  could  be  visible  at  the  same  time.  If  we  calculate  the
               individual area of all its sides using the net, we will get the total surface area. See the
               figure below to find the net for the rectangular prism.




















               You can see from the above figure, all the sides of the prism are in a rectangular
               shape. By using the formula for the area of rectangle, you can find the areas for each
               face and add all the areas to get the net of the prism.




                         Exercise
               Find the volume of the following rectangular prism.]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[Cube

               Sometimes, the shape of a cube is considered as “cubic”. We
               can also say that a cube is considered as a block, where all
               the length, breadth and height are the same. Along with that,
               it has 8 vertices and 12 edges such that 3 edges meet at one
               vertex point. Check the given image below, defining its faces,
               edges  and  vertices.  It  is  also  known  as  a  square
               parallelepiped,    an    equilateral   cuboid    and     a   right
               rhombohedrum. The cube is one of the platonic solids and it
               is considered as the convex polyhedron where all the faces
               are  square.  We  can  say  that  the  cube  has  octahedral  or
               cubical symmetry. A cube is the special case of the square
               prism.


                                        Cube is a solid three-dimensional figure, which has 6 square
                                        faces, 8 vertices and 12 edges. It is also said to be a regular
                                        hexahedron. You must have seen 3 × 3 Rubik’s cube, which
                                        is the most common example in the real-life and it is helpful
                                        to  enhance  brain  power.  In  the  same  way,  you  will  come
                                        across  many  real-life  examples,  such  as  6  sided  dice,  etc.
                                        Solid  geometry  is  all  about  three-dimensional  shapes  and
                                        figures,  which  have  surface  areas  and  volumes.  The  other
                                        solid shapes are cuboid, cylinder, cone, and sphere. We will
               discuss  here  its  definition,  properties  and  its  importance  in  Math.  Also,  learn  the
               surface area formula for the cube along with its volume formula.


               Cube Definition
               As discussed earlier, a cube is a 3-D solid shape, which has 6 faces. A cube is one
               of the simplest shapes in three-dimensional space. All the six faces of a cube are
               squares, a two-dimensional shape.




















               In the above figure, you can see, edge, face and vertex of the cube. Here, L stands
               for  length,  B  stands  for  breadth  and  H  stands  for  height. We  can  see  the  length,
               breadth and height of the cube, which represents the edges of the cube, connected
               at a single point which is the vertex. The faces of the cube are connected by four]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[vertices.  Since  the  cube  is  a  3D  shape,  the  two  important  parameters  used  to
               measure the cube are surface area and volume. Now let us discuss the properties of
               the cube along with the formula for surface area and volume.


               Properties
               The following are the important properties of cube:

                     It has 6 rectangular faces, 12 It has all its faces in a square shape.
                     All the faces or sides have equal dimensions.
                     The plane angles of the cube are the right angle.
                     Each of the faces meets the other four faces.
                     Each of the vertices meets the three faces and three edges.
                     The edges opposite to each other are parallel.


               Difference between Square and Cube
               The  major  difference  between  the  square  and  the  cube  is  the  square  is  a  two-
               dimensional  figure  and  it  has  only  two  dimensions  such  as  length  and  breadth,
               whereas the cube is a three-dimensional figure and its three dimensions are length,
               breadth and height. The cube is obtained from the shape square.




















                                  Square                                         Cube


               Volume
               The  volume  of  the  cube  is  the  space  contained  in  it.  Suppose,  if  an  object  is  in
               cubical  shape  and  we  need  to  immerse  any  material  in  it,  say  water,  then  the
               measure of water in liters to be kept in the object is calculated by its volume. The
               formula of the volume is given by:

                       Formula:



                                                           or





                                           Where s is the length of one of its sides.]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[Example:

                              What is the volume of a cube whose sides are 10 cm each?


                       Given:




                       Solution:





                                   (             )





               Surface Area
               We know that for any shape, the area is defined as the region occupied by it in a
               plane. A cube is a three-dimensional object; therefore, the area occupied by it will be
               in  a  3D  plane.  Since  a  cube  has  six  faces,  therefore,  we  need  to  calculate  the
               surface area of the cube, covered by each face. The formula to find the surface area
               can be found as given below.


                       Formula:

                       Let a be the edge of the cube




                       We know that the cube has 6 square shaped faces.

                                      (

                                                           or




                       Then,






                                                           Or



                       Therefore,




                                               Where a is the side of a square.]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[Example:

                              Find the surface area of a cube of a side length of 10 cm.


                       Given:




                       Solution:





                                    (    )


                                    (      )








                         Exercise
               The side length of the cube is 6 cm. Find its surface area.]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[Square Pyramid

               A three-dimensional geometric shape having a square
               base  and  four  triangular  faces/sides  that  meet  at  a
               single  point  is  called  a  square  pyramid.  If  all  the
               triangular faces have equal edges, then this pyramid
               is  said  to  be  an  equilateral  square  pyramid.  If  the
               apex  of  the  pyramid  is  right  above  the  center  of  its
               base, it forms a perpendicular with the base and such
               a  square  pyramid  is  known  as  the  right  square
               pyramid.

               A  Pyramid  is  a  polyhedron  that  has  a  base  and  3  or  greater  triangular faces  that
               meet at a point above the base (the apex). In the case of a square pyramid, the base
               is in square shape and it has four faces. A most famous example of such a pyramid
               in  real  life  is  the  Great  Pyramid  of  Giza.  On  a  small  scale  when  we  learn  about
               pyramids, then we have to learn the other concepts related to them, such as volume
               of pyramid, area of the pyramid. In this article, we will learn the definition of a square
               pyramid, types, properties, area and volume formulas with many solved examples.



               Representation of Square Pyramid
               A square pyramid is shown by the Wheel graph W5. A wheel graph is one formed by
               connecting a single universal vertex to all vertices of a cycle.















               Properties
               Let us discuss some of the properties of the square pyramid.

                     It has 5 Faces
                     The 4 Side Faces are Triangles
                     The Base is a Square
                     It has 5 Vertices (corner points)
                     It has 8 Edges


               Types
               Rectangular prism can be classified into two different types. They are:

                   1.  Equilateral Square Pyramid
                   2.  Right Square Pyramid]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[Equilateral Square Pyramid
               If all the edges are of equal length, then the sides form equilateral triangles, and the
               pyramid is an equilateral square pyramid.

               The Johnson square pyramid can be classified by a single edge-length parameter l.
               The height h, the surface area A, and the volume V of such a pyramid are:

                                   ( √ )



                                   (    √ )

                                    √





               Right Square Pyramid
               In a right square pyramid, all the lateral edges are of the same length, and the sides
               other than the base are congruent isosceles triangles.

               A right square pyramid with base length l and height h has the following formula for
               surface area and volume:

                                           √    (  )






                                        ( )





                                                      √





                                               √]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[Volume
               The volume of a pyramid is defined as the number of cubic units occupied by the
               pyramid. As stated before, the name of a pyramid is derived from the shape of its
               base. Therefore, the volume of a pyramid also depends on the shape of the base.


                       Formula:





                                       Where a is the base edge length and h is the height


                       Example:

                              Find  the  volume  of  a regular square  pyramid  with  base  sides  10  cm
                       and altitude 18 cm.


                       Given:





                       Solution:








                                   (    )]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[Surface Area
               We know that for any shape, the area is defined as the region occupied by it in a
               plane. A cube is a three-dimensional object; therefore, the area occupied by it will be
               in  a  3D  plane.  Since  a  cube  has  six  faces,  therefore,  we  need  to  calculate  the
               surface area of the cube, covered by each face. The formula to find the surface area
               can be found as given below.


                       Formula:


                                                            √




                                       Where a is the base edge length and h is the height

                       The general formula for the total surface area of a regular pyramid is given by:






                           Where P is the perimeter of the base, l is the slant height and B is the area of the base.


                       Example:

                              Find the total surface area of a regular pyramid having a square base
                       where the length of each edge of the base is equal to 16 cm, the slant height
                       of a side is 17 cm and the altitude is 15 cm.

                       Given:






                       Solution:






                                    (    )]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[(    )













                                     (    )(    )





















               Square Prism Net
               A net of a 3D shape is a pattern reached when the surface of a three-dimensional
               figure  is  laid  out  horizontally  showing  each  face  of  the  figure.  A  solid  may  have
               different nets.

               Steps to determine whether net forms a solid are as follows:

                   1.  Solid and the net should have the same number of faces. Also, the shapes of
                       the  faces  of  the  solid  should  match  with  the  shapes  of  the  corresponding
                       faces in the net.
                   2.  Imagine how the net is to be folded to create the solid and assure that all the
                       sides fit collectively properly.

               Nets are of use when we need to find the surface area of the solids.]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[Exercise
               Find the surface area of a square pyramid with a base length of 5 cm, and a slant
               height of 10 cm.]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[Triangular Pyramid

               A  triangular  pyramid  is  a  pyramid  which  has  a
               triangular  base.  In  geometry,  vertices  are
               essentially     corners.    All    triangular-based
               pyramids,  either  regular  or  irregular,  have  four
               vertices.

               Triangular-based pyramids have 6 edges, 3 are
               along the base and 3 are extending up from the
               base. If the six edges are of the same length, all
               the triangles are equilateral, and the pyramid is
               called a regular tetrahedron.

               A Pyramid is a polyhedron that has a base and three or more than three triangular
               faces  that  meeting  at  a  point  above  the  base  (the  apex). Triangular  pyramids  are
               formed  solely  from  triangles.  The  3  triangular  sides  slant  upwards  to  form  the
               triangular base. As it is formed from four triangles, a triangular-based pyramid is also
               called a tetrahedron.

               The  base  of  the  pyramid  could  be  based  on  different  types  of  triangles.  If  all  the
               faces are equilateral triangles or triangles whose edges are all the equal lengths, the
               pyramid  is  called  a  regular  tetrahedron.  If  the  triangles  have  edges  of  various
               lengths, the pyramid is an irregular tetrahedron.


               Properties
               Let us discuss some of the properties of the triangular pyramid.

                     It has 4 faces.
                     The 3 side faces are triangles.
                     The base is also a triangle.
                     It has 4 vertices (corner points).
                     It has 6 edges & also a tetrahedron.



               Types
               Rectangular prism can be classified into two different types. They are:

                   1.  Regular Triangular Pyramid
                   2.  Non-Regular Triangular Pyramid
                   3.  Right Triangular Pyramid


               Regular Triangular Pyramid
               A pyramid which has a base with sides those are equal in length. For the triangular
               pyramid, the base of regular tetrahedron should be an equilateral triangle.]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[Non-Regular Triangular Pyramid
               A pyramid which has a base with sides that have different lengths. The base of the
               triangular pyramid has unequal sides. Or we can say, the base could be a scalene
               triangle or an isosceles triangle.


               Right Triangular Pyramid
               Three-Dimensional  shape  with  a  right-angle  triangle  at  its  base  extruding  up  to  a
               single point is a right-triangular pyramid.


               Volume
               To find the volume of a triangular-based pyramid, multiply the area of the triangular
               base and  the  height  of the  pyramid  (measured from the  base  to  the  apex).  Then,
               divide this number by three.

                       Formula:





                                          Where B is the base area and h is the height


                       Example:

                              Find  the  volume of  a triangular  pyramid  with  the base  area  is 28cm,
                       height is 4.5cm.


                       Given:





                       Solution:






                                    (    )(     )




                                    (      )]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[Surface Area
               To determine the surface area of a triangular-based pyramid, add together the area
               of the base and area of all the sides.

               For regular tetrahedra, this calculation is simple. Find the length of the base and the
               height of one of the triangles. Multiply those measurements collectively and divide
               this number by two. This is the area of one of the triangles.

               Now, multiply this area by four to account for all the triangular faces of the pyramid.
               For irregular tetrahedra, find the area of every triangle individually, using the area
               formula. Then, add all the areas together.


                       Formula:





                             Where B is the base area, P is the perimeter and l is the slant length/height


                       Example:

                              Find  the  surface  area  of  a  triangular  pyramid  with  the  base  area  is
                       28   , perimeter is 20cm, and slant length is 5cm.



                       Given:







                       Solution:






                                          (    )(   )






                                          (      )]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[Triangular Prism Net
               A net of the triangular pyramid is the pattern formed when the surface of it is laid out
               flat showing each triangular face of the figure. For different types of solids, the net
               pattern is different.

               To find the net of a solid we should keep a note of the following points:

                     Make sure the pyramid and the net have an equal number of faces.
                     The shapes of the faces of the pyramid should match the shapes of the
                       corresponding faces in the net.
                     Imagine how the net can be folded to form the pyramid and assure that all the
                       sides fit together properly.
























                     Note: Nets are helpful when we need to find the surface area of the solids.



                         Exercise
               Find  the  volume  of  the  following  triangular  pyramid,

               rounding your answer to two decimal places.]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[Chapter
                                    Three Dimensional Figures with



                      2                             Curved Surfaces



               Cylinder

               A cylinder is a three-dimensional solid that holds two
               parallel bases joined by a curved surface, at a fixed
               distance.  These  bases  are  normally  circular  in
               shape (like a circle) and the center of the two bases
               is joined by a line segment, which is called the axis.
               The  perpendicular  distance  between  the  bases  is
               the height, “h” and the distance from the axis to the
               outer surface is the radius “r” of the cylinder.

               Cylinder is one of the basic 3D shapes, in geometry, which has two parallel circular
               bases at a distance. The two circular bases are joined by a curved surface, at a fixed
               distance from the center. The line segment joining the center of two circular bases is
               the axis of the cylinder. The distance between the two circular bases is called the
               height of the cylinder. LPG gas-cylinder is one of the real-life examples of cylinders.

               Since,  the  cylinder  is  a  three-dimensional  shape;  therefore  it  has  two  major
               properties,  i.e.,  surface  area  and  volume. The  total  surface  area of  the  cylinder is
               equal to the sum of its curved surface area and area of the two circular bases. The
               space occupied by a cylinder in three dimensions is called its volume.


               Properties
               Each  shape  has  some  properties  that  differentiate  one  shape  from  another.
               Therefore, cylinders also have its characteristics.

                     The bases are always congruent and parallel.
                     If  the  axis  forms  a  right  angle  with  the  bases,  which  are  exactly  over  each
                       other, then it is called a “Right Cylinder”.
                     It is similar to the prism since it has the same cross-section everywhere.
                     If the bases are not exactly over each other but sideways, and the axis does
                       not produce the right angle to the bases, then it is called “Oblique Cylinder”.
                     If the bases are circular in shape, then it is called a right circular cylinder.
                     If the bases are in an elliptical shape, then it is called an “Elliptical Cylinder”.]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[Cylinder Shape
                                            A cylinder is a three-dimensional shape consisting of two
                                            parallel  circular  bases,  joined  by  a  curved  surface.  The
                                            center of the circular bases overlaps each other to form a
                                            right cylinder. The line segment joining the two centers is
                                            the axis, which denotes the height of the cylinder.

                                            The top view of the cylinder looks like a circle and the side
                                            view of the cylinder looks like a rectangle.

                                            Unlike cones, cube and cuboid, a cylinder does not have
                                            any vertices, since the cylinder has a curved shape and
               no straight lines. It has two circular faces.


               Volume
               Every three dimensional shape or a solid has volume that occupies some space. The
               volume of the cylinder is the space occupied by it in any three-dimensional plane.
               The amount of water that could be immersed in a cylinder is described by its volume.
               The formula for the volume of cylinder is given by:


                       Formula:





                                           Where r is the radius and h is the height


                       Example:

                              What is the volume of a cylindrical shape water container that has a
                       height of 7cm and diameter of 10cm?


                       Given:





                       Solution:]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[(    )(   ) (   )


                                    (    )(     )(   )


                                    (    )(      )






               Surface Area
               There are two types of surface area when dealing with cylinder:

                   1.  Curved Surface Area
                   2.  Total Surface Area



               Curved Surface Area
               It is the area of the curved surface of the cylinder which is contained between the
               two parallel circular bases. It is also stated as a lateral surface area. The formula for
               it is given by:


                       Formula:




                                           Where r is the radius and h is the height


                       Example:

                              Find the area of the curved surface of a cylindrical tin with radius 7 cm
                       and height 4 cm.


                       Given:]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[Solution:



                                       (    )(   )(   )


                                       (    )(     )


                                       (        )





               Total Surface Area
               The total surface area of a cylinder is the sum of curved surface area and the area of
               two circular bases.


                       Formula:

                                                                    (     )


                                           Where r is the radius and h is the height

                       Example:

                              Find  the  total  surface  area  of  the  cylinder,  whose  radius  is  5cm  and
                       height, is 10cm?

                       Given:





                       Solution:

                                                        (     )

                                       (    )(   )(          )

                                       (    )(   )(    )


                                       (    )(     )


                                       (        )]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[Exercise
               A cylinder has height 5cm and radius of 3cm. Find the volume,
               curved surface area and total surface area.]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[Cone

               A  cone  is  a  three-dimensional  shape  in  geometry  that  narrows
               smoothly from a flat base (usually circular base) to a point (which
               forms an axis to the center of base) called the apex or vertex. We
               can also define the cone as a pyramid which has a circular cross-
               section,  unlike  pyramid  which  has  a  triangular  cross-section.
               These cones are also stated as a circular cone.

               A  cone  is  a  shape  formed  by  using  a  set  of  line  segments  or  the  lines  which
               connects a common point, called the apex or vertex, to all the points of a circular
               base (which does not contain the apex). The distance from the vertex of the cone to
               the base is the height of the cone. The circular base has measured value of radius.
               And the length of the cone from apex to any point on the circumference of the base
               is the slant height. Based on these quantities, there are formulas derived for surface
               area and volume of the cone. In the figure you will see, the cone which is defined by
               its height, the radius of its base and slant height.


               Properties
               Each  shape  has  some  properties  that  differentiate  one  shape  from  another.
               Therefore, cone also has its characteristics.

                     A cone has only one face, which is the circular base but no edges
                     A cone has only one apex or vertex point.


               Frustum of Right Circular Cone
               Frustum of a cone is a piece of the given circular or right circular cone, which is cut
               in a manner that the base of the solid and the plane cutting the solid are parallel to
               each other. Based on this, we can calculate the surface area and volume also.


               Types
               Basically, there are two types of cones;

                   1.  Right Circular Cone
                   2.  Oblique Cone


               Right Circular Cone
                            A  cone  which  has  a  circular  base  and  the axis from  the  vertex  of  the
                            cone towards the base passes through the center of the circular base.
                            The vertex of the cone lies just above the center of the circular base.
                            The word “right” is used here because the axis forms a right angle with
                            the base of the cone or is perpendicular to the base. This is the most
                            common  types  of  cones  which  are  used  in  geometry.  See  the  figure
                            below which is an example of a right circular cone.]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[Oblique Cone
               A  cone  which  has  a  circular  base  but  the  axis  of  the  cone  is  not
               perpendicular with the base, is called an Oblique cone. The vertex of this
               cone  is  not  located  directly  above  the  center  of  the  circular  base.
               Therefore, this cone looks like a slanted cone or tilted cone.



               Slant Height
               The slant height of the cone (specifically right circular) is the distance from the vertex
               or apex to the point on the outer line of the circular base of the cone. The formula for
               slant height can be derived by the Pythagoras Theorem.


                       Formula:

                                                               √



                                           Where r is the radius and h is the height


               Volume
               We can write, the volume of the cone (V) which has a radius of its circular base as
               “r”, height from the vertex to the base as “h”, and length of the edge of the cone is “l”.

                       Formula:


                                                        ( )



                                           Where r is the radius and h is the height


                       Example:

                              Find the volume of the cone if radius, r = 4 cm and height, h = 7 cm.


                       Given:





                       Solution:


                                      ( )]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[(    )(   ) (   )




                                    (    )(     )(   )




                                    (    )(      )




                                    (         )







               Surface Area
               The surface area of a right circular cone is equal to the sum of its lateral surface area
               (πrl) and surface area of the circular base(πr2). Therefore,

                       Formula:

                                                             (   )

                                           Where r is the radius and h is the height

                       Example:

                              What is the total surface area of the cone with the radius = 3 cm and
                       height = 5 cm?

                       Given:





                       Solution:


                                              √



                                        √(   )   (   )



                                  √



                                  √]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[(   )

                                       (   )

                                  (    )(   ) (√          )


                                  (    )(   )(            )

                                  (    )(   )(      )


                                  (    )(        )








                         Exercise
               Calculate the volume of a cone if the height is 12 cm and the radius is 7 cm.]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[Sphere

               In geometry,  a  sphere  is  a  solid  that  is  absolutely  round  in  shape
               defined in three-dimensional space (XYZ space). Mathematically, a
               sphere is defined as the set of points that is at equal distances from
               a common point in three dimensional spaces. This constant distance
               is  called  radius  of  sphere  and  the  common  point  is  the  center  of
               sphere. An example of sphere in real life is a ball.


               A sphere is a geometrical round shape in three
               dimensional  space.  It  is  three  dimensional        Facts
               solid that has surface area and volume. Just                 A sphere is always round
               like a circle, each point of the sphere is at a              A  sphere  does  not  have
               equal distance from the center.                               any sides or flat surfaces
                                                                            Volume  of  Sphere  =  4/3
               Unlike  circle,  which  is  a  plane  shape  or  flat         πr3
               shape,  defined  in  XY  plane,  a  sphere  is               Surface  area  of  sphere  =
               defined in three dimensions, i.e. x-axis, y-axis              4πr2
               and z-axis.                                                  A  sphere  is  a  symmetrical
                                                                             object
               The  shape of a  sphere  is round  and  it does              All  the  surface  points  of
               not have any faces. Sphere is a geometrical                   sphere  are  at  equidistant
               three  dimensional  solid  having  curved                     from center
               surface.  Like  other  solids,  such  as  cube,              A  sphere  has  only  curved
               cuboid, cone and cylinder, a sphere does not                  surface, no flat surface, no
                                                                             edges and no vertices.
               have any flat surface or a vertex or an edge.

               The real-life examples of sphere are:

                     Basket balls
                     World Globe
                     Marbles
                     Planets
                     Moon


               Properties
               The  important  properties  of  the  sphere  are  given  below.  These  are  also  called
               attributes of sphere.

                     A sphere is perfectly symmetrical.
                     It is not a polyhedron.
                     All the points on the surface are equidistant from the center.
                     It does not have a surface of centers.
                     It has constant mean curvature.
                     It has a constant width and circumference.]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[Hemisphere
               A hemisphere is exactly half of a sphere. It has a curved surface and a flat surface.


               Diameter
               We know that, the diameter is twice the radius. Therefore, diameter of a sphere is
               given as:

                       Formula:




                                                   Where r is the radius.


               Volume
               The  amount  of  space  occupied  by  the  object  three-dimensional
               object  called  a  sphere  is  known  as  the  volume  of  the  sphere.
               According  to  the  Archimedes  Principle,  the  volume  of  a  sphere  is
               given as:


                       Formula:



                                                         ( )


                                                   Where r is the radius.

                       Example:

                              Find the volume of the sphere that has a diameter of 10 cm.


                       Given:




                       Solution:]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[( )



                                    (    )(   )





                                    (    )(      )




                                    (        )










               Surface Area
               The surface area of a sphere is the total area covered by the surface of a sphere in a
               three dimensional space. The formula of surface are is given by:

                       Formula:


                                                                 (  )


                                             Where r is the radius of the sphere.

                       Example:

                              Determine the surface area of a sphere having a radius of 7 cm.


                       Given:




                       Solution:


                                                         (  )


                                    ( )(    )(   )]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[( )(    )(     )


                                    ( )(    )(     )


                                    ( )(          )








                         Exercise
               Find the volume of a sphere whose radius is 5 cm.]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[References

               Basic Mathematics. (n.d.). Surface area of a square pyramid. Retrieved June 2021,
                       from  BasicMathematics.com:  https://www.basic-mathematics.com/surface-
                       area-of-a-square-pyramid.html


               ByJu's.      (n.d.).     Cone.      Retrieved       June      2021,      from      ByJu's:
                       https://byjus.com/maths/cone/

               ByJu's.      (n.d.).     Cube.      Retrieved       June      2021,      from      ByJu's:
                       https://byjus.com/maths/cube/

               ByJu's.      (n.d.).    Cylinder.     Retrieved      June      2021,     from      ByJu's:
                       https://byjus.com/maths/cylinder/

               ByJu's.  (n.d.).  Rectangular  Prism.  Retrieved  June  2021,  from  ByJu's:
                       https://byjus.com/maths/rectangular-prism/

               ByJu's.      (n.d.).    Sphere.      Retrieved      June      2021,      from      ByJu's:
                       https://byjus.com/maths/sphere/


               ByJu's.    (n.d.).   Square     Pyramid.    Retrieved     June    2021,    from    ByJu's:
                       https://byjus.com/maths/square-pyramid/

               ByJu's.    (n.d.).   Triangular   Prism.    Retrieved     June    2021,    from    ByJu's:
                       https://byjus.com/maths/triangular-prism/

               ByJu's.  (n.d.).  Triangular  Pyramid.  Retrieved  June  2021,  from  ByJu's:
                       https://byjus.com/maths/triangular-pyramid/

               Lumen. (n.d.). Finding the Volume and Surface Area of a Cylinder. Retrieved June
                       2021,                  from                  Lumen:                   Prealgebra:
                       https://courses.lumenlearning.com/prealgebra/chapter/finding-the-volume-
                       and-surface-area-of-a-cylinder/

               Math-Exercises.  (n.d.).  Math  Exercises  &  Math  Problems:  Volument  and  Surface
                       Area  of  Solids.  Retrieved  June  2021,  from  Math-Exercises.com:
                       https://www.math-exercises.com/stereometry/volume-and-surface-area-of-
                       solids


               Maths  Teachers.  (n.d.).  Curved  Surface  Area  of  a  Cylinder.  Retrieved  June  2021,
                       from                                                               MathsTeacher:
                       https://www.mathsteacher.com.au/year9/ch14_measurement/14_curved/cylin
                       der.htm

               Online Math Learning. (n.d.). Surface Area of a Pyramid. Retrieved June 2021, from
                       OnlineMathLearning.com:  https://www.onlinemathlearning.com/surface-area-
                       pyramid.html]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[Online Math Learning. (n.d.). Volume of a Rectangular Prism. Retrieved June 2021,
                       from  OnlineMathLearning.com:  https://www.onlinemathlearning.com/volume-
                       rectangular-prism.html

               Story  of  Mathematics.  (n.d.).  Surface  Area  of  a  cube  -  Explanation  &  Examples.
                       Retrieved     June      2021,     from     The      Story     of    Mathematics:
                       https://www.storyofmathematics.com/surface-area-of-a-cube

               Story of Mathematics. (n.d.). Volume of Cubes - Explanation & Examples. Retrieved
                       June        2021,       from        The        Story        of      Mathematics:
                       https://www.storyofmathematics.com/volume-of-a-cube


               Story  of  Mathematics.  (n.d.).  Volume  of  Pyramid  -  Explanation  &  Examples.
                       Retrieved     June      2021,     from     The      Story     of    Mathematics:
                       https://www.storyofmathematics.com/volume-of-a-pyramid]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[S
                                                                        k

                                                                o
                                                                   f
                                                                          i

                                                                                 o
                                                                                   n
                                                                           l
                                                                            l
                                                                             s
                                             s
                                               e
                                           s
                                        Assessment of Skills on
                                        A
                                                 s
                                                           n
                                                              t
                                                         e
                                                   s
                                                      m
                                    W  r i t i n g   a n d   S p e a k i n g   P o e t r y
                                    Writing and Speaking Poetry]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="132"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="133"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="134"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="135"><![CDATA[Assessment of Skills on

                                             Technical Writing]]></page><page Index="136"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="137"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="138"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="139"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="140"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="141"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="142"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="143"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="144"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="145"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="146"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="147"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="148"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="149"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="150"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>