<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="65"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.5.   The institution has an approved


                              and copyrighted Extension


                              Manual.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[RULE X
                                               EXTENSION OPERATIONS



                                                    INTRODUCTION

                       University  Mandate  on  Extension  Services  –  Extension  Services  is  is  an
               outreach unit of the Cavite State University. As mandated, the University shall “provide
               advanced instruction and professional training in agriculture, science and technology,
               education  and  other  related  fields,  undertake  research  and  extension  services,  and
               provide progressive leadership in these areas.” (Republic Act No. 8468, converting the
               Don  Severino  Agricultural  College  into  University  Status,  to  be  called  Cavite  State
               University).

                       Republic act 8435, or the Agriculture and Fisheries  Modernization Act of
               1997 (AFMA) under section 86 stated that: “It is hereby declared the policy of the state
               to promote science and technology, as essential for national development and progress.
               The State shall give priority to the utilization of research results through formal and non-
               formal education, extension and training services.”

                       Historical  Background  –  For  decades,  the  University  has  been  involved  in
               community  outreach  and  extension  activities.  When  .this  was  converted  into  Don
               Severino Agricultural College (DSAC) in 1964, extension became one of the functions of
               this institution, in addition to instruction and research. DSAC started with two major
               units,  the  Secondary  Department  and  the  College  Department.  The  latter  conducted
               extension services in the form of seminars on improved farm practices and certified seeds
               and  veterinary  services  to  the  animals  of  the  service  area.  In  addition,  the  College
               maintained a one-and-a-half hectare nursery for the propagation of and multiplication of
               important plants for on-campus and for farmers’ use. The Swine Project which was used
               for  instruction  purposes  also  served  as  source  of  foundation  stock  for  farmers.  Boar
               services were made available to small hog raisers for the improvement of their stock
               (DSAC Annual Report, SY 1968-69).

                       Since  then,  the  milestones  of  extension  services  were  recorded  in  the  Annual
               Reports of this educational institution.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Article 1. Organizational Philosophy



                       Section 1.    Vision - “Help alleviate the standard of living of the economically
                                     and socially disadvantaged sectors of society through the Extension
                                     of the University.”

                       Section 2.    Mission - “To engage in the improvement of the quality of life of
                                     farmers/fishermen,      women,      out-of-school    youths,    local
                                     government employees, and other clients through the conduct of
                                     relevant  education  and  training;  farm  and  business  advisory
                                     services; demonstration services; and information, communication
                                     and technology services.”

                       Section 3.    Goals

                                     a)  Disseminate and promote innovative, relevant, appropriate and
                                         research-based  knowledge,  information  and  technologies  to
                                         various clients.

                                     b)  Engage  and  enhance  partnership  with  various  stakeholders,
                                         local and international to address the needs of the target clients
                                         and  the  communities,  and  the  resource  limitation  of  the
                                         extension organization.

                                     c)  Enhance the organization’s capability to provide excellent and
                                         world-class extension services.

                       Section 4.    Objectives


                                     a)  To conduct and/or coordinate relevant training programs and
                                         short non-degree courses in agriculture and other disciplines

                                     b)  To promote agricultural entrepreneurship and other business
                                         enterprises.

                                     c)  To  establish  and  maintain  on-campus  and  off-campus
                                         demonstration  projects  showcasing  various  appropriate
                                         technologies.

                                     d)  To  package  and  disseminate  through  tri-media  the  needed
                                         technology/information  relevant  to  the  improvement  of  the
                                         farming and rural/urban living

                                     e)  To coordinate and monitor the extension activities of various
                                         colleges and branch campuses of the University]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[f)  To  collaborate  and  establish  linkages  with  government  and
                                         private  agencies  engaged  in  extension  and  rural/urban
                                         development in the pursuit of common goals and objectives

                                     g)  To generate income from established projects and from other
                                         resource generation activities.


                       Section 5.    Thrusts - Extension projects and other activities are in accord with
                                     the  identified  Research,  Development  and  Extension  (RD  &  E)
                                     thrusts. These are:

                                     •  Poverty alleviation
                                     •  Food security
                                     •  Primary health care and public health
                                     •  Alternative medicine
                                     •  Cultural heritage preservation
                                     •  Ecosystem Management
                                     •  Energy conservation and utilization
                                     •  Institutional capability building
                                     •  Information and communication technology
                                     •  Infrastructure planning and design
                                     •  Bio-technology
                                     •  Industrial Technology
                                     •  Pedagogy/Andragogy
                                     •  Gender and development
                                     •  Coffee
                                     •  Pineapple
                                     •  Banana
                                     •  Kaong
                                     •  Makapuno
                                     •  Herns and spices
                                     •  Ornamentals
                                     •  Ugnayan Agriculture

                       Section 6.    Core Values - Extension strongly adheres to CvSU’s three tenets of
                                     a) Truth, b) Excellence and c) service.


                       Section 7.    Guiding Principles
                                     a)  Globally competitive – world class in quality.

                                     b)  Credibility – delivery of responsive, appropriate, relevant and
                                         research-based knowledge and technologies.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[c)  Partnership  –  collaborate  with  international  and  national
                                         agencies, public and private partners, engaging the community
                                         to  maximize  resources,  encourage  wider  participation  and
                                         facilitate achievement of mutual objectives.

                                     d)  Accountability  –  results-oriented  focusing  on  measurable
                                         outcomes, documenting the impact and publishing the same for
                                         public and stakeholders’ information.

                                     e)  Diversity  –  involve  faculty  and  staff  with  various  field  of
                                         expertise, serving and responding to different needs of clients
                                         such  as  farmers,  fishermen,  women,  out-of-school  youths,
                                         pupils/students, professionals and the community as a whole.


               Article 2. Organization and Management


                       Section 1.    Organization  Structure  -  “The  Extension  Services  at  CvSU  is
                                     usually shortened and referred to as Extension only. It is one of the
                                     four  major  units  directly  under  the  Vice  President  for  Research,
                                     Extension,  and  Continuing  Education  and  Training  Services
                                     (RECETS). The Extension Services is headed by a Director (Figure
                                     1.)

                                            The office shall be a distinct office to be headed by the Vice
                                     President who shall be designated by the University President. The
                                     Extension office will be in-charge of facilitating the diffusion and
                                     adoption of appropriate fisheries and social technologies through
                                     the use of integrated, multi-disciplinary and participatory program
                                     and services.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[OP



                                                         OVP - RDE


                                              Research Mgt. &     Monitoring &
                                              Operation Section   Evaluation Section

                                              Publication Unit   Intellectual Property
                                                                  Rights  Section


                                                        EXTENSION
                                                         CENTER


                                               Management        Support Services
                                             Information System     Section


                                              Monitoring and
                                             Evaluation Section

                        Technology      Business and     Community         Applied       Training Services
                       Demonstration   Marketing Division   Development and   Communication   Division
                                                       Outreach Division
                         Division
                                                                           Division


                                                                CvSU FITS Center


                                                                CvSU PAC Center


                                                                 Ugnayan Project


                    Figure 1: The  revised organization structure of the Extension Services]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[The  Extension  Services  has  five  major  divisions  with  the
                              corresponding  heads,  namely:  a)  Technology  Demonstration  Services
                              Division;  b)  Business  and  Marketing  Services  Division;  c)  Community
                              Development and Outreach Services Division; d)

                                     a)  Under the Technology Demonstration Services Division are
                                         three demonstrations cum income generating projects (IGPs).
                                         These include: 1) Multiple Cropping Projects composed of eight
                                         (8)  modules  or  planting  combination;  2)  Urban  Agriculture
                                         Projects  which  are  also  divided  into  modules;  and  3)  Other
                                         Open-Field Demonstration Projects.

                                     b)  The  Business  and  Marketing  Division  has  two  major
                                         concerns: The Farmers’ Training Center and the business aspect
                                         of the different demonstration projects. This division disposes
                                         the products produced by the Extension Services. Expenses and
                                         income from the different production projects are recorded and
                                         reported by this division.

                                     c)  The  Community  Development  and  Outreach  Services
                                         Division has three major sections which include the UGNAYAN
                                         Project; Community Development Projects; and CvSU Palengke.

                                     d)  The  Training  Services  Division  takes  charge  of  the
                                         identification,  planning,  implementation,  and  evaluation  of
                                         training programs;


                                     e)  The last division is the Applied Communication which takes
                                         charge  of  the  production,  packaging,  publication  and
                                         dissemination of relevant technologies and other information.


                                     Other sections directly under the Office of the Director for Extension
                              Services are: Support Services Section, Budget, Properties and Records;
                              Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Section;  and  the  two  Centers,  namely:  the
                              Farmers’  Information  and  Technology  Services  (FITS)  Center  and  the
                              Palengke-Alaman Center (PAC).]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Article 3. Functions – The CvSU Extension Services

                       The  Extension  Services  performs  the  third  major  function  of  Cavite  State
               University. It links this educational institution with the community through the conduct
               of  non-formal  education  and  trainings;  technology  demonstration  and  technology
               transfers to farmers, rural women, pupils, out-of-school youths (OSYs), and other clients;
               and do other community development activities.

                       The Extension Services performs overall coordinative function. While it is tasked
               to perform the major extension activity of the University, it has no direct supervision over
               the  extension  activities  of  the  different  colleges  and  branch  campuses.  Each
               College/Campus  designates an Extension (RDE) Coordinator who takes charge of the
               planning,  implementation  and  monitoring  of  its  respective  extension  programs.  The
               Office of the Director for Extension Services monitors all the extension activities of the
               University.



               Article 4. The Major Divisions/Sections

                       Section  1.    Technology  Demonstration  Service  Division  (TDS)  –  The
                                     Technology  Demonstration  Farm  (TDF)  composing  of  Multiple
                                     Cropping  Projects,  Urban  Agriculture  Projects  and  Open-Field
                                     Demo Projects shall be under this division.


                                     The TDS Division shall:
                                     a)  Showcase indigenous and innovative agricultural technologies.

                                     b)  Operate  the  Technology  Demonstration  Farm  as  a
                                         demonstration      farm-cum      income-generating       project.


                                     c)  Operate all income-generating projects as farm business where
                                         expenses  and  income  are  strictly  monitored  and  recorded.

                                     d)  Add value to TDF by developing the area as site for agritourism.

                                     e)  Coordinate with other divisions of the Extension Services.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Section 2.    Business,  Marketing  Services  (BMS)  -  The  Farmers’  Training
                                     Center (FTC) composing of six (6) housing units shall be under this
                                     division.

                                     The BMS Division shall:

                                     a)  Take  charge  of  the  business  operations  at  the  TDF  and  FTC.

                                     b)  Take charge of the Student Loans Project.

                                     c)  Take charge of the marketing of the different agricultural and
                                         processed  products  in  coordination  with  the  TDS  Division.

                                     d)  Monitor, consolidate and record all the expenses and income of
                                         the TDF and FTC.

                                     e)  Take charge of the FTC composed of six (6) housing units, as
                                         business enterprise; and

                                     f)  Provide necessary data and information to other divisions of the
                                         Extension Services.

                       Section 3.    Community Development and Outreach Services Division
                                     (CDOS) shall:


                                     a)  Oversee all the community development projects and other
                                         outreach activities of the Extension Services;

                                     b)  Take charge of the Palengke Alaman Project

                                     c)  Handle all outside requests for outreach and other extension
                                         services

                                     d)  Coordinate and monitor extension activities under the
                                         UGNAYAN project

                                     e)  Provide necessary data and information to other
                                         units/divisions of the Extension Services.

                       Section 4.    Applied Communication Division (ACD)

                                            Under this division are the Farmers’ Information and
                                     Technology Services (FITS) Center, Palengke-Alaman Center (PAC)
                                     and the publication aspect of the Extension Services.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[The ACD shall:

                                         a)  Take charge of all the regular publications of the Extension
                                            Services which include Ugnayan, Midland Forum and
                                            Occasional Paper

                                         b)  Produce and publish other informative materials suitable to
                                            various clients

                                         c)  Prepare the training materials appropriate to target clients;

                                         d)  Write and submit up-to-date news materials to local and
                                            national newspaper agencies

                                         e)  Package the proceedings of all the trainings, seminars, and
                                            other activities of the Extension Services; and

                                         f)  Provide necessary data and information to other
                                            division/sections of the Extension Services.

                       Section 5.    Training Services Division

                                     a)  Take charge of the conduct of training needs assessment (TNA)
                                         of the clientele in the service area;

                                     b)  Plan the training activities/program based on the results of
                                         TNA;


                                     c)  Take charge of the conduct of identified training
                                         activities/program; and

                                     d)  Monitor and evaluate the impact of the training
                                         program/activities coordinated.



               Article 5. Duties and Responsibilities

                       Section 1.    Director for Extension Services shall:

                                     a)  Take charge of the planning, development and supervision of
                                         the Extension Services

                                     b)  Prepare budgetary estimates for Extension in coordination
                                         with division heads and project/section in charge]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[c)  Propose new and/or revision of policies, rules and regulations
                                         affecting the Extension Services

                                     d)  Coordinate and monitor all the extension programs of the
                                         university

                                     e)  Establish linkages with government and non-government
                                         agencies for the effective implementation of the extension and
                                         community outreach programs of the university

                                     f)  Prepare and submit yearly performance target and
                                         accomplishment reports

                                     g)  Sign vouchers and RIVs up to amount approved by the
                                         university

                                     h)  Sign the daily time records of all faculty and staff under his/her
                                         office

                                     i)  Approve the application of leave of absence of faculty and staff

                                         up to the number of days allowed by the University

                                     j)  Perform such other duties and responsibilities as may be
                                         assigned by higher authorities.
                       Section 2.    Division Heads, Project/Section In-Charge


                              All heads and project-in-charge of the Extension Services shall:

                                     a)  Assist in the preparation of strategic plan for their respective
                                         units

                                     b)  Prepare yearly financial work plans and accomplishment
                                         reports for their respective units

                                     c)  Implement target plans accordingly

                                     d)  Monitor and evaluate the planned and implemented activities

                                     e)  Document and possibly publish all lessons and notable
                                         experiences in their respective areas

                                     f)  Submit required data and other reports]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[g)  Perform such other duties and responsibilities as may be
                                         assigned by higher authorities

                       Section 3.    Other Designations

                              a.  Manager of the Farmers’ Training Center

                                     ▪  Oversee the operation of the Farmers’ Training Center

                                     ▪  Take charge of the maintenance and repair of the different
                                         housing facilities

                                     ▪  Record all the expenses and income of the FTC

                                     ▪  Submit required data and other reports

                                     ▪  Perform such other duties and responsibilities as may be
                                         assigned by higher authorities

                              b.  Manager of the FITS Center and Palengke-Alaman Center shall:


                                     ▪  Oversee the operation of the FITS Center and PAC

                                     ▪  Prepare yearly financial work plans and accomplishment
                                         reports

                                     ▪  Conduct technology promotion activities in collaboration with
                                         PCARRD, DA, DAR and other partner agencies

                                     ▪  Maintain and update the data base of the FITS Center

                                     ▪  Disseminate ICT materials to clients in coordination with ACD

                                     ▪  Monitor feedback and needs of clients to enable the R & D
                                         community to respond accordingly

                                     ▪  Submit required data and other reports

                                     ▪  Perform such other duties and responsibilities as may be
                                         assigned by higher authorities.]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[c.  Property Custodian of TDF and FTC shall:

                                     ▪  Keep records of all the facilities and other resources at the TDF
                                         and FTC

                                     ▪  Make a regular inventory of all the facilities at the TDF and FTC
                                         in coordination with the Projects-In-Charge and the FTC
                                         Manager

                                     ▪  Ensure that all incoming and outgoing materials and products
                                         at TDF and FTC are properly noted and recorded

                                     ▪  Submit required data and other reports

                                     ▪  Perform such other duties and responsibilities as may be
                                         assigned by higher authorities

               Article 6. Research Development and Extension Council (RDEC)

                       There  shall  be  a  University  Research,  Development  and  Extension  Council

               (URDEC)  to  be  constituted  by  the  Vice  President  for  Research,  Development  and
               Extension  as  Chairman.  The  members  of  the  Council  shall  consist  of  specialists
               representing the different research commodity emphases of the University, extension
               and continuing education and training specialists. The members of the Council shall serve
               for two years renewable up to the second term. In case of vacancy in membership, a
               substitute maybe designated by the University President and shall serve only for the
               remaining period of appointment.

                       The  duties  and  responsibilities  of  the  Research,  Extension  and  Continuing
               Education and Training Services Council shall be as follows:

                          ▪  Assist  the  VPRE  in  the  formulation  of  policies,  plans  and  programs,
                              guidelines  and  regulations  pertinent  to  the  research  and  extension
                              programs of the entire university;

                          ▪  Determine, review and recommend to the Administrative Council, policies,
                              rules  and  regulations,  and  the  directions  for  the  University  research,
                              extension,     continuing     education     and      training    programs;

                          ▪  Screening, evaluating and recommend research and extension proposals

                          ▪  Review  the  findings  and  recommendations  of  faculty  and  institutional
                              research]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[The Research, Extension and Continuing Education and Training Services Council
               shall hold at least one meeting every quarter at the date and venue to be determined by
               the Council members.



               Article 7. College/Campus Research, Development and Extension (RDE)
                       Coordinator

                       College/Campus Dean recommends RDE Coordinator for approval by the
               University President. The RDE Coordinator shall:

                          ▪  Plan      and      implement       the      research      and      extension
                              programs/projects/activities of the college in consultation with and under
                              the close supervision of the Dean;

                          ▪  Coordinate  and  monitor  the  research  and  extension  programs  of  the
                              college

                          ▪  Serve as a link between the college and RECETS

                          ▪  Attend the regular meeting of RDE Coordinators chaired by the VP-RDE or
                              Research/Extension Director


                          ▪  Represent the College during the research and extension inhouse reviews

                          ▪  Provide  the  College  Dean,  VPRDE  and  other  concerned  offices  the
                              necessary data on research and extension

                          ▪  Perform  such  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by
                              higher authorities.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Article 8. Extension Strategies

                       Extension Services is committed towards the attainment of three renewed goals,
               hence the following strategies and indicators are included in this operations manual:

                 GOALS/OBJECTIVE/STRATEGY                        PERFORMANCE INDICATOR
                                                       Output                  Verifiable Indicators
                 Goal 1. Promotion and                                         Number of brochures,
                 dissemination of relevant                                     techno guides and
                 information and technologies                                  articles published and
                                                                               disseminated
                 1.1 Packaging of research results     Research results
                    into technologies for              packaged into           Number of clients served
                    dissemination to various           information or

                    clients.                           technologies            List of publications /IEC
                                                                               materials collected
                 1.2 Collecting publication            Collections of          Percentage of collections
                    materials from other agencies      publications / IEC      encoded
                    for library use and for            materials from other
                    reproduction for distribution      sources/ agencies       Number of readers

                 1.3 Promoting and marketing of        Promotional             Number of promotional
                    the services of Farmer’s           materials produced      materials
                    Information and Technology         and activities
                    Services (FITS) Center and the     undertaken /            Number of promotional
                    Palengke-Alaman Center (PAC)  Visitors of FITS and         materials produced and
                                                       PAC                     activities done.

                 1.4 Establish technology              Established on-         Number of FITS/PAC
                    demonstration farms off-           campus and off-         visitors/readers
                    campus at the barangay level       campus techno
                    and oncampus within the            demonstration farms  List of experts.
                    Technology Demonstration
                    Farm (TDF)                                                 Number of technology
                                                                               demonstration projects
                                                                               established on campus
                                                                               and off campus.

                 1.5 Conduct any of the following      Conducted Seminars,  Number of visitors who
                    based on the problems and          workshops, trainings  have seen the
                    needs of the community and         and technology          technology
                    the target beneficiaries:          clinics                 demonstration farms
                    a)  Seminar]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[b)  Workshop                                               Number of seminars,
                    c)  Training                                               workshops, trainings,
                    d)  Technology Clinic                                      technology clinics and
                    e)  Consultative Meetings                                  consultative meetings
                                                                               conducted

                                                                               List of participants to
                                                                               the abovementioned
                                                                               activities

                                                                               Percentage of users/
                                                                               adopters of the
                                                                               technologies among the
                                                                               attendees to these
                                                                               activities


                 Goal 2. Strengthen and establish                              Number of linkages /
                 local and international linkages                              partnerships with MOA
                 and Partnerships
                                                                               Number of meetings
                 2.1 Conduct meetings and other        Activities              conducted
                 collaborative activities with         undertaken to
                 existing partners and linkages        strengthen              Number of collaborative
                                                       established linkages    activities or projects
                                                       and partnerships        jointly conducted

                 2.2 Enhance                           Meetings and            Amount of support
                 coordination/collaboration with       collaborative           funds received in
                 the RDE Coordinators of the           activities conducted    cash/kind
                 different colleges/branch
                 campuses                                                      Number of meetings and
                                                                               collaborative projects
                                                                               conducted with RDE
                                                                               coordinators
                 2.3 Strengthen local &                New linkages            Number of linkages
                 international linkages and            established             established
                 partnerships
                                                                               Number of
                                                                               Memorandum of
                                                                               Agreement /
                                                                               Understanding signed]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Goal 3. Enhance organizational
                 excellence in extension

                 3.1 Restructure extension             Organization            Restructured
                 organization in response to           structure               organization
                 changes (e.g. retirement of staff)    restructured

                                                       New designation of      New designation
                                                       staff

                 3.2 Review and revise extension       Planning write shop     Revised extension
                 vision, mission, goals and            conducted               vision, mission, goals
                 objectives                                                    and objectives

                 3.3 Review and revise                                         Revised operational
                 implementing guidelines                                       /implementing
                                                                               guidelines


                                                                               Integrated university
                                                                               extension projects

                 3.4 Update programs and projects      Prevailing updated      Integrated university
                 according to needs                    programs                extension projects

                                                                               Updated programs


                 3.5 Implement formal reviews          Extension In house      Number of papers
                 process for various extension         review conducted        presented and evaluated
                 programs and projects                 annually


                 3.6 Upgrade/update knowledge          Attended local and      Best extension practices
                 and skills of faculty and staff in    national conferences,  identified
                 extension and related fields          seminars and
                 through attendance to local,          trainings               Number of attendance to
                 national and international                                    local, national and
                 conferences, seminars and                                     international
                 trainings                                                     conferences, seminars
                                                                               and trainings]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Article 9 . UGNAYAN: A Unified Community-Based Project

                       Section 1.    Ugnayan  is  a  Tagalog  word  which  connotes  linkages  and
                                     coordination among the stakeholders. The University selected an
                                     UGNAYAN barangay or village where the extension services of the
                                     different colleges are focused.

                                            UGNAYAN is a unified extension and research program for
                                     the academic units of Cavite State University. Ugnayan is a Tagalog
                                     word  which  connotes  coordination  and  cooperation.  While  this
                                     program was approved by the Board of Regents (BOR No. 55) on 6
                                     December 2001, the practice dates back in the late 70’s as Project
                                     UGNAYAN.

                                            Originally, its philosophy stated that “it is an approach  to
                                     rural development where the spirit of coordination among those
                                     concerned in the upliftment of a community is given importance.
                                     From a singly focused agricultural extension project, the project, the
                                     project evolved into a unified extension and research program.

                                            This  approach  allows  each  major  academic  unit  of  the
                                     University  to  pursue  community  service  projects  and  applied
                                     research in a beneficiary barangay that is adopted as pilot area by

                                     the University. The problem to be solved should be within the area
                                     expertise of the College concerned. Each College establishes its own
                                     Project  Implementation  Unit  (PIU)  with  a  Central  Project
                                     Implementation Unit (CPIU) at the office of the Vice President for
                                     Academic Affairs and coordinated by OVP RECETS.
                                            At present, the adopted barangay is Banaba Lejos, Indang,

                                     Cavite. Ugnayan approach permits maximization of resources and
                                     unification of efforts.

                                     Location:     Banaba Lejos, Indang, Cavite

                                     Clientele:    Farmers, Rural women, Youth and other people in the
                                                   community

                                     Leader/Coordinator: All Colleges at the Main Campus Coordinated
                                                           by the University Extension Services

                                     Funding Source:       Local  government,  CvSU  and  other  linkage
                                                           institutions,  Cooperating  Agency:  Municipal
                                                           Government, Department of Agriculture (DA),
                                                           Department of Agrarian Reform (DAR), other
                                                           concerned government agencies.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Section 2.    Farmers’ Information and Technology Services (FITS) Center

                                            The Farmers’ Information and Technology Services (FITS)
                                     Center  is  under  the  Applied  Communication  Unit  of  Extension
                                     Services. It was established primarily through the assistance of the
                                     Philippine Council for Agriculture, Forestry and Natural Resources
                                     Research and Development (PCARRD).

                                     Location:     Cavite State University (CvSU)

                                     Clientele:    Farmers, Rural women and youth, students, teachers,
                                                   researchers, extension workers

                                     Leader/Coordinator: CvSU Extension Services

                                     Funding Source:       CvSU, Department of Science and Technology
                                                           (DOST),  Philippine  Council  for  Agriculture,
                                                           Forestry, and Natural Resources Research and
                                                           Development  (PCARRD),  Southern  Tagalog
                                                           Agriculture  and  Resources  Research  and
                                                           Development Consortium (STARRDEC)

                       Section 3:    Palengke-Alaman Center (PAC).

                                            Palengke-Alaman Center is a joint  project of  theMunicipal
                                     Government of Indang, DAR-Indang, PCARRD and STARRDEC. PAC
                                     is located within the market place or “palengke”. Palengke-Alaman
                                     serves as a one-stop information shop for farmers, rural women,
                                     out-of-school youth and other interested parties. The Center has a
                                     collection of brochures, leaflets and other reading materials. It links
                                     clients to experts in various fields and post current prices of basic
                                     commodities. The staff assigned to this Center report every Market

                                     day.

                                     Location:     Indang Municipal Market

                                     Clientele:    Indang and nearby community

                                     Leader/Coordinator: CvSU Extension Services

                                     Funding Source:       CvSU, Municipal government, and other local
                                                           line agencies, PCARRD and STARRDEC



                       Section 4.    Technology Promotion Center (TPC).

                                            TPC is a joint program of the Land Bank of the Philippines
                                     (LBP),  Cavite  State  University  and  the  Provincial  Government  of
                                     Cavite.  The  RECETS  represented  CvSU  in  this  program.  TPC]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[program aims to: a) promote appropriate, updated and sustainable
                                     technologies that will generate and enhance production and post-
                                     production  efficiencies  and  guarantee  increases  in  income  to
                                     farmers and fisher folks; b) enhance the Banks’ lending programs
                                     through  technology  validation  for  effective  delivery/transfer  of
                                     technologies to rural farmers, fisher folks and entrepreneurs; and c)
                                     facilitate  technology  transfer  by  showcasing  sustainable
                                     technologies to serve as a learning center for farmers and fisher
                                     folks.

                                     Location:     CvSU

                                     Clientele:    Farmers,  women  and  youth,  students,  extension
                                                   workers and researchers in the Cavite province

                                     Leader/Coordinator: Land Bank of the Philippines

                                     Funding Source:       Land  Bank  of  the  Philippines  (LBP)  and
                                                           Provincial   Government,     Office   of   the
                                                           provincial governor and other line agencies.

                       Section 5.    Technology Promotion and Dissemination

                                     Location:             CvSU

                                     Clientele:            Farmers,  women  and  youth,  students,
                                                           extension workers and researchers


                                     Leader/Coordinator: Technology and Livelihood Resource Center
                                                                  (TLRC)
                                     Funding Source:       CvSU and TLRC



                       Section 6.    Publication of Information Materials


                                     Location:     CvSU

                                     Clientele:    Farmers,  women  and  youth,  students,  extension
                                                   workers and researchers

                                     Leader/Coordinator: Extension Services

                                     Funding Source: CvSU colleges and branch campuses]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Section 7.    Technology Demonstration Project
                                     (Both on-campus and off-campus)

                                     a)  On-campus
                                            ▪  Multiple Cropping Projects comprising of eight (8)
                                                modules
                                            ▪  Coconut Pith Demo Project
                                            ▪  Urban Agriculture Demo Project
                                            ▪  Ornamental and Cut flower Production Project
                                            ▪  Herbs, Spices and Medicinal Plants Collection Project
                                            ▪  Carbonized Rice Hull (CRH) Production Project
                                            ▪  Indigenous Root/ Tuber and Vegetables Collection
                                                Project
                                            ▪  Protected High Value Vegetables Production Project
                                            ▪  Tissue-Cultured Banana Seedlings Production Project

                                     b)  Off-campus – Depending on the need of the clients
                                            Location:      CvSU Technology Demonstration Farm
                                                           /outside of the University-clients’ location
                                            Clientele:     Farmers, women and youth, students,

                                                           extension workers and researchers and other
                                                           University visitors
                                            Leader/Coordinator: Extension Services


                                            Funding Source:       CvSU colleges and branch campuses


                       Section 8.    Student Loan Fund (SLF)
                                     Location:     CvSU Extension Services
                                     Clientele:    CvSU students
                                     Leader/Coordinator: Extension Services
                                     Funding Source: CvSU

                       Section 9.    Student Loan Fund (SLF)
                                            This  is  a  million-peso  joint  technology  commercialization
                                     project of the Commission on Higher Education (CHED) and CvSU
                                     partnership with the local government units (LGUs). The goals of
                                     the project are to: 1) Support the AFMA and MTPDP, 2004-2010 in
                                     attaining food security at all times through the implementation of
                                     an  agricultural  diversification  program  in  an  underutilized  farm
                                     lands; 2) Improve the productivity of rainfed rice farms; 3) Increase
                                     the  income  of  rice  farmers;  4)  Ensure  sustainability  of  land]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[resource;  and  5)  Strengthen  stakeholders’  collaboration  and
                                     coordination towards agricultural development.

                                     Location:     Selected municipalities in the province of
                                                    Cavite
                                     Clientele:    40 – 50 Rice farmers
                                     Leader/Coordinator: CvSU
                                     Funding Source: CvSU, CHED, LGUs – DA

                       Section 10.   Seminars, Trainings and Other Services
                                     Location:             Provincial, Regional and National Level
                                     Clientele:            People involved in extension
                                     Leader/Coordinator: CvSU
                                     Funding Source: Local and international funding agencies

                       4.2.11 Consultancy, Advisory and Other Forms of Services
                                     Location:             On and off-campus, National and
                                                           International
                                     Clientele:            Varied, Walk-in clients and/or selected
                                                           clients

                                     Leader/Coordinator: CvSU Extension Services and
                                                           College/Campus
                                     Funding Source: Clients, Local and international funding agencies


               Article 10. Policies, Guidelines and Procedures

                       Section 1.     Extension Program/Project Planning and Implementation

                                     a)  The planning and implementation of the extension activities of
                                         the  university  is  decentralized,  integrated,  coordinated,
                                         participatory  and  needs-based.  The  extension  program
                                         support  the  Millennium  Development  Goals  (MDGs)  of  the
                                         United  Nations,  the  national,  regional,  provincial  and  local
                                         development plans.

                                     b)  Colleges  and  branch  campuses  plan  and  implement  their
                                         respective  extension  programs  in  coordination  with  the
                                         University  Extension  Services.  The  process  is  participatory
                                         involving the stakeholders which include the target clients, the
                                         students,  alumni,  faculty  members,  representatives  of
                                         government and non-government agencies and other concerned
                                         individuals. The needs and concerns of these stakeholders are]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[considered in the planning and implementation of the extension
                                         programs.

                                     c)  The  different  colleges/branch  campuses  and  the  Extension
                                         Services apply the different strategies for identifying the needs.
                                         These  include  survey,  focus  group  interviews,  experts’
                                         contributions,  direct  participation  of  the  target  clients  in  the
                                         planning process, and the use of secondary data.

                                     d)  Decentralization  of  the  planning  process  shall  start  at  the
                                         department  level.  The  colleges  integrate  all  the  planned
                                         extension  programs  of  their  respective  departments  into  one
                                         Research,  Development  and  Extension  Agenda  and  Programs
                                         (RDEAP).  There  is  a  designated  RD  and  E  coordinator  at  the
                                         department level (depending on the size of the department) and
                                         at the college level. The college RD and E Coordinator under the
                                         direct supervision of the Dean consolidates and  prepares the
                                         RDEAP.

                       Section 2.     Formulation of Research, Development and Extension Agenda
                                     and Program (RDEAP)

                                     CvSU-RDEAP evolved through the following integrated and
                                     participatory processes:

                                     a.  The  university  Research  Development  and  Extension  office
                                         conducts planning workshop. Headed by the Vice President, The
                                         RDE  spearheads  the  formulation  of  the  RDEAP  through  a
                                         workshop. Participants in this planning workshop are the Deans
                                         of  the  different  Colleges  and  branch  campuses  together  with
                                         their  respective  Research,  Development  and  Extension  (RDE)
                                         Coordinators.

                                     b.  During  the  University  planning  workshop,  the  thrusts  of  the
                                         University  are  reviewed  and  revised.  In  this  process,
                                         identification and selection of research and extension thrusts
                                         are  guided  by  the  stated  vision  and  mission  of  the
                                         university/college/campus.      Likewise,     the    Millennium
                                         Development Goals (MDGs), national and provincial, municipal

                                         and local development goals are considered.

                                     c.  The  research,  development  and  extension  (RDE)  thrusts
                                         resulting  from  the  latest  (2004)  RDEAP  planning  workshops
                                         include: poverty alleviation, food security, primary health care]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[and  public  health,  alternative  medicine,  cultural  heritage
                                         preservation, ecosystem management, energy conservation and
                                         utilization,  institutional  capability  building,  information  and
                                         communication technology, infrastructure planning and design,
                                         bio-technology,  industrial  technology,  pedagogy/andragogy,
                                         gender  and  development,  coffee,  pineapple,  banana,  kaong,
                                         makapuno,herbs  and  spices,  ornamentals,  and  urban
                                         agriculture.


                       Section 3.     Presentation of RDEAP by College

                                     a.  Prior to the actual conduct of RDEAP planning workshop, the
                                         RDE Coordinators present their draft plans with their respective
                                         Deans  for  further  comments  and  suggestions.  During  the
                                         workshop, the RDE Coordinators polish their prepared Agenda.
                                         As  part  of  the  workshop,  the  RDEAP  of  the  different
                                         Colleges/Campuses  are  presented  to  the  RECETS  Council  for
                                         comments and suggestions.

                                            Also,  during  the  presentation  of  various  agenda  and
                                         programs  by  College/Campus,  duplication  of  plans  and
                                         programs  are  eliminated.  In  cases  where  similar  areas  of
                                         concerns  are  presented  by  two  or  more  Colleges,  either  one
                                         party will drop its proposed knowledge area or integrate such
                                         with the others of similar nature. Also, group members openly
                                         discuss and decide as to who would lead the implementation of

                                         such programs.

                                     b.  Deans endorse the corrected copy of their RDEAPs to Research
                                         Center  for  consolidation.  RDE  Coordinators  incorporate  the
                                         comments and suggestions made during the presentation. The
                                         Deans submit the corrected copy to the Research Center Council
                                         for consolidation.
                                            ▪  Research Center collects the RDEAPs of the different
                                                colleges. The RDEAP of the different colleges/campuses
                                                are consolidated by Research Center into one University
                                                RDEAP for the final review of the URDEC members.

                                            ▪  URDEC  endorses  the  University  RDEAP  to  the
                                                Administrative Council. The RECETS Council through
                                                the VP-RECETS, who chairs endorses the RDEAP to the
                                                Administrative  Council  for  approval  of  the  Board  of
                                                Regents.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[▪  Administrative  Council  endorses  and  recommends
                                                the RDEAP for approval of the Board of Regents.

                                            ▪  Once approved, the RDEAP shall be disseminated to
                                                the entire university

                                            ▪  URDEC provides the approved RDEAP to concerned
                                                offices.


                       Section 4.    Presentation of RDEAP by College

                                     ▪  Call for capsule proposals. Office of the Director for Extension
                                         calls for the submission of an extension proposal. Although the
                                         extension  has  its  own  format,  format  shall  be  based  on  the
                                         requirement of the funding agency and in case that the fund shall
                                         come  from  the  university,  the  proposal  should  follow  the
                                         extension format.

                                     ▪  College/Campuses  prepare  capsule  proposals.  Faculty
                                         members  of  the  different  colleges  with  varied  fields  of

                                         specialization  prepare  capsule  proposal  on  their  areas  of
                                         expertise and interest. The proposal maybe singly prepared or
                                         in  cooperation  (interdisciplinary  approach)  with  other
                                         extensionists.  The  proposals  are  in  line  with  the  approved
                                         RDEAP. Capsule proposals are reviewed at the department level
                                         to the college levels by the respective research and extension
                                         committee in coordination with RDE Coordinator.

                                     ▪  Deans endorse capsule proposals to URDE Council through
                                         the  Extension  Director.  The  reviewed  proposals  are  then
                                         endorsed to the URDEC through the Director for approval.

                                     ▪  URDEC reviews and approves the capsule proposals. All the
                                         extension  proposals  must  be  reviewed  and  approved  by  the
                                         URDEC prior to their implementation.

                                     ▪  URDEC endorses the approved proposals for University or

                                         external  funding.  Proposals  requiring  bigger  funding  are
                                         usually  submitted  to  external  funding  institution  while  the
                                         remaining projects are recommended for local funding.

                                     ▪  Extension Director prepares work and financial plans for

                                         approved  projects.  Extension  Director  considers  the  newly]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[approved proposals in the preparation of their annual work and
                                         financial plan.


                       Section 5.    Implementation of Approved Projects

                                     a.)  Proponents implement their approved projects following
                                         their    scheduled     activities.   Program/project     leaders
                                         implement  their  approved  projects  at  their  respective
                                         colleges/campuses  in  coordination  with  RECETS.  While  the
                                         University  has  RECETS  that  is  in-charge  of  the  research  and
                                         extension  functions,  the  planning  and  implementation  of
                                         research and extension projects is decentralized but unified up
                                         to  the  department  level.  This  approach  has  been
                                         institutionalized and exemplified in CvSU through the concept
                                         called UGNAYAN.


               Article 11. Monitoring and Evaluation

                       Monitoring  continuously  tracks  performance  against  what  was  planned  by
               collecting and analyzing data on the indicators established for monitoring and evaluation
               purposes. It provides continuous information on whether progress is being made toward
               achieving  results  (outputs,  outcomes  and  goals)  through  record  keeping  and  regular
               reporting  systems.  Monitoring  looks  at  both  programmed  processes  and  changes  in
               conditions of target groups and institutions brought about by programmed activities. It
               also identifies strengths and weaknesses in a programmed. The performance information
               generated from monitoring enhances learning from experience and improves decision-
               making. Management and programmed implementers typically conduct monitoring.

                       Evaluation is a periodic, in-depth analysis of programmed performance. In relies
               on data generated through monitoring activities as well as information obtained from
               other  sources  (e.g.,  studies,  research,  in-depth  interviews,  focus  group  discussions,
               surveys etc.). Evaluations are often (but not always) conducted with the assistance of
               external evaluators (UNFPA, 2004).




                       Section 1.    Monitoring Strategies

                       a.  Mechanisms and Processes
                          1.  Creation of the University Research, Development and Extension
                              Council (URDEC)
                                     The Council is composed of the Research and Extension Directors
                              and selected faculty members who are considered experts in their
                              respective fields. The Vice President for Research Development and]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Extension chair this council. The University President designates the
                              members of the URDEC.
                                     The Council primarily reviews research and extension policies,
                              guidelines, programs and projects. In relation to monitoring and
                              evaluation, the group acts as Panel of Reviewers during the Extension
                              Agency In-House Review. They review and evaluate various on-going and
                              completed extension programs/projects and activities of the different
                              colleges and branch campuses.

                          2.  Appointment/Assignment of the Research, Development and
                              Extension (RDE) Coordinators for the different colleges and
                              campuses.
                                     Each  of  the  Colleges  and  branch  Campuses  assigns  Research,
                              Development  and  Extension  (RD  and  E)  Coordinator.  The  main  role  of
                              these coordinators is to coordinate and monitor the research and extension
                              activities in their respective colleges/campuses. He or she serves as the
                              point  person  and  as  conduit  to  other  units/agencies,  both  internal  and
                              external in matters pertaining to research and extension activities. RD and
                              E  coordinator  under  the  guidance  of  the  Dean  prepares  the  Research,
                              Development and Extension Agenda of the college/campus.


                          3.  CvSU Extension Agency Annual In-House Review
                              The stated goals and objectives of this Review are as follows:

                              Goals: The annual agency in-house review for extension aims to:
                                 ▪  Establish an additional institutional mechanism for the monitoring
                                     and       evaluation       of      the      different      extension
                                     programs/projects/activities  (E-PPAs)  of  the  Cavite  State
                                     University system

                                 ▪  Increase faculty and staff participation in extension and outreach
                                     activities

                                 ▪  Acquire papers on CvSU extension services which are acceptable for
                                     publication on appropriate Journals;

                                 ▪  Improve techniques, strategies and/or approaches in extension;

                                 ▪  Assess  the  attainment  of  objective  of  the  College/University
                                     completed and on-going extension; and

                                 ▪  Identify  problems  met  during  project  implementation  and
                                     recommend specific courses of action to these problems;]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Objectives: Also this activity aims to:

                                 ▪  Encourage  faculty  and  staff  to  write  their  extension  works  and
                                     outputs

                                 ▪  Present  the  extension  activities  of  the  different  colleges  and
                                     campuses

                                 ▪  Recognize and award commendable extension programs, projects
                                     and activities

                                 ▪  Document results of extension programs, projects and activities

                                 ▪  Acquire  effective  and  innovative  techniques  and/or  strategies  in
                                     extension

                                 The  mechanics  of  Extension  In-House  Review  are  indicated  in
                                 Appendix 1.

                          4.  Meetings –  Dean or Director conducts regular meetings with their unit
                              heads and/or staff to monitor the planned and on-going activities

                              including that of extension matters.

                                     The Director of Extension services coordinates and monitors the
                              extension activities of the different colleges primarily through meetings
                              with the different Research, Development and Extension (RD E)
                              Coordinators.

                          5.  Field Visits – All faculty members and staff engaged in extension activities
                              are conducting regular field’s visits to their respective service areas. In the
                              UGNAYAN  service  area  of  the  CvSU  main  campus,  the  RD  and  E
                              Coordinators either go in group or individually.

                          6.  Accomplishment Reports – The Extension Services regularly submits
                              monthly, weekly and daily accomplishment reports to the concerned
                              offices. At the end of the year, a Performance Accomplishment Report
                              (PAR) is submitted to the Office of the President through the RECETS
                              office. This PAR compares the year accomplishments vis-à-vis targeted
                              activities.

                          7.  Telephone calls – The presence of modern technologies like the cell
                              phones make it easy to contact and collect information and updates from
                              RD and E Coordinators, faculty extentionists and clients.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[8.  Memorandum and Other Written Communication – The Conventional
                              methods of monitoring projects are through memoranda and other
                              written communication, e.g. letters.

                              a.  Monitoring Reports and Other Forms
                                     To effectively monitor planned and on-going extension projects and
                                 resources of Extension Services, the following forms shall be used:
                                         ▪  Daily Performance Report
                                         ▪  Activities/Projects Progress Report (Weekly/Monthly)
                                         ▪  Monthly Expenditure and Income of Projects/Services
                                         ▪  Student Loan Fund
                                         ▪  Loan and Payment Status (Semestral)
                                         ▪  Form  to  Monitor  Number  of  Visitors  Served  and
                                            Accommodated

                       Section 2.    Evaluation Strategies

                       a.) Mechanisms and Processes
                              The  University  has  established  mechanisms  and  processes  by  which
                          regular  monitoring  and  evaluation  of  extension  services  and  resources  are
                          ensured. As mentioned earlier, these include designation of RDE Council and
                          RDE Coordinators; and the conduct of yearly in-house review.

                              The Extension Services has just introduced the logical framework approach
                          (LFA) or concept in the evaluation of extension programs and projects. It has
                          adopted the use of Logical Framework Model (Appendix 2) in the presentation
                          of papers during the In-House Review. This model is able to represent the
                          different types of evaluation.

                       b.) Types of Evaluation

                                 There are different kinds of approaches to evaluation, based on when it
                          occurs (process vs. outcome), the intentions of the evaluator (formative vs.
                          summative), and who does the evaluation (internal vs. external).

                                 Evaluations  maybe  conducted  at  any  of  several  phases  of  program
                          development and implementation. Process and outcome evaluations relate to
                          the phase of the program studied. Process evaluations examine what goes on
                          inside the program while it is in progress, focusing on such things as activities
                          offered, staff practices, and client actions. Evaluating program processes may
                          be very helpful in understanding why program objectives are or are not met.
                          Outcome evaluations put emphasis on the program objectives or outcomes:
                          what happens to clients as a result of their participation in the program. The
                          processes and outcome evaluations may either be formative or summative,
                          depending on the intentions of the evaluator (or those who hire the evaluator).]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Program sponsors and taxpayers typically are interested in program
                          accountability, which calls for summative evaluation. Summative evaluation
                          helps to answer the question, “Is the program earning its keep?” and provides
                          information  which  can  be  used  to  help  program  sponsors  make  informed
                          decisions about program funding. In comparison, a person who implement
                          programs  are  often  more  interested  in  learning  how  to  improve  their
                          programs.  Program  improvement  is  the  purpose  of  formative  evaluation.
                          When an organization has an evaluator or evaluation team on staff to evaluate
                          their  own  programs,  this  is  considered  internal  evaluation.  External
                          evaluations are conducted by outside by outside evaluation organizations or
                          independent evaluators (PREL).

                                 With the use of Logical Framework Approach in the In-House Review,
                          CvSU  Extension  Services  performs  process  and  outcome  evaluations,
                          formative and summative evaluations (ongoing and completed projects) and
                          considered internal and external evaluator as stated in the approved proposal

                       c.) Reports and Other Forms

                              Extension  evaluation  takes  place  in  all  stages:  the  planning,
                          implementation and after implementation phase of a program/project.

                                 ▪  Interview schedules and questionnaires  – are frequently used on
                                     these activities in the conduct of Benchmark Survey and Training
                                     Needs  Assessments  (TNA)  and  in  the  evaluation  of  ongoing
                                     extension activities.
                                 ▪  CEAAIREV Format for Writing Extension Report – for on-going and
                                     completed extension activities.
                                 ▪  CEAAIREV Abstract (For Paper and Poster Presentation)
                                 ▪  CEAIREV  Format  for  PowerPoint  Presentation  –  for  reporting
                                     extension activities.
                                 ▪  Poster  Presentation  –  for  on-going  and  completed  extension
                                     activities.
                                 ▪  CEAIREV  Criteria  for  Paper  Presentation  –  for  on-going  and
                                     completed extension activities.
                                 ▪  CEAIREV  Criteria  for  Poster  Presentation  –  for  on-going  and
                                     completed extension activities.
                                 ▪  Logical  Framework  Model  –  for  planning,  monitoring  and
                                     evaluation of extension programs, projects and activities.
                                 ▪  Annual Performance Target and Accomplishment
                                 ▪  Annual Report]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Article 12. ATTACHMENT A:
               Mechanics of Implementation for Extension In-House Review

                   1.  Coverage

                              The activities in the proposed agency in-house review include paper and
                       poster    presentations     of    completed      and/or     on-going     extension
                       programs/projects/activities.  An  activity  like  the  conduct  of  a  seminar  or
                       symposium  on  particular  issue,  topic  or  innovative  approach  in  extension
                       education and extension-related subject maybe included.

                   2.  Management and Administration

                              The CvSU Extension Services will lead in the conduct of the agency in-house
                       review in coordination with the different colleges and campuses.

                              The Director of Extension Services or his/her designated staff shall serve
                       as the overall Coordinator of this event.

                              Various  committees  will  be  created  with  members  coming  from  the

                       University Research Development and Extension Council [URDEC] and the pool of
                       Research, Development and Extension [RDE] Coordinators from the main campus.

                              The URDEC members and invited individuals from the linkage agencies will
                       compose the Panel of Evaluators.

                              The  Panel  of  Evaluators  shall  be  responsible  for  the  evaluation  and
                       selection of the best extension paper.

                              A committee for the evaluation of posters presentation will be created by
                       the Extension Services Director.

                   3.  Paper and Poster Presentation and Evaluation

                          ▪  Completed and on-going extension programs/projects/activities (E-PPAs)
                              shall be presented. Each E-PPA shall have an approved proposal from the
                              respective authorities prior to its implementation.

                          ▪  This  proposed  activity  covers  the  E-PPAs  of  the  whole  Cavite  State
                              University system.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[▪  E-PPA  without  approved  proposal  prior  to  its  implementation  shall  be
                              accepted for presentation in the initial in-house review, as long as this is
                              recognized  as  an  extension  or  outreach  activity  of  the  unit  concerned
                              through the endorsement of their respective heads.*

                          ▪  Extension program/project/activity to be presented shall be outside or not
                              considered part of the academic requirements of the students.*

                          ▪  There shall be a common format for report writing and oral (PowerPoint)
                              presentation.

                          ▪  Report to be submitted for presentation shall be properly endorsed by the
                              respective authorities such as the Department Chairperson and Dean.

                          ▪  A clear, concise abstract is required for all presentations. An abstract is a
                              narrative description of the content of presentation. This will be attached
                              in the documentation of the in-house proceedings.

                          ▪  Presenters  shall  be  given  20  minutes,  5  minutes  for  AV  equipment
                              preparation and 15 minutes actual presentation.


                          ▪  There shall be a poster presentation during the in-house review. Top three
                              commendable papers and posters presentation shall be selected and the
                              first in rank shall be given best poster and best paper awards for extension.

                          ▪  There shall be a set of criteria for the evaluation of paper presentation and
                              poster presentation.

                   4.  Implementation Period
                              The CvSU Extension Annual Agency In-House Review will be conducted

                       yearly, for one whole day period, tentatively two weeks after the local Research
                       in-house review. In the future, the duration may extend to two days, if necessary.
                       Table  1  shows  the  activities  to  be  done  before  the  actual  implementation  of
                       CEAAIREV, while Figure 2 shows the flowchart of these activities.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Volume 5




                                                EXTENSION SERVICES




                                                   INTRODUCTION


                       As  mandated,  the  University  shall  “provide  advanced  instruction  and  professional

               training in agriculture, science and technology, education and other related fields, undertake
               research  and  extension  services,  and  provide  progressive  leadership  in  these  areas.”

               (Republic Act No. 8468, converting the Don Severino Agricultural College into University
               Status, to be called Cavite State University).


                       The Republic Act No. 8435, or the Agriculture and Fisheries Modernization Act of

               1997 (AFMA) under section 86 stated that: “It is hereby declared the policy of the state to
               promote science and technology, as essential for national development and progress. The State

               shall  give  priority  to  the  utilization  of  research  results  through  formal  and  non-formal
               education, extension and training services.”


                       Extension  project  or  programs  are  set  of  activities  aimed  to  transfer  knowledge or

               technology or to provide services to the community in consonance with the programs being
               offered by the University. It is being conducted as an outreach towards the improvement of the

               community’s quality of life (CHED CMO No. 22, s 2008).

               Article 1. Extension Services Goal, Objectives, Agenda, and Banner Program


                       Section 1. Goals. The Extension Services of Cavite State University (CvSU) shall be
               geared towards the improvement of the lives of the community especially those that belong to

               economically and socially disadvantaged sectors through the conduct of relevant education and

               training;  farm  and  business  advisory  activities;  demonstration  projects;  and  information,
               communication and technology services.]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Section 2. Objectives. The University shall provide excellent and socially responsive

               extension services to its target clientele.

                       Specifically, it aims to:


                       1.  conduct  and/or  coordinate  relevant  training  programs  as  well  as  appropriate,
                          efficient and sustainable interdisciplinary extension programs;

                       2.  promote community and social enterprises;

                       3.  coordinate  and  monitor  the  extension  activities  of  various  colleges  and  branch
                          campuses of the University;

                       4.  establish linkages with government and private agencies engaged in extension and
                          development;

                       5.  coordinate  with  the  Office  of  the  Vice  President  for  Resource  Generation  and

                          Production  (OVPRGP)  in  promoting  agricultural  and  other  potential  income
                          generating projects; and

                       6.  promote gender-responsive extension programs and activities.



                       Section  3.  University  Extension  Agenda.  The  University  shall  pursue  extension

               agenda  which  are  responsive  to  the  specific  needs  of  the  community  brought  by  present
               environmental and developmental challenges. Guided by the local and national development

               thrusts, the University research and extension agenda shall be focused but not limited on the
               following:


                       1.  Agri-Fisheries and Food Security. This thematic area emphasizes on developing
                          agriculture and food systems that are economically viable and sustainable to ensure

                          food security as well as to improve the quality of life of farmers and fisherfolks.

                          Research  and  extension  activities  on  the  following  commodities  shall  be  given
                          priority: coffee; kaong; rice; corn; root crops; high value crops (banana, pineapple,

                          mango, cacao and vegetables); poultry and livestock; fisheries and aquaculture;
                          urban agriculture; and organic agriculture.



                       2.  Biodiversity and Environmental Conservation. This thematic area is concerned
                          with environmental stewardship and equitable allocation and sustainable use of

                          natural  resources.  Emphases  include:  environmental  protection;  biodiversity
                          assessment and monitoring; cleaner environment; climate change; risk reduction]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[management;  renewable  energy  and  green  technologies;  natural  resource

                          management; and ecotourism.

                       3.  Smart Engineering, Information and Communication Technology (ICT), and

                          Industrial  Competitiveness.  The  term  smart  engineering  covers  the  methods,
                          processes,  systems  and  tools  for  the  cross-disciplinary,  system  oriented

                          development  of  innovative  and  interconnected  products,  services  and
                          infrastructures in the field of engineering. Products and process models shall be

                          developed  in  which  networking  encompasses  all  stages  of  development,  from

                          interdisciplinary design, to production processes and piloting, right the way through
                          product  usage  and  disposal.  Smart  engineering  is  about  the  integration  of

                          appropriate product planning, development, and management to ensure the rapid
                          market-ready  implementation  of  innovative  product  and  services  and  industrial

                          competitiveness through digital development process.


                                 The convergence of the latest computer science and ICT developments in

                          the  areas  of  micro-devices,  mobile  communication,  hardware  infrastructures,

                          internet  and  software  technologies,  image  recognition  and  processing,  parallel
                          computing, complex adaptive systems and bioinformatics shall be given emphasis.

                          Strong focus shall also be given to mathematics and statistics applications such as
                          industrial and biological modelling, biomedical, social and theoretical statistics,

                          computational mathematics, discrete pure mathematics and physics/engineering.

                       4.  Social Development and Equality. This thematic area focuses on educational,

                          criminological  and  social  sciences  researches  and  development  initiatives  with

                          emphasis  on  sustainable  development,  economic  development,  gender  and
                          development,  community  development,  governance,  poverty  alleviation,  social

                          behavior,  attitude  and  norms,  capacity  building,  peace  process  and  conflict

                          resolution,  disaster  risk  management  and  social  transitions,  pedagogy,  special
                          education, ICT and education, among others.


                                 This area aims to create inclusive growth and development, social harmony,
                          and equal opportunities among the different social groups and to lessen economic

                          divide, inequality and marginalization in the society.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[5.  Public Health and Welfare. This area deals with researches on protecting and

                          improving  human  health  and  welfare  which  includes  researches  on  diseases  or
                          conditions that may be transmitted to humans from humans or animals and vice

                          versa as well as those connected with the environment as a whole. Disciplines that
                          are  also  covered  are  those  dealing  with  epidemiology,  statistics,  environment,

                          behavior and  sociology, economics,  mental  health,  public  policy,  public  safety,

                          delivery of health services, occupational safety and other related fields.

                       Section 4. Banner Program. The Ugnayan 2.0 is the new banner extension program

               of Cavite State University and is the updated version of the previous Ugnayan Program which
               was  originally  intended  as  a  unified  research  and  extension  program  focused  on  rural

               development and improving the lives of the community. Ugnayan is a Tagalog word which
               connotes coordination and cooperation.


                       The  new  Ugnayan  2.0  will  continue  the  goal  of  the  former  extension  program  to

               improve the lives of the community and to help in alleviating poverty in Cavite. The approach
               of this program is to establish communication, coordination, cooperation, and collaboration

               among the University’s colleges and satellite campuses, public and private industries, and other
               stakeholders in providing necessary knowledge and technical assistance to target communities.

               The program will be anchored towards poverty alleviation with specific focus on delivering

               the matured technologies generated from the researches of the University to the community
               based on their needs.


               Article 2. Extension Organization and Management

                       Section 1. Organizational Structure. The organizational structure of the Extension

               Services is shown in Figure 1. The Extension Services is directly under the supervision of the

               Office of the Vice President for Research and Extension (OVPRE). The center has four major
               divisions:  Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division,  Monitoring  and

               Evaluation  Division,  Training  and  Courseware  Development  Division,  and  Technology
               Demonstration and Promotion Division. It also oversees all extension concerns of the different

               colleges and satellite campuses.

                       Section 2. Functions of the Extension Services. The Extension Services performs the

               third major function of Cavite State University. It links this educational institution with the

               community  through  the  conduct  of  non-formal  education  and  trainings;  technology
               demonstration and technology transfers to farmers, fisherfolks, women and children, persons]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[with  disabilities  out-of-school  youths,  disadvantaged  families  and/or  households,  workers,

               migrants and other clients; and other community development activities.

                       The Extension Services performs overall coordinative function among the Colleges and

               Campuses’ extension-related activities. It is tasked to perform the major extension activity of
               the University and to assist in the conduct, evaluation and monitoring of the extension activities

               of the different colleges and satellite campuses.





























                                     Figure 1. Organizational structure of Extension Services




                       Section 3. Functions of the Major Divisions


                           a.  Extension Monitoring and Evaluation Division. The Extension Monitoring

                              and Evaluation Division is responsible for the overall monitoring and evaluation
                              of  the  ongoing  extension  projects  of  the  colleges  and  campuses  of  the

                              University.
                           b. Community Engagement and External Relations Division. The Community

                              Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division  is  responsible  for  the
                              implementation  of  activities  pertaining  to  community  development.  These

                              activities   include    Community       Needs     Assessment,     Extension

                              programs/projects/activities and other outreach activities.]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[c.  Training  and  Courseware  Development  Division.  The  Training  and

                              Courseware Development Division plans and conducts training programs based
                              on the needs of the target communities/clienteles.

                           d. Technology Demonstration Farm Division. The Technology Demonstration
                              Farm Division oversees the operations of the TechnoDemo Farm and showcases

                              matured technologies.

                           e.  Technology  Promotion  Division.  The  Technology  Promotion  Division
                              validates  and  packages  appropriate  and  matured  technology  for

                              delivery/transfer.

                       Section 3. Duties and Responsibilities


                              a.  Director,  Extension  Services. The  Director  of Extension  Services  shall

                                 perform the following functions:
                                     •  Prepare and implement the strategic and development plan of the

                                         Extension Services Center;

                                     •  Coordinate and monitor all the extension programs and activities of
                                         all the colleges and campuses;

                                     •  Prepare budgetary estimates for all the programs and activities of the
                                         center  in  coordination  with  division  heads  and  project/section  in

                                         charge;

                                     •  Design and propose new extension projects/activities/programs;
                                     •  Make  revisions  on  policies,  rules,  and  regulations  affecting  the

                                         Extension Services Center;

                                     •  Establish linkages with government and non-government agencies
                                         for the effective implementation of the extension and community

                                         outreach programs of the University;
                                     •  Prepare and submit yearly performance target and accomplishment

                                         reports of the Extension Services Center;

                                     •  Sign vouchers and RIVs up to amount approved by the University,
                                         subject to Commission on Audit (COA) rules and regulations; and

                                     •  Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by

                                         higher authorities.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[b.  Head,  Extension  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Division.  The  Head  of

                                 Extension Monitoring and Evaluation Division shall perform the following
                                 duties:

                                     •  Conduct regular and periodic monitoring and yearly evaluation of

                                         the different extension programs/activities of each college/campus;
                                     •  Prepare and submit regular M&E reports (monthly, quarterly, and

                                         yearly)

                                     •  Monitor the conduct of trainings;
                                     •  Conduct follow-ups and updates on the trainees and adopters;

                                     •  Prepare tracer studies on the adopters and clienteles;

                                     •  Conduct impact assessments on extension projects and activities;
                                         and

                                     •  Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by

                                         higher authorities.
                              c.  Head, Community Engagement and External Relations Division. The

                                 Head  of  Community  Engagement  and  External  Relations  Division  shall
                                 perform the following duties:

                                     •  Oversee  all  the  community  development  projects  including  the
                                         conduct    of    community     needs    assessment,    extension

                                         activities/projects and other outreach activities;

                                     •  Handle all outside requests for community outreach and extension
                                         services;

                                     •  Coordinate the extension activities of all the colleges and

                                         campuses;
                                     •  Provide necessary data and information to other units/divisions of

                                         the Extension Services;

                                     •  Establish linkages with the target communities;
                                     •  Establish linkages with government and non-government agencies

                                         for the effective implementation of the extension and community

                                         outreach programs of the University;
                                     •     Forge a good relationship with all the partner

                                         agencies/institutions;]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[•  Facilitate the collaboration between the University and partner

                                         agencies and private entities; and
                                     •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by

                                         higher authorities.

                              d.  Head, Training and Courseware Development Division. The Head of
                                 Training and Courseware Development Division shall perform the

                                 following duties:

                                     •  Conduct of training needs assessment in the target
                                         communities/clienteles;

                                     •  Prepare and submit training proposals for implementation;

                                     •  Conduct and facilitate planned/approved/requested trainings in the
                                         community;

                                     •  Prepare the training materials/modules appropriate to target
                                         clientele;

                                     •  Package the proceedings of all trainings, seminars, and other

                                         activities of the Extension Services;
                                     •  Submit proceedings or reports of each training/seminar conducted;

                                         and

                                     •  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by
                                         higher authorities.

                              e.  Head, Technology Demonstration Farm Division. The Head of
                                 Technology Demonstration Farm Division shall perform the following

                                 duties:

                                     •  Supervise the day-to-day operations of the Techno-Demo Farm;
                                     •  Prepare reports on the operations/management of the TechnoDemo

                                         Farm;

                                     •  Make necessary recommendations for the improvement of the
                                         Techno-Demo Farm;

                                     •  Manage the showcase of farming technologies among the on-site

                                         visitors and clientele;
                                     •  Coordinate with the Research Center to determine the matured

                                         technology and/or product of research experiments; and]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[•  Perform other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by

                                         higher authorities.
                              f.  Head, Technology Promotion Division. The Head of the Technology

                                 Promotion Division shall perform the following duties:

                                     •  Establish linkages with the target communities;
                                     •  Assist in the conduct of Community Needs Assessment to

                                         determine the appropriate technology needed by the

                                         community/clientele;
                                     •  Validate and package appropriate technology for efficient

                                         delivery/transfer;

                                     •  Prepare reports and make necessary recommendations on possible
                                         technology transfers to be done in the community/clientele;

                                     •  Spearhead information dissemination activities;

                                     •  Facilitate technology forum, consultative dialogues, fairs, exhibits,
                                         etc.; and

                                     •  Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by
                                         higher authorities

                              g.  College/Campus  Extension  Coordinators.  The  College/Campus
                                 Extension Coordinator shall perform the following duties:

                                     •  Initiate the planning, implementation and evaluation of extension

                                         programs/activities in their respective colleges/campuses;
                                     •  Supervise,  coordinate  and  monitor  the  conduct  of  extension

                                         activities in their adopted communities;

                                     •  Coordinate  with  the  University  Extension  Services  the  extension
                                         activities of the campus/college;

                                     •  Prepare and submit progress and accomplishment reports (monthly,

                                         quarterly and annually) to the University Extension Services;
                                     •  Establish linkages with government and non-government agencies

                                         for the effective implementation of the extension and community

                                         outreach programs of the College/Campus;
                                     •  Serve  as  a  link  between  the  College/Campus  and  the  University

                                         Extension Services;

                                     •  Attend the regular meeting of Extension Coordinators;]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[•  Represent  the  College/Campus  during  the  Extension  in-house

                                         reviews; and
                                     •  Perform  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be  assigned  by

                                         higher authorities.


               Article 3. Extension Services Resources

                       Section 1. Manpower Resources


                       a.  Extension Services Director. The Extension Services Director must possess the
                          following qualifications:

                              •  Must have at least a Master’s Degree, preferably with Doctoral units/degree

                              •  Must have at least one (1) year of administrative experience
                              •  Must have at least one (1) year of experience in extension work

                              •  Must hold a permanent position

                              •  Must have no administrative or criminal case
                       b.  Support  Staff.  The  Extension  Services  support  staff  should  be  of  different

                          disciplines related to the thrusts of the University. They shall be selected using the

                          evaluation system stated in Sections 1 to 5 of Rule VIII (Terms and Conditions of
                          Employment) of the University Code. All support staff shall be selected based on

                          the qualifications set by the Civil Service Commission.
                       c.  College/Campus  Extension  Coordinators.  The  College/  Campus  Extension

                          Coordinators must possess the following qualifications:

                              •  Must have at least a Master’s Degree
                              •  Must have at least one (1) year of experience in extension work

                              •  Must hold a permanent position

                              •  Must have no administrative or criminal case

                       Section 2. The Extension Services houses the Farmers’ Technology Demonstration

               Farm which serves as a showcase platform of different farming systems and technologies. This

               aims to assist the farmers/clients/students to have actual exposures and experiences in the
               operation of a farm or an agro-entrepreneurial project.


                       Section 3. Finance

                       a.  Sources of Funds. Financial resources are generated through grants, donations,

                          bilateral  agreements  and  collaborations  with  government  and  nongovernment]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[agencies private institutions, foreign funding institutions and other agencies and

                          councils.

                                 There are two major classifications of fund sources: the internal and external

                          funds. The internal funds come from the general appropriation allocation (GAA) of
                          the Philippine government. The Center also generates fund from various income

                          generating projects of the University and a portion of which is allocated for the

                          conduct of the University’s extension activities. On the other hand, the external
                          funds  can  come  from  government  agencies  such  as  Department  of  Agriculture

                          (DA),  Department  of  Interior  and  Local  Government  (DILG),  Department  of
                          Agriculture - Agricultural Training Institute (DA-ATI), Department of Agrarian

                          Reform (DAR), Department of Social Welfare and Development (DSWD), Local
                          Government Unit (LGUs) and others as well as private individuals and institutions

                          both in the Philippines and abroad.


                       b.  Handling of Extension Funds. All funds of Extension Services are handled by the
                          Finance  Management  Office  in  coordination  with  the  Office  of  the  Extension

                          Director. Books of Accounts are kept by the Accounting Department which is under
                          the  supervision  of  the  Vice  President  for  Administrative  and  Support  Services

                          (VPASS). Personnel is assigned at the Accounting Department to handle documents

                          of all extension projects and activities of the University to expedite processing.

                                 External  grants  are  treated  as  trust  funds.  Funds  are  released  to  the

                          Accounting Department by project allotment whereby project/study leaders handle
                          the  processing  of  papers  to  release  the  fund  meant  for  their  extension

                          projects/studies  in  coordination  with  the  Extension  Services  Director.  Funds

                          allocated from the income generating projects are also handled by the Accounting
                          Department and managed by the Extension Services Director.


                       c.  Management of Extension Services Funds.  Extension Services funds shall be
                          reported in terms of obligation or liquidation. The Accounting Department monitors

                          the expenditures in accordance with the items in the budget and sub-allotment.

                          Payrolls, vouchers, request for supplies and materials and other obligation of the
                          projects shall be paid through the Accounting Department with approval from the

                          Vice President for Administrative and Support Services following the accounting
                          and auditing rules and regulations.]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[As  with  any  government  agency,  expenditures  incurred  in  the

                          implementation  of  research  and  extension  programs  in  State  Universities  and
                          Colleges (SUCs) shall be subjected to auditing procedures prescribed by the COA.

                          The  internal  audit  which  is  under  the  supervision  of  the  Office  of  University
                          President and a representative from COA shall conduct the auditing.


               Article 4. Grant Opportunities, Submission of Proposal, Implementation, and Monitoring

               and Evaluation of Extension Projects

                       Section 1. Extension Grant Opportunities


                              Section  1.1.  CvSU  Extension  Grant.  Cavite  State  University  (CvSU)  has
                       trilogy of functions – instruction, research, and extension. All the three functions of the

                       University stand in a tripod in order to attain its mission of educating future leaders,
                       expanding knowledge, and developing technological innovations and provide services

                       to the community.


                              Extension is very significant in the promotion of research outputs for national
                       development.  Without  extension,  information  and  technologies  developed  and

                       produced by the University would not be able to reach its target beneficiaries.


                              Recently, the Commission on Higher Education (CHED) is strengthening the
                       extension function of the Higher Education Institutions (HEIs). In fact, the Commission

                       has Grant-In-Aids (GIA) for extension programs and projects. Aside from CHED, other
                       institutions such as Department of Science and Technology (DOST) and Department

                       of Agriculture (DA) provide grants for extension.

                              To better reinforce the extension function of the University, the creation of the

                       CvSU Extension Grant is proposed. The grant aims to produce high quality and relevant

                       extension projects for the promotion of community development.

                              The CvSU Extension Grant shall give priority to extension projects which are:

                       aligned with the University Research and Extension Agenda; based on the needs of the
                       community;  utilize  University  research  outputs;  multidisciplinary;  and  apply

                       appropriate extension approaches, strategies and methods.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Section 1.1.1. Objectives of the CvSU Extension Grant


                                     1.  Topromote  and  encourage  faculty  and  staff  to  conduct  relevant
                                         extension  activities  and/or  public  service  work  in  line  with

                                         institutional, regional, national, and global thrusts;
                                     2.  To  provide  financial  support  for  extension  projects  that  receive

                                         minimal funds; and

                                     3.  To strengthen the extension function of the University.

                                     Section 1.1.2. Amount of Grant. A maximum of P200,000.00 grant

                                     money per proponent shall be awarded for a one-year extension project.
                                     Once all legal and documentary requirements have been accomplished,

                                     70% of the total amount of grant shall be released to the proponent. The

                                     remaining  balance  shall  only  be  released  after  the  Monitoring  and
                                     Evaluation Division had issued Certificate of Acceptability. It means

                                     that the  project  had  undergone  and  passed  on-site  monitoring,  semi-
                                     annual review, and financial monitoring.


                                            In the case of multi-year projects (with duration of more than one

                                     year),  release  of  grant  money  shall  be  on  an  annual  basis  and  shall
                                     depend on its yearly budgetary requirement. Funds for the succeeding

                                     year/s  shall  only  be  released  after  the  Monitoring  and  Evaluation
                                     Division had issued Certificate of Acceptability.


                              Section 1.2. External Grants. The University Extension Services is tasked to
                              prepare project proposals for external funding to be submitted in accordance to

                              the funding agency or institution’s research and extension thrusts and priorities

                              and  following  the  agency/institution’s  prescribed  format.  However,  in  the
                              absence of any desired format, the CHED’s format for extension proposal may

                              be used (Appendix A. CHED NAFES Proposal Format). In the event that the
                              funding agency/institution requires a counterpart funds, the matter shall be first

                              discussed  with  the  Administrative  Council  of  the  University  and  with

                              consideration of the COA and DBM Rules and Regulations.

                       Section 2. Evaluation of the Extension Project Proposal]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[2.1. Eligibility of the Proponent. Any faculty, non-faculty or extension staff

                              (temporary or permanent) is eligible and encouraged to submit proposals. The
                              extension worker must possess the academic qualifications and track record of

                              successful implementation of projects.

                                     The Extension Services and/or Office of the Vice President for Research

                              and Extension may directly solicit proposals from selected faculty and staff as

                              the need arises.

                              Section 2.2. Format of the Proposal. When applying for extension grant, an

                              extension  project  proposal  must  be  submitted  using  the  prescribed  format
                              proposals (Appendix B. Form No. 5 Extension Project Proposal Format).


                                     Proposal Format for the extension project consists of eight (8) parts. The
                              first  part  is  the  Project  Description  which  contains  the  project’s  basic

                              information such as the Project Title, Agenda Classification, Project Proponent,

                              Target  Beneficiaries,  Community  Location,  Period  of  Implementation,  and
                              Total  Budgetary  Requirement,  Rationale,  Objectives,  Strategies,  Desired

                              Outcome/Impact, Organization and Staffing, Plan of Activities and Budgetary

                              Requirement.

                                     The second part is the Rationale, followed by the Objectives, Strategies,

                              Desired  Outcome/Impact,  Organization  and  Staffing  (Persons  Involved  and
                              Responsibility), Plan of Activities and Budgetary Requirement.


                                     The Extension Project Proposal is signed by the person who prepares
                              the proposal, recommended by the Director/Dean/Head of the division/unit, and

                              approved  by  the  Vice  President/President  of  the  agency  for  the  Extension

                              Services.

                              Section 2.3. Submission of Proposals. The Extension Services requires that

                              proposals be submitted in two (2) copies and electronic copy together with the
                              Endorsement Letter from the College/Campus Dean or /Unit Head.]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[All proposals together with the necessary attachments must be submitted to:


                                            The                                                   Director
                                            Extension                    Services                  Center
                                            Cavite                     State                    University
                                            Don         Severino         delas       Alas         Campus
                                            Indang,                                                Cavite
                                            Phone: (046) 8620 859

                                     Electronic copy of the proposal and its attachments may be sent via

                              email at extensionservices@cvsu.edu.ph.

                                     Prior to submission, all proposals should have been pre-evaluated by the

                              proponent using the Harmonized Gender and Development Guidelines (HGDG)
                              Program/Project Development Evaluation Checklist.


                              Section 2.1.4. Pre-Screening of Proposals. All proposals submitted shall be

                              initially screened by the Monitoring and Evaluation Division of the Extension
                              Services  to  determine  its  completeness,  conformity  with  the  format,

                              nonduplication,  and  alignment  with  the  University  Research  and  Extension
                              Agenda.


                              Approved proposals during the pre-screening shall be endorsed to the Regional

                              Gender and Development Resource Center (RGADRC) for validation of points
                              obtained  by  the  proposal  using  the  HGDG  Program/Project  Development

                              Evaluation Checklist. In case of commodityspecific extension proposals (i.e.
                              coffee,  kaong),  proposals  should  also  be  prescreened  by  the  concerned

                              Commodity RDE Center prior to endorsement to RGADRC. Once proposals are
                              validated/pre-screened,  it  shall  be  returned  back  to  the  Extension  Services

                              together with comments (if there is any). In case of revision, one week shall be

                              given to the proponent to revise the proposal.

                       Section 3. En Banc Evaluation. Once the proposal passes the initial screening, it shall

                       be presented to and evaluated by the Research and Extension Council. The following
                       criteria shall be used for evaluation:


                              a.  Contribution  of  the  program/project  to  regional/national  development
                                 (30%)

                              b.  Contribution to the advancement of target community/clientele (30%)

                              c.  Quality of information/technology to be promoted/disseminated (20%)]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[d.  Appropriateness of approaches/strategies/methods (20%)


                       Section 4. Budget Allocation. Upon approval by the Extension Council, all extension
                       projects whether funded by the University or by external sources are endorsed by the

                       Extension Services Director to the University President for final approval and budget
                       allocation with the recommending approval of the VP for  Research and Extension.

                       Extension  projects  seeking  external  fund  must  conform  to  the  requirements  and

                       procedures of the funding agency. The proponents shall be the one responsible for
                       communicating with external funding agencies regarding the status of their submitted

                       proposals. Moreover, the proponents are required to submit to the Extension Center a
                       copy of the approved memorandum of agreement, photocopy of the check voucher or

                       other records of fund transfer.


                       Section 5. Endorsement of Proposal. Proponents shall be notified of the results of the
                       review whether their proposal passed, needs revision or rejected. If it needs revision,

                       the proponent shall be given ample time to revise the proposal. Extension proposals
                       which passed the review shall be endorsed by Extension Director to the Vice President

                       for  Research  and  Extension,  who  shall  then  endorse  it  to  the  President  for  final
                       approval.


                              The  proposals  shall  also  be  given  attribution  to  GAD  budget.  For  record

                       purposes, RGADRC, Concerned Commodity R&E Center and MIS Officer shall be
                       furnished a copy of the approved proposals. List of approved proposals shall also be

                       presented to the CvSU Administrative Council for confirmation.

                       Section 6. Processing of Funds. The Extension Services shall prepare the contract for

                       signature of the proponent and all authorities concerned.


                              The Extension Services shall also facilitate the processing of the project fund.
                       Under the CvSU Extension Grant, the release of funds shall depend on the approved

                       line item budget.

                              Section 7. Program/Project Implementation. After approval of the proposal

                       for  funding,  the  project  proponent/s  must  attend  a  pre-implementation  meeting  to

                       finalize the project timeline and activities and to be aware of their duties and obligations
                       during the period of implementation.]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Section  7.1.  Pre-Implementation  Meeting.  A  pre-implementation

                                     meeting  shall  be  conducted  prior  to  the  start  of  implementation  of
                                     extension  projects.  It  aims  to  fine-tune  or  finalize  the  project

                                     implementation  timelines  as  well  as  the  monitoring  and  evaluation
                                     arrangements.  During  the  said  meeting,  Notice  to  Proceed  and  first

                                     tranche  of  project  funds  shall  be  released  to  the  proponent.  Also,

                                     duration  (start  and  end)  of  the  project  shall  also  be  adjusted  (if
                                     necessary) and finalized.


                                            The Extension Services shall set the schedule and venue of the
                                     meeting. Pre-implementation meeting is usually conducted only once

                                     but in case there are issues or recommendations not threshed out during
                                     the meeting, a follow-up pre-implementation meeting may be agreed

                                     upon.


                                            The  following  are  expected  to  attend  the  pre-implementation
                                     meeting:


                                                •  Extension Services Director/representative

                                                •  Extension  M&E  Division  Staff  (shall  serve  as  the
                                                   moderator during the meeting)

                                                •  Proponent

                                                •  Extension Coordinator of the Campus/College where the
                                                   proponent belongs

                                                •  Representative from OVPRE

                                                •  Representative from Administration Office
                                                •  Representative from Finance Office

                                                •  Technical expert (identified by the Extension Services) *


                                                *The identified expert shall serve as one of the evaluators for
                                                the whole duration of the project.


                                            During  the  pre-implementation  meeting,  the  proponent  shall
                                     present  the  general  framework  of  the  project  and  its  strategies  for

                                     implementation  including  the  work  plan  and  budget  summary.  The
                                     M&E  Division  staff  of  the  Extension  Services  shall  discuss  the]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[parameters  for  monitoring  and  evaluating  the  project.  Meanwhile,

                                     representatives  from  the  Administration  and  Finance  Offices  shall
                                     present  the  guidelines  for  purchasing  supplies  and  materials,  hiring

                                     project staff, among others. All comments and recommendations shall
                                     be  documented  by  the  M&E  Division.  Afterwards,  a  copy  of  the

                                     highlights of the meeting shall be distributed to all the attendees of the

                                     meeting for their guidance

                                     Section  7.2.  Hiring/Appointment  of  Personnel  and  Professional

                                     Services.  Upon  the  approval  of  the  proposal,  the  proponent  or  the
                                     appointed project leader is authorized to hire the necessary project staff

                                     or  expert  required  to  conduct  and  complete  the  deliverables  of  the
                                     project. The hired or appointed staff must be paid for the services they

                                     rendered; provided that the terms, conditions, and salary rates are strictly

                                     in accordance with the approved line item budget of the project and
                                     following  the  accounting  and  auditing  rules  and  regulations  of  the

                                     University.

                                     Section 7.3. Responsibilities of the Program/Project Personnel


                                     a.  Program Leader. The Program Leader shall perform the following

                                         functions in the implementation of the program:
                                            •  Provide  overall  direction  in  terms  of  setting  common

                                                directions of the projects under the program;

                                            •  Set  the  work  plan  of  the  various  projects  to  establish
                                                synchronicity  and  coordination  between  project  activities

                                                and schedule in order to attain the objectives of the program;
                                            •  Represent  the  program  in  dealing  with  collaborating  and

                                                other external agencies; and

                                            •  In  cases  where  the  Program  Leader  is  concurrently  the
                                                Project  Leader  of  a  component  project,  he  must  also

                                                accomplish the duties expected of a Project Leader.

                                     b.  Project  Leader.  The  Project  Leader  shall  perform  the  following
                                         functions in the implementation of the program:

                                            •  Plan, organize and direct the overall conduct of the project;]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[•  Spearhead the conduct of extension activities;

                                            •  Hire and recommend the appointment of the required project
                                                personnel;

                                            •  Recommend  payment  of  salaries  and  compensations  of

                                                project personnel; and
                                            •  Prepare  and  submit  progress  reports,  annual  reports,  and

                                                terminal report

                                     c.  Project Staff/Extension Officer
                                            •  Assist the Project Leader in planning and managing overall

                                                extension project operations;

                                            •  Initiate the daily conduct of extension activities;
                                            •  Supervise  the  collection  of  necessary  data  and  materials

                                                related to the extension activities; and

                                            •  Assist the Project Leader in preparing progress reports

                                     Section 7.4. Collaborations.  Established linkages and collaborations

                                     must  have  either  a  Memorandum  of  Agreement  or  Memorandum  of
                                     Understanding  forged  between  the  University  and  the  collaborating

                                     agency/institution/establishment. The document shall be duly signed by

                                     the  parties  involved  and  shall  be  notarized  by  authorized  legal
                                     authorities.


                                            Terms of reference, responsibilities of each party, contents and
                                     other pertinent items shall be discussed between the concerned parties

                                     before drawing the agreements.

                                     Section  7.5.  Conduct  of  Trainings.  The  conduct  of  trainings  and

                              seminars related to the extension project shall be based on the needs of the

                              community or stakeholders as per results of the Community Needs Assessment
                              conducted  by  the  Extension  Office.  An  activity  proposal  containing  the

                              mechanics and the budgetary requirement shall be submitted to the University
                              President before the conduct of the training/seminar. Moreover, training for

                              capability enhancement of the Extension Coordinators/Staff may also be done
                              subject to availability of funds. Request from other stakeholders and partner

                              communities and agencies may also be conducted provided that they have sent]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[letter  of  request  to  the  University  President  who  has  the  sole  authority  to

                              approve the request.

                       Section 8. Monitoring and Evaluation of Extension Projects. To ensure efficient and

                       effective project implementation, monitoring and evaluation shall be conducted by the
                       Monitoring and Evaluation Division with the identified technical expert.


                              a.  Progress Reports. All project proponents are required to submit two (2)

                                 hard copies and electronic copy of their semi-annual and annual reports duly
                                 endorsed by the Campus/College Dean or Unit Head.

                              b.  On-site/Field Monitoring. If necessary, on-site or field monitoring shall be
                                 conducted to validate the progress reports submitted by the proponent. The

                                 schedule shall be set by the Extension M&E Division.

                              c.  Semi-Annual/Annual Review. Semi-annual review (for one year projects)
                                 and annual review (for multi-year projects) are conducted to determine the

                                 continuance or termination of an extension project. The number of reviews
                                 to be conducted annually shall depend on the number of on-going projects.

                                 Schedule of which shall be set by the Extension Center. Selected members
                                 of Research and Extension Council and/or experts from other institutions

                                 shall be invited as evaluators during the review.

                                         During the review, proponents shall present the progress and plans
                                 for  the  continuation  of  implementation  of  the  project.  Evaluators  shall

                                 provide  their  comments/suggestions/  recommendations  on  the  progress
                                 report  and  presentation.  The  M&E  division  shall  document,

                                 integrate/consolidate the given comments and suggestions. The same shall

                                 provide the proponents copy 29 of the review results for their guidance.
                                 Once the project passed the review, a Certificate of Acceptability shall be

                                 issued to the proponent.
                                         The Extension Services reserves the right to discontinue the project

                                 anytime upon due consultation with the proponent and the technical expert

                                 and upon the approval of the President if there is a violation of the contract
                                 or if the soundness of the extension project becomes questionable.


                       Section  9.  Annual  Extension  Agency  In-House  Review.  One  major  activity  to
                       facilitate the monitoring and evaluation of extension projects is the conduct of the]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Annual Extension Agency In-house Review. It involves the evaluation of all extension

                       projects that are either completed or ongoing during the particular year under review.
                       During  these  reviews,  individuals  involved  in  the  projects  shall  present  the

                       progress/highlights of their extension projects. Evaluators consist of members from the
                       Research  and  Extension  Council,  Southern  Tagalog  Agriculture,  Aquatic  and

                       Resources Research and Development Consortium (STAARRDEC), and experts from

                       other HEIs.

                              A.  Goals. The goals of conducting annual agency in-house review are to:

                                     •  Establish an additional institutional mechanism for the monitoring

                                         and   evaluation    of   the   different   extension   programs/
                                         projects/activities (E-PPAs) of the University;

                                     •  Increase faculty and staff  participation in extension and outreach
                                         activities;

                                     •  Acquire papers on CvSU extension services which are acceptable

                                         for publication on appropriate Journals; and
                                     •  Improve techniques, strategies and/or approaches in extension

                              B.  Objectives. The objectives of conducting annual agency in-house review
                                 are to:

                                     •  Encourage  faculty  and  staff  to  write  their  extension  works  and

                                         outputs;
                                     •  Present  the  extension  activities  of  the  different  colleges  and

                                         campuses;

                                     •  Recognize and award commendable extension programs, projects
                                         and activities;

                                     •  Document results of extension programs, projects and activities; and

                                     •  Acquire  effective  and  innovative  techniques  and/or  strategies  in
                                         extension

                              C.  Schedule. The reviews shall be conducted at least twice a year to select

                                 papers in time for the regional reviews and publication.
                              D.  Evaluation Panel. The University shall notify STAARRDEC regarding the

                                 upcoming  agency  in-house  review  to  identify  external  evaluators  of  the
                                 extension projects. The evaluators shall be composed of the following:

                                     •  Experts within the University or experts from other HEIs]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[•  Members  of  the  national/regional  commodity  R&E  team/pool  of

                                         experts
                                     •  Farmer co-operators

                                     •  Representatives from funding agencies (e.g. PCAARRD, DA-BAR,

                                         CHED, etc.)
                              E.  Evaluation Criteria. The major criteria that shall be used in evaluating the

                                 ongoing extension projects are the following:

                                     •  Attainment of the objectives
                                     •  Adherence  to  the  approved  methodology  or  recommendation  of

                                         more appropriate methodology

                                     •  Adherence to the approved budget
                                     •  Accomplishments including status of technology generated/verified

                                     •  Actions taken in response to previous year’s comments


                                     For completed extension projects, the major criteria for evaluation that
                                     shall be used are the following:


                                         •  Creativity, originality, and quality of work

                                         •  Significance of findings
                                         •  Manuscript/write-up

                                         •  Presentation

                       Section 10. Request for Extending Project Extension. Requests for extension of the

                       project shall only be entertained at least three (3) months before the completion date.

                       Requests for project extension shall be submitted to the Extension Services and shall
                       be supported by the following documents:


                              a.  Request letter duly endorsed by the Campus/College Dean or Unit Head
                              b.  Latest financial report

                              c.  Revised Work Plan

                              d.  Justification for extension

                              There shall be no additional budget that shall be released for project extension.

                       A  project  proponent  shall  only  be  allowed  once  to  request  for  project  extension.
                       However, in extreme and justifiable reasons may be allowed another re-extension.]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Section 11. Project Completion/Termination


                              Section 11.1. Submission of Terminal Report. Not more than thirty (30) days
                              after  the  project  was  completed/terminated,  five  (5)  hard  copies  of  the  32

                              Terminal  Report,  duly  endorsed  by  the  Campus/College  Dean  or  Unit
                              Head,should be submitted.


                                     The terminal report should be accompanied by supporting documents

                              such  as  pictures,  evaluation  sheets,  IEC  materials,  Community  Needs
                              Assessments,  and  other  outputs  that  may  show  the  results  of  the  activities

                              conducted.

                                     Undisbursed funds shall be returned to the Cashier and an official receipt

                              shall be properly issued.


                              Section 11.2. Conduct of Terminal Review. A Terminal Review is conducted after
                              the completion of an extension program/project to determine if the proposed objectives
                              were met. A panel of evaluators, which is composed of technical experts from within

                              or outside the University, shall be invited to conduct the review.

                       Section 12. Publication. Proponents with outputs that are publishable should submit at least
                       one article (per study) to the CvSU Research Journal or any reputable journal for possible

                       publication. It is the responsibility of the proponent to ensure that the Extension Services is
                       furnished a copy of the evidence of submission including the copy of the article submitted.

                       Section  13.  Intellectual  Property.  For  output  that  is  new,  novel  or  an  inventive

                       technique,  the  proponent  is  advised  to  seek  assistance  from  Intellectual  Property

                       Management Office (IPMO) for application of IP protection.

                       Section  14.  Paper  Presentation.  The  extension  paper  may  be  presented  in  any

                       regional, national, or international extension conference, fora, seminar, or meeting as
                       long as full acknowledgement shall be given to the University. Also, the presentation

                       should  not  prejudice  the  proprietary/confidential  nature  of  the  information  for  the

                       purposes of IP protection.

               Article 5. Awards and Incentives for Conducting Extension Activities


                       Section  1.  Workload.  A  workload  points  shall  be  given  to  a  faculty  member  as
               incentive for conducting extension projects/activities based on the guidelines set in the Unified

               Workload System approved by the Board of Regents during its 70th Regular Meeting held on]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[March 24, 2017. It covers the core (e.g. instruction, research and extension) and strategic (e.g.

               administrative assignments and o other services) functions of a faculty member (Appendix C.
               University Workload System).


                       Section 2. Honorarium. A faculty or staff involved in extension projects or activities
               is entitled to receive honoraria from externally-funded projects or activities provided that it is

               clearly  indicated  in  the  approved  line  item  budget  (LIB),  memorandum  of

               understanding/agreement (MOU/MOA) or certificate of compensation.

                       Project  leaders  of  externally-funded  R  and  E  projects  without  honorarium  (e.g.

               institutional development grant; grants in kind; conduct of training, workshop, conference and
               etc.) shall be entitled to receive honorarium under the indirect cost or admin cost of the project’s

               approved LIB. The project leader shall receive 30% of the total amount of indirect cost or the

               amount specified in the LIB.

                       No  honorarium  from  the  University’s  fund  is  given  to  the  extension  worker  in

               accordance with DBM Budget Circular 2007-1 Approved on April 23, 2007. Furthermore, all
               R and E activities with honorarium shall be excluded from the computation of work overload

               pay of the researcher.

                       Section 3. Publication Awards. A monetary and certificate of recognition shall be

               given to faculty and staff who published extension-related articles in scientific journals based

               on the Guidelines for Granting Incentives for Publication of Faculty and Staff (Appendix D)
               approved during the 63rd Regular Meeting of the CvSU's Board of Regents held on March 19,

               2015.

                       Section  4.  Best  Performing  College/Campus.  The  objective  of  this  award  is  to

               compensate and give due recognition to the concerted efforts and exemplary accomplishments

               in research and extension activities of different Colleges and Campuses of the University.

                       The awarding shall be done during the Annual R and E Week. A special committee

               composed of the VPRE, VPAA and VP for Planning and Development shall be formed to
               conduct the selection of the Best Performing College/Campus. Criteria for evaluation shall be

               based on indicators of MFO 3, MFO 4, KRA 2, KRA 3 and KRA 4. The college/campus with

               the highest points shall be declared as the winner.

                       A  Certificate  of  Recognition  shall  be  given  to  the  Dean/Campus  Director;

               College/Campus R and E Coordinator and the College/Campus. A monetary award of not less]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[than P300, 000.00 shall be given to the Best Performing College/Campus to be used for conduct

               of  R  and  E  activities  and  research  capacity  building.  An  additional  amount  not  less  than
               P100,00.00 shall be given if the proposal is focused on coffee and not less than P50,000 if on

               other focus commodity thrusts of the University.

                       Section  5.  Outstanding  Extensionist  Award.  This  award  recognizes  the  exemplary

               performance of faculty and staff to encourage and to promote excellence in extension services.


                       Faculty and staff of the University must satisfy the minimum qualifications in order to
               be nominated for the Outstanding Research Award and Outstanding Extension Award.


                       These qualifications are the following:

                          •  Permanent or temporary appointment during the period under review

                          •  Has  at  least  three  years  of  continuous  service  immediately  preceding  the

                              nomination
                          •  Has not committed acts of plagiarism, intellectual dishonesty and other acts of

                              unprofessionalism

                          •  Should have at least one funded extension project/program during the period
                              under review


                       The applicant must submit the prescribed application form together with the required
               supporting documents.


                       Selection of the awardee is based on the following criteria:


                          •  Originality (25%) - the extension work should contribute new knowledge and
                              service to the community

                          •  Productivity  (20%)  -  shall  consider  the  amount  of  resource  generated  as

                              principal investigators. Only those projects which have been acknowledged by
                              the Extension Services shall be considered.

                          •  Paper presentations and publications (20%) - shall be based on papers published

                              in  scientific  journals,  monographs,  information  bulletins,  books  and  other
                              refereed publications in the last three years and papers presented I n national

                              and international conferences and unpublished reports of completed projects.
                          •  Significance of extension activity/project (20%) - the extension projects should

                              have significant impact to institutional, regional or national development.]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[•  Recognition given to the extension project (15%)– this includes awards received

                              associated with the extension project conducted; citations, and other forms of
                              recognition from academic institutions/organizations or societies (scientific or

                              learned) given to the extensionist.

                       A Selection committee shall be formed and recommended to the University President

                       by the OVPRE. The College Dean/Campus Directors shall endorse one nominee. A

                       minimum score of 80 is required for a nominee to win the award

                              A plaque of recognition shall be given to the outstanding researcher. In addition

                       to this, a monetary award of not less than P20, 000.00 shall be given to the awardee.
                       The award shall be given during the annual University Foundation day celebration. A

                       call  for  nominations,  selection  process  and  amount  prizes  shall  be  announced  by

                       OVPRE not later than January 15 of each year. Winners shall not be eligible for the
                       award for 2 consecutive years.


                              Section 6. Travel Grant. The University provides travel grant to its faculty
                       members and staff to present their research and extension outputs in recognized fora. It

                       is the responsibility of the concerned personnel to facilitate the processing of their

                       request for travel including the necessary travel arrangements.

                              Travel  request  should  be  submitted  to  the  Office  of  the  Vice  President  for

                       Research and Extension, at least three working days prior to the scheduled travel. In
                       case  the  travel  requires  cash  advance,  R&E  personnel  are  advised  to  process  their

                       requests at least a month before the date of departure.

                              In case the travel requires airfare and/or budget more than P 10,000.00, the letter

                       of request approved by the President should be attached. Please note that budgetary

                       requirement for travel should be stipulated in the letter of request. In the case of travel
                       abroad, the faculty member or staff must also secure Travel Authority from the Human

                       Resource Management Office (HRMO) before the travel.

                              If the purpose of travel is initiated by the office/unit where the faculty/staff

                       belongs, any supporting document indicating the purpose of travel shall be attached.

                       Requester with pending travel report shall not be processed.

                              Upon approval of the travel grant, the faculty/staff must submit a Travel Report

                       including  attachments  which  are  applicable  (i.e.  publication,  minutes  of  meeting,]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[accomplished  monitoring  forms,  proceedings,  certificate  of  appearance  and/or

                       participation, attendance sheet, project proposal, etc.) a week after the travel to the
                       Office of the VP for Research and Extension.]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>