<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.6.            The following basic services are


                        available:


                        S.6.1.  Student Welfare;

                                        S.6.1.5.  Student Handbook


                                                         Development;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Student Handbook]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Section 3. The Institutional Student Programs and Services

                              The Institutional Student Programs and Services are designed to
                       proactively respond to the basic health, food, shelter and safety concerns of
                       students.

                       Section 4. The Research, Monitoring and Evaluation of Student Services Unit

                              The  Research,  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Student  Services  Unit  shall
                       conduct  researches  related  to  student  welfare  and  development,  and  shall  be
                       in-charge of evaluating student services with the objective of utilizing research
                       and evaluation results in institutional development.

               Article 5. Student Welfare Services

                       The Student Welfare Services (SWS) are basic services and programs needed to
               ensure and promote the well-being of students. These include Information, Orientation
               and Awareness, Guidance and Counselling, Career and Placement, Student Handbook
               and Economic Enterprise Development.

                       Section 1. Information and Orientation

                              1.1.  The  Information  and  Orientation  Services  shall  prepare
                                     information  materials  on  institutional  mission,  vision,  and goals,
                                     academic  rules  and  regulations,  student  conduct  and  discipline,
                                     student  programs,  services  and  facilities  which  should  be  made
                                     accessible and available to all students.
                              1.2.  A  regular  comprehensive  orientation  program  for  new  and
                                     continuing students shall be conducted.
                              1.3.  An  organized,  updated  and  readily  available  educational,  career
                                     and personal/social materials in different accessible formats shall
                                     be prepared and made available to students.

                       Section 2. Guidance and Counselling

                              2.1.   A  counselling  room  shall  be  provided  to  ensure  the  privacy  and
                                     confidentiality counselling sessions.
                              2.2.   Guidance service offers a set of services using integrated approach
                                     to  the  development  of  well-functioning  individuals  primarily  by
                                     helping them to utilize their potentials to the fullest.
                              2.3.   Counselling shall be provided by way of individual and/or group
                                     intervention  designed  to  facilitate  positive  change  in  student
                                     behaviour, feelings and attitudes.
                              2.4.   The  guidance  office  shall  maintain  a  regularly  updated student’s
                                     cumulative records which contain relevant information about the
                                     student.
                              2.5.   A well planned assessment program for students with appropriate
                                     standardized psychological tests shall be implemented, the results
                                     of which shall be interpreted to students, teachers and concerned
                                     individuals



                Excerpts from the Manual of Operation]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[2.6.   There  shall  be  adequate  and  appropriate  follow-up  and  referral
                                     schemes known to students and concerned parties.

                       Section 3. Career and Job Placement

                              3.1.   There shall be regular career seminars and job placement services
                                     available for students
                              3.2.   Valid appraisal data of students for career and job placement shall
                                     be instituted.
                              3.3.   The  University  through  the  Career  and  Placement  Office  shall
                                     provide assistance in seeking career and job placement.

                        Section 4. Student Handbook and Enterprise Development

                              The  Central  Student  Government,  assisted  by  designated  faculty
                      members  and  OSAS  staff,  shall  be  responsible  in  the  preparation,  revision,
                      updating and distribution of student handbook which should be made available
                      into accessible formats for dissemination, information and guidance of students
                       and university stakeholders .


               Article 6. The Student Development Services (SDS)
                       These are services and programs designed  for the   exploration, enhancement
               and development of student’s full potential for personal development , leadership and
               social responsibility through various institutional and/or stu
                       dent-initiated  activities.  These  programs  and  activities  include  Student
               Organizations  and  Activities,  Leadership  Training  Programs,  Student  Government,
               Student Discipline and Student Publication.

                       Section 1. Student Privileges and Responsibilities.
                              Unless,  otherwise  superseded  by  a  more  recent  basis,  the  rights,
                       privileges  granted  to  students  and  their  responsibilities  while  in  school  shall
                       conform to those promulgated in the Education Act of 1982. These are:
                              1.1.   The  right  to  receive,  primarily  through  competent  instruction,
                                     relevant  quality  education  in  line  with  national  goals  and
                                     conducive to their full development as persons with human dignity
                              1.2.   The right to freely choose their fields of study subject to existing
                                     curricula  and to  continue  their  course  therein  up to  graduation,
                                     except in cases of academic deficiency, or violation of disciplinary
                                     regulations
                              1.3.   The  right  to  University  guidance  and  counseling  services  for
                                     making  decisions  and  selecting  the  alternatives  in  fields  of  work
                                     suited to their potentialities
                              1.4.   The  right  to  access  to  their  own  records,  the  confidentiality  of
                                     which the University shall maintain and preserve
                              1.5.   The  right  to  the  issuance  of  official  certificates,  diplomas,
                                     transcript  of  records,  grades,  transfer  credentials,  and  other
                                     similar documents within thirty (30) days from request.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>