<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="21"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[O.1.            Awareness and acceptance of the


                        VMGO by the administrators, faculty,


                        staff, students, and other stakeholders

                        are evident.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Study on the awareness




                   and acceptance of the




               VMGO by the stakeholders




               published in international




                       refereed journal]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

                           STAKEHOLDERS' ACCEPTANCE AND PERCEIVED
                     ATTAINABILITY OF CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY – TANZA

                CAMPUS VISION, MISSION, GOALS, AND OBJECTIVES TOWARDS
                              EDUCATIONAL ACTIVITIES AND PRACTICES



                               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN* AND ESTELITA A. VILLA
                                            Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                   *Corresponding Author



               ABSTRACT

               This study focused on determining the perception and acceptance of the stakeholders towards
               the  vision,  mission,  goals,  and  objectives  (VMGO)  of  Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza
               Campus. It also assessed the attainability and congruence of the VMGO to the educational
               practices and activities of the said institution. It employed a descriptive research design using
               a survey questionnaire administered using Google forms. A total of 794 internal and external
               stakeholders participated in the study using snowball sampling to reach the stakeholders via
               email and other social media sites before and during the pandemic. Data were tabulated and
               analyzed using SPSS. Results show that all the internal and external stakeholders are highly
               aware, moderately understood, and greatly accept the VMGO. Results also show that all the
               internal and external stakeholders generally perceived that the VMGO is very clear, highly
               attainable,  and  highly  relevant/congruent.  It  also  reveals  no  significant  differences  in  the
               stakeholders' responses regarding their  perception  of the awareness, understanding,  clarity,
               acceptance, attainability, and congruence to the educational practices, activities, projects, and
               operations of CvSU. Thus, it is recommended that CvSU-Tanza Campus continue the widest
               dissemination of the VMGO through various forms, conduct training for the stakeholders to
               fully understand the VMGO, and encourage the stakeholders to take part in the realization of
               the VMGO through quality instruction, research, and extension activities.


               Keywords:  Vision  and  mission  statements,  VMGO,  Cavite  State  University,  acceptance,
               attainability, congruence

               1.0 INTRODUCTION


               Cavite  State  University  (CvSU)  envisages  being  the  premier  University  in  historic  Cavite
               (Philippines),  recognized  for  excellence  in  the  development  of  globally  competitive  and
               morally upright individuals. It articulates this vision by providing excellent, equitable, and
               relevant  educational  opportunities  in  the  arts,  sciences,  and  technology  through  quality
               instruction and responsive research and development activities. It shall produce professional,
               skilled, and morally upright individuals for global competitiveness (Cavite State University,
               2022).

               All academic units (i.e., colleges and campuses) within CvSU are required to have goals that
               align with the University's vision and mission, and all programs within an academic unit are
               required to have objectives that align with those goals.CvSU – Tanza Campus (TC), one of

               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 145]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               its ten campuses, is no exemption as it aims to provide high-quality instruction to produce
               skilled, morally upright, and globally competitive graduates; develop and pursue advanced
               research activities through arts, sciences, and technology to support instruction; and develop
               and  conduct  extension  activities  that  will  empower  people  and  communities.  Hence,  its
               program offerings aim to produce graduates who can demonstrate competencies in their fields
               of  specialization  or  chosen  careers  and  with  critical  and  creative  thinking  skills,  ethical
               leadership, and morally upright values.

               CvSU  –  TC  continuously  seeks  accreditation  from  the  Accrediting  Agency  for  Chartered
               Colleges  and  Universities  in  the  Philippines  (AACCUP)  for  its  different  programs.
               Accreditation is a review procedure used to determine whether educational programs meet
               specific  quality  standards.  Accreditation  is  not permanent.  After  being  granted, it  must  be
               renewed periodically to ensure that the caliber of the educational program is maintained. It
               culminates in an external quality review by a team of professional experts from the AACCUP
               officials  and  senior  accreditors,  academic  program  specialists,  the  AACCUP  pool  of
               institutional accreditors, and international experts (Corpuz, n.d). There are ten standards/key
               result areas in all program accreditation instruments. The ultimate goal is to assess whether
               the  institution  has  achieved  its  vision,  mission,  goals,  and  objectives  (VMGO)  through
               relevant instruction, research, and extension activities.

               The efficacy of the VMGO depends on how it is disseminated and understood. To attain this,
               the stakeholders of an educational institution have to be fully aware of its VMGO and fully
               accept  its  implication  (Castillo,  2014).  Various  authors  have  assessed  the  awareness,
               acceptability, and perception of CvSU  stakeholders towards its  VMGO  (Gomez  & Basco,
               2022; Cahapin,  Malabag, Samson,  & Santiago, 2022). While these  studies  focused on  the
               awareness, acceptability, and perception of CvSU stakeholders towards its VMGO, this study
               has also assessed the stakeholders' perception of the CvSU-TC VMGO and its attainability
               and  congruence  to  educational  activities  and  practices  aside  from  the  factors  mentioned
               above.

               Perception  of  VMGO  means  how  the  stakeholders  are  aware  of  and  how  clear  they
               understand and accept the CvSU-TC VMGO. Having clarity of perception about the VMGO
               means having a clear view or understanding. Hence, if CvSU – TC stakeholders have high
               clarity of perception towards its VMGO, it is tantamount to say that the vision and mission
               statements are clearly defined, stated, and reflect what CvSU hopes to become in the future.

               On the other hand, having congruency between actual educational practices and activities and
               the VMGO means that there is a clear consensus that VMGO were clearly defined and that
               the processes and activities to achieve such are clear and in the correct order.

               In view of the preceding statements, this study was conducted to:

               1. Determine the perception of CvSU stakeholders towards its VMGO in terms of:

                   a.  awareness;
                   b.  understanding;
                   c.  clarity;



               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 146]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               2. Determine the level of acceptance CvSU stakeholders towards its VMGO;

               3. Assess the extent of attainability and congruence of the VMGO to educational practices
               and activities;

               4.  Determine  the  significant  differences  in  the  stakeholders'  perception  and  level  of
               acceptance  towards  CvSU-TC  VMGO  and  its  attainability  and  congruence  to  educational
               practices and activities.


               2.0 METHODOLOGY

               The  study  used  a  descriptive  research  method  to  determine  the  perception  and  level  of
               acceptance  of  the  CvSU  stakeholders  towards  its  VMGO.  Likewise,  the  attainability  and
               congruence  of  the  said  VMGO  to  the  educational  practices  and  activities  in  the  different
               programs of CvSU-TC were also assessed.

               A stakeholder survey questionnaire via Google forms was used to gather data from a total of
               794  stakeholders  consisting  of  91  alumna/alumnus,  79  community  members  or  extension
               clientele, 29 administrators,  faculty  members and  staff, 23 industry linkage and/or partner
               agencies,  128  parents  and/or  guardians,  and  444  students.  The  researchers  used  snowball
               sampling to reach the stakeholders during the pandemic via any possible means (i.e., email
               and/or social media sites).

               Data were tabulated and analyzed using SPSS. Descriptive statistics using weighted means
               and  standard  deviations  were used to  determine the  perception (awareness, understanding,
               clarity)  and  level  of  acceptance  of  CvSU-TC  stakeholders  towards  its  VMGO.  The  same
               statistical tools were used to determine the extent of attainability and congruence of VMGO
               to educational practices and activities. On the other hand, analysis of variance (ANOVA) was
               used to determine if there are significant differences in the stakeholders' perception and level
               of acceptance towards CvSU-TC VMGO and its attainability and congruence to educational
               practices and activities when grouped according to the nature of stakeholders.

               The following scale and interpretation were used to better understand the quantitative data:


               Table 1. Verbal Interpretation of the Stakeholder's Perception and Acceptance of the
               VMGO
                      Weighted Means      Awareness     Understanding      Clarity      Acceptance
                         3.26 – 4.00     Highly aware       Highly       Very clear    Greatly accept
                                                          understood
                         2.51 – 3.25      Moderately      Moderately        Clear         Accept
                                            aware         understood
                         1.76 – 2.50     Slightly aware    Slightly     Slightly clear  Slightly accept
                                                          understood
                         1.00 – 1.75      Not aware     Not understood    Not clear     Not accept

               Table  2.  Verbal  Interpretation  of  the  Attainability  of  VMGO  and  its  Relevance  and
               Congruence to Educational Practices and Activities



               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 147]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

                               Weighted          Attainability      Relevance and Congruence
                                Means                               to Practices and Activities
                              3.26 – 4.00       Highly attainable    Highly relevant/congruent
                              2.51 – 3.25     Moderately attainable        Moderately
                                                                        relevant/congruent
                              1.76 – 2.50      Slightly attainable   Slightly relevant/congruent
                              1.00 – 1.75        Not attainable       Not relevant/congruent

               3.0 RESULTS AND DISCUSSION

               3.1 Stakeholders' Profiles

               Table  3  shows  the  internal  stakeholders'  demographic  profile  regarding  age  and  sex.  The
               majority (34.48%) of the administrators/faculty/staff range from 28-32 years of age and most
               (78.83%) of the students range from 18-22 years of age. Female administrators/faculty/staff
               (75.86%) are more than thrice higher than male administrators/faculty/staff (24.14%). Female
               students (62.61%) are higher than male students (37.39%).

               Table 3. Distribution of Internal Stakeholders according to profiles

                     Demographic Profiles      Administrators/Faculty/Staff           Students
                                                   F               %              F            %
                     Age         18 – 22            2             6.90           350          78.83
                                 23 – 27            8             27.59           64          14.41
                                 28 – 32           10             34.48           22           4.95
                                 33 – 37            9             31.03            8           1.80
                                  Total            29            100.00          444         100.00
                      Sex        Female            22             75.86          278          62.61
                                  Male              7             24.14          166          37.39
                                  Total            29            100.00          444         100.00

               Table 4 shows the demographic profile of the external stakeholders in terms of age and sex.
               Most alumni (68.13%) and community members (83.54) range from 18-22 years of age. The
               majority  (84.38%)  of  the  parents  range  from  18-22  years  of  age  while  many  (73.91%)
               industry  partners  range  from  28.32  years  of  age.  All  the  female  (alumni,  parents,  and
               community  members)  respondents  dominate  the  male  (alumni,  parents,  and  community
               members) respondents. The percentage of female respondents is as follows: 60.44% alumni,
               63.28%  parents,  and  70.89%  community  members.  In  contrast,  male  industry  partners
               dominate female industry partners. 14 out of 23 (60.87%) are male.

               Table 4. Distribution of External Stakeholders according to profiles

              Demographic          Alumni              Parents           Community         Industry Partners
                Profiles           (n = 91)           (n = 128)        Members (n=79)          (n = 23)
                                 F        %          F        %          F         %         F         %
             Age    18 – 22     62       68.13       0        0.00       66      83.54       3        13.04
                    23 – 27     18       19.78       0        0.00       9       11.39       2        8.70
                    28 – 32      8       8.79        0        0.00       4        5.06       17       73.91
                    33 – 37      2       2.20        0        0.00       0        0.00       0        0.00
                    38 – 42      0       0.00       108      84.38       0        0.00       1        4.35

               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 148]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

                    43 – 47      1       1.10       13       10.16       0        0.00       0        0.00
                    48 – 52      0       0.00        6        4.69       0        0.00       0        0.00
                    53 – 57      0       0.00        1        0.78       0        0.00       0        0.00
                     Total      91      100.00      128      100.00      79      100.00      23      100.00
             Sex    Female      55       60.44      81       63.28       56      70.89       9        39.13
                     Male       36       39.56      47       36.72       23      29.11       14       60.87
                     Total      91      100.00      128      100.00      79      100.00      23      100.00

               Overall, based on  the  results the high  number  of  students as  stakeholders  implies that the
               major clienteles of the services offered by the campus are the students.

               3.2 Stakeholders' Perception towards CvSU-TC VMGO

               Table 5 shows the level of awareness among the internal stakeholders regarding the vision,
               mission, and goals of the campus and the objectives of the different programs. The results
               revealed that the internal stakeholders, administrators/faculty/staff, and students, are highly
               aware of the VMGO of the campus. The integration of the VMGO in the course syllabi and
               the  holding  of  students'  orientation  program  every  first  semester of the academic  year  are
               some of the practices of the campus for proper information dissemination. In addition, the
               posting of the VMGO especially in the classroom makes it accessible for the students to read
               its content.


               The findings also revealed that the student stakeholders are highly aware that the "VMGO are
               displayed in bulletin boards" but moderately aware that the "VMGO are printed in brochures,
               manuals, and other materials, are broadcast in media and/or internet/website, are posted in
               social  media  sites  (Facebook,  Twitter,  etc.),  and  are  widely  disseminated  to  the  different
               agencies,  institutions, industry  sector and the  community as a  whole". The reason  for this
               may be  that  bulletin boards are everywhere  on the campus and  can be  found inside  some
               offices of the campus where students are allowed to enter.

               In addition, the administrators/faculty/staff stakeholders are highly aware that the "VMGO
               are  posted  in  social  media  sites  (Facebook,  Twitter,  etc.)"  but  moderately  aware  that  the
               "VMGO  are  displayed  in  bulletin  boards,  are  printed  in  brochures,  manuals,  and  other
               materials, and are widely disseminated to the different agencies, institutions, industry sector
               and  the  community". The reason  for this  may be  that  social  media are  more accessible to
               administrators, faculty, and staff. Although administrators and faculty members are involved
               in the formulation and revisions of VMGO and this was always integrated into the course
               syllabi, the materials and location where they are available and located may not be visible to
               them.

               Generally, the internal  stakeholders are  highly aware of CvSU's  VMGO  with the  students
               having the highest mean of 3.41.

               Table 5. Awareness of CvSU Internal stakeholders towards its VMGO

              Awareness on the CvSU Vision, Mission, Goals and     Administrators/            Students
                                 Objectives                          Faculty/Staff            (n= 444)
                                                                         (of



               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 149]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

                                                                     ̅       VI             ̅      VI

             1.  I am aware of the CvSU vision and mission.      3.93        HA         3.60       HA
             2.  I am aware of the goals of CvSU – Tanza Campus.   3.59      HA         3.55       HA

             3.  I am aware of the program educational objectives   3.45     HA         3.56       HA
                 of the program where I belong.
             4.  I am aware that the VMGO are conspicuously      3.10        MA         3.27       HA
                 displayed in bulletin boards.
             5.  I am aware that the CvSU VMGO are printed in    3.00        MA         3.16       MA
                 brochures, manuals and other material.
             6.  I am aware that the CvSU VMGO are broadcast in   3.17       MA         3.14       MA
                 media and/or internet/website.
             7.  I am aware that the CvSU VMGO are posted in     3.28        HA         3.25       MA
                 social media sites (Facebook, Twitter, etc.)
             8.  I am aware that the CvSU VMGO are widely        3.10        MA         3.02       MA
                 disseminated to the different agencies, institutions,
                 industry sector and the community as a whole.
                             Overall Awareness                   3.34        HA         3.41       HA

               VI – Verbal Interpretation          HA – highly aware            MA – moderately aware

               Table 6 shows the level of awareness among the external stakeholders on the vision, mission,
               and goals of the campus and the objectives of the different programs. The results revealed
               that the external stakeholders are highly aware of the VMGO of the campus.

               The results indicated that the  external  stakeholders are  highly aware that the "VMGO are
               displayed in bulletin boards." Bulletin boards and electronic boards are displayed in public
               places  within  the  vicinity  of  the  campus.  Alumni  and  parents  are  highly  aware  that  the
               "VMGO is printed in brochures, manuals, and other materials while community members and
               industry partners are moderately aware. All stakeholders except alumni are moderately aware
               that the "VMGO are broadcast in media and/or internet/website." All stakeholders are highly
               aware  that  the  "VMGO  are  posted  in  social  media  sites  (Facebook,  Twitter,  etc.)"  It  also
               shows that all stakeholders are moderately aware that the "VMGO are widely disseminated to
               the different agencies, institutions, industry sector and the community".

               Generally, the results indicated that  the  external  stakeholders, alumni, parents,  community
               members, and industry partners, are highly aware of the VMGO of CvSU. This may indicate
               that  the  campus  had  disseminated  the  vision  and  mission  through  various  means  that  are
               visible to them.

               Table 6. Awareness of CvSU External stakeholders towards its VMGO

                Awareness on the CvSU Vision,         Alumni         Parents      Community       Industry
                Mission, Goals and Objectives         (n = 91)      (n = 128)      Members        Partners
                                                                                    (n=79)         (n = 23)

                                                        ̅   VI         ̅   VI         ̅   VI         ̅   VI




               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 150]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

            1.  I am aware of the CvSU vision and   3.68    HA     3.59    HA     3.62    HA     3.61    HA
               mission.
            2.  I am aware of the goals of CvSU –   3.64    HA     3.65    HA     3.59    HA     3.48    HA
               Tanza Campus.
            3.  I am aware of the program           3.58    HA     3.66    HA     3.58    HA     3.57    HA
               educational objectives of the program
               where I belong.
            4.  I am aware that the VMGO are        3.30    HA     3.45    HA     3.29    HA     3.52    HA
               conspicuously displayed in bulletin
               boards.
            5.  I am aware that the CvSU VMGO are   3.30    HA     3.34    HA     3.24    MA     3.13    MA
               printed in brochures, manuals and
               other material.
            6.  I am aware that the CvSU VMGO are   3.30    HA     3.20   MA      3.24    MA     3.13    MA
               broadcast in media and/or
               internet/website.
            7.  I am aware that the CvSU VMGO are   3.31    HA     3.27    HA     3.29    HA     3.26    HA
               posted in social media sites
               (Facebook, Twitter, etc.)
            8.  I am aware that the CvSU VMGO are   3.22   MA      3.18   MA      3.08    MA     3.04    MA
               widely disseminated to the different
               agencies, institutions, industry sector
               and the community as a whole.
                      Overall Awareness             3.45   HA      3.52    HA     3.43    HA     3.39    HA

               VI – Verbal Interpretation          HA – highly aware            MA – moderately aware

               The researchers also determine the extent of the understanding of the internal and external
               stakeholders in terms of the vision, mission, and goals of the campus and the objectives of the
               different  programs.  Table  7  presents  the  level  of  understanding  among  the  internal
               stakeholders  on  CvSU's  VMGO.  Generally,  the  results  showed  that  understanding  of  the
               VMGO       is   moderately    understood   by    all   the   internal   stakeholders.   The
               administrators/faculty/staff have the highest overall mean of 3.14.


               The  campus  offers  an  institutional  orientation  subject  for  all  first-year  students  which
               provides  an  opportunity  for  them  to  understand  the  VMGO  through  presentation  and
               discussion of its content. Students may know exactly the vision and mission of CvSU but do
               not  fully  understand  the  meaning  behind  all  the  statements  under  the  VMGO.  There  are
               faculty members who are given a teaching load for this subject but not all were given the
               opportunity.


               Table 7. Understanding of CvSU Internal stakeholders towards its VMGO
             Understanding on the CvSU Vision, Mission, Goals and     Administrators/          Students
                                  Objectives                           Faculty/Staff           (n= 444)
                                                                          (n = 29)
                                                                         ̅      VI            ̅      VI
            1.  The vision of the Cavite State University foresees   3.25      MU         3.20       MU
                contribution of CvSU towards the promotion of


               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 151]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

                national identity through development of professions
                that will provide leadership in the nation.
            2.  The vision of Cavite State University encourages an   3.19     MU         3.11       MU
                outstanding performance from the school's
                administrators, faculty members, support staff, and
                students
            3.  The vision of Cavite State University envisages a   3.19       MU         3.10       MU
                situation where the scholarly outputs of the University's
                faculty members and students are extended to and used
                by the community
            4.  Its vision portrays CvSU as an academic institution that   3.10   MU      3.03       MU
                is concerned with both institutional efficiency and
                effectiveness in its service delivery to the community.
            5.  The vision of the University describes a condition   3.21      MU         3.13       MU
                where CvSU shall contribute to the development of
                globally competitive and morally upright individuals.
            6.  The mission of the University states that the University   3.11   MU      3.23       MU
                shall (a) provide excellent, equitable and relevant
                educational opportunities; (b) deliver quality
                instruction and responsive research and development
                activities; and (c) produce professional, skilled and
                morally upright individuals
            7.  Its mission directs CvSU to undertake instruction,   3.20      MU         3.15       MU
                research and extension.
            8.  Its mission assigns the University to provide, as a major   3.14   MU     3.09       MU
                function, undergraduate and graduate programs.
            9.  Its mission allows Cavite State University the offering   3.23   MU       3.08       MU
                of arts, sciences, and technology courses.
            10. The University shall uphold the following core values   3.19   MU         3.15       MU
                of truth, excellence, and service.
            11. The goals of CvSU – Tanza contains specific relevant   3.12    MU         3.16       MU
                and quality course offerings in the following field/s of
                business administration, information technology, and
                teacher education.
            12. The goals of the campus indicate that its research and   3.08   MU        3.09       MU
                extension activities shall be linked with business
                organizations, government agencies, and non-
                government agencies
            13. The goals of the campus hint that the faculty members   3.14   MU         3.20       MU
                of the campus must undertake instruction, research, and
                extension activities.
                            Overall Understanding                   3.14       MU         3.05       MU

               VI – Verbal Interpretation       HU – highly understood          MA – moderately understood


               Table 8 presents the level of understanding among the external stakeholders on the vision,
               mission, and goals of the campus, and the objectives of the different programs. The results
               revealed  that  understanding  of  the  VMGO  is  moderately  understood  by  all  the  external
               stakeholders. Both parents and community members have the highest overall mean of 3.10
               while the alumni have the lowest overall mean of 3.04.


               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 152]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               The VMGO is disseminated in various forms that are visible to external stakeholders. They
               may be aware of the VMGO but not totally understood all the statements behind the VMGO.

               Table 8. Understanding of CvSU External stakeholders towards its VMGO

              Understanding on the CvSU Vision,       Alumni         Parents      Community        Industry
                Mission, Goals and Objectives         (n = 91)      (n = 128)      Members         Partners
                                                                                     (n=79)        (n = 23)

                                                        ̅   VI         ̅   VI         ̅   VI         ̅   VI

            1.  The vision of the Cavite State      3.17   MU      3.17   MU      3.25   MU      3.26    MU
                University foresees contribution of
                CvSU towards the promotion of
                national identity through
                development of professions that will
                provide leadership in the nation.
            2.  The vision of Cavite State University   3.09   MU   3.24   MU     3.16   MU      3.15    MU
                encourages an outstanding
                performance from the school's
                administrators, faculty members,
                support staff, and students
            3.  The vision of Cavite State University   3.13   MU   3.21   MU     3.13   MU      3.08    MU
                envisages a situation where the
                scholarly outputs of the University's
                faculty members and students are
                extended to and used by the
                community
            4.  Its vision portrays CvSU as an      3.00   MU      3.10   MU      3.05   MU      3.03    MU
                academic institution that is concerned
                with both institutional efficiency and
                effectiveness in its service delivery to
                the community
            5.  The vision of the University        3.09   MU      3.14   MU      3.19   MU      3.15    MU
                describes a condition where CvSU
                shall contribute to the development
                of globally competitive and morally
                upright individuals.
            6.  The mission of the University states   3.17   MU   3.24   MU      3.26   MU      3.14    MU
                that the University shall (a) provide
                excellent, equitable and relevant
                educational opportunities; (b) deliver
                quality instruction and responsive
                research and development activities;
                and (c) produce professional, skilled
                and morally upright individuals
            7.  Its mission directs CvSU to         3.09   MU      3.17   MU      3.13   MU      3.06    MU
                undertake instruction, research and
                extension.
            8.  Its mission assigns the University to   3.09   MU   3.14   MU     3.08   MU      3.14    MU
                provide, as a major function,


               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 153]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

                undergraduate and graduate
                programs.
            9.  its mission allows Cavite State     3.09   MU      3.03   MU      3.15   MU      3.14    MU
                University the offering of arts,
                sciences, and technology courses.
            10. The University shall uphold the     3.09   MU      3.21   MU      3.14   MU      3.06    MU
                following core values of truth,
                excellence, and service.
            11. The goals of CvSU – Tanza contains   2.91   MU     3.14   MU      3.04   MU      3.15    MU
                specific relevant and quality course
                offerings in the following field/s of
                business administration, information
                technology, and teacher education.
            12. The goals of the campus indicate that   2.96   MU   3.07   MU     3.16   MU      3.13    MU
                its research and extension activities
                shall be linked with business
                organizations, government agencies,
                and non-government agencies
            13. The goals of the campus hint that the   3.13   MU   3.10   MU     3.12   MU      3.06    MU
                faculty members of the campus must
                undertake instruction, research, and
                extension activities.
                    Overall Understanding           3.04   MU      3.10   MU      3.10   MU      3.08   MU

               VI – Verbal Interpretation      HU – highly understood           MA – moderately understood

               Table 9 shows the perception of the internal stakeholders on the clarity of its VMGO.


               The administrators/faculty/staff have the highest mean on the perception of the following: the
               mission clearly reflects CvSU's legal and educational mandate; the Program Objectives are
               consistent with the goals of CvSU-Tanza; the Program Objectives clearly state the expected
               outcomes in terms of competencies or technical skills, research and extension capabilities of
               students and graduates, and students' own ideas, desirable attitudes, and personal discipline.


               The  students  have  the  highest  mean  on  the  perception  that  the  goals  of  CvSU-Tanza  are
               clearly  stated  and  are  consistent  with  the  mission  of  CvSU,  and  the  Program  Objectives
               clearly state the expected outcomes in terms of critical thinking skills.

               Both administrators/faculty/staff have the same meaning for the vision clearly reflects what
               CvSU  hopes  to  become  in  the  future,  the  Program  Objectives  clearly  state  the  expected
               outcomes in terms of moral character and aesthetic and cultural values.

               Generally, the results revealed that the perceived clarity on the vision, mission, goals, and
               objectives  of  CvSU  is  very  clear  to  the  internal  stakeholders  with  the
               administrator/faculty/staff having the highest overall mean of 3.69.


               Table 9. Perceived Clarity of CvSU Internal stakeholders towards its VMGO

              Perceived Clarity on the CvSU Vision, Mission, Goals    Administrators/          Students
                                and Objectives                         Faculty/Staff


               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 154]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

                                                                          (n = 29)             (n= 444)

                                                                          ̅      VI             ̅      VI
            1.  The vision clearly reflects what CvSU hopes to become   3.69     VC        3.69        VC
                in the future
            2.  The mission clearly reflects CvSU's legal and         3.69       VC        3.64        VC
                educational mandate.
            3.  The goals of CvSU – Tanza are clearly stated and are   3.62      VC        3.65        VC
                consistent with the Mission of CvSU.
            4.  The program objectives are consistent with the goals of   3.62   VC        3.59        VC
                CvSU – Tanza.
            5.  The program objectives clearly state the expected     3.62       VC        3.60        VC
                outcomes in terms of competencies or technical skills
                of students and graduates.
            6.  The program objectives clearly state the expected     3.69       VC        3.58        VC
                outcomes in terms of research and extension
                capabilities of students and graduates.
            7.  The program objectives clearly state the expected     3.72       VC        3.62        VC
                outcomes in terms of students' own ideas, desirable
                attitudes and personal discipline.
            8.  The program objectives clearly state the expected     3.62       VC        3.62        VC
                outcomes in terms of moral character.
            9.  The program objectives clearly state the expected     3.55       VC        3.58        VC
                outcomes in terms of critical thinking skills.
            10. The program objectives clearly state the expected     3.59       VC        3.59        VC
                outcomes in terms of aesthetic and cultural values
                           Overall Perceived Clarity                  3.69       VC        3.68        VC

                                 VI – Verbal Interpretation                                  VC – very clear

               Table 10 presents the perception of the external stakeholders on the clarity of its VMGO.

               Parents have the highest mean on the perception that the vision clearly reflects what CvSU
               hopes  to  become  in  the  future  and  the  Program  Objectives  clearly  state  the  expected
               outcomes in terms of moral character.


               Alumni have the highest mean on the perception of the following: the mission clearly reflects
               CvSU's legal and educational mandate; the Goals of CvSU – Tanza are clearly stated and are
               consistent with the Mission of CvSU; the Program Objectives are consistent with the goals of
               CvSU  –  Tanza;  the  Program  Objectives  clearly  state  the  expected  outcomes  in  terms  of
               competencies  or  technical  skills,  research  and  extension  capabilities  of  students  and
               graduates, students' own ideas, desirable attitudes and personal discipline, moral character,
               critical thinking skills, and aesthetic and cultural values.

               Generally, the results revealed that the perceived clarity on the vision, mission, goals, and
               objectives of CvSU is very clear to the external stakeholders. Alumni have the highest mean
               of 3.77 while community members have the lowest mean of 3.63.

               Table 10. Perceived Clarity of CvSU External stakeholders towards its VMGO


               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 155]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               Perceived Clarity on the CvSU Vision,      Alumni        Parents     Community      Industry
                   Mission, Goals and Objectives          (n = 91)     (n = 128)     Members       Partners
                                                                                      (n=79)       (n = 23)

                                                            ̅   VI        ̅   VI        ̅   VI        ̅   VI

            1.  The  vision  clearly  reflects  what  CvSU  3.76   VC   3.78   VC   3.66   VC     3.70   VC
                hopes to become in the future
            2.  The mission clearly reflects CvSU's legal  3.74   VC   3.73   VC    3.57   VC     3.70   VC
                and educational mandate.
            3.  The  goals  of  CvSU  –  Tanza  are  clearly  3.77   VC   3.73   VC   3.63   VC   3.74   VC
                stated and are consistent with the Mission
                of CvSU.
            4.  The  program  objectives  are  consistent  3.74   VC   3.65   VC    3.62   VC     3.57   VC
                with the goals of CvSU – Tanza.
            5.  The  program  objectives  clearly  state  the  3.77   VC   3.66   VC   3.59   VC   3.57   VC
                expected   outcomes   in   terms   of
                competencies  or  technical  skills  of
                students and graduates.
            6.  The  program  objectives  clearly  state  the  3.74   VC   3.68   VC   3.54   VC   3.61   VC
                expected  outcomes  in  terms  of  research
                and extension capabilities of students and
                graduates.
            7.  The  program  objectives  clearly  state  the  3.70   VC   3.69   VC   3.62   VC   3.61   VC
                expected  outcomes  in  terms  of  students'
                own ideas, desirable attitudes and personal
                discipline.
            8.  The  program  objectives  clearly  state  the  3.67   VC   3.69   VC   3.58   VC   3.65   VC
                expected  outcomes  in  terms  of  moral
                character.
            9.  The  program  objectives  clearly  state  the  3.70   VC   3.68   VC   3.53   VC   3.57   VC
                expected  outcomes  in  terms  of  critical
                thinking skills.
            10. The  program  objectives  clearly  state  the  3.69   VC   3.66   VC   3.62   VC   3.52   VC
                expected  outcomes  in  terms  of  aesthetic
                and cultural values
                     Overall Perceived Clarity          3.77   VC     3.75   VC     3.63   VC     3.70   VC

                                          VI – Verbal Interpretation     VC – very clear

               Table 11 shows the level of acceptance of the internal stakeholders on its VMGO.


               Students have the highest mean on the acceptance of the vision and mission of CvSU, the
               objectives  of  the  program  where  they  belong,  and  the  responsibility  of  realizing  such
               objectives in their own capacity. Both administrators/faculty/staff and students have the same
               mean of 3.83 on the acceptance of the Goals of CvSu-Tanza Campus.

               Generally,  the  results  indicate  that  the  VMGO  is  greatly  accepted  by  the
               administrators/faculty/staff, and students. Students have the highest overall mean of 3.84.

               Table 11. Level of Acceptance of CvSU Internal stakeholders towards its VMGO

               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 156]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

             Level of Acceptance on the CvSU Vision, Mission, Goals   Administrators/          Students
                                and Objectives                         Faculty/Staff           (n= 444)
                                                                          (n = 29)
                                                                          ̅      VI             ̅      VI

            1.  I accept the vision and mission of CvSU.              3.76       GA        3.84        GA

            2.  I accept the goals of CvSU – Tanza Campus.            3.83       GA        3.83        GA
            3.  I accept the objectives of the program where I belong.   3.72    GA        3.79        GA

            4.  I accept the responsibility of realizing such objectives   3.66   GA       3.73        GA
                in my own capacity.
                          Overall Level of Acceptance                 3.83       GA        3.84        GA

                                   VI – Verbal Interpretation      GA – greatly accepted

               Table 12 shows the level of acceptance of the internal stakeholders on its VMGO.


               Parents  have  the  highest  mean  of  acceptance  of  the  Vision,  Mission  of  CvSU,  and  the
               responsibility  of realizing  such  objectives in their own  capacity.  Alumni have the  highest
               mean on the acceptance of the objectives of the program where they belong.

               Generally, the results revealed that the vision and  mission  of CvSU, the  goals  of CvSU  –
               Tanza Campus, the objectives of the program where the external stakeholders belong, and the
               responsibility  of  realizing  such  objectives  in  their  own  capacity  are  greatly  accepted  by
               external  stakeholders.  Parents  have the  highest  overall  mean of 3.88 while the  community
               members have the lowest overall mean of 3.76.

               Table 12. Level of Acceptance of CvSU External stakeholders towards its VMGO


               Level of Acceptance on the CvSU        Alumni         Parents      Community        Industry
             Vision, Mission, Goals and Objectives    (n = 91)      (n = 128)      Members         Partners
                                                                                     (n=79)        (n = 23)

                                                        ̅   VI         ̅   VI         ̅   VI         ̅   VI
            1.  I  accept  the  vision  and  mission  of   3.85   GA   3.88   GA   3.73   GA     3.87    GA
                CvSU.
            2.  I accept the goals of CvSU – Tanza   3.85   GA     3.87    GA     3.76    GA     3.83    GA
                Campus.
            3.  I accept the objectives of the program   3.85   GA   3.84   GA    3.75    GA     3.74    GA
                where I belong.
            4.  I accept the responsibility of realizing   3.79   GA   3.81   GA   3.63   GA     3.65    GA
                such objectives in my own capacity.
                 Overall Level of Acceptance        3.86    GA     3.88    GA     3.76    GA     3.83    GA

                                      VI – Verbal Interpretation      GA – greatly accepted


               Table  13  presents  the  perception  of  the  internal  stakeholders  on  the  attainability  of  the
               VMGO.



               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 157]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               The administrators/faculty/staff have the highest mean on the attainability of the Objectives
               of the program. The students have the highest mean on the attainability of the Goals of CvSU
               – Tanza and the Vision and Mission of CvSU.


               Generally, the results revealed that the Vision, Mission, Goals, and Objectives of the program
               are highly attainable by the internal stakeholders. Students have the highest overall mean of
               3.59.

               Table 13. Attainability of the VMGO as perceived by CvSU Internal stakeholders

              Attainability of the CvSU Vision, Mission, Goals and    Administrators/          Students
                                  Objectives                           Faculty/Staff           (n= 444)
                                                                          (n = 29)
                                                                          ̅      VI             ̅      VI

            1.  The  Objectives  of  the  program  where  I  belong  are   3.59   HAt      3.52       HAt
                being attained.
            2.  The Goals of CvSU – Tanza are being achieved.         3.52       HAt       3.55       HAt

            3.  The vision and mission of CvSU are being realized.    3.55       HAt       3.64       HAt

                             Overall Attainability                    3.52       HAt       3.59       HAt

                                 VI – Verbal Interpretation    HAt – highly attainable

               Table  14  presents  the  perception  of  the  external  stakeholders  on  the  attainability  of  the
               VMGO.

               Alumni have the highest mean on the attainability of the Vision, Mission, and Objectives of
               the program. Both alumni and the industry partners have the highest mean on the attainability
               of the goals of CvSU – Tanza.

               Generally, the results reveal that the vision, mission, goals, and objectives of the program are
               highly attainable by the external stakeholders. Alumni have the highest overall mean of 3.70.

               Table 14. Attainability of the VMGO as perceived by CvSU External stakeholders

              Attainability of the CvSU       Alumni           Parents         Community         Industry
             Vision, Mission, Goals and       (n = 91)         (n = 128)        Members          Partners
                     Objectives                                                  (n=79)           (n = 23)

                                               ̅     VI          ̅    VI          ̅    VI          ̅     VI

            1.  The  Objectives  of  the   3.69     HAt     3.56     HAt      3.43    HAt      3.57     HAt
                program  where  I  belong
                are being attained.
            2.  The  Goals  of  CvSU  –    3.65     HAt     3.61     HAt      3.49    HAt      3.65     HAt
                Tanza are being achieved.
            3.  The vision and mission of   3.69    HAt     3.67     HAt      3.54    HAt      3.65     HAt
                CvSU are being realized.




               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 158]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

                Overall Attainability      3.70     HAt     3.64     HAt      3.52    HAt      3.65     HAt

                                  VI – Verbal Interpretation      HAt – highly attainable

               Table  15  presents  the  perception  of  the  internal  stakeholders  on  the  congruence  of  the
               VMGO.

               The administrators/faculty/staff have the highest mean on the congruence of the following:
               the actual educational practices and activities that are consistent with the Objectives of the
               program; the projects and activities carried out by the faculty and students directly contribute
               toward the achievement of the program outcomes, and the VMGO are the bases of all CvSU
               operations.

               The students have the highest mean on the congruence of the actual educational practices and
               activities  that  are  consistent  with  the  Goals  of  CvSU  –  Tanza.  Both  the
               administrators/faculty/staff have the same mean on the congruence of the actual educational
               practices and activities that are consistent with the Mission of CvSU.

               Generally,  the results reveal that  based  on the  perception of the internal  stakeholders,  the
               Vision, Mission, Goals, and Objectives of the program are highly relevant/congruent with the
               actual  educational  practices,  activities,  projects,  and  operations  of  CvSU.  The
               administrators/faculty/staff have the highest overall mean of 3.55.

               Table 15. Congruence of the VMGO as perceived by CvSU Internal stakeholders

              Congruence of the CvSU Vision, Mission, Goals and       Administrators/          Students
                                  Objectives                           Faculty/Staff           (n= 444)
                                                                          (n = 29)
                                                                          ̅      VI             ̅      VI

            1.  The actual educational practices and activities are   3.48      HRC        3.48       HRC
                consistent with the mission of CvSU.
            2.  The actual educational practices and activities are   3.45      HRC        3.53       HRC
                consistent with the goals of CvSU – Tanza.
            3.  The actual educational practices and activities are   3.48      HRC        3.44       HRC
                consistent with the objectives of the program where I
                belong.
            4.  The projects and activities carried out by the faculty   3.62   HRC        3.52       HRC
                and students directly contribute toward the achievement
                of the program outcomes
            5.  The VMGO are the bases of all CvSU operations.        3.59      HRC        3.52       HRC

                             Overall Congruence                       3.55      HRC        3.50       HRC

                                  VI – Verbal Interpretation      HRC – highly relevant/congruent

               Table  16  presents  the  perception  of  the  external  stakeholders  on  the  congruence  of  the
               VMGO.





               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 159]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               Alumni  have the  highest  mean on the  congruence of  the  following:  the actual  educational
               practices and activities are consistent with the Mission of CvSU, the Goals of CvSU – Tanza,
               and the Objectives of the program; the projects and activities carried out by the faculty and
               students  directly  contribute  toward  the  achievement  of  the  program  outcomes;  and  the
               VMGO are the bases of all CvSU operations.

               Generally, the  results reveal that  based  on the  perception  of the  external stakeholders,  the
               Vision, Mission, Goals, and Objectives of the program are highly relevant/congruent with the
               actual educational practices, activities, projects, and operations of CvSU. Alumni have the
               highest overall mean of 3.70.

               Table 16. Congruence of the VMGO as perceived by CvSU External stakeholders


                                                   Alumni          Parents       Community        Industry
              Congruence of the CvSU Vision,       (n = 91)       (n = 128)       Members         Partners
              Mission, Goals and Objectives                                        (n=79)         (n = 23)

                                                     ̅   VI          ̅   VI          ̅   VI         ̅    VI
            1.  The  actual  educational  practices
                and activities are consistent with   3.70   HRC   3.59   HRC    3.59    HRC     3.48    HRC
                the mission of CvSU.
            2.  The  actual  educational  practices
                and activities are consistent with   3.66   HRC   3.61   HRC    3.65    HRC     3.52    HRC
                the goals of CvSU – Tanza.
            3.  The  actual  educational  practices
                and activities are consistent with   3.62   HRC   3.57   HRC    3.42    HRC     3.48    HRC
                the  objectives  of  the  program
                where I belong.
            4.  The  projects  and  activities
                carried  out  by  the  faculty  and
                students   directly   contribute   3.67   HRC   3.60    HRC     3.53    HRC     3.52    HRC
                toward  the  achievement  of  the
                program outcomes
            5.  The  VMGO are the  bases  of  all   3.60   HRC   3.58   HRC     3.51    HRC     3.48    HRC
                CvSU operations.
                   Overall Congruence           3.70    HRC     3.61    HRC     3.53    HRC     3.52    HRC

                                  VI – Verbal Interpretation      HRC – highly relevant/congruent

               Differences in the Stakeholders' Perception of the CvSU VMGO

               This section makes clear the differences or similarities in the responses among all the internal
               and external stakeholders of CvSU – Tanza.

               Differences in Perception of the CvSU Stakeholders to its VMGO

               Table 17 indicates the test of the differences in the perception of the CvSU stakeholders to its
               VMGO using the F statistics.  It is evident that there is no significant difference, F (5, 788) =
               0.847,  p  >  0.05,  among  the  responses  of  the  internal  (administrators/faculty/staff,  and


               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 160]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               students)  and  external  (alumni,  parents,  community  members,  and  industry  partners)
               stakeholders regarding their awareness of the CvSU VMGO. This implies that the internal
               and external stakeholders have similar levels of awareness of the CvSU VMGO. Likewise, no
               significant  differences  are  observed  among  the  responses  of  the  internal  and  external
               stakeholders in their understanding, F (5, 788) = 0.704, p > 0.05, perceived clarity, F (5, 788)
               = 0.365, p > 0.05, and level of acceptance F (5, 788) = 0.439, p > 0.05, of the CvSU VMGO.

               Table 17. Analysis of Variance on the Differences in the Stakeholders' Perception and
               Acceptance of the CvSU VMGO


                 Perception and Acceptance of the CvSU Vision,   Sum of     df     Mean       F       Sig.
                        Mission, Goals and Objectives           Squares            Square
                   Awareness              Between Groups         1.577      5       0.315    0.847    0.516
                                           Within Groups        293.251    788      0.372
                                               Total            294.827    793
                 Understanding            Between Groups         0.468      5      0.094     0.594   0.704
                                           Within Groups        124.183    788     0.158
                                               Total            124.651    793
                Perceived Clarity         Between Groups         1.360      5      0.272     1.088   0.365
                                           Within Groups        196.882    788     0.250
                                               Total            198.242    793
               Level of Acceptance        Between Groups         0.786      5      0.157     0.964   0.439
                                           Within Groups        128.535    788     0.163
                                               Total            129.321    793

               Differences  in  the  Stakeholders'  Perceived  Level  of  Attainability  and  Congruence  of  the
               CvSU VMGO to Educational Activities and Practices

               Table 18 indicates the test of differences in the perception of the CvSU stakeholders on the
               attainability and congruence of its VMGO.  No significant differences are observed among
               the responses of the internal and external stakeholders in their perceived level of attainability,
               F (5, 788) = 1.339, p > 0.05, and perceived level of congruence, F (5, 788) = 2.183, p > 0.05
               of the CvSU VMGO to its educational activities and practices.

               Table 18. Analysis of Variance on the Differences in the Stakeholders' Perceived Level
               of  Attainability  and  Congruence  of  the  CvSU  VMGO  to  Educational  Activities  and
               Practices

               Attainability of the CvSU Vision, Mission, Goals and   Sum of   df   Mean      F       Sig.
                                 Objectives                     Squares            Square
                  Overall Attainability      Between Groups      2.024      5      0.405     1.339   0.245
                                             Within Groups      238.212    788     0.302
                                                 Total          240.237    793
                   Overall Perceived         Between Groups      3.643      5      0.729     2.183   0.054
                     Congruence              Within Groups      263.038    788     0.334
                                                 Total          266.681    793

               4.0 CONCLUSIONS AND RECOMMENDATIONS





               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 161]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               The study assessed the perception and acceptance of the different stakeholders towards the
               CvSU  –  Tanza  Campus  VMGO  and  their  attainability  and  congruences  to  educational
               practices. Based on the findings, the following conclusions are drawn:


                   1.  All the internal and external stakeholders are highly aware of the Vision and Mission
                       of  CvSU,  Goals  and  the  Objectives  of  the  different  programs  of  CvSu  –  Tanza
                       Campus.
                   2.  All the internal and external stakeholders moderately understood all the statements in
                       the   Vision and Mission of CvSU, Goals and the Objectives of the different programs
                       of CvSu – Tanza Campus.
                   3.  The  clarity  of  the  Vision  and  Mission  of  CvSU,  Goals  and  the  Objectives  of  the
                       different programs of CvSu – Tanza Campus are very clear as perceived by all the
                       internal and external stakeholders.
                   4.  The Vision and Mission of CvSU, Goals and the Objectives of the different programs
                       of CvSu  – Tanza Campus are  greatly accepted as perceived by all the internal and
                       external stakeholders.
                   5.  The Vision and Mission of CvSU, Goals and the Objectives of the different programs
                       of CvSu – Tanza Campus are highly attainable as perceived by all the internal and
                       external stakeholders.
                   6.  The Vision and Mission of CvSU, Goals and the Objectives of the different programs
                       of CvSu – Tanza Campus are highly relevant/congruent to the educational practices,
                       activities,  projects,  and  operations  of  CvSU  as  perceived  by  all  the  internal  and
                       external stakeholders.
                   7.  All the responses among the internal and external  stakeholders have  no  significant
                       difference  regarding  their  perception  on  the  awareness,  understanding,  clarity,
                       acceptance,  attainability,  and  congruence  to  the  educational  practices,  activities,
                       projects, and operations of CvSU.

               Based on the above conclusions, the following recommendations are made:

                   1.  Tanza Campus should continue its practices in the widest dissemination of the VMGO
                       through  various  forms  of  communication  media  and  ensure  that  it  is  properly
                       disseminated to all areas that can reach all the stakeholders.
                   2.  The campus should conduct a training on how the stakeholders will be able to fully
                       understand all the statements behind the VMGO.
                   3.  Activities  for instruction, research, and extension  should be  sustained  to  encourage
                       the stakeholders to take part on the realization of the VMGO.


               REFERENCES

               Accrediting  Agency  of  the  Chartered  Colleges  and  Universities  of  the  Philippines
                      (AACCUP)         (n.d.).     The      Outcomes-Based        Quality      Assurance.
                      http://www.aaccupqa.org.ph/

               Arado,  L.M.,  Mendoza,  A.D.,  Esmero,  D.R.P.,  (2019).  Awareness,  Understanding,
                      Acceptance,  and  Congruency  of  the  PIT  Vision  and  Mission,  College  Goal  and
                      Program  Objectives".  International  Journal  of  Science  and  Management  Studies,
                      02(02), 168-175.

               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 162]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[International Journal of Research in Education Humanities and Commerce

                                                          Volume 03, Issue 05 "September - October 2022"

                                                                                          ISSN 2583-0333

               Cahapin, EL., Malabag, BA., Samson, BD & Santiago, CS. (2022). Stakeholders' Awareness
                      and  Acceptance  of  the  Institution's  Vision,  Mission  and  Goals  and  Information
                      Technology  Program  Objectives  in  a  State  University  in  the  Philippines.  Globus
                      Journal of Progressive Education. 12 (1). 51-60.

               Castillo, R.C., (2014). Awareness, Acceptance and Perception of Batangas State University
                      Stakeholders  towards  its  Vision,  Mission,  Goals  and  Objectives".  International
                      Journal of Sciences: Basic and Applied Research, 14(1), 546-563.

               Cavite State University (2022). Mission, vision, and quality policy. https://cvsu.edu.ph/

               Gomez, AC & Basco, MC (2022). Awareness, Acceptability, and Perception of Stakeholders
                      on the Vision and Mission of Cavite State University, Teacher Education Department
                      Goals, and Education Program Objectives. International Journal of Multidisciplinary:
                      Applied Business and Education Research. 3 (1), 66 – 75.


               Pelicano, A.C & Lacaba, L. D. (2016). Awareness and Acceptability of the Vision, Mission,
                      Goals  and  Objectives  of  Eastern  Samar  State  University.  International  Journal  of
                      Innovation and Research in Educational Sciences. 3(6). 432-435.

               Salom, MD & Florendo, ZT. (2013). Awareness, Acceptability, and Relevance of the Vision,
                      Mission,  Goals,  and  Objectives  of  the  BSEMT  Program.  International  Scientific
                      Research Journal. V(1). 236-246.










































               www.ijrehc.com                             Copyright © IJREHC 2022, All right reserved   Page 163]]></page></pages></Search>