<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="21"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.15.           Skills development programs are


                        conducted.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Letters/Memo]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                      OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES

               September 16, 2022


               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Campus Administrator
               This University


               Dear Sir:

               The University will be holding the 2022 Cultural and the Arts Festival on October 5, 2022 at
               the  University  International  Convention  Center.  As  part  of  our  participation  on  the  said
               activity, we are asking your good office to allow us to conduct an in-person screening for the
               participants on September 26, 2022.


               Attached is the list of events and prospected participants. Looking for your approval on this
               activity. Thank you and stay safe!


               Respectfully yours,



               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, OSAS





               Approved:


               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                      OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES

               February 25, 2022


               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Campus Administrator
               This University


               Dear Sir:

               Respectfully  submitting  the  proposed  activities  of  the  National  Service  Training  Program
               (NSTP) for the Second Semester A.Y 2021-2022 for your approval.


               Thank you and stay safe!


               Respectfully yours,

               RITCH M. BANATE
               NSTP Coordinator



               Noted by:





               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, OSAS





               Approved:


               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                    CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                 Tanza Campus
                                                                          Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                             (046) 414-3979
                                                                            www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                                    PROPOSED NSTP 2 ACTIVITIES
                                                                     Second Semester, AY 2021-2022

           WEEK                          TOPIC                           EXPECTED OUTPUT                     IN-CHARGE                  TENTATIVE DATE
              1                        Orientation                                                        All NSTP Facilitators            March 11, 2022
              2            Fire Prevention and Safety Webinar         Video Demonstration of Fire         Mark Joel C. Sibulo              March 25, 2022
                                                                                  Drill                 John Edison J. De Silva
                                                                                                        Mary Rose E. Elamparo
                                                                                                            Noemi A. Perida
              3            Webinar on Small Space and Bottle         Photo Documentation of Small         Mildred A. Sebastian              April 8, 2022
                                        Gardening                       Space and Bottle Garden        Jessica Avon A. Quezada
                                                                                                         Mary Joy Angelique R.
                                                                                                                 Mojica
                                                                                                             Estelita A. Villa
              4               How to Start a Small Business                Proposed Business                Ritch M. Banate                 April 22, 2022
                                  (Proposed Business)                                                    Debbie Rose B. Fabian
                                                                                                         Joyce Erika S. Senaris
              5           First Aid and Risk Reduction Webinar                   Video                      Melona I. Saquin                 May 6, 2022
                        (Video Demonstration/Reenactment of First    Demonstration/Reenactment of            Ivory P. Mojica
                                     Aid Procedure)                        First Aid Procedure           Charlene De Las Alas
                                                                                                         Sharmaine M. Banate
              6           Preparation of Accomplishment Report                                                          May 13 – June 2, 2022
              7           Final meeting (submission of all output)                                                           June 3, 2022]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
       Tanza Campus
 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
  (046) 414-3979
 www.cvsu.edu.ph


 PROPOSED NSTP 2 ACTIVITIES
 Second Semester, AY 2021-2022

 WEEK   TOPIC   EXPECTED OUTPUT   IN-CHARGE         TENTATIVE DATE
 1   Orientation      All NSTP Facilitators            March 11, 2022
 2   Fire Prevention and Safety Webinar   Video Demonstration of Fire   Mark Joel C. Sibulo   March 25, 2022
    Drill           John Edison J. De Silva
                    Mary Rose E. Elamparo
                        Noemi A. Perida
 3   Webinar on Small Space and Bottle   Photo Documentation of Small   Mildred A. Sebastian   April 8, 2022
 Gardening   Space and Bottle Garden   Jessica Avon A. Quezada
                     Mary Joy Angelique R.
                             Mojica
                        Estelita A. Villa
 4   How to Start a Small Business   Proposed Business   Ritch M. Banate   April 22, 2022
 (Proposed Business)   Debbie Rose B. Fabian
                     Joyce Erika S. Senaris
 5   First Aid and Risk Reduction Webinar   Video   Melona I. Saquin   May 6, 2022
 (Video Demonstration/Reenactment of First   Demonstration/Reenactment of   Ivory P. Mojica
 Aid Procedure)   First Aid Procedure   Charlene De Las Alas
                     Sharmaine M. Banate
 6   Preparation of Accomplishment Report      May 13 – June 2, 2022
 7   Final meeting (submission of all output)      June 3, 2022]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Registration and Evaluation: Melona I. Saquin
        Technical: Jeffrey M. Delgado/ John Edison J. De Silva
        Moderator/s: Audreyson H. Borilla/Gerry Mae T. Silverio
        Finance: Mary Joy Angelique R. Mojica


        Prepared by:


        RITCH M. BANATE
        NSTP Coordinator





        Noted by:



        MELONA I. SAQUIN
        Head, OSAS





        Approved:


        GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
        Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Registration and Evaluation: Melona I. Saquin
 Technical: Jeffrey M. Delgado/ John Edison J. De Silva
 Moderator/s: Audreyson H. Borilla/Gerry Mae T. Silverio
 Finance: Mary Joy Angelique R. Mojica


 Prepared by:


 RITCH M. BANATE
 NSTP Coordinator





 Noted by:



 MELONA I. SAQUIN
 Head, OSAS





 Approved:


 GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
 Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                     TANZA ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                             414 – 3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ 437-0693
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                         CIRCLE OF POTENTIAL EDUCATORS
               November 16, 2021

               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Campus Administrator
               CvSU – Tanza Campus

               Dear Prof. Ramos:

                       The Circle of Potential Educators (CoPE) would like to request permission from your
               good  office  on  the  conduct  of  Engaging  ICT  Development  and  Understanding  multi-
               Cultural Education (EDUC) Congress: The New Normal on December 2 – 3, 2021.  This
               activity aims to provide our teacher education students, both from BEE and BSE programs,
               meaningful  activities  relative  to  the  works  of  an  in-service  teachers,  such  as  instructional
               materials development, lesson planning activity, demonstration teaching, and test and TOS
               construction  to  prepare  them  in  planning,  monitoring,  assessing,  and  reporting  learning
               processes and outcomes.

                       Webinar on ICT, mental health and multilingual education and Academic Contests will
               highlight this year’s two-day EDUC Congress.

                       This  activity  will  be  done  with  the  help  of  the  instructors  from  Teacher  Education
               Department in facilitating and evaluating the Academic Contests.

                       Attached is the activity proposal for your reference.

                       It is hoped that this request merits your most favorable consideration.

                       Thank you very much.

               Very truly yours,


               MA. WOODELYN P. REYES
               CoPE President

               Noted by:

               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                                      MARIA CRISTINA C. TAGLE
               Senior Adviser, CoPE                                      Junior Adviser, CoPE

               Recommending Approval:

               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                                      MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Chairperson, TED                                          Head, OSAS

               Approved:

               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                     TANZA ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                             414 – 3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ 437-0693
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                         CIRCLE OF POTENTIAL EDUCATORS

               I. Title:      Engaging  ICT  Development  and  Understanding  multi-Cultural  Education
                              (EDUC) Congress: The New Normal

               II. Proponent: Circle of Potential Educators

               III. Rationale:
                            The Teacher Education Department of Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                     provides  quality  education  to  teacher  education  students  by  conducting  meaningful
                     activities  that  will  equip  them  with  concrete  experiences  and  adequate  and  relevant
                     competencies  to  teach  in  their  chosen  area  of  specialization.    Meaningful  activities
                     include  academic  competitions  relative  to  the  works  of  in-service  teachers,  such  as
                     instructional materials development, lesson planning activity, demonstration teaching,
                     and  test  construction.    To  further  determine  their  readiness  in  taking  the  Licensure
                     Examination  for  Teachers  (now  Board  of  Licensure  Examination  for  Professional
                     Teachers), general and professional education quiz bee will be conducted.

                            The Bachelor of Elementary Education and Bachelor of Secondary Education
                     programs both aims to facilitate learning using a wide range of teaching methodologies
                     and  delivery  modes  appropriate  to  specific  learners  and  their  environments.    In  this
                     regard, this activity will also engage them into interactive discussions on how they can
                     facilitate  multilingual  education  considering  the  multiple  languages,  cultures  and
                     practices  that  are  being  manifested  by  our  students.    Also,  they  will  become  more
                     involved in facilitating their learners through emerging technologies that can be utilized
                     in presenting lessons more interactively.  It is in this end that they shall be able to apply
                     skills  in  the  development  and  utilization  of  ICT  to  promote  quality,  relevant  and
                     sustainable educational practices.

               IV. Objectives:
                            This activity will aid our teacher education students in demonstrating a variety of
                     thinking skills in planning, monitoring, assessing, and reporting learning processes and
                     outcomes.
                            Specifically, the activity aims to:
                            1.  lead the path of teacher education students from pre-service to in-service
                                teaching;
                            2.  gain a deeper understanding of the nature of the 21st century learners;
                            3.  demonstrate  knowledge  of  the  contents  of  professional  subjects  in  the
                                teacher education course;
                            4.  develop  self-confidence  among  contestants  and  sense  of  sportsmanship
                                among participating teacher education students;]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[V. Mechanics of Implementation
                       A.  List of Participants
                              The activity will engage all teacher education students from the Bachelor of
                          Secondary Education and Bachelor of Elementary Education from Cavite State
                          University – Tanza Campus.

                       B.  Date and Venue
                              The activity will conduct online on December 2 – 3, 2021.

                       C.  Strategies/Mechanics
                          1.  The activity will engage all teacher education students from the Bachelor of
                              Secondary Education and Bachelor of Elementary Education from Cavite
                              State University – Tanza Campus.
                          2.  The webinars are free, obligatory and mandatory.  However, students may opt
                              to participate in the following contests:

                        A.  Webinar
                            i.  There will be three topics for webinar:
                                1. Adapting, Evolving and Thriving in Remote Learning
                                2. Multilingual Education in the New Normal Education
                                3. Coping with the New Normal: Addressing the Emotional and Mental Needs
                                of Education Students

                            ii.  Three invited resource persons will discuss the topics.
                              1.  Prof. Joyce Senaris
                              2.  Prof. Noel Manarpiis
                              3.  Ms. Farah Contessa Suzon

                            iii.  The first two webinars will be conducted on December 2, 2021 from 8:00AM
                                to 12:00NN at via Google meet and/or other meeting conference platforms.

                            iv.  The last webinar will be conducted on December 3, 2021 from 8:00AM to
                                10:00AM.

                            v.  Each participating student shall fill out and submit the evaluation form at the
                                end of every webinar. This will serve as their entry for a raffle on December
                                3, 2021.

                        B.  Academic Contests
                            i.   There will be five academic contests that a teacher education student may
                                 opt  to  participate:  (1)  instructional  materials  development,  (2)  lesson
                                 planning, (3) test and TOS construction, (4) demonstration teaching, and
                                 (5) general and professional education quiz bee.

                                 1) instructional materials development, (2) lesson planning, (3) test
                                 and TOS construction, (4) demonstration teaching
                            ii.   These academic contests shall be conducted on December 2, 2021 from
                                 1:00 PM to 6:00 PM.

                            iii.   Each participant will be given a maximum of one hour in the preparation of
                                 IMs,  lesson  plan,  and  test  and  TOS  construction.    These  will  be  done
                                 simultaneously online.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[iv.   Each participant for the demonstration teaching shall be given a maximum
                                 of 30 minutes to present his/her lesson based on the IMs developed, lesson
                                 plan written, and test constructed in the first part of the event.

                                 General and Professional Education Quiz Bee
                              i.  The contest is open to all regular first year, second year, and third year
                                 teacher education students in Cavite State University  – Tanza Campus.
                                 Student must fill out the registration form on or before the December 2,
                                 2021.

                              ii.  The contest will be done on December 3, 2021 from 8:00 AM to 12:00 NN.

                              iii.  The contest questions shall be based on the following courses:
                                 Professional Education
                                     Child and Adolescent Learning
                                     Technology in Education
                                     Building and Enhancing Literacy Across Curriculum
                                     Foundations of Special and Inclusive Education
                                     Social Dimensions of Education

                                 General Education
                                     Purposive Communication
                                     The Contemporary World
                                     Understanding the Self
                                     Science, Technology and Society
                                     Readings in the Philippine History
                                     Rizal’s Life and Writings

                            iv.   The quiz master shall present and read the question twice.

                            v.   The contestant shall provide his/her choice of answer after the question has
                                 been read by the quiz master or immediately after the signal to do so has
                                 been  given.  He/She  will  be  instructed  to  answer  after  the  time  limit  is
                                 reached for checking purposes. All contestants shall be given only ten (10)
                                 seconds to answer each question.

                            vi.   Each question is equivalent to one (1) point for every correct answer and
                                 zero for incorrect or no answer.

                            vii.  The first three (3) contestants with the highest points shall be declared as
                                 winners: 1st Place, 2nd Place, and 3rd Place, respectively.

                            viii.  The winners of Instructional materials development, lesson planning, test
                                 and TOS construction, demonstration teaching and Quiz bee will receive a
                                 printed certificate, plaque and cash prize

                            ix.   An electronic Certificate of Participation shall be given to all participating
                                 students.
                       D.  Safety and Security Measures
                              All  of  these  activities  will  be  conducted  online  to  ensure  the  safety  of  the
                          students, resource persons and instructors. On the other hand, winners that will
                          claim their prizes have to wear face shield and face mask.
                       E.  Budgetary Estimate]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Particulars                                             Amount (Php)
                            Printed Certificates and Plaque for Academic                  100.00
                            Contest Winners

                            Prizes                                                      2,500.00
                               st
                              1 Place   – 200 * 5 (contest)                                 1000
                              2  Place  – 150 * 5 (contest)                                  750
                               nd
                               rd
                              3  Place  – 100 * 5 (contest)                                  500
                              5 winners of 50 pesos Gcash load                               250

                            Token for the Resource Persons                              3,000.00
                            Php 1000 x 3 Resource Person

                            Total Projected Expenses                                    5,600.00

                                 Note: The plaque will be requested from the Office of the Mayor and
                                     Prizes are from sponsorship.

               VII. Contact Person (Organization President and Adviser, include contact number)

                   CoPE President: Ma. Woodelyn P. Reyes
                                     09068835078
                                     ma.woodelyn.reyes@cvsu.edu.ph

                   CoPE Advisers:

                       Mildred A. Sebastian                       Maria Cristina C. Tagle
                       09178036141                                09068727389
                       mildred.sebastian@cvsu.edu.ph              maria.tagle@cvsu.edu.ph


               Respectfully,


               MA. WOODELYN P. REYES
               President, CoPE

               Noted by:

               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                               MARIA CRISTINA C. TAGLE
               Senior Adviser, CoPE                               Junior Adviser, CoPE

               Recommending Approval:

               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Chairperson, TED                                   Head, OSAS



               Approved:

               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Invitations posted in CvSU-Tanza




                                     Facebook Page]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                           Tanza Campus
                                                   Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                      (046) 414-3979
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph


































                Disaster Preparedness: Basic Life Support and First Aid webinar invitation posted in
                                                 CvSU-Tanza Facebook Page


































                Green the Bottle and Save the Mother Earth webinar invitation posted in CvSU        -
                                                Tanza Facebook Page]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                           Tanza Campus
                                                   Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                      (046) 414-3979
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                Sana All Business Owner: How to Start a Business in 2022 webinar invitation posted
                                          in CvSU- Tanza Facebook Page


























                 Fire Prevention and Safety webinar invitation posted in CvSU-Tanza Facebook
                                                          Page]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Webinar Series: “Managing and Teaching in the New Normal and

                          Special Education”. The webinar invitation posted in CvSU-Tanza
                                                 Campus Facebook Page]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Topics on the Webinar Series]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>