<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.6.            The following basic services are


                        available:


                        S.6.2.  Student Development;

                                        S.6.2.3.  Leadership Training;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[1


                                                         RULE VII

                                          STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES

               Article 1. Office of Student Affairs and Services.

                       The student services unit of Cavite State University shall be known as the Office
               of Student Affairs and Services (OSAS).  It shall provide relevant programs for student-
               centered activities and mandated services in support of academic instruction intended
               to facilitate well-rounded student development.

               Article 2. Vision, Mission and Objectives

                       Section 1. Vision

                              The  OSAS  shall  be  a  resource  of  high  quality  student  welfare  and
                       development  programs,  efficient  services  and  relevant  opportunities  geared
                       towards  the  development  of  morally  upright  and  globally  competitive
                       professionals.

                       Section 2. Mission

                              The  OSAS  shall  provide  an  atmosphere  where  students’  talents,
                       interests,  and  values  are  developed  to  the  fullest,  and  shall  deliver  efficient
                       student  services  which  can  contribute  to  the  achievement  of  academic
                       excellence  and  high  professional  competency  which  can  be  recognized
                       internationally.

                       Section 3. Objectives

                              3.1.   regularly implement comprehensive guidance programs with a full
                                     range of activities such as assessment, information, consultation,
                                     counselling, referral, placement, follow-up and follow-through;
                              3.2.   implement  effective  information  and  orientation  strategies  in
                                     promoting awareness on student rights and obligations
                              3.3.   provide  financial  assistance  to the  needy  and deserving  students
                                     through scholarship grants, service and job experience programs,
                                     student  loans  and  mutual  aid  funds,  giving  priority  to  those
                                     belonging to the vulnerable and marginalized sector
                              3.4.   provide leadership trainings to enhance leadership effectiveness of
                                     students both at  personal and organizational levels
                              3.5.    strictly  implement  institutional  rules  and  regulations  governing
                                     student  behaviour  and  conduct  to  be  able  to  produce  morally
                                     upright professionals
                              3.6.    provide avenues to hone students’ talents and interest to ensure
                                     social and cultural growth;
                              3.7.    implement  relevant  sports  development  programs  to  provide
                                     opportunities  for  athletic  competition,  physical  fitness  and  well-
                                     being of students]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[2



                              3.8.   develop skills and potentials of student writers
                              3.9.   promote  student  involvement  in  community  development
                                     programs
                              3.10.  provide  an  environment  conducive  to  free  expression  of  one’s
                                     religious orientation in accordance with institutional principles


               Article 3. Organizational Structure of OSAS

                       The OSAS shall be headed by a dean who shall be under the direct supervision
               of the Vice-President for Academic Affairs. The OSAS shall have four service units, the
               Student  Welfare  Services  (SWS)  Unit,  the  Student  Development  Services  (SDS)  Unit,
               the  Institutional  Student  Programs  and  Services  (ISPS)  Unit  and  the  Research,
               Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Student  Services  (RMESS)  Unit.  Each  unit  shall  be
               headed by an over-all coordinator who shall report directly to the OSAS dean.

               Article 4. Student Services and Programs.

                       The  OSAS  shall  deliver  three  basic  academic  support  services  to  students:
               student  welfare  services,  student  development  services  and  those  that  relate  to
               institutional  programs  and  services.  In  addition,  there  shall  be  a  separate  support
               service  for  research,  monitoring  and  evaluation  of  student  services.  These  services
               shall be delivered by the following units:

                       Section 1. The Student Welfare Services Unit

                              The  Student  Welfare  Services  Unit  shall  deliver  student  services  and
                       programs needed to ensure and promote the well-being of students. This shall
                       include information and orientation services, guidance and counselling services,
                       career  and  job  placement  services,  and  student  economic  enterprise
                       development services.
                       Section 2. The Student Development Services Unit


                              The  Student  Development  Services  Unit  shall  provide  services  and
                       programs  designed  for  the  exploration,  enhancement  and  development  of  the
                       students’  full  potential  for  personal  development,  leadership  and  social
                       responsibility  through  various  institutional  student  activities.  The  student
                       development  services  include  student  organization  and  activities,  student
                       government, student discipline, and student publication.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Approved Continuity Plan for







































              OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES






                           Leadership Training 2021-2022]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>