<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="11"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.2.            The financial management personnel


                        are responsible for the efficient


                        management of financial resources/

                        funds of the institution.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Section 3.3. Director for Financial Management Services. The Director shall perform
                              the following:



               a.) Exercise direct supervision on the following offices:
                              ▪  Cashier

                              ▪  Budget

                              ▪  Accounting

                       a)  Prepare,  consolidate  and  review  annual  budget,  supplemental  and
                          special budgets;


                       b)  Take action on request for funding on various requisitions of different
                          units;

                       c)  Coordinate with concerned offices in connection with budget operations
                          and guidelines;

                       d)  Assist the VPASS and the University President during budget hearings
                          and review and during BOR meeting whenever necessary;

                       e)  Monitor disbursement of approved agency budget;

                       f)  Prepare financial plan for Fund 164 for BOR approval;

                       g)  Prepare  and  submit  financial  report  to  DBM  and  other  concerned
                          offices;

                       h)  Follow-up request for budget like NOSCA, NCA, SARO, etc.;

                       i)  Initiate  and  follow-up  request  for  funding  from  other  government
                          agencies;

                       j)  Prepare  periodic,  annual  and  other  required  report  related  to  the
                          financial management function; and]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[k)  Perform other functions that may be assigned by higher authorities.


               Excerpt from the Manual of Operations Vol I pp. 29-30]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                           (CvSU)

                                               Don Severino de las Alas Campus

                                                        Indang, Cavite
                                           (046) 415-0010 / 415-0011     (046) 415-0012
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                 CASHIER’S OFFICE



                              SPECIFIC WORK ASSIGNMENT OF NON-ACADEMIC STAFF




                Rowena V. Peñalba

                Administrative Officer V - Permanent



                   •  Posting of monthly collection of Main Campus to Cash Receipt Record for Trust 101, Fund
                       164, Fund 163 and Fund 161.


                   •  Preparation of deposit of collection.


                   •  Issues and sign checks in payment of obligations.


                   •  Secure and encash checks for cash advances.


                   •  Signs monthly collection and disbursement reports.

                   •  Supervise  and  participate  in  payment  of  salaries,  wages  and  scholarship  grants  and
                       financial assistance of students


                   •  Prepares all documents/reports needed for compliance to COA & other offices as the need
                       arises.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Alma C. Cunanan

               Administrative Assistant III - Permanent


                   •  Issuance of Official Receipts for collection of payment for Fund 101,164, 161 and other
                       trust fund.

                   •  Preparation of monthly Report of Collection for Fund 101, 164, 161 and other trust fund.




               Shirley G. Aldea
               Administrative Assistant III - Permanent



                   •  Preparation of checks for all funds.

                   •  Preparation of advice of checks issued for all funds.


                   •  Preparation of monthly Report of Checks Issued and Cancelled for MDS/ADA.

                   •  Act as liaison officer for GSIS & Pag-ibig remittances.



               Concepcion T. Farro

               Administrative Aide I - Permanent


                   •  Preparation and payment of BIR remittances for withholding and sales tax through eFPS
                       for Fund 161, 163, 164, Trust Miscellaneous & for Carmona Campus.


                   •  Preparation and issuance of withholding tax certificates for all suppliers.

                   •  Assist in releasing of checks issued to suppliers, faculty & employees and students.


                   •  Act as liaison officer to the unit when it comes to LBP transactions and bills payment
                       (MERALCO & PLDT).]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Mary Neth P. Ramos
               Administrative Aide III - Casual



                   •  Releasing of checks issued to suppliers, faculty & employees and students.

                   •  Preparation of monthly Report of Checks issued and cancelled for Trust and Fund 164.


                   •  Preparation of monthly Report of Staled & Unclaimed Checks.

                   •  Preparation of monthly Report of Accountability for accountable forms.

                   •  Preparation of monthly Check Disbursement Record for Trust and Fund 164.

                   •  Other task that may be assigned from time to time.




               Ma. Angelika F. Menil

               Administrative Aide III - Casual


                   •  Receiving & recording of vouchers for check preparation of all funds except Fund 101 MDS
                       and ADA.


                   •  Assists in the preparation of checks and advice of checks issued and cancelled.


                   •  Receiving & checking of collections of Campuses.


                   •  Preparation and payment of BIR remittances for withholding and sales tax through eFPS
                       for Imus Campus.

                   •  Receiving and filing of incoming communication and other documents.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Erra Jane M. Medina

               Administrative Aide III - Casual


                   •  Issuance of Official Receipts for collection of payment of Fund 163.


                   •  Preparation of monthly Report of Collection and Deposit for Fund 163.

                   •  Preparation and payment of BIR remittances for withholding and sales tax through eFPS
                       for Cavite City Campus.

                   •  Preparation of monthly Check Disbursement Record for all funds except Trust & Fund 164.

                   •  Preparation of monthly Report of Checks Issued and Cancelled for all funds except Trust
                       & Fund 164.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>