<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="15"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.15.           There is a medical and dental program


                        designed for:


                        S.15.4. physical-dental exam.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Manual of Operations]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         186





                                                             R R U U L L E E     X X V V

                                    G G U U I I D D E E L L I I N N E E S S     O O N N     M M E E D D I I C C A A L L     A A N N D D     D D E E N N T T A A L L

                                                        E E X X A A M M I I N N A A T T I I O O N N





                   Article  1.          Students.    All  students  are  required  to  undergo  medical,
                          dental,  and  laboratory  examinations  to  determine  fitness  to  perform
                          various school activities.

                          Section 1.  All new students enrolling at the University are required
                          to undergo the following examinations/tests prior to enrollment.  The
                          new  students  are  required  to  undergo  chest  X-ray  and  routine
                          laboratory  examinations  such  as  complete  blood  count,  blood
                          typing  and  Hepatitis  B  Screening  as  necessary  for  Health
                          Science  and  Hospitality  Service  courses.  A  physical  and  dental
                          examination, conducted by the Unviersity Physician and Dentist will
                          follow  upon  completion  of  all  the  laboratory  requirements.    This  is
                          normally  scheduled/conducted  in  the  months  of  April  and  May  or
                          during  the  first  semester  enrollment  and  in  September  and  October
                          during the second semester.

                          Section  2.    Old  students  should  submit  the  results  of  their
                          medical/dental examinations, conducted during the first semester as
                          a  requirement  for  enrollment  during  the  second  semester.  Their
                          annual physical (medical/dental) examination(s) schedule shall be as
                          follows:

                                 Senior (4 , 5  & 6  )  -            1  week of June to July 15
                                             th
                                                  th
                                                                       st
                                                         th
                                 Junior                       -      July 16  to last week of August
                                 Sophomore                    -      1  wk of Sept. to last wk of
                                                                       st
                                                                     October

                           Section 3.  If upon physical examination, the student is diagnosed to
                                         be:

                          a.  Suffering  from  a  suspicious  disease(s),  a  special/additional
                              laboratory  examination(s)  shall  be  required  and/or  the  student
                              shall be referred to a medical specialist for further evaluation and

                                                                                                           186]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         187

                              management of his/her health status. Submission of a medical
                              certificate  from  the  medical  specialist  shall  be  required  to
                              determine their fitness to go on with schooling; or

                          b.  Afflicted  with  a  communicable  disease(s),  especially  Pulmonary
                              Tuberculosis,  he/she  shall  be  advised  not  to  enroll  until  the
                              student can present a medical certificate duly signed by the
                              medical specialist(s) indicating that he/she is physically fit to
                              continue  his/her  studies  and  already  under  continued
                              medication.

                          Section 4.  The rates for           physical,      dental     and      laboratory
                   examinations for   incoming freshmen shall be as follows:


                                 a. Physical Examination fee         -       P      125.00
                                 b. Dental Examination fee           -              125.00
                                 c. Blood Typing                     -                60.00
                                 d. Complete Blood Count             -                90.00
                                 d. Chest X-ray                      -              150.00
                                 e. Hepatitis B Screening*           -              100.00
                                 (*for Health Science and Hospitality Service courses only)

                          Old  students  will  be  charged  One  Hundred  Pesos  (P100.00)  as
                          payment for the annual physical and dental examination. This fee is
                   an addition to the medical fee being paid during enrollment.

                          Section 5.  Should  a  student  lose  his  or  her  medical  and/or  dental
                   forms and request for another copy, the student will have to pay Fifty Pesos
                   (P50.00) or Twenty Five pesos (P 25.00) per form (medical or dental).

                          Section  6.  Should  a  student  request  for  physical  and/or  dental
                   examination/          certificate for the purpose of employment and/or training,
                   the student will have to pay Fifty Pesos P 50.00.

                          Section 7.  All rates are subject to change without prior notice.

                          Section  8.  The  Medical  and  Dental  examination  fees  as  well  as  the
                   laboratory fees to be collected shall be deposited in the Infirmary’s Fiduciary
                   Fund    and  will  be  used  to  purchase  medical/dental  supplies  and
                   equipment. Compensation and benefits of personnel of the University clinic
                   and  other  needs  are  subject  to  accounting  and  auditing  rules  and
                   regulations.



                                                                                                           187]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         188





               Article  2.a    University  Personnel.  Every  year,  all  faculty  members,
                          employees and         staff  of  the  university  are  required  to  undergo
                          medical and laboratory check- up  to  ensure  optimum  health  and
                          efficiency.

                          Section 1.  All university personnel are required to undergo the
                                         following:

                          1.  Routine Laboratory Tests
                                 Complete Blood Count
                                 Urinalysis
                                 Fecalysis
                                 Chest X-ray
                                 Drug Test (Shabu and Marijuana)
                                 Hepatitis B Screening
                          2.  Special Laboratory Examination ( as needed )
                                 Electrocardiogram (ECG)
                                 Blood Chemistry (FBS, BUN, BUA, Creatinine, lipid profile)
                                 Pap Smear (For Female Employees)*
                                 Ultrasound (whole abdomen for both male and female: pelvic for
                                 female and prostate for male)*
                                 Pregnancy test*       (*as necessary)
                          3.  Physical  and  Dental  Examinations  to  be  conducted  by  the
                              University Physician and Dentist.


                          Section 2.  As per Board of Regents Resolution No. 65 series of 2007,
                   the  University  shall  subsidize  the  annual  medical  examination  fees  and
                   charges of its personnel using the following schedule:

                                 Salary Grade of Personnel                   Amount of Subsidy

                                   Grades 1-3                                      100%
                                   Grades 4-7                                        90%
                                   Grades 8-11                                       80%
                                   Grades 12 and above                               70%

                          Section 3.  If upon examination, a faculty member/ staff is diagnose
                   to be:

                                 1.  Suffering  from  a  suspicious  disease(s),  he/she  shall  be
                                     required  to  undergo  a  special/additional  laboratory  or
                                                                                                           188]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         189

                                     diagnostic  examination(s)  or  shall  be  referred  to  a  medical
                                     specialist for further evaluation and management; or

                                 2.  Afflicted  with  a  communicable  disease(s),  he/she  shall  be
                                     advised to follow a specific treatment/regimen or take a leave
                                     of  absence  for  a  certain  period  of  time  until  such  time
                                     he/she gets well or until he/she submits/presents a medical
                                     certificate  from  a  medical  specialist  confirming  fitness  to
                                     continue work, if the condition is proven otherwise.

                          Section      4.    Should      a    faculty/staff     request      for   physical
                   examination/certificate for the purpose of training, scholarship,              etc.,
                   he/she will have to pay fifty pesos P 50.00.

                   Article 2.b  University Applicants.           To ensure fitness to perform varying
                   university   jobs/work,  all  university  applicants  are  required  to  undergo
                   physical and          laboratory examinations.

                          Section  1.    All  applicants  of  the  university  shall  undergo  the
                          following:

                                 1.  Laboratory examinations such as:
                                         Chest X-ray
                                         Complete Blood Count
                                         Urinalysis
                                         Drug Test (Shabu and Marijuana)
                                         Neuro-Psychiatric Exam
                                         Pregnancy  Test  (as  necessary  for  married,  female
                                 applicants)
                                 2.  Physical examination conducted by the University Physician
                                     upon submission of the necessary laboratory examinations.

                              Section 2.  Medical certificate of fitness to perform work for those
                       who are afflicted with any of the following mental, medical, and physical
                       problems/conditions shall not be approved:

                                 a.  Communicable  diseases  which  include  active  Pulmonary
                                     Tuberculosis (PTB) and replicative Hepatitis B
                                 b.  Debilitating disease such as renal, liver, and blood diseases
                                     and cancer
                                 c.  Uncontrolled Hypertension
                                 d.  Uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus
                                 e.  Severe Heart Disease/Condition
                                 f.  Drug Addiction
                                 g.  Pregnancy in the Third Trimester


                                                                                                           189]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         190

                                 h.  Other mental, medical and physical problems, as determined
                                     by the university physician to have direct bearing or effect on
                                     the work of the employee.
                          Section  3.    A  physical  examination  fee  of  one  hundred  pesos
                   (P100.00) shall be charged per applicant / new employee.

                          Section 4.  Laboratory examination/s may be conducted in any other
                   healthcare  facility  or  hospitals  outside  the  University  Laboratory  duly
                   accredited by the Department of Health (DOH) and Dangerous Drug Board.

                          Section 5.  The Medical and Dental examination fees as well as the
                   laboratory fees to be collected shall be deposited in the Infirmary’s Fiduciary
                   Fund    and  will  be  used  to  purchase  medical/dental  supplies  and
                   equipment. Compensation and benefits of personnel of the University clinic
                   and  other  needs  are  subject  to  accounting  and  auditing  rules  and
                   regulations.

                   Article  2.c    Renewal  of  Contractual  Status  of  Employees.              University
                          personnel  whose  contractual  appointment  is  recommended  for
                          renewal shall be required to undergo the following tests :

                          Section 1.  6-Month Renewal
                                       a.  Blood     Test     (CBC,      Blood      Chemistry,       HbsAg
                                          Determination)
                                       b.  Urinalysis  (including  pregnancy  test  for  female
                                          applicants 18 to 45 years of age as necessary)

                          Section 2.  One (1)-Year Renewal
                                       a.      Blood     Test    (CBC,     Blood     Chemistry,      HbsAg
                                       Determination)
                                       b.    Urinalysis  (including  pregnancy  test  for  female
                                       applicants 18 to  45 years of age as necessary)
                                       c.   Chest X-ray
                                       d.   Drug Test (Shabu and Marijuana)
                                       e.   Electrocardiogram (ECG)

                                 3.  Physical examination conducted by the University Physician
                                     upon submission of the necessary laboratory examinations.

                          Section 3.  Recommendation for those who are afflicted with any of
                     the  following  mental,  medical,  and  physical  problems  shall  not  be
                     approved:

                                 a.  Communicable  diseases  which  include  active  Pulmonary
                                     Tuberculosis (PTB) and replicative Hepatitis B


                                                                                                           190]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         191

                                 b.  Debilitating disease such as renal, liver, and blood diseases
                                     and cancer
                                 c.  Uncontrolled Hypertension
                                 d.  Uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus
                                 e.  Severe Heart Disease/Condition
                                 f.  Drug Addiction
                                 g.  Other mental, medical and physical problems, as determined
                                     by the university physician to have direct bearing or effect on
                                     the work of the employee.

                          Section 4.  Laboratory examination/s may be conducted in any other
                     healthcare  facility  or  hospitals  outside  the  University  Laboratory  duly
                     accredited  by  the  Department  of  Health  (DOH)  and  Dangerous  Drug
                     Board.

                          Section  5.  Expenses  incurred  on  the  abovementioned  laboratory
                     examinations  are  reimbursable  to  the  employee’s  respective  unit  or
                     department up to a maximum amount of P 1,500.00* (*subject to approval
                     and  availability  of  funds).  Any  amount  in  excess  shall  be  shouldered  by
                     the employee.

                   Article  2.d    Change  of  Status  from  Temporary  to  Permanent  of
                   Employees.

                          Section 1.  University personnel whose status is recommended to be
                     changed  from  contractual  to  temporary  and/or  temporary  to  permanent
                     shall  be  required  to  undergo  the  same  tests  that  are  required  for  the
                     renewal of contractual personnel (1-year renewal).

                          The  required  tests  shall  be  conducted,  if  possible,  at  the  University
                     Laboratory.  Otherwise,  the  tests  can  be  done  in    other  laboratories  and
                     hospitals  accredited  by  the  Department  of  Health  (DOH)  and  Dangerous
                     Drug Board.

                          Section 2.  Recommendation for those who are afflicted with any of
                     the  following  mental,  medical,  and  physical  problems  shall  not  be
                     approved:

                                 a.  Communicable  diseases  which  include  active  Pulmonary
                                     Tuberculosis (PTB) and replicative Hepatitis B
                                 b.  Debilitating disease such as renal, liver, and blood diseases
                                     and cancer
                                 c.  Unmanageable Hypertension
                                 d.  Unmanageable Diabetes Mellitus
                                 e.  Severe Heart Disease/Condition
                                 f.  Drug Addiction
                                                                                                           191]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Students proceed to the Affiliated




               Diagnostic Clinic accessible




               to their location]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Sample Referral given to Students]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[No Schedule of Medical and Dental




             for 2020-2022 due to Pandemic]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>