<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="40"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.18.           There are financial assistance


                        programs designed for:


                        S.18.2. student assistantship;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Manual of Operations]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           208
                                Printed  materials  should  not  be  placed  on  vehicles  parked  on
                                 campus or inside the classrooms. They may be distributed only
                                 with the consent of the Instructor or teacher of the class at the
                                 time.

                                Literature  materials  may  be  distributed  within  the  college
                                 premises only after prior authorization.

                                Materials  in  the  form  of  protest,  expressing  certain  views  or
                                 espousing ideas not contrary to prudent taste may be posted on
                                 the structure or bulletin board provided by the University.

                                The  college/department  official  bulletin  boards  are  exclusively
                                 for  announcements,  notices  or  programs  and  activities
                                 sponsored  by  the  said  college/department.  Their  use  by  any
                                 student groups may be allowed upon previous approval by the
                                 college  dean/department  chairman  concerned.  Walls  shall  not
                                 be used for posting announcements.

                   Article 8. Student’s Code of Conduct

                                The  University,  in  consultation  with  the  students,  shall
                                 promulgate  and  implement  a  student’s  code  of  conduct  as  a
                                 general guide on the actions and activities of students while in
                                 campus.  The  rules  and  guidelines  shall  include  wearing  of
                                 identification  cards  and  uniforms;  abusive  language,  assault
                                 against  others  and  persons  in  authority;  smoking;  alcoholic
                                 drinks and prohibited drugs; and others that shall contribute a
                                 peaceful,  harmonious  and  orderly  academic  atmosphere.    The
                                 full  text  of  Student’s  Code  of  Conduct  is  in  Rule  VIII  of  this
                                 Manual.

                   Article 9. Student Financial Assistance

                                Included  in  this  portion  is  the  overall  student  financial
                                 assistance program of the University. Any revision thereof shall
                                 be approved by the Board of Regents.

                                The Financial Assistance Services Unit of the Office of Student
                                 Affairs  shall  be  responsible  for  the  implementation  of  the
                                 University Student Financial Assistance Program.

                                Listed  too  are  the  current  types  of  scholarship/financial
                                 assistance  offered  by  the  University.  Other  types  of  financial


                                                                                                         208]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           209
                                 assistance  may  be  implemented  later  upon  approval  by  the
                                 Board of Regents.

                                          a.) CvSU  State  Scholarship.  This  scholarship  is
                                              awarded to financially deserving students who excel
                                              in  academic  performance.  The  grant  is  classified  as
                                              full and partial. In order to avail the full and partial
                                              grant, the students shall have a Grade Point Average
                                              (GPA)  of  1.50  or  better,  and  1.51  to  1.75,
                                              respectively.

                                          b.) Honorific       or    Academic        Scholarship.        This
                                              scholarship  is  awarded  to  students  whose  Grade
                                              Point Average (GPA) is not lower than 1.75 and with
                                              no  failing  or  incomplete  grade(s)  in  the  preceding
                                              semester. The grant is classified as full scholars with
                                              GPA of 1.50 or better and partial scholars with GPA
                                              of 1.75 to 1.51. Valedictorians and salutatorians are
                                              considered  entrance  scholars  and  are  entitled  full
                                              scholarship.  Honor  graduates  maybe  considered
                                              partial  scholars  depending  on  the  class  size  of
                                              graduating class.

                                          c.) Private  Scholarship.  This  is  granted  to  students
                                              who  are  selected  and  sponsored  by  private
                                              individuals  and  organizations.  The  continuance  or
                                              the default of scholarship is at the discretion of the
                                              sponsor.

                                          d.) Endowed Scholarship.  This is a scholarship set up
                                              when donors provide grant money or raise a

                                          e.) certain  amount,  which  will  be  the  principal  of  a
                                              scholarship fund. The earnings of the endowment be
                                              utilized  to  support  scholarship  grants.  The  fund  is
                                              managed  by  the  office  in  charge  of  the  University
                                              Development Fund/Office of Student Affairs.

                                          f.)  Student  Assistantship.  This  is  a  grant  available  to
                                              students who desire to render service to the

                                          g.) University  and  receive  remuneration  for  services
                                              while  studying.  The  allowable  number  of  hours  of
                                              work service shall be maximum of 100.



                                                                                                         209]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           210
                                          h.) Service  scholarship.  This  is  a  program  which
                                              provides  free  tuition  or  tuition  discount  to  students
                                              who  have  rendered  service  to  the  University  as
                                              members of the varsity teams, CvSU band and socio-
                                              cultural,  senior  staff  of  student  publication,  officers
                                              of  the  University  Central  Student  Government  and
                                              first class ROTC Cadet Officers.
                                          i.)  Job Experience Program (formerly known as Work
                                              for  Tuition).  This  is  a  form  of  student  assistance
                                              extended to financially handicapped students so they
                                              can  enroll  in  a  particular  course  and  pay  the
                                              corresponding  school  fees  incurred  for  the  semester
                                              through  work  services  rendered  to  the  University.
                                              The number of work service depends on the amount
                                              of fees discounted.

                                          j.)  Government  Scholarship.  This  is  a  scholarship
                                              given  to  any  student  under  the  Philippine  Veterans
                                              Affairs  (PVA),  R.A.  7160,  PD  577,  DND-CHED-
                                              PASUC,  AFP-Educational  Benefit  System  and  other
                                              similar  recognized  government  scholarship  honored
                                              by the University upon presentation of the necessary
                                              credentials.

                                          k.) CvSU  Scholarship  Privilege.  This  scholarship  is
                                              awarded  to  employees  of  the  University  and  their
                                              dependents  provided  that  such  employees  have
                                              rendered  at  least  one  year  of  continuous  service  to
                                              the  University,  irrespective  of  their  employment
                                              status.

                                In  general,  the  criteria  in  the  selection  of  financial  awardees
                                 include: good moral character; economic background of parents
                                 or guardians; willingness to work; and academic performance.
                                 The University shall promulgate the details of selection criteria
                                 and  the  mechanics  of  implementation  and  revise  the  same
                                 accordingly, as the need arises.

                                 The  benefits  to  the  awardees  of  the  financial  assistance
                                 program include: either free tuition or discounts in tuition;

                                monthly  stipend;  allowance  per  semester;  book  allowance  and
                                 others.  In  addition,  some  types  of  financial  assistance  include
                                 priority booking in the University Dormitory. The


                                                                                                         210]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Policy Guidelines on Granting



                    of Student Assistantship]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[199]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[200]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[201]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[202]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[203]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[204]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[205]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[206]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[207]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[208]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[209]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[210]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[211]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[212]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[213]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[214]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[215]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[216]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[217]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[218]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[219]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[220]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[221]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>