<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="37"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.           There is a distinct office that manages


                         the Extension Program.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Figure 1. Organizational structure of Extension Services]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Figure 1. Organizational structure of Extension Services]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Organizational Structure of Extension Services]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Organizational Structure of Extension Services]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Extension Services Directory]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Extension Coordinators of College/Campuses and RDE Units]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Extension Coordinators of College/Campuses and RDE Units]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Cavite State University-Main Campus
                                                        Extension Office]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Office of the Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[TANZA CAMPUS EXTENSION SERVICES OFFICE





























                               Mr. Ritch M. Banate, the extension coordinator of Tanza Campus















                    Prepared by:



                    RITCH M. BANATE
                    Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Workplace in the Community]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[OFFICE OF BARANGAY BAGTAS
















































                    Prepared by:




                    RITCH M. BANATE
                    Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Lifted from the CvSU Extension Manual

                             Terms of Reference of Extension

                                                    Personel]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[25


                                         During the pre-implementation meeting,  the proponent shall present the

                                 general framework of the project and its strategies for implementation including


                                 the work plan and budget summary. The M&E Division staff of the Extension

                                 Services shall discuss the parameters for monitoring and evaluating the project.


                                 Meanwhile, representatives from the Administration and Finance Offices shall

                                 present the guidelines for purchasing supplies and materials, hiring project staff,


                                 among others. All comments and recommendations shall be documented by the

                                 M&E Division. Afterwards, a copy of the highlights of the meeting shall be


                                 distributed to all the attendees of the meeting for their guidance.

                                 Section 7.2. Hiring/Appointment of Personnel and Professional Services.


                                 Upon the approval of the proposal, the proponent or the appointed project leader

                                 is authorized to hire the necessary project staff or expert required to conduct

                                 and complete the deliverables of the project. The hired or appointed staff must


                                 be paid for the services they rendered; provided that the terms, conditions, and

                                 salary rates are strictly in accordance with the approved line item budget of the


                                 project and following the accounting and auditing rules and regulations of the

                                 University.


                                 Section 7.3. Responsibilities of the Program/Project Personnel

                                 a.  Program  Leader.  The  Program  Leader  shall  perform  the  following


                                     functions in the implementation of the program:

                                     •  Provide overall direction in terms of setting common directions of the


                                         projects under the program;]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[26


                                     •  Set the work plan of the various projects to establish synchronicity and

                                         coordination between project activities and schedule in order to attain


                                         the objectives of the program;


                                     •  Represent the program in dealing with collaborating and other external

                                         agencies; and

                                     •  In cases where the Program Leader is concurrently the Project Leader


                                         of a component project, he must also accomplish the duties expected

                                         of a Project Leader.


                                 b.  Project Leader. The Project Leader shall perform  the  following functions

                                     in the implementation of the program:


                                     •  Plan, organize and direct the overall conduct of the project;

                                     •  Spearhead the conduct of extension activities;

                                     •  Hire and recommend the appointment of the required project

                                         personnel;


                                     •  Recommend  payment  of  salaries  and  compensations  of  project

                                         personnel; and

                                     •  Prepare and submit progress reports, annual reports, and terminal


                                         report

                                 c.  Project Staff/Extension Officer

                                     •  Assist the Project Leader in planning and managing overall extension

                                         project operations;


                                     •  Initiate the daily conduct of extension activities;]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[27


                                     •  Supervise the collection of necessary data and materials related to the

                                         extension activities; and


                                     •  Assist the Project Leader in preparing progress reports

                                 Section  7.4.  Collaborations.  Established  linkages  and  collaborations  must

                                 have either a Memorandum of Agreement or Memorandum of Understanding

                                 forged      between     the     University     and      the    collaborating


                                 agency/institution/establishment.  The  document  shall  be  duly  signed  by  the

                                 parties involved and shall be notarized by authorized legal authorities.


                                         Terms of reference, responsibilities of each party, contents and other

                                 pertinent items shall be discussed between the concerned parties before drawing


                                 the agreements.

                                 Section 7.5. Conduct of Trainings.  The conduct of trainings and seminars

                                 related to the extension project shall be based on the needs of the community or


                                 stakeholders as per results of the Community Needs Assessment conducted by

                                 the Extension Office. An activity proposal containing the mechanics and the


                                 budgetary requirement shall be submitted to the University President before the

                                 conduct of the training/seminar. Moreover, training for capability enhancement


                                 of the Extension Coordinators/Staff may also be done subject to availability of

                                 funds. Request from other stakeholders and  partner communities and agencies


                                 may  also  be  conducted  provided  that  they  have  sent letter  of  request  to  the

                                 University President who has the sole authority to approve the request.]]></page></pages></Search>