<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="63"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.3.            The Institution’s/Academic Unit’s/


                        College faculty, personnel, students


                        and other stakeholders (cooperating

                        agencies, linkages, alumni, industry


                        sector and other concerned groups)


                        participate in the formulation, review

                        and/or revision of the VMGO.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Chronological Events in the Formulation, Review and Revision of the Cavite
     Chronological Events in the Formulation, Review and Revision of the Cavite
           State University Vision, Mission, Goals and Objectives (CvSU VMGO)
           State University Vision, Mission, Goals and Objectives (CvSU VMGO)


               A series of meetings/workshops were conducted to formulate, review, and revise the
               A series of meetings/workshops were conducted to formulate, review, and revise the
        CvSU  Vision,  Mission,  Goals,  and  Objectives.  The  chronological  events  supporting  the
        CvSU  Vision,  Mission,  Goals,  and  Objectives.  The  chronological  events  supporting  the
        formulation of the VMGO of CvSU are illustrated below.
        formulation of the VMGO of CvSU are illustrated below.




       January 22, 1988








     February 27-28 2001













          June 7-8 2001












       December 19, 2001
















       January 23, 2002]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[April 5, 2005




      November 23, 2011




     January 24-27, 2017]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                                        235-7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph



                                 Faculty Orientation and Capability Enhancement

                                                September 2 to 3, 2021



                  Two days Faculty Orientation and Capability Enhancement Webinar was

                  held at Cavite State University – Tanza Campus, September 2 to 3, 2021,
                  through online Webex.


                        The program started with a summary using online quiz regarding previous
                  topic such as CvSU at Glance, introduction to key officials, gender development

                  and  campus  extension  services.  It  was  followed  by  discussing  the  test
                  construction,  Table  of  Specifications  (TOS),  content  of  written  examinations,

                  rubrics preparation and other activities.


                        Meanwhile, Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, chairperson of the department of

                  education,  discussed  the  content  of  course  syllabus,  laboratory  report,  and

                  learning guide.

                        “Learning  guide  is  the  best  materials  and  easy  to  use,  through  this,

                  students will work on their own based on the tasks that the instructor assigned
                  to them,” she added.


                        Moreover,  Ms.  Charmaine  T.  Banag,  faculty  member  under  information

                  technology,  oriented  all  faculty  members  about  the  CvSU  Learning

                  Management System, its procedure, and imperative feature.  Besides, a short
                  tutorial was presented to broaden the knowledge of all participants.


                        Furthermore, Mr. Mark  Joel  S.  Sibulo,  chairperson of  the  department  of

                  arts and sciences, discussed the proper attire, grading system, and netiquettes

                  that  need  to  consider  during  online  class;  and  each  department  conducted  a
                  break out session to deliberate a sample draft of course syllabus, objectives of

                  the department and establish rapport with each member.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[In addition, an open forum was conducted to answer the questions of the

                  teaching  personnel  and  to  edify  them  about  the  upcoming  school  year  2021-
                  2022.  During  the  open  forum,  various  questions  were  raised  by  the  faculties

                  and were answered by Prof. Mildred Sebastian, chairperson of the department

                  of education and other key officials.

                        The  virtual  orientation  ended  with  the  closing  statement  of  Ms.  Debbie
                  Rose Banag, HR Coordinator, gave welcome statements about the newly hired

                  faculty  with  emphasis  that  despite  the  pandemic,  Cavite  State  University  -

                  Tanza Campus will continue serving and providing quality education throughout
                  the semester.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Faculty Orientation and Capability Enhancement 2022 Attendance





































                   Parents and Students Virtual Orientation and Re-Orientation 2022 Participants]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



                         PARENTS’ AND STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION AND
                                        RE-ORIENTATION PROGRAM 2022
                                                 September 16, 2022



                         The  Cavite  State  University-Tanza  Campus  conducted  the  virtual
               parents and student orientation and re-orientation last September 12, 2022,
               1:00pm-4:00pm via FB live. The implementing guidelines on the limited face-
               to-face  classes,  academic  policies  and  grading  system,  student  code  of
               conduct  and  other  student  services,  learning  delivery  modes,  orientation
               about  the  Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  of  the  University,  and
               orientation on the library system are some of the topics discussed during the
               program.

























                             Activity banner posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook page]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph






















                          Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro, Vice President for Academic Affairs, giving her
                                             welcome remarks to the participants
























                                           Introduction to the Campus’ key officials and support personnel]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                            Introduction to the faculty members of the Teacher Education Department
























                            Introduction to the faculty members of the Department of Management]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                                     The University academic calendar for S.Y 2022-2023, presented by the
                                                    Campus Registrar, Ms. Noemi A. Perida
























                              Discussion on the academic policies and grading system of the University]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph























                   Discussion on the student programs and service provided by the Office of Student
                         Affairs and Services, presented by Ms. Melona I. Saquin, OSAS Head




































                                        Discussion on the student code of conduct]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and Children Act, Anti-
                  bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on Drug Abuse and Drug
                  Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442 vilification against Person with
                                                          Disability





























                 Presentation on the CvSU Learning Management System (LMS) and flexible learning delivery
                                modes, presented by the MIS officer, Ms. Charmaine T. Banag]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

























                         Library orientation presented by the Campus’ Librian, Ms. Roselyn C. Baltar
























                               Mr. Gerard Advincula, program host, facilitating the open forum]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines                                                                CvSU Mission
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                 Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus                                                Cavite State University shall provide
                                         235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693                                                         excellent, equitable and relevant
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph                                                                educational opportunities in the arts,
                                                                                                                                  sciences and technology through quality
                                                                                                                                  instruction and responsive research and
               August 19, 2020                                                                                                          developmental activities.
                                                                                                                                  It shall produce professional, skilled and
                                                                                                                                   morally upright individuals for global
               DR. HERNANDO D. ROBLES                                                                                                      competitiveness.
               President
               This University

               Dear Sir:

               Good day!

               The Cavite State University – Tanza, Trece Martires City and General Trias City Campuses
               (T3 Campuses) will conduct its Faculty Orientation via Zoom on September 1 to 3, 2020 and
               Students’ Orientation through the FB livestream on September 21, 2020 respectively. These
               activities aim to orient faculty members, employees and students on various administrative
               and academic policies relating to Flexible Learning Modality and inform about the forthcoming
               school activities and schedules.

               In this regard, we would like to seek your approval to allow us to conduct the said activities.

               Attached is the proposal for your reference.

               Thank you very much for your usual support.

               Very truly yours,

               JESSIE ANNE T. DEMETILLO, PhD
               T3 Secretary


               Recommending Approval


               NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
               T3 Campuses Administrator


               MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Vice President, Academic Affairs

               Approved


               HERNANDO D. ROBLES, PhD
               President]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines                                                                   CvSU Mission
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus                                                  Cavite State University shall provide
                                                                                                                                     excellent, equitable and relevant
                                          235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693                                                      educational opportunities in the arts,
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph                                                               sciences and technology through quality
                                                                                                                                  instruction and responsive research and
                                                 ACTIVITY PROPOSAL                                                                      developmental activities.
                                                                                                                                  It shall produce professional, skilled and
                                                                                                                                   morally upright individuals for global
               I. TITLE:      T3 (TRECE MARTIRES CITY, TANZA AND GENERAL TRIAS CITY                                                        competitiveness.
                              CAMPUSES) FACULTY AND STUDENTS’ ORIENTATION


               II. RATIONALE:

                       This  coming  First  Semester  AY  2020-2021,  Cavite  State  University  is  faced  with
               various challenges pertaining to Flexible Learning Modality and in handling online classes in
               this so-called new normal. In this relation, CVSU T3 – Trece Martires City, Tanza and General
               Trias City Campuses will conduct orientations for its faculty members via Zoom and students
               through the FB livestream. These activities aim to inform faculty members, employees and
               students  on  the  various  administrative  policies  and  academic  updates  regarding  the
               aforementioned  modality.  Further,  it  will  also  orient  faculty  members  with  some  of  the
               netiquettes  in  handling  online  classes  and  as  well  as  with  academic  policies  and  grading
               system for the forthcoming semester.

               III. OBJECTIVES:

                   This activity aims to:

                     formally introduce the key officials, old and new faculty members, employees, and new
                       and old students;

                     conduct faculty orientation on academic policies and grading system appertaining to
                       Flexible Learning Modality;

                     conduct student orientation on Flexible Learning Modality policies and guidelines and
                       grading system; and

                     inform students on forthcoming school activities and schedules.

               IV. MECHANICS OF IMPLEMENTATION


                       The T3 Campuses faculty and students’ orientation will be conducted as follows:

                 DATE                  PLATFORM            ACTIVITY
                 September 1, 2020     Zoom                Trece Martires City Campus Faculty
                                                           Orientation

                 September 2, 2020     Zoom                General Trias City Campus Faculty Orientation
                 September 3, 2020     Zoom                Tanza Campus Faculty Orientation
                 September 21, 2020  FB Livestream         T3 Students’ Orientation]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Participants

                       Participants would be the campus dean, all faculty, employees and students of the
               three campuses.

                         T3 participants are as follows:
                              Campus Dean                  -         1
                              Faculty                      -       119
                              Staff                        -       10
                              New and Old Students         -           4,200

                         Everyone is required to attend Student Orientation
                         All faculty members are required to attend the Faculty Orientation

               V. BUDGETARY ALLOCATION

                           None

               VI. PROGRAMME:


                                        FACULTY ORIENTATION PER CAMPUS
                                                 SEPTEMBER 1-3, 2020
                                                   (7:00PM via Zoom)

                           PROGRAM                     SEPT 1, 2020         SEPT 2, 2020        SEPT 3, 2020
                                                           (7PM)                (7PM)               (7PM)
                                                     TRECE CAMPUS  GENTRI CAMPUS  TANZA CAMPUS
               I. Prayer/CvSU @ a Glance             Mr. Keno A.         Mr. Keno A.          Mr. Keno A.
                                                     Villavicencio       Villavicencio        Villavicencio
                                                                         Mr. Mikael Florenz   Ms. Joyce Erika
                                                                         P. Nuestro Mr.       S. Senaris/Mr.
                                                                                              Mark Joseph
                                                                                              Sibulo
               II.  Introduction  of  Key  Officials  and  Dr. Jessie Anne T.  Dr. Jessie Anne T.   Dr. Jessie Anne T.
               Support Personnel per campus          Demetillo           Demetillo            Demetillo
               III. Welcome Remarks                  Prof. Noel A.       Prof. Noel A.        Prof. Noel A.
                                                     Sedigo              Sedigo               Sedigo
               IV.   Presentation    of   Academic  Prof. Vienna Mi A.  Ms. Roncesvalle J.    Prof. Mildred A.
               Calendar                              Feranil             Caipang              Sebastian
               V.  Academic  Policies  and  Grading  Ms. Mary Ann L.     Ms. Rogelyn Arca     Ms. Noemi A.
               System                                Anonas                                   Perida
               VI.  HR  Policies  (RA  6713  Code  of  Ms. Jelyn D.      Ms. Shaine C.        Ms. Debbie Rose
               Conduct  and  Ethical  Standards  for  Digma              Hayag                T. Banag
               Public Officials and Employees)
               VII.  Orientation  to  CvSU  e-Library  Ms. Loran         Ms. Loran Camille    Ms. Loran
               System,  open  Education  Resources  Camille Villarante  Villarante            Camille Villarante
               and Creative Commons
               VIII.  Netiquettes  in  Handling  Online  Mr. Gideon Luke   Mr. Gideon Luke P.  Mr. Gideon Luke
               Classes                               P. Ty               Ty                   P. Ty
               IX.  Discussion  on  Gender  and  Prof. Arlene L.         Ms. Estelita A. Villa  Ms. Debbie Rose
               Development                           Estrada                                  T. Banag
               X. Closing Remarks                    Ms. Lilian O.       Ms. Shaine C.        Mr. Cris Albert P.
                                                     Sidamon             Hayag                Cajigas
               Moderator                             Ms. Pamela          Mr. Aljhevin A.      Mr. Audreyson
                                                     Daphnie R.          Comiso               Borilla
                                                     Busog]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[WORKING COMMITTEE
                                               (FACULTY ORIENTATION)

                     Committee            Trece (Sept. 1,     Gen. Trias (Sept. 2,     Tanza (Sept. 3,
                                           2020 @ 7PM)           2020 @ 7PM)           2020 @ 7 PM0
                 Activity in Charge    Lilian O. Sidamon      Shaine C. Hayag       Mildred A. Sebastian
                 Program and           Keno A.                Mikael Florenz P.     Joyce Erika S.
                 Technical Flow        Vilalvicencio          Nuestro               Senaris
                                                                                    Ron Mariah Kristafer
                                                                                    J. Manlapig
                 Program and           Pamela Daphne R.       Aljhevin A. Comiso    Charmaine T. Banag
                 Certificate Layouts   Busog                  Diolits C.Gregorio,
                                       Richard A. Rocillo     Jr.
                 Attendance            Kristel Shane C.       Roncesvalle J.        Debbie Rose T.
                 Monitoring            Paminter               Caipang               Banag
                                       Desiree Anne D.        Cheyne L. Banogon
                                       Mendoza
                 Documentation         Cristza DO.            Noel B. Manarpiis     Ritch M. Banate
                                       Manlapig               Louziela P. Masana    Mary Rose
                                       Rose Ann R. Tobias                           Elamparo
                                                                                    Jeffrey M. Delgado
                 Over-all in Charge    Noel A. Sedigo         Noel A. Sedigo        Noel A. Sedigo
                                       Jessie Anne T.         Jessie Anne T.        Jessie Anne T.
                                       Demetillo              Demetillo             Demetillo



                                           STUDENTS’ ORIENTATION PART II
                                         September 21, 2020 (FB Live Stream)


                 PROGRAM                                       IN-CHARGE
                   I.   Prayer/CvSU @ a Glance                 Ms. Charmaine T. Banag
                                                               MIS Officer, CvSU – Tanza Campus
                  II.   Introduction of T3 Key Officials and   AVP
                        Support Personnel per Campus
                  III.   Introduction of Faculty per           AVP
                        Department
                 IV.    Introduction of Students per Program   Ms. Lilian O. Sidamon
                        and their Class Adviser                Ms. Shaine C. Hayag
                                                               Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian

                  V.    Academic Policies and Grading          Ms. Mary Ann L. Anonas
                        System                                 Ms. Rogelyn Alarca
                                                               Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                 VI.    Scholarships                           Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                                               Ms. Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                               Ms. Shaine C. Hayag
                 VII.   Orientation to CvSU e-Library          Ms. Lora Camille Villarante
                        System, open Education Resources
                        and Creative Commons
                VIII.   Open Forum                             Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                               Ms. Mary Ann Anonas
                                                               Ms. Rogelyn Alarca
                                                               Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                                                               Ms. Camille Villarante
                                                               Ms. Melona I. Saquin]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Ms. Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                               Ms. Shaine C. Hayag
                 IX.    Announcements
                  X.    CvSU Hymn                              AVP


               Working Committee Student Orientation
                 Activity in Charge                           Jessie Anne T. Demetillo
                                                              Mildred A. Sebastian
                 Program Flow and Posting                     Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                              Shaine C. Hayag
                                                              Melona I. Saquin
                 Program Layout and Certificates              Vienna Mi A. Feranil
                                                              Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                              Roncesvalle J. Caipang
                 Technical Requirements                       Charmaine T. Banag
                                                              Jeffrey M. Delgado
                                                              Ron Mariah Kristafer Manlapig
                 Registration/ Attendance and Evaluation  Charles Vincent Pitagan
                                                              Pamela Daphne R. Busog
                                                              Diolito Gregorio Jr.
                 Screening of Questions                       Joyce Erika Senaris
                                                              Christian P. Langit
                                                              Diolito Gregorio Jr.
                 Panel Members                                Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                              Ms. Mary Ann Anonas
                                                              Ms. Rogelyn Alarca
                                                              Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                                                              Ms. Camille Villarante
                                                              Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                                              Ms. Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                              Ms. Shaine C. Hayag
                 Documentation                                Ritch M. Banate
                                                              Arlene L. Estrada
                                                              Noel B. Manarpiis
                 In Charge of Ceremonies                      John Daniel Cap-atan
                 Overall in Charge                            Prof. Noel A. Sedigo

                                                   Mr. Audrey Borilla
                                                        Moderator

               Prepared by:


               JESSIE ANNE T. DEMETILLO, PhD
               T3 Secretary



               Approved:


               NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
               T3 Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines                                                                CvSU Mission
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                 Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus                                                Cavite State University shall provide
                                         235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693                                                         excellent, equitable and relevant
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph                                                                educational opportunities in the arts,
                                                                                                                                  sciences and technology through quality
                                           STUDENTS’ ORIENTATION PART II                                                          instruction and responsive research and
                                     September 21, 2020; 1:00PM (FB Live Stream)                                                        developmental activities.
                                                                                                                                  It shall produce professional, skilled and
                                                                                                                                   morally upright individuals for global
               Working Committee Student Orientation                                                                                       competitiveness.
                 Activity in Charge                           Jessie Anne T. Demetillo
                                                              Mildred A. Sebastian
                 Program Flow and Posting                     Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                              Shaine C. Hayag
                                                              Melona I. Saquin
                 Program Layout and Certificates              Vienna Mi A. Feranil
                                                              Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                              Roncesvalle J. Caipang
                 Technical Requirements                       Charmaine T. Banag
                                                              Jeffrey M. Delgado
                                                              Ron Mariah Kristafer Manlapig
                 Registration/ Attendance and Evaluation  Charles Vincent Pitagan
                                                              Pamela Daphne R. Busog
                                                              Diolito Gregorio Jr.
                 Screening of Questions                       Joyce Erika Senaris
                                                              Christian P. Langit
                                                              Diolito Gregorio Jr.
                 Panel Members                                Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                              Ms. Mary Ann Anonas
                                                              Ms. Rogelyn Alarca
                                                              Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                                                              Ms. Camille Villarante
                                                              Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                                              Ms. Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                              Ms. Shaine C. Hayag
                 Documentation                                Ritch M. Banate
                                                              Arlene L. Estrada
                                                              Noel B. Manarpiis
                 In Charge of Ceremonies                      John Daniel Cap-atan
                 Overall in Charge                            Prof. Noel A. Sedigo

               Approved:



               NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
               T3 Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                     T3 STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION 2020
                                                  September 21, 2020

                       Cavite State University – T3 Campuses held the Students’ Virtual Orientation
               on September 21, 2020 thru Facebook live stream. The program started with the AVP

               of the T3 campuses, CvSU Tanza, Gen. Trias City, and Trece Martires City Campuses

               facilities, its development through the years, and University Misison and Vision. It was
                followed by the introduction of T3 key officials, support personnel, faculty per

               department and students class adviser per program.

                       Meanwhile,  Ms.  Mary  Ann  L.  Anonas,  T3  Campus  Registrar,  discussed  the
               academic  policies  and  grading  system  followed  by  the  discussion  of  different

               scholarship offered in the University and other external agencies.
                       Furthermore,  Ms.  Loran  Camille  Villarante  oriented  the  students  about  the

               CvSU e-Library System Open Education Resources and Creative Commons.
                       In  addition,  an  open  forum  was  conducted  to  answer  the  questions  of  the

               students  and  to  enlighten  them  about  the  “new  normal”  academic  set-up  of  T3

               Campuses. During the open forum, various questions were raised by the students and
               were answered by Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3 Campus Administrator, and other key

               officials.
                       The virtual orientation ended with the closing statement of Prof. Sedigo with his

               emphasis that despite the pandemic, T3 Campuses will continue serving and providing
               quality education and ensuring that no students will be left behind.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                         TANZA FACULTY ORIENTATION 2020
                                                   September 3, 2020

                       Cavite State University – Tanza Campus conducted a virtual faculty orientation
               on September 3, 2020 thru Zoom to help all the newly hired and rehired faculty and

               staff of the campus make a smooth and enjoyable transition to the new normal of

               education and to prove that a crisis cannot impair its academic functions. The program
               started with a prayer led by Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo and followed by the AVP of CvSU

               at a Glance which featured the humble beginnings of the University and its vision of

               becoming a global University.
                       Meanwhile, Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3 Campus Administrator, welcomed all the

               faculty members and staff with gratitude as he witnessed the untiring support and
               whole-hearted dedication  of faculty  and  staff  to  continue  the  semester despite the

               current situation of the academic community.
                       Furthermore,  the  old  and  new  faculty  members  were  introduced  by  their

               respective department chairpersons. Each department chairpersons provided a brief

               background of their educational attainment, specializations, and accomplishments.
                       Moreover,  Prof.  Mildred  A.  Sebastian,  Chairperson  of  Teacher  Education

               Department,  presented  the  academic  calender.  This  was  followed  by  academic
               policies and grading system discussed by Ms. Noemi A. Perida.

                       After that, the discussion of HR Policies and Gender and Development was led
               by Tanza campus’ HR and GAD Coordinator, Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag.

                       In addition,  Ms. Loran  Camille  Villarante, T3  Librarian, tackled  the  CvSU e-

               Library System and Open Education Resources. It was followed by the discussion of
               Mr. Luke Ty about netiquettes in handling online classes.

                       The virtual orientation ended with the closing statement of Mr. Cris Albert P.

               Cajigas, Tanza Campus Coordinator, who said that as the University embraced the
               first semester of the Academic Year 2020 – 2021 under the new normal context, the

               administration,  faculty  members  and  the  students  should  embraced  altogether  to
               continually  uplift  CvSU’s  tenets  of  Truth,  Service  and  Excellence,  despite  the

               paralyzing effect of the COVID-19 pandemic.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>