<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="55"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.1.         The faculty demonstrate professional


                    competence and engaged in any or a

                    combination of the following:


                    I.1.3.   extension]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                    SUMMARY OF PRIORITY AND RELEVANT
                                      EXTENSION ACTIVITIES CONDUCTED



                        Date                     Title of Activity                      Venue


                                             Successful Digital Business        Zoom abd Facebook
                                             Strategies: Creating Online                 Live
                 December 17, 2021
                                           Marketplace and Digital Supply
                                                    Management


                                             The New Normal of Online           Zoom and Facebook
                 December 16, 2021         Business: Setting, Starting, and              Live
                                                       Selling

                                           Product Distribution in the New      Zoom and Facebook
                    June 14, 2021                      Normal                            Live


                 December 11. 2020        Gourmazing na Negosyo, Kita ay       Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                          Sigurado: A webinar on gourmet
                                                products’ processing

                 September 14, 2020       Gourmazing na Negosyo, Kita ay       Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                          Sigurado: A webinar on gourmet
                                                products’ processing
                  November 8, 2019
                                         Training on Food Preservation and     Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                 Gourmet Products

                 November 8, 2019         Training on Food Preservation        Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                              and Gourmet Products

                 September 6, 2019        Training on Embutido Making          Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

                  August 30, 2019        Training on Dishwashing Liquid        Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                      Making

                  August 23, 2019        Training on Dishwashing Liquid        Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                      Making

                  March 8-15, 2019       Training on Dishwashing Liquid        Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                            Fabric Conditioner Making]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                Tanza Campus
                                                                      Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                (046) 414 – 3979
                                                                                www.cvsu.edu.ph
                                                                         SUMMARY OF EXTENSION ACTIVITIES
                                                                           Second Semester, AY 2021-2022
                                                                   03/11 &                      03/2022-                                 03/2022-  05/2022-
                                           01/12/2022  01/25/2022            03/24/2022  03/18/2022     04/8/2022  4/29/2022   5/6/2022
                                                                  03/18/2022                    04/2022                                  05/2022  06/2022
                                                                             Webinar on   Fire Safety   Webinar on   Webinar on
                                           Consultative           Mentoring                                                Webinar on Disaster
                                           Meeting with   Meeting for   Session of   Business Pitching   and   Preparation  How to Start  Green the Bottle   Preparedness: Basic  Community   Revision of   TOTAL
               Faculty        Designation  DepEd ALS -   Planning of   Balikabayanihan   of   Prevention   of Extension  a Business in   + Save the   Life Support and   Needs   Extension
                                             Tanza     Extension   Micro-Business   Balikabayanihan   Webinar   Project   2022   Mother Earth   First Aid including its  Assessment  Project
                                           Implementers  Activities 2022  Training  Micro-Business   including its   Proposal  including its   including its   preparation  Proposal
                                                                              Training  preparation     preparation  preparation
                                            3 Hours     3 Hours    8 Hours    4 Hours   8 Hours  16 Hours  8 Hours  8 Hours    8 Hours   16 Hours  8 Hours  90 Hours
         1 Mildred A. Sebastian  Project Leader  ü        ü                               ü       ü        ü         ü           ü          ü       ü      78 Hours
         2 Ritch M. Banate  Project Coordinator  ü        ü          ü          ü         ü                ü         ü           ü          ü       ü      74 Hours
         3 Joyce Erika S. Senaris  Project Coordinator  ü  ü                              ü                ü         ü           ü          ü       ü      62 Hours
         4 Estelita A. Villa  Project Coordinator  ü      ü                     ü         ü       ü        ü         ü           ü          ü       ü      82 Hours
         5 Debbie Rose B. Fabian  Project Facilitator  ü  ü          ü          ü         ü                ü         ü           ü          ü              66 Hours
         6 Melona O. Igmasine  Project Facilitator  ü     ü          ü          ü         ü                ü         ü           ü          ü              66 Hours
         7 Charmaine T. Banag  Project Facilitator  ü     ü                               ü                ü         ü           ü          ü              54 Hours
         8 Mary Rose E. Elamparo  Project Facilitator  ü  ü          ü          ü         ü                ü         ü           ü          ü              66 Hours


           Prepared and Approved by:
                                                                                      Noted

                    ESTELITA A. VILLA                                                            PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
                   Extension Coordinator                                                          Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza Campus
 Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 (046) 414 – 3979
 www.cvsu.edu.ph
 SUMMARY OF EXTENSION ACTIVITIES
 Second Semester, AY 2021-2022
 03/11 &    03/2022-                                 03/2022-  05/2022-
 01/12/2022  01/25/2022  03/24/2022  03/18/2022  04/8/2022  4/29/2022  5/6/2022
 03/18/2022  04/2022                                 05/2022  06/2022
 Webinar on   Fire Safety   Webinar on   Webinar on
 Consultative   Meeting for   Mentoring   Business Pitching   and   Preparation  How to Start  Green the Bottle   Webinar on Disaster   Revision of
 Meeting with   Session of             Preparedness: Basic  Community   TOTAL
 Faculty  Designation  DepEd ALS -   Planning of   Balikabayanihan   of   Prevention   of Extension  a Business in   + Save the   Life Support and   Needs   Extension
 Tanza   Extension   Micro-Business   Balikabayanihan   Webinar   Project   2022   Mother Earth   First Aid including its  Assessment  Project
 Implementers  Activities 2022  Training  Micro-Business   including its   Proposal  including its   including its   preparation  Proposal
 Training  preparation  preparation  preparation
 3 Hours  3 Hours  8 Hours  4 Hours  8 Hours  16 Hours  8 Hours  8 Hours  8 Hours  16 Hours  8 Hours  90 Hours
 1 Mildred A. Sebastian  Project Leader  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü     78 Hours
 2 Ritch M. Banate  Project Coordinator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  74 Hours
 3 Joyce Erika S. Senaris  Project Coordinator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  62 Hours
 4 Estelita A. Villa  Project Coordinator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  82 Hours
 5 Debbie Rose B. Fabian  Project Facilitator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  66 Hours
 6 Melona O. Igmasine  Project Facilitator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  66 Hours
 7 Charmaine T. Banag  Project Facilitator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü        54 Hours
 8 Mary Rose E. Elamparo  Project Facilitator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  66 Hours


 Prepared and Approved by:
  Noted

 ESTELITA A. VILLA  PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
 Extension Coordinator  Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                         CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                   Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                  ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                         EXTENSION PROJECT PROPOSAL

                   I.     Project Description

                        Title        :      BAGTAS with CvSU-Tanza


                                            (Bagtas ay Aasenso at Giginhawa kung Tayo Ay Sama-sama
                                            with CvSU – Tanza)

                        Location     :      Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

                        Proponent  :        Cavite State University – Tanza Campus


                        Beneficiaries:      Out-of-school  Children  and  Youth,  Brgy.  Officials,  and  non-
                                            working members of the community


                        Project Components:

                               Program 1: Oplan Karunungan
                               Program 2: Computer Literacy Program
                               Program 3: Livelihood Programs for Non-Working Members of the
                               Community
                               Program 4: Health and Wellness

                       Partner Agencies:  Local Government Unit of the Municipality of Tanza, Cavite;
                                            Provincial Cooperative, Livelihood, and Entrepreneurial
                                            Development Office (PCLEDO); Farmers Training Center
                                            (FITS); Companies in Export Processing Zone Authority
                                            (EPZA)

                       Estimated Budget:   Php 610,000

                       Duration      :      5 years


                   II.    Rationale
                              The population explosion in Brgy. Bagtas has led to an initiative to alleviate
                        poverty in the barangay. Brgy. Bagtas, having the most population in Tanza (20,370
                        out of 188,755), has been the site for relocation and reclamation. However, people,
                        who were displaced out of their previous addresses, were relocated in the said barangay
                        without having a regular source of living. Some of them could not find a decent job
                        because they lack the educational and other requirements for the job that they were]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[applying  for.  Others  could  not  start  any  business  because  they  lack  the  skills  in
                        preparing innovative products that could help them earn additional income for their
                        families.


                              Thus, different extension activities are being proposed to increase the quality of
                        life of the citizens in the said barangay. Non-formal education will help out-of-school
                        children to be able to read, write and count. Also, livelihood programs are deemed to
                        strengthen housewives’ skills and at the same time, augment the meager income of
                        their families. In addition, awareness drives concerning health and other GAD-related
                        issues are being proposed to inculcate the importance of appropriate living conditions
                        for every member of the community.


                   III.   Strategies of Implementation
                          A.  Formation of Committee

                                     A committee was formed to study and gather benchmark information
                              on the status, needs, and conditions of selected communities in Tanza, Cavite
                              during the second semester, AY 2014 – 2015. The committee was headed by
                              the  Extension  Coordinator.  Two  faculty  members  from  the  different
                              departments of the campus were selected as members of the committee to
                              ensure that the programs will conform to the mandate of the university. The
                              committee  used  the  following  benchmark  information,  provided  by  Tanza
                              Municipal Planning and Development Office (TMPDO), in order to assess
                              which group of individuals will be the target beneficiaries of the proposal.

                              Table 1. Data of Brgy. Bagtas population 2010 by sex, age, and employment

                                                          Male             Female          Total
                            Brgy. Bagtas Population       12,316           8,054           20,370
                            Age Bracket
                            5 – 9                         1,453            951             2,404
                            10 – 14                       1,299            849             2,148
                            OTHERS                        9,564            6,254           15,818
                            Enrolment Data
                            Pre-School (3 – 6)            1,213            878             2,091
                            Elementary (7 – 12)           1,176            823             1,999
                            Employment Data
                            Employed                      6,908            4,517           11,425
                            Unemployed                    600              393             993
                            Not in the labor force        4,808            3,144           7,952
                            Source: Philippine Statistics Authority and Tanza Municipal Planning and Development Office
                                     The committee used the descriptive design of a study. Data utilized in
                              the  study  mainly  came  from  the  responses  on  the  self-administered  survey
                              questions that were distributed to the residents of Brgy. Bagtas. Residents were
                              selected using simple random sampling.]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Results revealed that:

                                     •  87.14% of the residents perceived that they lack regular sources of
                                         living  in  the  barangay  because  most  (48.15%)  of  them  lack  the
                                         educational  requirements  and  some  (38.99%)  lack  the  technical
                                         skills to either start a small business or to apply for a regular job;
                                     •  47.06% of the residents believed that these problems and issues may
                                         be  addressed  through  conduct  of  free  seminars/trainings  on
                                         livelihood programs;

                                     •  47.06% of the residents believed that these problems and issues may
                                         be  addressed  through  conduct  of  free  seminars/trainings  on
                                         livelihood programs;

                                     •  47.06% of the residents believed that these problems and issues may
                                         be  addressed  through  conduct  of  free  seminars/trainings  on
                                         livelihood programs;

                          B.  Preparation of Committee

                                     The  proposal  to  conduct  extension  programs  in  the  community  was
                              based upon the respondent’s needs and interests that are consistent with the
                              goals of the campus and that have been identified through surveys.
                                     Some programs relative to the needs and interests of the residents were
                              not  considered  due  to  insufficiencies  on  facilities  and  absence  of  qualified
                              faculty members to handle such programs. This includes recycling of plastic
                              products, water lily bags, and perfume-making which may require raw materials
                              that are unavailable from the community.
                                     While having consultative meetings with the local government of the
                              concerned  barangay,  some  requests  to  the  university  were  raised.  First,  the
                              campus  will  have  to  offer  a  computer  literacy  program  for  their  barangay
                              officials and 4P’s members. This program aims to extend computer literacy to
                              the Brgy. Officials and selected 4P’s members, who, based on observation, lack
                              sufficient skills in computer manipulation and processes. The LGU believes that
                              technical  skills  must  be  manifested  by  their  officials  to  better  serve  their
                              constituents  and  for  those  4P’s  members  for  employment  and  business
                              opportunities.

                                     Also,  the  LGU  requested  that  the  proponents  offer  literacy  skills
                              development among their children. According to them, a number of children
                              were not enrolled in a formal school and parents of these children affirm that
                              they could not send them to formal school due to lack of financial resources,
                              that although education is free in public schools, they could not provide the
                              requirements that their children must submit.

                                     Another  request  from  the  LGU  is  that  the  proponent  should  give
                              awareness campaigns on different health issues. According to them, the increase
                              in the rate of patients with dengue and AIDS/HIV in the province had been
                              alarming them and the residents. And because the proponent is a GAD advocate,
                              GAD-related issues and concerns were included in this awareness campaign,
                              such as Anti-Violence against Women and their Children (anti-VAWC), sexual
                              harassment among others.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[C.  Meeting of the Committee
                                     A meeting of the campus Committee on Curriculum and Instruction
                              was conducted on April 10, 2015 to deliberate on the proposed extension
                              programs in the campus.
                                     The following is the decision of the members of the committee:

                                            Total Number of Committee Members          :       15

                                            Total Number of Committee Members
                                            who were present                           :       15

                                            Total Number of Committee Members
                                            who were absent                            :       0

                                            Number of Members in favor
                                                   of the proposal                     :       15

                                            Number of Members not in favor
                                                   of the proposal                     :       0

                                     With  this  result,  the  following  resolutions  were  passed  by  the
                              Committee:

                              Resolution No. 3, s. 2015

                                     “Approving  the  extension  project  proposal  to  alleviate  poverty  in
                              Barangay Bagtas with the following components: (1) Oplan Karunungan; (2)
                              Computer Literacy for Brgy. Officials; (3) Livelihood Programs for the citizens
                              of Brgy. Bagtas; and (4) Health and Wellness; subject to the endorsement of the
                              University  Administrative  Council  and  approval  of  the  University  Board  of
                              Regents.”

                              Resolution No. 4, s. 2015

                                     “Approving the name of the extension project proposal to be BAGTAS
                              with  CvSU-Tanza  (Bagtas  ay  Aasenso  at  Giginhawa  kung  Tayo  Ay

                              Sama-sama with CvSU – Tanza) subject to the endorsement of the University
                              Administrative Council and approval of the University Board of Regents.”


                          D.  Memorandum of Agreement



                                     A Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) will be drafted and signed by
                              different stakeholders involved in the conduct of such extension programs.
                              Stakeholders such as Local Government Unit of the municipality of Tanza,

                              Cavite; Provincial Cooperative, Livelihood, and Entrepreneurial Development
                              Office  (PCLEDO);  Farmers  Training  Center  (FITS);  Companies  in  Export
                              Processing Zone Authority (EPZA); and others.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[E.  Actual Implementation
                                    All the extension programs under this project will be spearheaded by the
                              campus dean and will be facilitated by faculty members and students in their
                              respective area of specialization. Since this is an extension project, voluntary
                              participation among faculty and students will be encouraged. Additional funds
                              for  the  project  proposal  will  be  sought  through  donations  from  the  Local
                              Government Unit of Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite and other concerned citizens
                              and government and non-government agencies, such as but are not limited to,
                              Provincial Cooperative, Livelihood, and Entrepreneurial Development Office
                              (PCLEDO); Farmers Training Center (FITS); Companies in Export Processing
                              Zone Authority (EPZA); and others.

                             Program 1: Oplan Karunungan

                              1.  All  BSE  students  and  faculty  members  under  the  Teacher  Education
                                 Department are enjoined to take part in this program.
                              2.  The program will be done during Fridays and Saturdays, 7:30 a.m. to 9:30
                                 a.m.at Rm. 102 of the Cavite State University – Tanza Campus.
                              3.  The BSE students and faculty members will have their own schedule on
                                 when to share their knowledge and teaching skills among the out-of-school
                                 youths.
                              4.  For security purposes, each participant will wear name tags during each
                                 session to recognize them as part of the program.
                              5.  On  the  first  day  of  the  session,  each  participant  will  undergo  a  pre-
                                 assessment to determine their basic literacy and numeracy skills.
                              6.  The  officers  will  coordinate  with  the  Barangay  Captain  to  recommend
                                 and/or suggest viable participants of this program.
                              7.  For the first year of implementation, at least 10 out-of-school youths will be
                                 the target participants.
                              8.  Assigned members will see to it that cleanliness and orderliness of the said
                                 classroom will be maintained during the session.
                              9.  The  teachers  and  student-teachers  will  select  three  best  students  to  be
                                 awarded during the Recognition Program.
                              10. Every participant will be awarded a Certificate of Completion upon finishing
                                 the program.
                              11. After  the  program,  each  participant  will  undergo  a  post-assessment  to
                                 determine the effect of the intervention that was conducted.
                              12. Students who have finished the program will be encouraged and supported
                                 to enroll in a formal elementary school.

                              Program 2: Computer Literacy Program
                              1.  All  BSIT  students  and  faculty  members  under  the  Department  of
                                 Information Technology are enjoined to take part in this program.
                              2.  The program will be done during Fridays and Saturdays, 8:30 a.m. to 10:30
                                 a.m. at the Computer Laboratory of the Cavite State University  – Tanza
                                 Campus.
                              3.  The BSIT students and faculty members will have their own schedule on
                                 when  to  share  their  knowledge  and  teaching  skills  among  the  barangay
                                 officials.
                              4.  For security purposes, each participant will wear name tags during each]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[session to recognize them as part of the program.
                              5.  The  officers  will  coordinate  with  the  Barangay  Captain  to  recommend
                                 and/or suggest viable participants of this program.
                              6.  For the first year of implementation, at least 10 selected barangay officials
                                 and  4P’s  members  will  be  taught  basic  computer  skills  during  the  time
                                 allotted.
                              7.  Assigned members will see to it that cleanliness and orderliness of the said
                                 classroom will be maintained during the session.
                              8.  The teachers and student-teachers will select three best participants to be
                                 awarded during the Recognition Program.
                              9.  Every participant will be awarded a Certificate of Completion upon finishing
                                 the program.
                              10. As part of the monitoring and evaluation of the program, each participant
                                 will undergo a pre- and post-test to determine whether they have achieved
                                 the basic skills that are expected of them.

                              Program 3: Computer Literacy Program
                              1.  All  BSBM  and  BSHRM  students  and  faculty  members  under  the
                                 Department of Management are enjoined to take part in this program and
                                 will be the facilitators and overall in-charge.
                              2.  The program will be done during Fridays and Saturdays, 7:30 a.m. to 9:30
                                 a.m. at Function Hall of the Cavite State University – Tanza Campus.
                              3.  The  officers  will  coordinate  with  the  Barangay  Captain  to  recommend
                                 and/or suggest viable participants of this program.
                              4.  Assistance  from  the  Provincial  Cooperative,  Livelihood,  and
                                 Entrepreneurial Development Office (PCLEDO) will be sought in terms of
                                 training of participants.
                              5.  At least 20 housewives will be invited to take part in each session
                              6.  All participants must be residents of Brgy. Bagtas as certified and referred
                                 to by the LGU officials.
                              7.  Participants  with  outstanding  performance  in  selected  activities  will  be
                                 rewarded accordingly. They will be given a small amount of money to start
                                 their own business.
                              8.  Every participant will be awarded a Certificate of Completion upon finishing
                                 the program.
                              9.  As part of the monitoring and evaluation of the program, each participant
                                 will undergo a pre- and post-test to determine whether they have achieved
                                 the basic skills that are expected of them.

                              Program 4: Health and Wellness
                              1.  All students and members of the Sports Club of the campus, and faculty
                                 members are enjoined to take part in this program.
                              2.  The  Aerobics/Zumba  session  will  be  done  every  Wednesday,  starting
                                 January to March 2016 thru the initiative of a competitive professional dance
                                 instructor. Summer Sports Clinic and Sports fest with the community will
                                 be held every weekend starting March to June 2016. Continuous awareness
                                 drive  on  health  issues  will  be  held  every  Friday  and  Saturday,  starting
                                 January to March 2016. Awareness drive on GAD-related concerns will be
                                 held every Wednesday, starting January to March 2016.
                              3.  The  officers  will  coordinate  with  the  Barangay  Captain  to  recommend
                                 and/or  suggest  viable  participants  of  this  program.  Also,  they  will  be]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[requested to lend a venue for the program.
                              4.  At least 20 housewives will be invited to take part in the aerobics/Zumba
                                 session. Outof-school youths will be the target participants in the summer
                                 sports clinic and sports fest with the community. At least 30 residents will
                                 be the target participants in the awareness drive on health and GAD-related
                                 issues.
                              5.  All participants must be residents of Brgy. Bagtas as certified and referred
                                 to by the LGU officials.
                              6.  Participants  with  outstanding  performance  in  selected  activities  will  be
                                 rewarded accordingly, especially  those who  excelled  in  sports and  other
                                 recreational activities.
                              7.  Every participant will be awarded Certificate of Completion upon finishing
                                 the program.
                              8.  As part of the monitoring and evaluation of the program, each participant
                                 will undergo a pre- and post-test to determine whether they have achieved
                                 the basic skills that are expected of them.

                          F.  Monitoring and Evaluation
                                     Each program will undergo three evaluations: before, during, and after
                              conduct of each evaluation. On the first week of each session, each participant
                              will undergo a pre-assessment to determine their current status in the program
                              they were registered to. Evaluation during the conduct of the program will also
                              be done in order to identify problems arising and to immediately resolve these
                              problems.  Post-assessment  will  be  done  in  order  to  determine  if  they  have
                              achieved the basic skills that are expected of them. This will also determine
                              whether the program is successful and has delivered significant impact to the
                              community.

                   IV.    Budgetary Allocation (5 years)


                                        PARTICULARS/PROGRAM                                AMOUNT (PhP)

                         Program 1: Oplan Karunungan                                           60,000.00

                         Program 2: Computer Literacy Program                                  45,000.00


                         Program 3: Livelihood Programs for Non-Working                       300,000.00
                         Members of the Community

                         Program 4: Health and Wellness                                       205,000.00


                                                    TOTAL                                     610,000.00


                   V.     Source Fund

                               The  main  source  of  funds  for  the  project  will  be  the  campus  budget  for

                          extension. The project proponent will solicit additional funding from the Local
                          Government Unit of Tanza and other partner NGO’s and GO’s such as, but not
                          limited to, Provincial Cooperative, Livelihood, and Entrepreneurial Development]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Office (PCLEDO); Farmers Training Center (FITS); and Companies in Export
                          Processing Zone Authority (EPZA).]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                         CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                   Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                  ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES

                               RESULTS OF COMMUNITY NEEDS ASSESSMENT IN
                                      BARANGAY BAGTAS, TANZA, CAVITE

                       The population explosion in Brgy. Bagtas has led to an initiative to alleviate

               poverty  In  the  barangay.  Brgy.  Bagtas,  having  the  most  number  of  populations  in
               Tanza  (20,370  out  of  188,755),  has  been  the  site  for  relocation  and  reclamation.

               However, people, who were displaced out of their previous addresses, were relocated

               in the said barangay without having a regular source of living. Some of them could not
               find a decent job because they lack the educational and other requirements for the job

               that they were applying for. Others could not start any business because they lack the
               skills in preparing innovative products that could help them earn additional income for

               their families.


                       Thus,  Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus  shall  launch  a  full  blown

               extension program through the Research and Extension Office. The campus extension
               program  shall  be  called  as  “BAGTAS  with  CvSU  –  Tanza  (Bagtas  ay  Aasenso  at

               Giginhawa kung Tayo Ay Sama-sama with CvSU – Tanza)". The main goal of the
               program is to increase the quality of life of the citizens in the said barangay.



                       For  this  reason,  it  is  essential  to  conduct  a  Community  Needs  Assessment
               (CNA) aiming to identify the needs in order to provide appropriate services to those

               needs.  CNA  will  provide  database  information  on  the  current  status  of  each
               community.  The  study  will  also  be  able  to  provide  a  framework  for  identifying

               appropriate community, profiling of their needs, and provide a sustainable extension
               program to meet specific needs.


                       Cavite State University – Tanza Campus is located in Tanza, Cavite so, the

               extension  unit  has  chosen  one  of  the  barangays  in  Tanza  to  be  adopted  for  its

               extension activities. It adopted barangay Bagtas since this is the barangay that has
               the most number of populations in the Municipality of Tanza.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Results and Quantitative Summary of Community Needs Assessment

                       A committee was formed to study and gather benchmark information on the
               status, needs, and conditions of selected communities in Tanza, Cavite during the

               second  semester,  AY  2014  –  2015.  The  committee  was  headed  by  the  Extension
               Coordinator. Two faculty members from the different departments of the campus were

               selected as members of the committee to ensure that the programs will conform to the

               mandate of the university. The committee used the following benchmark information,
               provided by Tanza Municipal Planning and Development Office (TMPDO), in order to

               assess which group of individuals will be the target beneficiaries of the proposal.


               Table 1. Data of Brgy. Bagtas population 2010 by sex, age, and employment

                                                 Male               Female                  Total
                 Brgy. Bagtas                   12,316               8,054                 20,370
                 Population
                 Age Bracket
                           5-9                  1,453                 951                  2,404
                          10-14                 1,299                 849                  2,148
                        OTHERS                  9,564                6,254                 15,818
                 Enrolment Data
                    Pre-School (3-6)            1,213                 878                  2,091
                   Elementary (7-12)            1,176                 823                  1,999
                 Employment Data
                        Employed                6,908                4,517                 11,425
                      Unemployed                 600                  393                   993
                 Not in the labor force         4,808                3,144                 7,952
               Source: Philippine Statistics Authority and Tanza Municipal Planning and Development Office

                       The committee used the descriptive design of a study. Data utilized in the study
               mainly came from the responses on the self-administered survey questions that were

               distributed to the residents of Brgy. Bagtas. Residents were selected using simple
               random sampling.

                       Results revealed that:
                          •  87.14% of the residents perceived that they lack regular sources of living
                              in the barangay because most (48.15%) of them lack the educational
                              requirements and some (38.99%) lack the technical skills to either start
                              a small business or to apply for a regular job;


                          •  47.06% of the residents believed that these problems and issues may
                              be addressed through conduct of free seminars/trainings on livelihood
                              programs;]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[•  18.33% of the residents suggested to conduct free seminar on candle
                              making; 17.33% suggested soap making; 15.33% suggested delicacy
                              preparation such as yema, ube, leche flan, puto, and others; 13.67%
                              suggested dishwashing liquid making; 13.00% suggested recycling of
                              plastic  products  and  water  lily  bags;  while  the  remaining  8.67%
                              suggested perfume-making;

                          •  46.50% of the residents said that they have baking and cooking skills
                              and they are willing to undergo trainings for delicacy preparation; also
                              22.50% reiterated that they have the skills in the arts and trades and that
                              they  are  willing  to  undergo  trainings  on  preparation  of  innovative
                              products such as candle, soap, and dishwashing liquid;


               Table 1. Main Source of Income
                Main Source of Income                       FREQUENCY                  PERCENT
                   Employment in government or                   123                     87.86
                            private sector
                               Farming                             6                      4.29
                Self-Employment/Entrepreneurship                   8                      5.71
                    Overseas Contract Workers                      3                      2.14



               Table 2. Monthly Family Income
                Monthly Family Income (Php)                FREQUENCY                  PERCENT
                           5000 & below                         101                      72.14
                           5001 – 10,000                         32                      22.86
                          10,001 – 15,000                         7                        5


               Table 3. Most Common Type/Kind of Dwelling Units
                   Most Common Type/Kind of                FREQUENCY                  PERCENT
                          Dwelling units
                              Concrete                            5                       3.57
                        Nipa/bamboo/wood                          2                       1.43
                             Row house                          133                        95


               Table 4. Most common source of drinking water
                      Most Common Source                   FREQUENCY                  PERCENT
                         of Drinking Water
                       Artesian wells (poso)                      7                        5
                        Water works system                      131                      93.57
                         Deep wells (balon)                       2                       1.43]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Table 5. Presence of school in the barangay
                             SCHOOL                       GOVERNMENT                   PRIVATE
                             Day Care                             5                        5
                             Pre-school                           1                        5
                            Elementary                            1                        5
                            High School                           1                        5
                              College                             1


               Table 6. Health facilities
                          HEALTH FACILITIES                                 FREQUENCY
                Government
                     Barangay Health Station                                   1
                      Health/Nutrition Center                                  0
                    Community Hospital Clinic                                  0
                              Private
                           Dental Clinic                                       0
                         Medical Hospital                                      0
                              Hospital                                         0


               Table 7. Most Common Transport Facilities
                           TRANSPORTATION                                   FREQUENCY
                                Jeep                                         140
                              Tricycle                                       140


               Table 8. Predominant Religion
                             RELIGION                      FREQUENCY                PERCENTAGE
                          Roman Catholic                         68                      48.57
                             Born Again                          17                      12.14
                                INC                              30                      21.43
                         Jehovah’s Witness                        4                       2.86
                               Aglipay                            6                       4.29
                               UCCP                               8                       5.71
                                Islam                             3                       2.14
                  Church of the Latter-Day Saints                 4                       2.86


               Table 9. Problems/issues encountered on living in barangay
                 PROBLEMS/ISSUES ENCOUNTERED                                FREQUENCY
                        Peace and Security                                     2
                           Overcrowding                                       12
                Lack of Regular Sources of Living                             122
                         Lack of Education                                    68
                      Lack of Technical Skills                                54
                      Lack of Job Experience                                  14
                           Health Issues                                      22
                              Abuses                                          13]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Table 10. Suggested ways to address problem
                SUGGESTED WAYS TO ADDRESS PROBLEMS                               FREQUENCY
                    Free tutorials on computer literacy                           31
                   Free seminars/trainings on livelihood                          66
                           Non-formal education                                   54

               Table 11. Suggested livelihood program
                 PROBLEMS/ISSUES ENCOUNTERED                                  FREQUENCY
                             Water Lily Bags                                      18
                                 Perfume                                          12
                              Candle Making                                       25
                               Soap Making                                        24
                        Recycling Plastic Products                                18
                 Dishwashing Liquid/Fabric Conditioner                            19
                           Delicacy preparation                                   22
                           Baking and Pastries                                    10
                             Eco-bag making                                       8
                           Flower Arrangement                                     8
                Meat/Food Processing and Preservation                             15


               Table 12. Skills
                                       SKILLS                                    FREQUENCY
                                 Computer                                          5
                                  Sewing                                           9
                              Arts and Crafts                                     23
                                   Baking                                         47
                                  Cooking                                         47



               Problems to be addressed:
                   1.  Seminars/trainings on livelihood education/program

                   2.  Non-formal education and remedial classes
                   3.  Tutorials/trainings on computer literacy

                   4.  Health and wellness



               Prepared by:


               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
               Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[PHOTO DOCUMENTATION OF THE COMMUNITY NEEDS ASSESSMENT IN

                                      BARANGAY BAGTAS, TANZA, CAVITE]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Processing
                                      December 11, 2020 and September 14, 2020]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Ms.  Jenelyn  N.  Relado  while  demonstrating  the


                                         procedures on how to make gourmet Tinapa with Mr.

                                         Ritch  M.  Banate,  Extension  Coordinator  of  Tanza
                                         Campus












                                        Ms.  Rina  D.  Compuesto  while  demonstrating  the

                                        procedures on how      to make gourmet Tinapa with Mr.
                                        Ritch  M.  Banate,     Extension  Coordinator  of  Tanza
                                        Campus












                                             Mr. Ritch M. Ban  ate together with Ms. Rina D.

                                          Compuesto (left) and Ms. Jenelyn N. Relado (Right)
                                          while giving tips on   how to have a lucrative gourmet
                                                               business]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[TRAINING ON Food Preservation And Gourmet Products
                                                    November 9, 2019



































































                                     Ms. Rina D. Compuesto during her lectures on how to

                                     cook Gourmet Tinapang Galunggong and Bangus and

                                                      Gourmet Bagoong]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Faculty members and trainees during the awarding of certificates



































                               Faculty members and students during the awarding of certificates]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Training On Embutido Making
                                                   September 6, 2019





















                                          Mr. Sibulo, faculty member, and participants during the
                                                                opening prayer























                                         Mr. Banate, extension coordinator, during his talk about the

                                                     extension programs of the campus]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[The trainees while attentively listening to the instruction of Ms. Elamparo on how to make Embutido]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Faculty members, students and trainees during the awarding

                                                            of certificates]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[TRAINING ON DISHWASHING LIQUID
                                     (Extension Activity at Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite)
                                                    August 30, 2019








































                                         The trainer and trainees while making dishwashing liquid]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[The trainer and trainees while making dishwashing liquid]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[The trainer, faculty members and trainees during the
                                                      awarding of certificates]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Training On Dishwashing Liquid Making
                                                    August 23, 2019

















































                                         The trainer and trainees while making dishwashing liquid]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[The trainer, faculty members and trainees during the awarding of

                                                                certificates]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Training On Dishwashing Liquid and Fabric Conditioner Making
                                                  March 8 and 15, 2019





































                                                   The trainer and the participants during the

                                                                demonstrations]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[The trainer and the participants who were proudly
                                                 holding their own-made dishwashing liquid]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Dishwashing liquid and fabric conditioner made by the
                                                  participants during the training]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Training On Skinless Longganisa Making
                                                   December 1, 2018























                                        The trainer demonstrates the procedures on how to make
                                                          skinless longganisa.






















                                              The trainees while actively listening during the

                                                       demonstration of the trainer]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Food Processing and Siomai Making
                                                   November 10, 2018





















                                          The trainer shows the ingredients and demonstrates
                                                          how to make siomai




















                                           Trainees eagerly participate in wrapping their own

                                                Siomai pieces while being supervised by

                                                        Mary Rose E. Elamparo.]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[The trainees were actively listening to the trainer.

















                                                   Puto Flan Making
                                                    November 2017






                                            The trainees while making their own siomai]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[dd














































                         The trainer while demonstrating the procedures on how to make puto flan]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[How To Start A Business
                                                    October 13, 2017





























                                               The participants during the seminar/workshop
























                                                Mr. Ritch M. Banate during his talk about the

                                              opportunities and challenges of doing business]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[-






























                                            Ms. Melona O. Igmasine during her talk about the

                                                requirements needed to put up a business
































                                          Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag during her talk about online

                                                                business]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[The participants and faculty members during the awarding of certificates






               Prepared by:


               RITCH M. BANATE
               Extension Coordinator]]></page></pages></Search>