<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="22"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.4.            There is a system to ensure that all of


                        the following are provided:


                        S.4.2.  Waste management program;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[The signage of NO Plastic and No Garbage allowed Policy]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[The Utility personnel maintains the cleanliness and orderliness of the campus.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                            Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                       Indang, Cavite
                                          (046) 4150-010 / (046) 4150-013 loc 206
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                     UNIVERSITY POLLUTION CONTROL OFFICE


               OFFICE MEMORANDUM
               No. 3 s. 2021



               TO             :      ALL UNITS, COLLEGES, and OFFICES


               FROM           :      JUNSER P. MAGPANTAY
                                     UNIVERSITY POLLUTION CONTROL OFFICER



               NOTED          :      CAMILO A. POLINGA
                                     Vice President for Administrative and Support Services


               SUBJECT        :      HAZARDOUS WASTES GENERATION REPORTING AND
                                     DESIGNATION OF POLLUTION CONTROL COORDINATORS


               DATE           :      June 07, 2021



               Please be informed that the University Pollution Control Office is conducting quarterly monitoring
               of the University’s hazardous wastes that is reported to DENR-EMB IVA Regional Office. This
               monitoring includes all types of hazardous wastes specified under DAO No. 2013-22 (please see
               attached file).

                       In conducting the inventory, please take note of the following:

                   1.  All hazardous wastes from different  colleges/units/offices should be properly classified
                       according to type.

                   2.  All solid hazardous wastes must be in kilograms kg for solid wastes, and in Liters (L) for
                       liquid wastes. No hazardous wastes shall be reported per piece.

                   3.  All empty ink bottles/ink cartridges, batteries should not be disposed together with the
                       waste delivered at the MRF for these are considered as hazardous wastes.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[4.  For electrical wastes that are hazardous, all must be categorized and weigh according to
                       its type. If wastes will be condemned to Supply Office, the inventory will be conducted by
                       the last office that will be handling the wastes.

                   5.  All colleges/units/ offices must designate their temporary hazardous wastes storage. Each
                       waste much be properly labeled using the prescribed yellow sticker.

                   6.  Each college/unit/office shall recommend to the University PCO their respective identified
                       Pollution Control Coordinator (PCC) where the responsibilities are as follows:

                       i.  The designated PCC will be in-charge in submitting a quarterly report on the inventory
                         of hazardous wastes generated by their respective college/unit/office to the University
                         PCO.

                      ii.  Attend  meeting/seminar/training/workshop  regarding  the  National,  Provincial,
                         Municipal,  and  University’s  environmental  policies  and  relay  it  to  their  respective
                         college/unit/office.

                      iii.  Monitor solid waste management within their respective college/unit/office.

                      iv.  Report environmental incidents to University PCO.

                   7.  For the college/unit/office who has hazardous wastes generation for this quarter, kindly
                       send  your  inventory  on  or  before  June  15,  2021  to  PCO  email  address  or  visit  our
                       temporary office located in Room 301 Agricultural Science Building, CAFENR.

                   8.  For strict compliance.

                   9.  Thank you for your cooperation.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>