<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="12"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.6.            The system of student evaluation and


                        grading is defined, understood and


                        disseminated to:

                        I.6.3.  academic administrators; and]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                                 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                        TEACHER EDUCATION DEPARTMENT


                    MINUTES OF MEETING HELD ON SEPTEMBER 26, 2022 VIA ZOOM MEETING


                                                                          .

               Call to order: The second meeting for the first semester of A.Y. 2022-2023 of the Teacher

               Education Department was called to order via Zoom Meeting application
               Agenda
                   •     School Calendar
                   •      Activities for students and faculty
                   •      Submission of Teaching Portfolio including requirements for submission
                   •      Accreditation task force
                   •      Research proposals

                   •      Extension activities
                   •      Other matters (IMs, regular meeting)


               Attendees

                   1.  Addangna, Teresa O.
                   2.  Ampon, Mary Dean
                   3.  Blanco, Sarah May
                   4.  Banate, Sharmaine M.
                   5.  Banate, Sheena M.
                   6.  Bonifacio, Janine B.
                   7.  Delgado, Jolai
                   8.  Gote, Fahad T.
                   9.  Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.
                   10. Mojica, Ivory P.
                   11. Monterey, Quincy Mae
                   12. Ortigosa, Rein R.
                   13. Peñaflorida Jr., Efren G.
                   14. Reyes, Woodelyn P.
                   15. Saguid, Jonane S.
                   16. Silverio, Gerry Mae T.
                   17. Tagle, Maria Christina C.
                   18. Tangalin, Marlou M.
                   19. Villa, Estelita]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Meeting Notes

                   •  The school calendar for the school year 2022-2023 is being discussed:

                   •  The first day of classes is September 12, 2022.
                   •  The deadline for adding or changing subjects is September 30th.

                   •  The deadline for dropping subjects without an evaluation is October 7, 2022.
                   •  The  copies of  the  students'  registration  certificates  (COR)  must  be  checked  by all
                       instructors  for  each  course  because  there  are  students  who  are  not  formally

                       registered but are nevertheless attending classes.
                   •  Do not accept a student in your class if he or she does not have a copy of his or her

                       COR.
                   •  There is no need for a preliminary examination. It is up to the course instructor.
                   •  There will be a midterm exam. It is conducted either in person or online. It is entirely

                       up to the course instructor. However, make sure that a face-to-face midterm exam is
                       scheduled ahead of time.

                   •  The academic break is set to take place from November 14 to November 19, 2022.
                       Make certain that no assessments are given to students during the academic break
                       so that they can enjoy their time off.

                   •  The  final  examination  for  graduating  students  is  scheduled  from  January  16  to
                       January  21,  2023,  while  the  final  examination  for  non-graduating  students  is

                       scheduled from January 23 to January 28, 2023. It is conducted either in person or
                       online. It is entirely up to the course instructor. However, make sure that a face-to-
                       face midterm exam is scheduled ahead of time.

                   •  If  the  course  instructor's  final  examination  is  about  culminating  activities  such  as
                       demonstration teaching, it must be conducted face-to-face. However, make certain

                       that it is approved and scheduled ahead of time.
                   •  The deadline for submitting and uploading grades is February 7, 2023.

                   •  A  second  agenda  is  being  discussed.  It's  about  a  Teacher  Education  Department
                       activity  proposal.  In  addition,  ma'am  Jerry  Mae  and  ma'am  Woodelyn  have  been
                       assigned to an Educ Congress activity, while Sir Marlou has been assigned to the

                       Faculty Research Forum.
                   •  Each instructor is required to review their online portfolio. They must ensure that it is

                       finished. These are the lists that will be submitted at the conclusion of the semester:
                       class records, quizzes, activities, sample student outputs, projects, modules, syllabi,
                       midterm exam, and final exam, TOS, and sample grading sheet.

                   •  Each instructor must submit a letter of intent along with their completed portfolio as
                       part of their requirements if they want to continue serving at CvSU-Tanza.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[•  Each  instructor must  have  a  non-disclosure agreement and a syllabus  acceptance

                       form to make sure that the students are well informed.
                   •  The students must be informed that they are not allowed to share any materials from
                       outside organizations.

                   •  As soon as feasible, the Teacher Education Department should start planning for the
                       upcoming accreditation in November 14 to November 18 2022.

                   •  The online class observation for accreditation will take place from November 14 to
                       November  18.  In  addition,  ma'am  Jolai  for  English  and  ma'am  Gerry  Mae  for

                       Mathematics subjects have been assigned to be observed.
                   •  The  fifth  agenda  focuses  on  research  activity.  The  Teacher  Education  faculty  is

                       strongly encouraged to take part in conducting and publishing their research.

                   •  The  proposed  activities  for  extension  activities  are  personality  development  and
                       UPLIFT Tanzaños.

                   •  As part of a sustainable development plan (Extension Activity), the teacher education
                       program intends to create an assessment instrument. The following instructors have
                       been  assigned  to  create  an  assessment  instrument  for  reading,  writing,  and

                       numeracy literacy:
                              •  Reading

                                     ▪  Ma’am Jolai Delgado
                                     ▪  Ma’am Janine Bonifacio
                                     ▪  Ma’am Sheena Banate

                                     ▪  Ma’am Sharmaine Banate
                              •  Writing
                                     ▪  Ma’am Jonane Saguid

                                     ▪  Sir Fahad T. Gote
                                     ▪  Ma’am Quincy Monterey

                              •  Numeracy
                                     ▪  Sir. Efren Peñaflorida Jr
                                     ▪  Sir Marlou Tangalin

                                     ▪  Ma’am Ma. Woodelyn Reyes
                                     ▪  Ma’am Maria Cristina Tagle

                   •  Ma'am  Sheena  and  ma'am  Woodelyn  were  assigned  to  do  and  manage  the  TED
                       Department Extension's Facebook page.
                   •  The  following  have  been  assigned  to  the  collaborative  project  of  copyrighted

                       instructional  materials  (module):  Ma’am  Jonane  (BEE  21),  Sir  Ef  and  Ma’am
                       Sharmaine (EDUC 55), Prof. Mildred]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[•  The RWL and NL meetings have been set for October 7, 2022, at 10 a.m.

                   •  Every last Friday of the month, the teacher education department holds its monthly
                       regular meeting.
                   •  The deadline for final syllabus submission is set for October 14, 2022.

                   •  The academic break is set to take place from November 14 to November 19, 2022.
                       Make certain that no assessments are given to students during the academic break

                       so that they can enjoy their time off.
                   •  The  final  examination  for  graduating  students  is  scheduled  from  January  16  to
                       January  21,  2023,  while  the  final  examination  for  non-graduating  students  is

                       scheduled from January 23 to January 28, 2023. It is conducted either in person or
                       online. It is entirely up to the course instructor. However, make sure that a face-to-

                       face midterm exam is scheduled ahead of time.
                   •  If  the  course  instructor's  final  examination  is  about  culminating  activities  such  as
                       demonstration teaching, it must be conducted face-to-face. However, make certain

                       that it is approved and scheduled ahead of time.


               Photo Documentation

































                           Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, department chair, discussing the calendar
                                              of activities for A.Y. 2022-2023]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Ms. Estelita Villa, Extension Services Coordinator,
                                        presenting the UPLIFT Tanzeños proposal

































                                Teacher Education Faculty Department Photo Opportunity



               Prepared by:                                              Noted:



               Sharmaine M. Banate                                       Mildred A. Sebastian
               Department Secretary, TED                                 Department Chair, TED]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                                 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                        TEACHER EDUCATION DEPARTMENT

                    MINUTES OF MEETING HELD ON SEPTEMBER 09, 2022 VIA WEBEX MEETING

                       The first meeting of the Teacher Education Department (TED) was made during the
               breakout session of the Faculty Orientation and Capability Enhancement Seminar Workshop
               on September 9, 2022, via Webex Meeting application led by Prof. Mildred A.  Sebastian,
               TED chairperson.


               Attendees

                   1.  Addangna, Teresa O.                      10. Mojica, Ivory P.
                   2.  Ampon, Mary Dean                         11. Monterey, Quincy Mae
                   3.  Blanco, Sarah May                        12. Ortigosa, Rein R.
                   4.  Banate, Sharmaine M.                     13. Peñaflorida Jr., Efren G.
                   5.  Banate, Sheena M.                        14. Reyes, Woodelyn P.
                   6.  Bonifacio, Janine B.                     15. Saguid, Jonane S.
                   7.  Delgado, Jolai                           16. Silverio, Gerry Mae T.
                   8.  Gote, Fahad T.                           17. Tagle, Maria Christina  C.
                   9.  Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.            18. Villa, Estelita A




               Meeting Notes

                   •  The copies of the students' registration certificates must be checked by all instructors
                       for each course because there are students who are not formally registered but are
                       nevertheless attending classes.
                   •  Instructors must remind their students about plagiarism (copy and paste) and help
                       educate them on how to avoid plagiarizing the intellectual property of other authors.
                   •  It is permissible to use any LMS to deliver teaching instruction.
                   •  The Faculty of Teacher Education agrees on the attendance policy.
                   •  To accommodate their students, the Teacher Education faculty agreed to 1.5 online
                       class  hours  per  week  (1.5  hours  for  synchronous  classes  and  1.5  hours  for
                       asynchronous classes).
                   •  As soon as feasible, the Teacher Education Department should start planning for the
                       upcoming accreditation in November 2022.
                   •  The online class observation for accreditation will take place from November 14 to
                       November 18. Instructors must prepare their teaching materials.
                   •  As  part  of  the  Teacher  Education  Department's  preparation  for  the  upcoming
                       accreditation,  all  instructors  are  encouraged  to  submit  the  chosen  output  of  their
                       students', a sample exam, a sample assessment using multiple intelligence, as well
                       as their updated syllabi, rubrics, and TOS.
                   •  Each instructor is required to review their online portfolio. They must ensure that it is
                       finished. These are the lists that will be submitted at the conclusion of the semester:]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[class records, quizzes, activities, sample student outputs, projects, modules, syllabi,
                       and so on.
                   •  The output of the students must reflect their multiple intelligences.
                   •  As  part  of  the  preparation  for  the  upcoming  accreditation,  the  assigned  faculty
                       member of the Teacher Education Department must accomplish the task assigned to
                       them. They are permitted to visit campus as long as the department chair requests
                       their assistance.
                   •  All  instructors  and  students  in  the  teacher  education  department  are  welcome  to
                       participate in a research study.
                   •  All instructors are greatly encouraged to engage in publishing their research studies,
                       especially those who are completing their masters or doctoral degrees in graduate
                       school studies for output and publication dissemination.
                   •  All Instructors in the teacher education department, as well as students, are welcome
                       to conduct or attend seminars/webinars.
                   •  As a key output, students are encouraged to engage in peer teaching, cooperative
                       learning,  group  projects  (feasibility  studies,  term  papers,  reaction  papers,  etc.),
                       performance tasks, role playing, and portfolio assessment.
                   •  As a student output, each instructor must encourage their students to participate in
                       reporting or microteaching.
                   •  Instructors must provide their instructional materials used to produce a module (or a
                       compiled copy of it)
                   •  The lists of key point instructors for making a collected copy of instructional materials
                       are as follows:
                          •  EDUC  55  (The  Teaching  Profession)  –  Mr.  Efren  Peñaflorida  Jr.  and  Ms.
                              Sharmaine Banate
                          •  Mathematics – Ms. Mary Joy Angelique Mojica and Ms. Gerry Mae  Silverio
                          •  English – Ms. Ivory Mojica
                   •  The  Teacher  Education  Department  collaborates  with  ALS  (Alternative  Learning
                       System)  in  its  extension  activities.  As  part  of the  extension  project  of the  Teacher
                       Education  Department,  they  planned  to  conduct  a  numeracy  and  literacy/reading
                       comprehension assessment (twice a week). Instructors as well as their students are
                       encouraged to make an assessment tool to help the beneficiaries.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Photo Documentation

































                         TED Faculty with other CvSU Tanza Faculty and Staff Photo Opportunity



































                         TED Faculty with other CvSU Tanza Faculty and Staff Photo Opportunity]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[TED Faculty with other CvSU Tanza Faculty and Staff Photo Opportunity











               Prepared by:




               Sharmaine M. Banate
               Department Secretary, TED






               Noted:


               Mildred A. Sebastian
               Department Chair, TED]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                                 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                        TEACHER EDUCATION DEPARTMENT

                     MINUTES OF MEETING HELD ON NOVEMBER 18, 2021 VIA GOOGLE MEET

               Call to order: The second meeting of Teacher Education was called to order by the
               department chair via Google Meet.

               Agenda

                   •  Faculty observation/evaluation

                   •  Faculty reports on students’ behaviors in online class, students’ attendance in
                       virtual discussion, and students’ status (Dropped Out, Transferred Out).
                   •  Announcement of Passing the BSE and BEE program in COPC


               Attendees

                          1.  Ampon, Mary Dean                         8.  Mojica, Ivory P.
                          2.  Banate, Sharmaine M.                     9.  Navida, Allan
                          3.  Bonifacio, Janine B.                     10. Ortigosa, Rein R.
                          4.  Borilla, Audreyson H.                    11. Peñaflorida, Efren G.
                          5.  Gote, Fahad T.                           12. Silverio, Gerry Mae T.
                          6.  Guban, Sarah Jane                        13. Tagle, Maria Christina C.
                          7.  Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.            14. Villa, Estelita A.


               Meeting Notes

                   •  Next week, from Tuesday to Friday every Department Chair will administer an online
                       class Observation/faculty evaluation.
                   •  Class  schedule  format  for  class  observation:  Date  and  Time,  Name,  Course  code
                       and Title, Program and Meeting link.
                   •  Passing of BSE and BEE program in COPC
                   •  Sharing  of  Teaching  Experiences:  students’  behaviors  in  online  class,  students’
                       attendance  in  virtual  discussion,  and  students’  status  (Dropped  Out,  Transferred
                       Out).]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Photo Documentation

































                                Teacher Education Faculty Department Photo Opportunity












               Prepared by:



               Sharmaine M. Banate
               Department Secretary, TED





               Noted:


               Mildred A. Sebastian
               Department Chair, TED]]></page></pages></Search>