<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="23"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.1.         The maximum total load of a regular full-


                    time faculty member is based on CMO

                    #30, s. 2004, CMO #52, s. 2007 and


                    institutional guidelines.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  54


                   Article  9.  Exchange  Professorship.  Exchange  arrangements  and
                       guidelines  and  consortia  may  be  made  with  a  school  of  recognized
                       standing,  both  in  the  country  and  overseas.  The  President  of  the
                       University  upon  approval  of  the  Board  of  Regents  may  allow  exchange
                       professorship with accredited schools of higher education for a period of
                       one year, renewable for another year. In addition to his regular salary, an
                       exchange professor assigned abroad or elsewhere may be given such

                       assistance that will enable him to maintain the dignity of his position in
                       his place of assignment.

                   Article 10.  Visiting Professorship. The President of the University, upon
                       approval by The Board of Regents, may appoint visiting professors who
                       shall serve in the University for some special purpose for a period of one
                       year  renewable  for  another  year.  The  University  President  may  also
                       appoint  visiting  professors  from  the  University  to  other  institutions  of
                       recognized  standing  by  special  arrangements  and  conditions  mutually
                       acceptable  to  both  institutions.  The  University  shall  make  adequate
                       provision  in  its  yearly  budget  to  ensure  the  implementation  of  this
                       program.

                   Article  11.  Professorial  Chair.  The  President  of  the  University  upon
                        approval  by  the  BOR  shall  award  Professorial  Chair  to  a  faculty
                        member  who  has  shown  exemplary  performance  in  his  field  of
                        specialization.  The  awardee  shall  be  required  to  conduct  professional
                        chair  lectures  within  the  duration  of  the  award.  The  University  shall
                        link with non-government organizations to support this program.

                   Article 12.  Specific  Policies  and  Guidelines  on  Faculty  Workload.  The
                       workload system shall be implemented by the University in line with the
                       guidelines  on  faculty  workload  policies  and  regulations  by  CHED.  The
                       current faculty workload system may be revised or totally replaced upon
                       approval of the Board.

                          The  workload  system  concerns  only  the  instruction  function  and
                       related activities of the academic teaching staff of Cavite State University.
                       This    was      finalized    on     14     July     2000      incorporating      the
                       comments/suggestions  of  the  University  Administrative  Council  during
                       its 03 July 2000 meeting. Amendments and revisions   were again made
                       in  December  2002  and  May  2007  for  the  following  purposes,  among
                       others: define credit units for other activities left to the discretion of the
                       College/Campus  Dean,  specify  the  mode  of  payment  for  overload
                       teaching and overtime teaching; and suggest  source  of  funds  for  such
                       payment.



                                                                                                           54]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  55


                       Section  1.  Coverage.  This  set  of  guidelines  covers  all  CvSU  faculty
                        members,  whether  permanent,  temporary,  or  contractual  teachers
                        reporting on full time.

                          a)      At the beginning of each school year, before the start of regular
                                 classes, the college/campus deans shall require the members of
                                 their  faculty  to  decide  whether  to  be  on  full-time  teaching,
                                 research or extension, provided that the needs of instruction are
                                 satisfied first and does not lead to extra hiring of personnel.

                                 It should be noted, however, that although faculty members are
                          classified  as  full-time  teachers,  they  are  still  required  to  conduct
                          either research or extension activities on top of their teaching loads.
                          The list of those on full-time teaching shall be submitted immediately
                          to the office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs (OVPAA) while
                          those on full-time research or extension shall be endorsed by OVPAA
                          to the Office of the Vice President for Research and Development.  For
                          efficient allocation of funds, tentative computation of faculty workload
                          for instruction shall be submitted to OVPAA one week, at the latest,
                          before the start of classes in each semester.

                          b)      Faculty  members  with  academic  ranks  who  opt  for  full–time
                                 research or extension shall be required to teach minimum of (9)
                                 contact hours per week.

                          c)      Credit  unit  load  of  faculty  members  on  full–time  research  or
                                 extension shall be covered by a separate research and extension
                                 workload system of the University.

                       Section 2.  Maximum Workload and Overload Compensation

                                 The maximum regular teaching load of an academic full – time
                          teaching  staff  without  administrative  and  supervisory  assignment  in
                          any given semester shall be 18 teaching hours (TCH) per week. (TCH)
                          and equivalent WL units shall be reduced to 18 and 25, respectively
                          effective First Semester, AY 2004 – 2005 depending on availability of
                          funds).  For  purposes  of  overload  pay,  this  is  equivalent  to  the
                          maximum of 25 instruction workload (WL) credit units

                                 a)       The regular workload of full–time teaching staff in a given
                                         semester  shall  include  only  those  related  to  instruction,
                                         administrative  assignments  and  other  services  duly
                                         supported  by  designations  issued  by  the  Office  of  the
                                         President of the University (OUP) as recommended by the
                                         vice president concerned.

                                                                                                           55]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  56


                                 b)      Faculty members who opt to be on full-time teaching but
                                         who   conduct  important  projects  under  the  priority
                                         commodity  thrusts  of  the  University  shall  earn  credit
                                         units  for  those  projects  based  on  the  guidelines  for
                                         research  and  extension  workload.  This  credit  unit
                                         shall be added to  instruction  workload  provided  that
                                         these credit units are not credited on full-time research.

                                 c)      The  final  report  on  faculty  workload,  including  the
                                         summary thereof, shall be submitted to the office of the
                                         Vice   President  for  Academic  Affairs  for  consolidation
                                         within the final examination period of every semester.

                                 d)      An academic staff who is unable to reach the maximum
                                         teaching  load  per  week  shall  be  required  to  teach  other
                                         courses  in  other  units  of  the  University  and/or  render
                                         other services deemed necessary as recommended by the
                                         Vice President for Academic Affairs and approved by the
                                         University President in order to reach the mandatory 40-
                                         hour  service  per  week  required  of  all  government
                                         personnel.    In  no  case,  however,  shall  the  conduct  of
                                         other services lead to hiring of additional part-time or full-
                                         time  faculty  member.  Hiring  will  only  be  done  when  all
                                         faculty  members  are  fully  loaded  at  18  TCH  each  per
                                         week.  Exemptions  to  the  required  18  TCH,  are  faculty
                                         members with management and supervisory designations
                                         specified.  The  assigning  of  such  other  services  shall  be
                                         endorsed  by  the  Vice  President  of  Academic  Affairs  for
                                         approval by the University President.

                                 e)      In case faculty members carrying the full load of 18 TCH
                                         are  given  extra  teaching  assignment  scheduled  outside
                                         the  official  time,  such  assignment  shall  be  covered  by  a
                                         job  order  in  order  for  the  faculty  member  to  receive
                                         equitable   remuneration.

                                 f)      The detailed guidelines for faculty workload system shall
                                         be  prepared,  reviewed  and  revised  periodically  by  the
                                         Academic  Council  taking  into  account the  policies  listed
                                         above.







                                                                                                           56]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                  CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                             Tanza Campus
                                                                      Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                          (046) 414-3979
                                                                         www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                               SUMMARY OF FACULTY TEACHING LOAD
                                                                 TEACHER EDUCATION DEPARTMENT
                                                                    First Semester, AY 2022-2023

                                                                                                                            TOTAL
                                                                     NATURE OF        TEACHING                                         NUMBER OF
                      NAME OF FACULTY          SPECIALIZATION                                     CONSULTATION HOURS      CONTACT
                                                                    APPOINTMENT        HOURS                                          PREPARATION
                                                                                                                           HOURS
                                                                                                  Monday 12:00 pm - 1:00 pm,
             1  TERESA O. ADDANGNA                 History         Contract of Service   21                                 23.00          2
                                                                                                 Tuesday 11:30 am - 12:30 pm
             2  MARY DEAN P. AMPON               Social Science    Contract of Service   24         Tuesday 1:00-3:00 pm    26.00          2
             3  AUDREYSON H. BORILLA           Language Education  Contract of Service   27         Monday 1:00-3:00 pm     29.00          4
             4  JHOLLIE ANNE D. LOPEZ          Language Education  Contract of Service   30         Saturday 3:00-5:00 pm   32.00          3

             5  NOEL B. MANARPIIS              Language Education     Permanent          12               None              12.00          2
             6  IVORY P. MOJICA                Language Education  Contract of Service   30         Monday 8:30-10:30 am    32.00          4
             7  MARY JOY ANGELIQUE R. MOJICA     Mathematics       Contract of Service   21         Monday 7:30-9:30 am     23.00          3
                                                                                                Wednesday and Thursday 10:00 am-
             8  JONANE SAGUID                 Elementary Education  Contract of Service  27                                 29.00          2
                                                                                                         11:00 am
             9  MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN             Mathematics          Permanent          19        Wednesday 1:00-3:00 pm   21.00          3
            10 GERRY MAE T. SILVERIO             Mathematics       Contract of Service   24         Monday 7:00-9:00 am     26.00          4
            11 MARIA CRISTINA C. TAGLE           Mathematics       Contract of Service   30       Thursday 10:00 am-12:00 nn  32.00        3

            12 MARLOU M. TANGALIN                Social Science    Contract of Service   18        Wednesday 6:00-8:00 pm   20.00          2
            13 ESTELITA A. VILLA                 Mathematics          Temporary          24       Thursday 10:00 am-12:00 nn  26.00        3

               Prepared by:                       Reviewed:                                    Certified True and Correct:

                                                        MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
               DEBBIE ROSE B. FABIAN              Chairperson, Teacher Education Department    GIL D. RAMOS
               HRDO Coordinator                                                                Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
       Tanza Campus
 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
  (046) 414-3979
 www.cvsu.edu.ph

 SUMMARY OF FACULTY TEACHING LOAD
 TEACHER EDUCATION DEPARTMENT
 First Semester, AY 2022-2023

                                       TOTAL
 NATURE OF   TEACHING                              NUMBER OF
 NAME OF FACULTY  SPECIALIZATION  CONSULTATION HOURS  CONTACT
 APPOINTMENT  HOURS                               PREPARATION
                                       HOURS
             Monday 12:00 pm - 1:00 pm,
 1  TERESA O. ADDANGNA  History  Contract of Service  21  23.00  2
             Tuesday 11:30 am - 12:30 pm
 2  MARY DEAN P. AMPON  Social Science  Contract of Service  24  Tuesday 1:00-3:00 pm  26.00  2
 3  AUDREYSON H. BORILLA  Language Education  Contract of Service  27  Monday 1:00-3:00 pm  29.00  4
 4  JHOLLIE ANNE D. LOPEZ  Language Education  Contract of Service  30  Saturday 3:00-5:00 pm  32.00  3

 5  NOEL B. MANARPIIS  Language Education  Permanent  12  None  12.00  2
 6  IVORY P. MOJICA  Language Education  Contract of Service  30  Monday 8:30-10:30 am  32.00  4
 7  MARY JOY ANGELIQUE R. MOJICA  Mathematics  Contract of Service  21  Monday 7:30-9:30 am  23.00  3
            Wednesday and Thursday 10:00 am-
 8  JONANE SAGUID  Elementary Education  Contract of Service  27  29.00  2
                    11:00 am
 9  MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN  Mathematics  Permanent  19  Wednesday 1:00-3:00 pm  21.00  3
 10 GERRY MAE T. SILVERIO  Mathematics  Contract of Service  24  Monday 7:00-9:00 am  26.00  4
 11 MARIA CRISTINA C. TAGLE   Mathematics  Contract of Service  30  Thursday 10:00 am-12:00 nn  32.00  3

 12 MARLOU M. TANGALIN  Social Science  Contract of Service  18  Wednesday 6:00-8:00 pm  20.00  2
 13 ESTELITA A. VILLA  Mathematics  Temporary  24  Thursday 10:00 am-12:00 nn  26.00  3

 Prepared by:  Reviewed:  Certified True and Correct:

 MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
 DEBBIE ROSE B. FABIAN  Chairperson, Teacher Education Department  GIL D. RAMOS
 HRDO Coordinator  Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[VPAA-QF-11
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                                   Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (  (046) 414-3979
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                       TANZA CAMPUS
                                                  Teacher Education Department
                                                  FACULTY CLASS SCHEDULE
                                                  First Semester A.Y. 2022-2023
                 Name:      MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                 Highest Educational Attainment:  Doctor of Philosophy in Mathematics Education (Completed Academic Requirements)
                 No. of Preparation(s):   3                 Total Number of Contact Hours per Week:   19


                          TIME          MONDAY     TUESDAY  WEDNESDAY   THURSDAY     FRIDAY   SATURDAY
                     7:00      7:30
                     7:30      8:00
                     8:00      8:30
                     8:30      9:00
                     9:00      9:30
                     9:30      10:00                                    BSEM 3-1 /
                    10:00      10:30              BSEM 4-1 /   BSEM 4 -1/   BSEM 28
                    10:30      11:00   BSEM 3-1 /   EDFS 23   EDFS 23
                    11:00      11:30    BSEM 28
                    11:30      12:00
                    12:00      12:30
                    12:30      1:00
                     1:00      1:30                                     BSEM 3-1 /
                     1:30      2:00                                      BSEM 32
                     2:00      2:30
                     2:30      3:00    BSEM 4-2 /   BSEM 4 -2/
                     3:00      3:30     EDFS 23    EDFS 23
                     3:30      4:00
                     4:00      4:30
                     4:30      5:00    BSEM 3-1 /
                     5:00      5:30     BSEM 32
                     5:30      6:00
                     6:00      6:30
                     6:30      7:00
                     7:00      7:30
                     7:30      8:00

                                      Course/ Year/    Contact Hours                            No. of
                         Subject                                           Total     Room
                                          Sec       Lecture  Laboratory                        Students
                    BSEM 28 - Calculus 2  BSEM3-1     4          0          4                     22
                  BSEM 32 - Number Theory  BSEM3-1    3          0          3                     22
                                        BSEM 4-1      6          0          6                     22
                  EDFS 23 - Teaching Internship
                                        BSEM 4-2      6          0          6                     22
                                                         SCHEDULE

                 Consultation:  W 1:00 pm - 3:00 pm                        Research: Learning Assessment in Flexible Learning Modality
                 Designation :   Chair, TED/Research Coordinator, Quality Assurance Coordinator  Extension: UPLIFT Tanzenos


                 Conforme:                                             Recommending Approval:


                 MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                                  MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                 Assistant Professor IV                                Department Chairperson

                 Reviewed by:                                          Approved:


                 NOEMI A. PERIDA                                       GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                 Campus Registrar                                      Campus Administrator
                V01-2018-07-24]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[VPAA-QF-11
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                                   Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (  (046) 414-3979
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                       TANZA CAMPUS
                                                  Teacher Education Department
                                                  FACULTY CLASS SCHEDULE
                                                  First Semester A.Y. 2022-2023
                 Name:      ESTELITA A. VILLA
                 Highest Educational Attainment:  Master of Arts in Mathematics
                 No. of Preparation(s):   3                 Total Number of Contact Hours per Week:   24


                          TIME          MONDAY     TUESDAY  WEDNESDAY   THURSDAY     FRIDAY   SATURDAY
                     7:00      7:30
                     7:30      8:00
                     8:00      8:30
                     8:30      9:00                                     BSEE 1-3 /
                     9:00      9:30                                      GNED 03
                     9:30      10:00
                    10:00      10:30              BSEE 4-2 /   BSEE 4-2 /
                    10:30      11:00   BSEE 1-3 /   EDFS 23   EDFS 23
                    11:00      11:30    GNED 03
                    11:30      12:00
                    12:00      12:30
                    12:30      1:00
                     1:00      1:30                                     BSEE 1-2 /
                     1:30      2:00    BSEE 1-2 /                        GNED 03
                     2:00      2:30     GNED 03
                     2:30      3:00               BSEE 4-1/   BSEE 4-1 /   BSEE 1-1 /
                     3:00      3:30                EDFS 23    EDFS 23    GNED 03
                     3:30      4:00
                     4:00      4:30                                     BSEM 2-2 /
                     4:30      5:00    BSEE 1-1 /   BSEM 2-2 /           BSEM 26
                     5:00      5:30     GNED 03    BSEM 26
                     5:30      6:00
                     6:00      6:30
                     6:30      7:00
                     7:00      7:30
                     7:30      8:00

                                      Course/ Year/    Contact Hours                            No. of
                         Subject                                           Total     Room
                                          Sec       Lecture  Laboratory                        Students
                                        BSEE1-1       3          0          3                     22
                  GNED 03 - Mathematics in
                     the Modern World   BSEE1-2       3          0          3                     22
                                        BSEE1-3       3          0          3                     21
                   BSEM 26 - Elementary   BSEM2-2     3          0          3                     22
                   Statistics and Probability
                                        BSEE 4-1      6          0          6                     33
                  EDFS 23 - Teaching Internship
                                        BSEE 4-2      6          0          6                     33
                                                         SCHEDULE

                 Consultation:  TH 10:00 am - 12:00 pm                     Research: Learning Assessment in Flexible Learning Modality
                 Designation :  Extension Coordinator/Budget Officer       Extension: UPLIFT Tanzenos


                 Conforme:                                             Recommending Approval:


                 ESTELITA A. VILLA                                     MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                 Instructor I                                          Department Chairperson

                 Reviewed by:                                          Approved:

                 NOEMI A. PERIDA                                       GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                 Campus Registrar                                      Campus Administrator
                V01-2018-07-24]]></page></pages></Search>