<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="89"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.4.            The institution encourages the conduct


                        of externally-funded researches.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                           Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                       Indang, Cavite
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                        OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH AND EXTENSION

                                                RESEARCH CENTER

               July 28, 2021


               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Administrator, Tanza Campus
               This University

               Dear Prof. Ramos:

               Good day!

               We  are  currently  updating  the  list  of  externally-funded  projects  implemented  by  the
               University.  In  this  regard,  please  furnish  our  office  through  the  Monitoring  and Evaluation
               Division the following:
                       1)  list of externally-funded projects implemented by Tanza Campus in 2018-2021
                       2)  Supporting documents of each of the project
                              a.  MOA and/or contract
                              b.  Copies  of progress reports  (for  ongoing  projects)  or  terminal  reports
                                 (completed project)

               We would like to furnish you also with the brochure version of the University Procedure on
               the Implementation, Monitoring and Evaluation of Externally-funded Research Programs and
               Projects (UREC-QP -05). Further, we take this opportunity to inform you that all externally-
               funded projects  are  required  to be presented  during  the CvSU  Research  Review  (Annual
               Agency In-house Review) which we have scheduled on August 25 and September 8, 2021,
               for ongoing and completed research projects respectively.

               We appreciate receiving the list of externally-funded researches until August 4, 2021 and the
               supporting documents until August 25, 2021.

               Should     you    have    any    queries,   please    communicate     with   us    through
               cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph or mobile number, 09069453267.

               Please see attached files. Thank you very much for your usual cooperation.

               Sincerely,


               MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
               Director


               Recommending Approval:

               MELBOURNE R. TALACTAC
               Vice President]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                           Don Severino delas Alas Campus
                                                      Indang, Cavite
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                               CvSU RESEARCH REVIEW (ANNUAL IN-HOUSE REVIEW)

                                 Information, Guidelines, and Mechanics for On-going
                                                        Research


               I.  RESEARCH
                     All researches duly recognized by the University are required to be  presented during
               the CvSU Research Review (Annual In-House Review). Recognized researches are those
               that  have  funding  through  the  Faculty-Students  Research  Capability  Enhancement
               Program (FSRCEP), CvSU Research Grant (CRG), Thesis Grant, College/Campus/RDE
               unit research funds, and other external funding agencies such as DOST, BAR, CHED, and
               others.

               II.  SUBMISSION OF ENTRIES
                    The ongoing research paper should:
                     1.  not be more than 30 pages including tables and figures, on A4 bond paper,
                     double-spaced, in 11 font size, preferably in Arial font.
                     2.  follow the format below:
                           a.  Title Page
                               •    Title
                               •   Researcher’s  name  including  designation  (Program/Project/Study
                                   leader, etc.) and contact information (i.e. office telephone and fax
                                   numbers,  mobile  number,  and  email  address).  For  student-
                                   researchers, also include the degree program. Indicate the nature of
                                   involvement in the  study (i.e. experimental design, the conduct of
                                   experiments, analysis of data, writing of the manuscript, etc.)
                               •   Duration (Month and year the project started and expected completion)
                               •   Budget
                               •   Source(s) of Funds
                               •   Collaborating Agency(ies)

                           b.  Technical Report

                               •   Introduction (rationale, state of the art, analysis of the problem)
                               •   Objectives (Indicate % accomplishment)
                               •   Expected Output
                               •   Procedure/Methodology
                                        ✓  Framework of the study
                                        ✓  Original procedure/methodology
                                        ✓  Change in procedure/methodology (cite reasons)
                               •   Research Highlights/Accomplishments
                                         ✓  Previous year’s comments and actions taken (if applicable)]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[✓  Year under review
                               •   Problems met/recommendations
                               •   Justification for continued implementation
                           c.  Financial Report (Please use UREC-QF-12)
                           d.  Plan of Activities (Gantt Chart)

                 III.  ORAL PRESENTATION
                    1.  Presentation must be made only by researchers directly involved in the
                        implementation of the project.
                    2.  All presentations must be pre-recorded following the prescribed PowerPoint template.
                       The maximum duration for the video presentation is 10 minutes.
                   3.  Ten (10) minutes will be allotted for the question-and-answer portion. If time permits,
                        questions from the audience may also be entertained. If time permits, questions from
                        the audience may also be entertained.
                   4.  An electronic copy of the paper and video presentation file must be sent through email
                        (cvsurcmande_monitoring@cvsu.edu.ph ) on or before October 18, 2022.

                IV.   EVALUATION
                    Ongoing researches  presented  will be evaluated by invited technical evaluators. The
                     criteria that will be used for evaluation are the following:
                    1.  Attainment of the objectives
                    2.  Adherence to the approved methodology/Recommendation of more appropriate
                        methodology
                    3.  Attainment of expected output
                    4.  Accomplishments, including the status of technology generated/verified
                    5.  Adherence to the approved budget
                    6.  Actions taken in response to previous year’s comments (if applicable)
                    7.  Recommendations on problems met
                    8.  Plan of activities

                       Upon  evaluation,  the  evaluators  will  make  necessary  recommendations  (i.e.  for
               information  dissemination,  completion,  termination,  suspension,  or  extension  of  the
               project/study).


                 V.    EXTERNALLY-FUNDED  RESEARCH  PROJECTS
                     Externally-funded research projects are not subject to evaluation, but project leaders  or
                     staff must present the research outputs for monitoring.
                    1.  The following should be submitted:
                        a.  The latest progress reports submitted to the external funding agency
                        b.  The percent accomplishment per objective
                        c.  A  table  indicating  the  comments/suggestions  during  the  latest  project
                            review/assessment (if applicable), and the corresponding action taken should be
                            submitted
                        d.  Plan of activities
                    2.  All presentations must be pre-recorded. The format of the PowerPoint presentation
                        may follow the prescribed format of the funding agency but should reflect the items
                        in 1.b-d.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[3.  The maximum duration for the presentation is 10 minutes. An additional 5 minutes
                        will be allotted for questions from the audience.
                   4.  An electronic copy of the paper and video presentation file must be sent through email
                        (cvsurcmande_monitoring@cvsu.edu.ph ) on or before October 18, 2022.
                                                                                                 .]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[REGIONAL RESEARCH AND INNOVATION COMMITTEE


               MEMORANDUM

               FOR            :      ALL RRIC MEMBERS

               SUBJECT        :      Call for Research Papers for the 7th CALABARZON Research,
                                     Statistics and Innovation Forum

               DATE           :      March 23, 2022


               1.  The RDC Regional Research and Innovation Committee (RRIC) will be conducting the
                   7th    CALABARZON          Research,      Statistics,   and    Innovation     Forum     on
                   October 14, 2022 (Friday).

               2.  The forum aims to promote a strong culture of research, showcase significant findings
                   of research studies, and strengthen the statistical capacities of academic institutions,
                   government agencies, and local government units in the region.

               3.  In this regard, may we request the submission of research papers for possible inclusion
                   in the forum. May we also request your assistance in disseminating the attached Call
                   for Research Papers.

               4.  Please submit research abstracts, accomplished registration form and endorsement
                   from the head of agency/institution through email at 2020researchforum4a@gmail.com
                   not later than May 25 (Wednesday).

               For consideration. Thank you and best regards.



               FELIXBERTO M. MERCADO
               RRIC Chairperson





                DRD/mtn]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[CALL FOR RESEARCH PAPERS

               Goal and Scope

               The  CALABARZON  Regional  Development  Council  –  Regional  Research  and
                                                                                      th
               Innovation  Committee  (RDC-RRIC)  will  be  conducting  the  7   CALABARZON
               Research,  Statistics  and  Innovation  Forum  on  October  14,  2022  (Friday).  The
               forum aims to promote a strong culture of research, showcase significant findings of
               research studies, and strengthen  the statistical capacities of academic institutions,
               government agencies, and local government units (LGUs) in the region.

               In line with the theme “Innovations Towards a Resilient, Healthy, and New Normal
               Ready CALABARZON”, the RDC-RRIC calls for the submission of quality research
               papers from the academe, research institutions (public and private), and consortia
                                                                                      2
               focusing  on  research  and  development  (R&D)   and  innovation   that  support  the
                                                                   1
               development of the following sectors and specific topics:

               a)  Industry and Services (labor, employment, and MSMEs)
               b)  Social  (education,  health,  gender  and  development,  disaster  risk  reduction
                    and management)
               c)  Infrastructure (Information and Communications Technology)
               d)  Agriculture and fisheries (reducing vulnerability of agriculture to climate change,
                    increasing productivity, innovative technologies)

               Participating Research Paper

               The  Call  is  open  to  all  scientists  and  researchers  (group  or  individual)  from
               CALABARZON  state  universities  and  colleges,  government  agencies,  LGUs,  R&D
               institutions, higher education institutions, and private industries doing R&D work.







               1  R&D is any systematic and creative work undertaken to increase the stock of new knowledge (idea/knowledge
                 generation) and the use of this idea/knowledge to devise new applications (technology generation). Prototyping
                 is its culmination (Republic Act 11293 Implementing Rules and Regulations).
               2  Innovation refers to the creation of new ideas that results in the development of new or improved products,
                 processes, or services which are then spread or transferred across markets. Innovation applies to the entire
                 spectrum of activities that provides value creation to the economy. Innovation thus covers commercialization,
                 utilization and even extension of R&D products, processes and services (RA11293 IRR).]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Submission of Research Papers

               Participants must submit the following documents in electronic copy not later than
               May 25, 2022 (Wednesday) by email to 2020researchforum4a@gmail.com:
                   1.  accomplished registration form
                   2.  one-page  Abstract  in  pdf  format,  250  to  300  words  including  keywords,
                       single-spaced, font: Arial 11
                   3.  endorsement by the head of agency/institution indicating that the paper has not
                       been published, nor was it registered or submitted to the Intellectual Property
                       Office of the Philippines (IPOPHL).

               General Guidelines

               Research papers must be completed within the past three years (2019-2021). Only
               unpublished  research  papers  will  be  accepted.  Similarly,  papers  registered  or
               submitted to the IPOPHL will not be accepted. Submitted entries will be reviewed by
               the Paper Evaluation Committee under the RDC-RRIC. Entries that are not compliant
               with the required format and not relevant to the theme, sectors, and specific topics
               identified will not be accepted. Plagiarism and other similar acts will not be tolerated.
               Authors of pre-qualified papers will be notified to submit a copy of their full paper on
               or before July 5, 2022 (Tuesday). There will be separate categories for professionals
               and students. Graduate/postgraduate students will be categorized as professionals.

               Both principal author and co-author can send a submission. For co-author, a written
               permission from the principal author should be provided. The principal author must
               acknowledge  his/her  co-author,  if  there  is  any.  A  maximum  of  two  entries  per
               researcher can be submitted, whether principal or co-author.

               For inquiries and clarifications, the Secretariat/NEDA Region IV-A may be reached at
               telephone number (049) 502-0229 or email at 2020researchforum4a@gmail.com.

               Indicative Calendar

                                            Activity                                    Schedule
                 Call for Papers                                                     March 25, 2022

                 Abstract Submission (deadline)                                          May 25

                 Notification of shortlisted/qualified papers*                           June 17

                 Full Paper Submission (deadline)*                                        July 5

                 Notification  of  approved  papers  for  oral  presentation  and        July 27
                 poster presentation
                 7th  CALABARZON  Research,  Statistics  and  Innovation            October 14, 2022
                 Forum                                                                   (Friday)

               *Researches submitted for poster presentation only will not be required to submit full papers.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Annexes

               Annex A – Guidelines on Full Paper Evaluation
               Annex B – Guidelines on Poster and Viewer's Choice Awards]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[19 July 2022

               DR. MELBOURNE R. TALACTAC
               Vice-President for Research and Extension
               Cavite State University
               Indang, Cavite

                                     ATTENTION: DR. MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
                                                     Director, Research Center

               Dear Vice-President Talactac,

               Greetings of peace!

               In celebration of this year’s National Peace Consciousness Month, the Office of the Presidential
               Adviser on Peace, Reconciliation and Unity (OPAPRU) is pleased to announce the conduct of
                    nd
               the 2  OPAPRU Peace Research Conference which will be held on 01-03 September 2022
               via  Hybrid  Modality.  The  main  conference  theme  for  this  year  is  “Ending  Conflicts:
               Women’s Role in Building and Sustaining Peace”

               The conference aims to serve as an avenue for knowledge advancement on the involvement of
               women  in  societal  transformation  of  conflict-ridden  and  disturbed  communities,  conflict
               prevention and peacebuilding, leadership and involvement in various levels of peace, program
               implementation and gender equality and women’s empowerment. Moreover, the conference
               aims to gather research and think pieces on the Philippine Women, Peace and Security Agenda
               and the vital role of women in conflict resolution and transformation, which shall serve as
                                                           rd
               supplementary to the sunset review of the 3  generation National Action Plan on Women,
                                                                                                        th
               Peace  and Security  (NAPWPS)  and additional recommendations  on the  crafting of the 4
               generation NAPWPS.

               In  view  of  the  foregoing,  we  would  like  to  invite  representatives/researchers  from  your
               institution to submit their papers in line with the main conference theme. Submitted papers will
               then  undergo  a  panel  selection  process  to  finalize  the  papers  to  be  presented  during  the
               conference.

               Participants may register through the link or the QR code and may also access the Research
               Paper Template and Guidelines provided below:





                            https://bit.ly/38Sd6we                        https://bit.ly/3FjWwlh
                                      (Registration Link)             (Research Paper Template and Guidelines)]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Research Abstracts and Partial or Full Research Article must be submitted on or before 10
               August 2022. The researchers/authors whose papers have been accepted shall be notified on
               19  August  2022.  Hotel  accommodation  for  all  speakers/presenters  will  be  covered  by
               OPAPRU and provision for Air Travel support will be provided upon request/need. For further
               inquiries, the Secretariat may be reached at opapru.researchcon@peace.gov.ph

               We hope to see you at the 2nd OPAPRU Peace Research Conference and kindly accept our
               sincerest appreciation for your continued support to the peace, reconciliation and unity.



               Respectfully yours,



               DIRECTOR MAE E. BALLENA
               Head, Knowledge Management and Peace Institute Service



               DIRECTOR VANESSA VIANCA S. PALLARCO
               Head, Social Healing and Peacebuilding Office]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                    OFFICE OF THE PRESIDENT
                                              COMMISSION ON HIGHER EDUCATION




               CHED MEMORANDUM ORDER
               No.     1
               Series of 2020


                       SUBJECT   :  GUIDELINES  FOR  THE  GRANT  OF  ASSISTANCE  TO  STATE
                                       UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES TO COMBAT COVID-19


               In accordance with the pertinent provisions of Republic Act (R.A.) No. 7722, otherwise known as
               the “Higher Education Act of 1994”; in support of the initiative of government with the declaration
               of a state of public health emergency under Proclamation 922, s. 2020 and a state of calamity under
               Proclamation No. 929, s. 2020,  and as approved during the virtual CEB meeting on 24 March 2020
               through Resolution No. 162, s. 2020, CHED hereby issues the Guidelines for the Grant of Assistance
               to State Universities and Colleges to Combat COVID-19.

               I. OBJECTIVES

               Republic Act No. 11469 granted the President powers and authorities necessary to carry out the
               urgent  measures  to  meet  the  COVID-19  national  health  emergency.  With  this  power,  the
               government has greater means to supplement, expand, improve and intensify existing COVID-19
               responses  and  preventive  measures,  and  to  further  mitigate  the  social,  economic  and  financial
               impact of COVID-19 on all Filipinos.

               Under  the  Memorandum  from  the  Executive  Secretary  dated  28  March  2020,  the    whole  of
               government must work together towards the following objectives: protect and support our health
               workers and front liners; provide the supplies and equipment necessary for  detecting the disease
               and  caring  to  those  infected;  ensure  that  community  quarantines  are  effectively  implemented;
               deliver essential necessities such as food and medicine to the most vulnerable; x x x, and, mobilize
               all  state  assets  to  sustain  the  operation  of  the  government.  Section  B  (4)  of  said  Memorandum
               allows  the  Department  of  Budget,  to  allocate  cash,  funds,  investments,  including  unutilized  or
               unreleased  subsidies  and  transfers,  held  by  national  government  agency  in  order  to  address  the
               COVID-19 emergency, as declared in Section 3 of RA No. 11469;

               State Universities  and Colleges  are  authorized by  law/charter to  conduct  research  and extension
               services, including projects that will improve and intensify the government’s existing COVID-19
               responses.  In  the  report  of  the  President  to  the  Congress  on  30  March  2020,  the  President  had
               identified the efforts undertaken by CHED such as mobilizing HEIs to assist   in the production and
               distribution of items (such as disinfectants, alcohol, face shields, etc.,) for use by frontline service
               providers. The Commission on Higher Education hereby issues the Guidelines in response  to this
               national emergency  by allocating/utilizing  its funds towards mitigating the social, economic and
               financial impact of COVID-19  on Filipinos.




                       Higher Education Development Center Building, C.P. Garcia Ave., U.P Campus, Diliman, Quezon City, Philippines
                       Web Site: www.ched.gov.ph Tel. Nos. 441-1177, 385-4391, 441-1169, 441-1169, 441-1170, 441-1216, 392-5296]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[II. ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS

                  1.  The grant is open to State Universities and Colleges (SUCs) to conduct extension and public
                      service programs to combat COVID-19.
                  2.  SUCs must possess the following expertise and capability:

                      a)  Manufacturing of products listed in Annex B of GPPB Resolution No. 3-2020 dated 9
                          March 2020 (see attached) except for drugs/medicines as evidenced by the involvement
                          of licensed chemists, pharmacists, and/or microbiologists in the team;

                      b)  Preparation  of  food  for  consumption  of  DOH,  AFP,  PNP  front  liners  and  stranded
                          students  including  marginalized  communities  only  during  the  period  of  community
                          quarantine;

                      c)  Deployment of volunteers to assist healthcare front liners in contact tracing, databasing,
                          and other similar services;

                      d)  Other  urgently  needed  equipment,  expertise  and  capability  to  be  determined  by  the
                          Commission, the Inter-agency Task Force for the Management of Emerging Infectious
                          Diseases and/or by the Chief Implementer Against COVID-19;


               III. CALL FOR AND SUBMISSION OF PROPOSALS

                   1.  A Call for Proposals shall be released through the Office of the Chairperson.

                   2.  During the period of public health emergency or state of calamity, documentary
                       requirements including a full-blown extension proposals shall be submitted directly to
                       Office of the Chairperson of CHED (chairperson@ched.gov.ph) copy furnished the
                       Commissioner-in-charge of the SUC and the Office of Planning Research and Knowledge
                       Management (research@ched.gov.ph).

                       The documentary requirement shall include the following:

                       a)  Certification by the President that the SUC has the expertise to undertake the proposed
                          project with CVs or short biosketches of experts (for Item 2.a and 2.b) or number of
                          potential volunteers (for Item 2.c) AND that it has the equipment, raw materials or
                          access thereof, and facilities to undertake the project including a description thereof;
                       b)  Full-blown proposal (see attached template) with the following information:
                              a.  Line item budget;
                              b.  Work plan;
                              c.  Terms of reference/scope of the project;
                              d.  Log frame;
                              e.  Description of the significance of the project in terms of its benefits to the
                                 community as well as the expected outcome of the activity
                              f.  Method
                              g.  Distribution plan for products, with the following prioritization: 1) LGUs using
                                 SUC’s facility as quarantine center/community isolation units, 2) LGUs, with
                                 little or no capacity of producing  the proposed products
                              h.  Email and mobile numbers of proponents;


                                                                                                              2]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[c)  Proof of coordination with the local government, the Department of Health, or the local
                          security forces, as applicable, to ensure reasonable compliance with their policies,
                          standards or guidelines related to the project, as evidenced by a letter sent and duly
                          received by the concerned offices;
                       d)  Proposed memorandum of agreement signed by the SUC President and a witness which
                          will be processed if the proposal is approved;
                       e)  Certification by the President that the proposed projects are subject to ratification by the
                          Governing Board of the SUC concerned and that it has been forwarded to the Board
                          Chair for approval via referendum;
                       f)  Project summary sheet;

                   3.  The submitted RDE proposals must be approved and endorsed by the President of the
                       SUC.

                   4.  Due  to  the  urgency  of  responding  to  COVID-19,  the  proposal  shall  be  processed
                       without  the  need  for  prior  endorsement  of  the  Board.  Provided  that,  a  copy  of  the
                       Memorandum of Agreement and its attachments shall be submitted to the Board for
                       its ratification.

                   5.  Clear scanned copies of the proposals shall be sent via email to research@ched.gov.ph
                       cc executivedirector@ched.gov.ph and chairperson@ched.gov.ph.

                   6.  Submitted  unsigned  applications  shall  be  considered  incomplete.  Incomplete
                       submissions shall be not considered for evaluation.


               IV. PROPOSAL REVIEW PROCESS

                    1.  The  extension  proposals  will  be  presented  virtually  by  the  President  or  his/her
                       designated  representative  before  a  panel  to  be  designated  by  the  Commission  which
                       must include the director-in-charge of the office which will sign for the release of funds,
                       the director of HEDFS, and a technical expert.

                    2.  After  the  deliberation,  the  agreed  revisions  shall  be  reflected  in  writing  and  will
                       constitute as an amendment of the proposal. Proponents of proposals that are not feasible
                       or viable even with revisions shall be informed by the Commission.

                    3.  The  panel  shall  consider  the  following  in  its  deliberation  with  priority  given  to  the
                       following:
                       a)  The volume of products that can be produced;
                       b)  The  ability  to  distribute  the  same  to  frontliners  (health,  security,  and  local
                           government personnel) and marginalized communities;
                       c)  The ability to demonstrate continued access to raw materials and machinery over a
                           period of one month;
                       d)  The quality and efficacy of the products produced.

                    4.  Once the proposal has been endorsed by the panel, the CHED OPRKM shall prepare the
                       MoA, Obligation Request, and Disbursement Voucher for the signature of the authorized
                       signatories. The Chairman is authorized to approve on behalf of the CEB the proposal of
                       the SUCs as evidenced by his approval for payment.


                                                                                                              3]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[5.  The total value of the project shall be released in full to the SUC within three working
                       days after the Chairman’s approval for payment.


              V. VALUE AND DURATION OF THE GRANTS

                   1.  Each  extension  project  shall  be  given  funding  based  on  the  institutional  grantee’s
                       capacity  to  utilize  within  the  grant  period  in  accordance  with  government
                       procurement,  accounting,  and  auditing  rules  and  regulations;  Provided  that  only  a
                       maximum of ten (10) percent shall be used for overhead cost.

                   2.  The  grant  is  for  a  period  of  2  to  3  months  from  the  release  of  funds  and  is
                       automatically extended should the community quarantine is extended by government
                       beyond the three-month period. Provided that grantees shall have sixty days from the
                       end of the grant period to liquidate and submit terminal reports.


              VI. MONITORING AND EVALUATION OF THE EXTENSION PROJECTS

                   1.  In order to keep track of the implementation of the project as well as the compliance
                       with the project deliverables and timelines, grantees shall send regular weekly updates
                       to the Commission or as requested by the Commission, comprising of the following:

                            a.  Properly  captioned  pictures  of  SUC  personnel/volunteers  in  action,  e.g.
                                conducting the project or delivering assistance to communities;

                            b.  No  of  units  of  goods  provided  and/or  services  rendered  to  beneficiaries  as  of
                                reporting date together with a description of these goods and/or services;

                            c.  List of recipient/s who received the good and/or service rendered (i.e. LGU);

                            d.  Challenges encountered in the field, if any, including recommended solutions;
                   `
                       These  shall  be  sent  to  research@ched.gov.ph  cc  executivedirector@ched.gov.ph  and
                       chairperson@ched.gov.ph.

                   2.  OPRKM shall consolidate the reports for the information of the Commission en banc and
                       the Management Committee.

                   3.  Requests for realignment is deemed approved if the funds realigned will increase the
                       number of products or services that the project will deliver without increasing the per unit
                       cost;

                   4.  Requests for realignment not covered in Item V.3, requests for reprogramming, and
                       extension of project implementation shall be approved jointly by the Director-in-charge and
                       the Director of HEDFS (hedf@ched.gov.ph) through their respective official CHED emails
                       upon submission of the following documents:




                                                                                                              4]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[For realignment not covered by Item V.3 and reprogramming:

                       a)  Letter request with justification
                       b)  Matrix of budget realignment/ reprogramming indicating the original allocation and the
                          proposed modification or in the case of reprogramming the new object of expenditure
                          not included in the original proposal;

                   For extension of project implementation beyond the State of Calamity or Enhanced
                   Community Quarantine:

                       a)  Letter request with justification

                       b)  Revised Gantt Chart/ schedule of the activities that will be conducted for the requested
                          period of extension

                       c)  Project accomplishment report

                   Requests  shall  be  sent  via  email  at  research@ched.gov.ph  and  hedf@ched.gov.ph  cc
                   executivedirector@ched.gov.ph, chairperson@ched.gov.ph, and ncainghog@ched.gov.ph.


              VII. WARRANTIES/REPRESENTATION

                   1.  Grantee SUCs hereby guarantee that only qualified personnel, facility and equipment, raw
                       materials, quality control and documentation, safety considerations, packaging and labeling
                       for  the  formulation  of  products,  including  but  not  limited  to  the  formulation  of  alcohol-
                       based sanitizers are strictly observed to ensure the safety and efficacy of the products.

                   2.  In  case  of  adverse  events  experienced  with  the  use  of  products,  like  hand  sanitizers,  it
                       should  be  reported  to  the  online  reporting  facility  of  Food  and  Drug  Administration,  at
                       www.fda.gov.ph\ereport,     email    via    report@fda.gov.ph     and    copy     furnish
                       chairperson@ched.gov.ph, research@ched.gov.ph and executivedirector@ched.gov.ph.

                   3.  Grantee SUCs guarantee to save, indemnify and keep harmless CHED against any and all
                       liability, claims, judgments or demands, including demands arising from injuries or death
                       of persons and damage to property, arising directly or indirectly out of obligations herein
                       undertaken and that Grantee SUCs shall be responsible from any adverse events or effects
                       that may arise from the formulation/manufacturing/distribution/use of the product.


              VIII. TERMINATION OF EXTENSION PROJECTS

                   1.  The  Commission  reserves  the  right  to  terminate  the  implementation  of  the  project  for
                       the following causes:
                          a.  Non-ratification  by  the  Governing  Board  of  the  project  prior  to  implementation
                              unless  the  President  has  delegated  authority  to  sign  and  commit  on  behalf  of  the
                              institution;
                          b.  Breach of the provisions of this MOA;
                          c.  Serious misconduct in the way the project is managed or governed;
                          d.  Safety of employees/staff/personnel is threatened;


                                                                                                              5]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[e.  failure on the part of the project team to make satisfactory progress toward achieving
                              a level of participation;
                          f.  or other evidence satisfactory to the Commission that the project team has failed or
                              is unable to perform in accordance with the provisions of the grant agreement.
                          g.  Other analogous reasons.

                   2.  The Commission through OPRKM shall issue a Termination Warning Notice of the whole
                       or part the project, said notice shall be given to the implementing HEI within ten (10) days.
                       The Termination Warning Notice will specify:
                          a.  The actions that the SUC must take;
                          b.  The date by which the action must be completed; and
                          c.  The date by which the SUC must make any representations, or confirm that it agrees
                              to undertake the specified action;

                   3.  If  the  OPRKM  Director  considers  that  the  SUC  has  not  responded  to  the  Termination
                       Warning Notice as specified under clause 3(c) or has not completed the action required in
                       the Termination Warning Notice as specified under clauses 3(a) or complied with 3(b), the
                       OPRKM Director may request authorization from the CEB to terminate the project in whole
                       or in part.

                   4.  Should  the  termination  be  due  to  the  inability  of  the  project  team  to  perform,  upon
                       termination, the implementing HEI must refund that portion of the grant funds paid or owed
                       to the Commission and allocable to the terminated project work. Only funds need to meet
                       existing obligations shall be retained. All other funds shall be refunded to the Commission.

                   5.  After  the  CEB  has  approved  the  termination,  the  OPRKM  shall  inform  in  writing  the
                       implementing  HEI.  The  notice  of  termination  shall  establish  the  effective  date  of
                       termination  of  the  grant  and  the  amount  and  date  of  payment  of  any  sums  due  to  the
                       Commission or the implementing HEI.


               IX. EFFECTIVITY

                     This CMO shall take effect immediately and remain in full force and effect until otherwise
                     revoked.

                     Quezon City, Philippines 02 April 2020.





                                                                  J. PROSPERO DE VERA III, DPA
                                                                                   Chairman











                                                                                                              6]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[he   _
                                                                                                        "
                                                                                            \eP on Hig    tv
                      o                                                                                    cv

                                                                                                            (.0.
                                                                                           .
                                               Republic of the Philippines                s.e
                                   c) 	                                                   8'OFFICIALT..
                                             OFFICE OF THE PRESIDENT
                                      COMMISSION ON HIGHER EDUCATION                     8  RELEASE g
                                 +                                                       °  CHED Central Office Ci
                                                                                          -o
                                                                                          *0   RECOSOS SECTION  rS
                                                                                                           ._4:'•
                                                                                            co,.
                                                                                             cy
                         MEMORANDUM FROM THE CHAIRMAN                                         I  -Tifep.,  to.O
                                                                                                AW

                                  : HEADS OF STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES (SUCs) AND
                         TO
                                    CHED-RECOGNIZED LOCAL UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES (LUCs)
                        SUBJECT: FY 2019 CALL FOR SUBMISSION OF PROJECT PROPOSALS FOR
                                    CHED INSTITUTIONAL GRANT

                                  : 23 August 2019
                         DATE
                         The Commission on Higher Education, through the Office of Institutional Quality
                         Assurance and Governance (01QAG), is inviting interested State Universities and
                         Colleges (SUCs) and CHED-Recognized Local Universities and Colleges (LUCs) to
                         submit project proposals for CHED Institutional Grant for Fiscal Year 2019.


                         SUCs and CHED-Recognized LUCs are encouraged to submit project proposals to be
                         able to improve the delivery of any of the major functions of the institution, namely,
                         instruction, research and extension. These project proposals should be part of the
                         institution's development plan in congruence to the regional development plan, must be
                         within the priority programs and projects of the Commission on institutional developmet
                         and enhancement.

                         For FY 2019 the project proposals should involve complementation/collaboration
                         scheme of two or more higher education institutions located within the province or
                         region on the following areas:

                              facilities upgrading/improvement and development of technology-based higher
                              education programs; and
                              promotion and development of tourism in a certain geographical location.

                        In order to be considered for the review, the following requirements should be
                        submitted:

                               Project Proposal (full blown) to include (Project Proposal Format Attachment 1):
                           1.
                                   Statement of Purpose/Objective(s)
                                   Background and Justification to include Cost-Benefit Analysis
                                   Project Plan/Methodology
                                   Project Team to indicate qualifications and terms of reference
                                   Budget/Indicative Cost with Work and Financial Plan (WFP) & Line Item
                                   Budget (LIB) to include the proponent SUC's counterpart, priorities and
                                   justifications
                                   Gantt Chart;
                               Log Frame (Attachment 2);
                               Summary Sheet (Attachment 3);
                               Certified True Copy of Board Resolution approving the project; and
                               Certificate of No Pending Request for Funding on this same project in any other
                               funding agency/institution.









               Higher Education Development Center Building, C.P. Garicia Ave., UP Campus, Diliman, Quezon City, Philippines
           Web Site: www.ched.gov.oh   Tel. Nos. 441-1177, 385-4391, 441-1169, 441-1149, 441-1170, 441-1216, 392-5296, 441-1220
                      441-1228, 988-0002, 441-0750, 441-1254, 441-1235, 441-1255, 411-8910, 441-1171, 352-1871]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Send your proposal and other required documents on or before September 30, 2019
                         for evaluation by the Technical Working Group of Institutional Grant to:

                                The Director IV
                                Office of Institutional Quality Assurance and Governance (01QAG)
                                Commission on Higher Education
                                HEDC Bldg. C.P. Garcia Avenue, Diliman, Quezon City

                         For further details, concerns and queries, you may contact Mr. Reyen M. Sabate, Chief
                         Education Program Specialist or Ms. Noemi A. Isidro, Sr. Education Program Specialist,
                         Coordination and Governance Division, 01QAG at telephone number (02) 441-1254 or
                         thru email oiqag.cgdivision@gmail.corn.




                         J. PROSPE 0 E. DE VERA III, DPA
                         Chairman]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[COMMISSION ON HIGHER EDUCATION
                       Office for Institutional Quality Assurance and Governance

                               CHECKLIST OF INSTITUTIONAL GRANTS REQUIREMENTS



                                                           Requirements
                   I. Full blown Project Proposal
                       Statement of Purpose/Objective(s)

                       Background and Justification to include Cost-Benefit Analysis
                       Project Plan/Methodology
                       Project Team (if any), to include qualifications and terms of reference
                       4.1 Qualification
                       4.2.Terms of Reference
                    5.Budget /Indicative Cost with Work and
                      Financial Plan (WFP) & Line Item
                      Budget (LIB) to include the proponent
                      SUC's counterpart (if any)
                      Log frame
                      Gantt Chart
                      Summary Sheet HEDFS
                  II.  Certified True Copy of Board Resolution
                  III. Certification signed by the President of the SUC that the project proposal is not submitted for
                     consideration/funding in other funding agency(ies)



                       Liquidation of Grants/Financial Assistance from CHED
                  IV.
                      HEDFS
                     Schedule of Due from NGAS
                       Title CHED Grant/Financial Assistance
                       Amount Received
                       Date Received /
                       Check No.
                       Status]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[CHED INSTITUTIONAL GRANTS Form 1
                                                 PROJECT PROPOSAL


               I. PROJECT TITLE:




              II. NAME OF INSTITUTION/PROPONENT:


                   Name of Institution

                   Complete Address

                   Contact Numbers
                       Telephone Nos.
                      Mobile Nos.
                      Email Address
                   Name of the Head of the
                  Institution
                  Designation
                  Name of Project Coordinator &
                  Designation
                  Contact Nos. & e-mail Address

                  Name of Project Leader &
                  Designation
                  Contact Nos. & e-mail Address



               III RATIONALE, BACKGROUND AND JUSTIFICATION TO INCLUDE COST-
                  BENEFIT ANALYSIS:
              (The proposed project will provide an opportunity for the proponent SUC to advance its commitment/the
              institution's Vision, Mission and Goals including mandate; impact to intended beneficiaries that will be
              affected by the reforms/improvements resulting from the project; outputs in each identified phase of the
              project implementation; and will the public see this project as good use of public fund?)]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[IV. STATEMENT OF PURPOSE/OBJECTIVE(S) AND SIGNIFICANCE OF THE
                   STUDY:
               (The proposed project addresses the goaUs or objective/s of the Higher Education Road Map/Regional
               Development Plan/Institutional Development Plan)

                      Statement of the Problem:
                       General:

                      Specific:


                     Significance of the Study
                     (Contribution of the project to national/regional/community/institutional goal/plans;
                    emerging realities, etc.)





               V. PROJECT /WORK PLAN
                (This includes a brief description in chronological order of each activity to undertaken in the conduct of
               the project. The starting and planned completion date are indicated in year and month and they may be
               presented via Gantt Chart)

                     Work Plan

                         Activities                      Output                       Due Date






                    Gantt Chart
                                                                              Months
                               Activities
                                                          1  2    3    4  5  6  7  8  9  10  11  12






               Note: Clear and viable timelines and deliverables with Logical Framework and Gantt chart that match
              both project description and proposed outcomes



               V-3 Detailed List/Breakdown of Equipment
                     Existing             No. of Units        To be purchased           No. of Units
                    E • uipment]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[PROJECT TEAM COMPOSITION, QUALIFICATIONS AND TERMS OF
                   REFERENCE
                     Activities  	Person                          Responsibility         Duration of
                                      Involved/Designation                              Involvement /
                                                                                         Time Frame









                   BUDGETARY REQUIREMENTS

               VII-1. Work and Financial Plan
                                                                Amount Der Months and Activities
                               Activities
                                                          1  _2    3   4  5  6    7  8  9     10  11  12








               VII-2 Detailed Line Item Bud et
                               Items/Particulars                                  Amount
                Maintenance and Other Operating Expenses                       Counterpart
                                    (MOOE)                            Institutions           CHED





                  Equipment Outlay**
                  Detailed List/ Breakdown of Equipment



                                             Submitted/Prepared by                 Endorsed by



              Signature             :
              Name                  •  .
              Designation/Title  :
              Date                  :

              Note: To be submitted together with Certification signed by the President of the SUC
              that the project proposal is not submitted for consideration/funding in other funding
              agencyAes; Board Resolution; HEDF Project Summary Sheet and Logical Framework]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[HEDF PROJECT SUMMARY SHEET
                COMMISSION ON HIGHER EDUCATION 	                           Proposed for calendar year
                -I Project Code 	                           Project Code to be  filled up by HEW staff for new projects  	.-
                                        I 	 1
                2  Project Title
                3 Project Description


                4  Proponent Name  	                                            i  goNATURE
                5 Proponent Org/Div
                6 Contact Information
                7 Project Dates & Duration 	                  to                       Duration      months
                                            Front
                8 Requested Support
                                         For the Year                      For the entire Project
                             Other Requests
                9 HEDF Priority Area
               10 Project Justification



               11 Project Deliverables



               12 Project Milestones        Date                               Output

                                                                                                           _








               13 Activity Chart       Mo. 1   Mo. 2   Mo. 3   Mo. 4   Mo. 5   Mo. 8   Mo. 7   Mo. 8   Mo. 9   Mo 10  Mo 11   Mo. 12
                  Delineation of Tasks
                  Requisition of Equipment
                  Delivery of Equipment
                  Retrofitting of Room
                  Training of Faculty/Staff
               14 Financial Timelines   mai   Mo. 2   Mo. 3   Mo. 4   Mo 5   Mo. 8   Mo. 7   Mo. 8   Mo. 9   Mo  10  Mo. 11   Mo .12   TOTAL
                 Source of Fund: CHED
                 1. e.g. Requisition of Equipment
                 Source of Fund: SUC Name
                                                                                                          _
                 2
                 3
                 4
                 5
                 6
                 7
                 8
                 9
                                                                 -
                 10. Other Expenses
                                  Total
               15 REVIEWED BY       RECOMMENDATIONS                                 APPROVED BY
                 DATE                                                               DATE]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[CHED HEDFS Form 4
                                     LOGICAL FRAMEWORK FOR HEDF PROJECT PROPOSAUS


                      Objectives 	                                 Means of Verification
                                            Measurable Indicators
                                                                                           Important Assumption
               Goal:
                  Wider problem the project   Quantitative ways of   Cost-effective methods   External factors necessary to
                  will help to resolve    measuring or qualitative ways   and sources to quantify   sustain objectives in the long
                                          of judging timed achievement   or assess indicators   run
                                          of goal

              Purpose:
                 The immediate impact on   Quantitative ways of   Cost-effective methods   (Purpose to Goal)
                 the project area or target   measuring or qualitative ways   and sources to quantify   External conditions necessary if
                 group i.e. the change or   of judging timed achievement   or assess indicators   achieved project purpose is to
                 benefit to be achieved by   of goal                                    contribute to reaching project
                 the project                                                            goal
              Outputs:
                 These are the specifically   Quantitative ways of   Cost-effective methods   (Output to Purpose)
                 deliverable results expected   measuring or qualitative ways   and sources to quantify   Factors out of project control
                 from the project to attain the   of judging timed production   or assess indicators   which, if present, could restrict
                 purpose                  of outputs                                    progress from outputs to
                                                                                        achieving project purpose
              Activities:              Inputs:
                 These are the tasks to be   This is a summary of the   Financial reports   (Activity to output)
                 done to produce the outputs   project budget                            Factors out of project control
                                                                                        which, if present, could restrict
                                                                                        progress from activities to
                                                                                        achieving outputs




                 Why use a LOG FRAME?  A Log Frame is' a logical summary of key factors of the project. "It" encourages the discipline of
                 clear and specific thinking about what the project aims to do and how, and highlighting those aspects upon which success
                 depends. "It is a tool for planning, monitoring and evaluating projects. — From the "Logical Framework Analysis" document of
                 BOND Networking for International Development.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[CHED HEDFS Form 4
                                     LOGICAL FRAMEWORK FOR HEDF PROJECT PROPOSALJS



                      Objectives 	Measurable Indicators  	Means of Verification
                                                                                           Important Assumption
               Goal:






               Purpose:




               Outputs:







              Activities:














                 Prepared by:                                     Approved by:



                 Signature over printed name                      Signature over printed name
                 Designation                                      Designation]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Research Center Operational Manual]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[RESEARCH


                                                    INTRODUCTION


                       Research at the Cavite State University (CvSU) began with the conversion of Indang

               Rural High School into Don Severino Agricultural College in 1964. Since then, the Research


               Center (RC) has evolved to function as one of the trilogy roles of the University. To date, the

               University is the seat of the national research, development, and extension for coffee – a status

               bestowed by the Department of Agriculture Bureau of Agricultural Research.


                       The  Research  Center  exerted  serious  efforts  toward  streamlining  the  Research,

               Development, and Extension (RDE) Program by establishing a strong and effective research

               program aimed to generate innovative and viable technologies useful to farmers and other


               clients.  This  is  done  with  the  goal  of  improving  their  standard  of  living.  The  University’s

               research  program  focuses  on  coffee  research,  development,  and  extension.  However,  to

               accommodate the ever-increasing need for RD&E activities brought about by the development

               of  the  University  into  a  comprehensive  one,  these  thrusts  have  become  more  elaborate

               through the “Faculty and Students Research Capability Enhancement Program” that has been

               approved by the University Board of Regents in 2004.



                       The  University  has  maintained  ties  and  established  collaborative  projects  with

               international  and  local  agencies  with  emphasis  on  plantation  crops,  high  value  fruits  and

               vegetables, ornamentals, herbs and spices and poultry and livestock among others.


                       The research of the University is anchored into specific thrusts otherwise known as

               thematic areas which set the direction for the researchers on which disciplines or commodities

               to prioritize. These thrusts have evolved from fourteen to seven as follows: Strengthening


               Leadership in Coffee R&D; Mainstreaming Kaong R&D towards Environmental Protection and

               Poverty  Alleviation;  Sustainable  Agriculture  and  Fisheries;  Environment  and  Natural

               Resources; Engineering and Technology Development; Health and Wellness; and Human and

               Societal Development.]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[However, it was deemed appropriate to remove the first two thematic areas because

               these are commodity-focused. Presently, the research thematic areas are as follows: Agri-

               Fisheries  and  Food  Security;  Biodiversity  and  Environmental  Conservation;  Smart

               Engineering,  Information  and  Communication  Technology,  and  Industrial  Competitiveness;


               Social Development and Equality; and Public Health and Welfare.


               Article 1. Research Goal, Objectives, and Agenda

                       Section 1. Research Goal.  Cavite State University shall be a research University

               equipped with modern facilities geared towards innovating knowledge and improving the lives

               of the community.


                       Section 2.  Objectives.  The University aims to develop innovative technologies in

               various disciplines and commodity thrusts, especially in agriculture.

                       Specifically, it aims to:

                       1.  generate technologies in various disciplines in the University with emphasis on its

                          major thrusts;


                       2.  disseminate research results;

                       3.  establish strong external linkages through formation of collaborative projects;

                       4.  strengthen the capability of faculty, researchers, students and other stakeholders

                          in performing research activities; and

                       5.  recognize outstanding achievements of researchers.

                       Section 3. Research Agenda.  The University shall pursue research agenda which


               are responsive to the specific needs of the community brought by present environmental and

               developmental  challenges.  Guided  by  the  local  and  national  development  thrusts,  the

               University research agenda shall be focused on but not limited to the following


                       1.  Agri-Fisheries and Food Security. This thematic area emphasizes on developing

                          agriculture  and  food  systems  that  are  economically  viable  and  sustainable  to

                          ensure food security as well as improve the quality of life of farmers and fisher]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[folks.  Research  and  extension  activities  on  the  following  commodities  shall  be

                          given priority: coffee, kaong, rice, corn, root crops, high value crops (e.g. banana,

                          pineapple,  mango,  cacao  and  vegetables)  poultry  and  livestock,  fisheries  and

                          aquaculture, urban agriculture, and organic agriculture.


                       2.  Biodiversity and Environmental Conservation. This thematic area is concerned

                          with environmental stewardship and equitable allocation and sustainable use of

                          natural  resources  with  emphasis  on  environmental  protection,  biodiversity

                          assessment and monitoring, cleaner environment, climate change, risk reduction

                          management,  renewable  energy  and  green  technologies,  natural  resource


                          management, and ecotourism.

                       3.  Smart Engineering, Information and Communication Technology (ICT), and

                          Industrial  Competitiveness.  The  term  smart  engineering  covers  the  methods,

                          processes,  systems  and  tools  for  the  cross-disciplinary,  system-oriented

                          development  of  innovative  and  interconnected  products,  services  and

                          infrastructures in the field of engineering. Products and process models shall be

                          developed  where  networking  encompasses  all  stages  of  development,  from


                          interdisciplinary design to production processes and piloting, right the way through

                          product  usage  and  disposal.  Smart  engineering  is  about  the  integration  of

                          appropriate product planning, development, and management to ensure the rapid

                          market-ready  implementation  of  innovative  product  and  services  and  industrial

                          competitiveness through the digital development process.

                                 The convergence of the latest computer science and ICT developments in


                          the  areas  of  micro-devices,  mobile  communication,  hardware  infrastructures,

                          Internet  and  software  technologies,  image  recognition  and  processing,  parallel

                          computing, complex adaptive systems and bioinformatics shall be given emphasis.

                          Strong focus shall also be given to mathematics and statistics applications such as

                          industrial  and  biological  modelling,  biomedical,  social  and  theoretical  statistics,

                          computational mathematics, discrete pure mathematics and physics/engineering.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[4.  Social Development and Equality. This thematic area focuses on educational,

                          criminological  and  social  sciences  researches  and  development  initiatives  with

                          emphasis  on  sustainable  development,  economic  development,  gender  and

                          development,  community  development,  governance,  poverty  alleviation,  social


                          behavior,  attitude  and  norms,  capacity  building,  peace  process  and  conflict

                          resolution,  disaster  risk  management  and  social  transitions,  pedagogy,  special

                          education, ICT and education, among others.

                                 This  area  aims  to  create  inclusive  growth  and  development,  social

                          harmony, and equal opportunities among the different social groups and to lessen


                          economic divide, inequality, and marginalization in society.

                       5.  Public Health and Welfare. This area deals with researches on protecting and

                          improving human health and welfare which includes researches on diseases or

                          conditions that may be transmitted to humans from humans or animals and vice

                          versa as well as those connected with the environment as a whole. Disciplines that

                          are  also  covered  are  those  dealing  with  epidemiology,  statistics,  environment,

                          behavior  and  sociology,  economics,  mental  health,  public  policy,  public  safety,


                          delivery of health services, occupational safety and other related fields.


               Article 2. Research Organization and Management

                       Section 1. Organizational Structure. The organizational structure of the Research

               Center is shown in Figure 1. The Research Center is directly under the supervision of the

               Office of the Vice President for Research and Extension (OVPRE). The center has three major

               divisions: Monitoring and Evaluation Division, Capacity Development Division and Technical

               Services Division. It also oversees all research concerns of the different colleges and satellite

               campuses. Moreover, it coordinates with the Responsible Conduct of Research Unit for the

               evaluation of relevant research projects.


                       Section 2. Functions of the Research Center.  The Research Center performs the

               second major function of Cavite State University.  The Center is responsible  for generating]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[and  monitoring  researches  and  technologies  in  accordance  with  the  University’s  research

               agenda as well as the national development thrusts. The Research Center also coordinates

               all the research-related activities implemented in colleges and satellite campuses.








































                                   Figure 1. Organizational Structure of Research Center



                      Section 2.1. Functions of the Major Divisions

                          a.  Project Monitoring and Evaluation Division (M and E). The M and E Division

                              of the Research Center is responsible for facilitating the review of research

                              proposals  submitted  for  funding  and  monitoring  and  evaluating  the

                              implementation  and  progress  of  all  the  research  programs/projects  of  the

                              University. The M and E Division also  keeps an updated database that will


                              facilitate data storage, processing, and retrieval. It shall provide assistance to]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[the Director for Research in the planning and formulation of short- and long-

                              term  R&D  plans  and  policies,  guidelines,  and  workplans  related  to  the

                              monitoring and evaluation of research projects and programs.

                          b.  Technical  Services  Division.  The  Technical  Services  Division  of  the


                              Research Center is in charge of the research laboratories, arts, humanities, and

                              social  sciences  research  unit,  and  central  experimental  stations  of  the

                              University. The TSD shall assist the Director for Research in the planning and

                              formulation of short- and long-term R&D plans and policies, guidelines, and

                              workplans related to the efficient management and improvement of the division.


                              It  is  also  responsible  for  keeping  an  updated  inventory  of  the  supplies  and

                              materials,  and  equipment,  and  maintenance  of  the  facilities  of  the  different

                              research laboratories and units involved in the conduct of research; identifying

                              and request for facility repairs and/or improvements. It shall provide technical

                              assistance in the use of facilities and equipment at the Research Center.

                          c.  Capacity Development Division. The CDD designs, evaluates, monitors, and

                              implements programs and projects that would develop the research capabilities


                              of  faculty  members  and  students  of  the  University.  The  CDD  division  shall

                              coordinate with the M and E Division and TSD; and the campus/college/RDE

                              units for the plans and implementation of research capacity-building activities.

                              The CDD shall assist the Director for Research in the planning and formulation

                              of  short-  and  long-term  R&D  plans  and  policies,  guidelines,  and  workplans

                              related to the efficient management and improvement of the division.


                       Section 2.2. Functions of the Responsible Conduct of Research Unit (RCRU). The

                       RCRU is an independent unit in-charge of evaluating research studies for compliance

                       to national or institutional standards for the responsible conduct of researches. Results

                       of evaluation shall be submitted to the Research Center for appropriate action.

                          a.  Ethics Review Board.  The Ethics Review Board is responsible for evaluating

                              researches which involves human participants such as clinical trials of drugs,


                              devices, and diagnostics.]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[b.  Institutional Biosafety Committee.  The Institutional Biosafety Committee is

                              in  charge  of  the  evaluation  of  researches  that  shall  employ  or  develop

                              genetically modified organisms (GMOs).


                          c.  Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee.  The Institutional Animal Care

                              and Use Committee is responsible for the evaluation of researches requiring

                              the use of animals.

                          d.  Institutional Chemical Safety Committee.  The Institutional Chemical Safety


                              Committee is in charge of the evaluation of research studies requiring the use

                              of  chemicals  which  include  but  are  not  limited  to  organic  substances,

                              pesticides, drugs, antibiotics and others which have toxic and/or carcinogenic

                              potential.

                       Section  3.  Duties  and  Responsibilities  of  the  Research  Center’s  human


                       resources

                           a.  Director,  Research  Center.  The  Director  of  the  Research  Center  shall

                              perform the following functions:

                               ●  Lead in the overall supervision of the affairs of the Research Center;

                               ●  Implement the existing policies pertaining to researches of the University;

                               ●  Lead  in  the  planning  and  implementation  of  the  University  research

                                  activities;

                               ●  Lead in improving and implementing the research services as prescribed

                                  in the manual of operations;

                               ●  Assist the development and/or revision/improvement and implementation

                                  of the RDE Agenda and Programs of the colleges in the main campus and

                                  the other satellite and integrated campuses;

                               ●  Lead the formulation of the annual budget and financial plan of the Center;

                               ●  Supervise and coordinate the operation of the newly created Research

                                  Centers;

                               ●  Lead  in  the  formulation  of  proposals  for  the  additional  research  and

                                  development centers of the University;

                               ●  Coordinate with the Center of Knowledge Management in the operations]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[of the CvSU Research Journal;

                               ●  Supervise the implementation of the CvSU Research Grant (CRG), Faculty

                                  and  Student  Research  Capability  Enhancement  Program  (FSRCEP),

                                  Undergraduate and Graduate Thesis Grant, and other research funding

                                  support that shall be implemented by the University;

                               ●  Lead the monitoring and evaluation of researches in the University both

                                  with internal and external funding;

                               ●  Lead the resource generation and linkages with international, national, and

                                  local agencies pertaining to research;

                               ●  Coordinate with the deans of colleges and satellite campuses and other

                                  administrators  on  matters  related  to  the  research  operations  of  the

                                  University;


                               ●  Prepare and submit reports pertaining to research as may be required; and

                               ●  Perform other related functions that may be assigned from time to time by


                                  the higher authorities.
                           b.  Head,  Research  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Division.  The  Head  of  the


                              Research Monitoring and Evaluation Division is responsible for the following

                              duties:

                              ●  Assist the Director for Research in the planning and formulation of short-
                                  and long-term R&D plans and policies, guidelines and work plans related

                                  to monitoring and evaluation of research projects;
                               ●  Facilitate the call for proposals for funding and evaluation until its approval;

                               ●  Implement  policies  and  procedures  for  the  effective  monitoring  and

                                  evaluation of researches;

                               ●  Keep an updated database that will facilitate data storage, processing,

                                  and retrieval;

                               ●  Determine problems and recommend solutions during the course of project

                                  implementation; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                  higher authorities.]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[c.  Research Monitoring and Evaluation Division Coordinator for internally

                              funded  research  projects.  The  coordinator  for  internally  funded  research

                              projects is responsible for the following duties:

                               ●  Assist the Director and Head of Monitoring and Evaluation Division in the


                                 formulation of short- and long-term R&D plans and policies, guidelines and

                                 workplans related to monitoring and evaluation of research projects;

                               ●  Assist in the facilitation of call for proposals for funding and evaluation until

                                 its approval;

                               ●  Assist  in  the  monitoring  of  on-going  and  completed  internally  funded

                                 researches;

                               ●  Keep an updated database of internally funded research that will facilitate

                                 data storage, processing and retrieval; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                 higher authorities.

                           d.  Research Monitoring and Evaluation Division Coordinator for externally

                              funded  research  projects.  The  coordinator  for  externally  funded  research

                              projects is responsible for the following duties:

                               ●  Assist the Director and Head of Monitoring and Evaluation Division in the

                                 formulation of short- and long-term R&D plans and policies, guidelines, and

                                 work plans related to monitoring and evaluation of research projects;

                               ●  Assist  in  the  monitoring  of  ongoing  and  completed  externally  funded

                                 research;

                               ●  Keep an updated database of the externally funded research projects that

                                 will facilitate data storage, processing, and retrieval; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                 higher authorities.

                           e.  Head,  Technical  Services  Division.  The  Head  of  the  Technical  Services


                              Division is responsible for the following duties:]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[●  Assist the Director for Research in the planning and formulation of short-

                                  and long-term R&D plans and policies, guidelines, and work plans related to

                                  the efficient management and improvement of the division;

                               ●  Consolidate  an  updated  inventory  of  the  supplies  and  materials  and

                                  equipment of the different research laboratories and units involved in the

                                  conduct of research;

                               ●  Identify and request facility repairs and/or improvements on a regular basis

                                  (quarterly or annually) and as the need arises;

                               ●  Maintain close coordination with researchers in terms of the use of facilities

                                  and equipment at the Research Center;


                               ●  Take charge of maintaining the common equipment room; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                  higher authorities.

                           f.  In-charge,  Research  Laboratory.  The  different  research  laboratories  are


                              headed by the laboratory in charge of a research laboratory and must perform

                              the following responsibilities:

                               ●  Coordinate  with  the  head  of  the  TSD  on  plans  and  policies,  for  the

                                  improvement and efficient management of the research laboratories;

                               ●  Lead  in  upgrading  and  maintaining  research  laboratories  as  well as

                                  ensuring cleanliness and orderliness;

                               ●  Keep an updated inventory of the supplies and materials and equipment

                                  of research laboratories;

                               ●  Lead the scheduling of equipment calibration in the research laboratories;

                               ●  Take  charge  of  facilitating  and  scheduling  the  research  laboratories  by

                                  internal and external users;

                               ●  Coordinate  with  the  head  of  TSD  to  request  facility  repairs  and/or

                                  improvements on a regular basis (quarterly or annually) and as the need

                                  arises;]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[●  Coordinate with the head of TSD researchers in terms of use of facilities

                                  and equipment at the Research Center; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                  the higher authorities.

                           g.  In-charge, Languages; Humanities; and Social Sciences Research Units.

                              The  persons  In-charge  of the  different research  units  under  Languages,

                              Humanities, and Social Sciences shall perform the following tasks:

                               ●  Coordinate  with  the  head  of  the  TSD  on  plans  and  policies,  for  the


                                  improvement and efficient management of the unit;
                               ●  Lead  in  upgrading  and  maintaining  the unit as  well as  ensuring


                                  cleanliness and orderliness;
                               ●  Keep an updated inventory of the supplies and materials, and equipment


                                  of the unit; and
                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by


                                  the higher authorities.
                           h.  In-charge, Central Experiment Station.  The person in charge of the Central


                              Experiment Station (CES) of the Research Center must perform the following

                              tasks:

                               ●  Coordinate  with  the  head  of  the  TSD  on  plans  and  policies,  for  the

                                  improvement and efficient management of the CES;

                               ●  Lead in upgrading and maintaining of facilities of CES as well as ensuring

                                  the cleanliness and orderliness;

                               ●  Keep an updated inventory of the supplies and materials and equipment of

                                  the unit;

                               ●  Take  charge  of  facilitating  and  scheduling  experiments  conducted  by

                                  internal and external stakeholders that require facilities of the CES;

                               ●  Identify and request for facility repairs and/or improvements on a regular

                                  basis (quarterly or annually) and as the need arises;]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[●  Maximize the utilization of the CES facilities such as crop production, the

                                  conduct of training and etc. when no experiments are scheduled; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                  the higher authorities.

                           i.  Statistician.  The  accredited  statistician  shall  perform  the  following

                              responsibilities:

                               ●  Provide statistical advice and services to the researchers of CvSU-funded

                                  researches  to  ensure  that  appropriate  statistical  techniques  and


                                  methodology are used;
                               ●  Monitor and evaluate the statistical soundness of submitted proposals and


                                  implemented projects;

                               ●  Assist in the operations of the M and E division; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                  higher authorities

                           j.  Staff,  Management  Information  System.  The  staff  for  Management

                              Information System must perform the following duties:

                               ●  Lead in the organization and management of the Research Management

                                  Information System;

                               ●  Assist in the preparation and submission of important documents for the

                                  consumption of the University and other agencies provided that permission

                                  has been granted by higher authorities;

                               ●  Take  charge  of  the  Research  Center  webpage  in  coordination  with  the

                                  University webmaster; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                  higher authorities.

                           k.  Administrative and Support Staff.  The support staff of the Research Center

                              shall perform the following duties:]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[●  Assist the director in the annual budget and financial plan for the Research

                                  Center;

                               ●  Lead  in  the  procurement  of  supplies,  materials,  and  equipment  for  the

                                  Center;

                               ●  Supervise the field laborers and accommodate University  visitors in the

                                  experiment stations;

                               ●  Submit daily/weekly/monthly accomplishment reports as may be required;

                               ●  Lead in the maintenance of cleanliness and orderliness in the stations;

                               ●  Supervise the distribution of office supplies, research materials and other

                                  equipment;

                               ●  Conduct  inventory  of  office  supplies,  research  materials  and  other

                                  equipment;

                               ●  File pertinent documents;

                               ●  Inspect  newly  delivered  supplies  for  the  Center  and  for  other  research

                                  projects as per Commission on Audit (COA) rules and regulations including

                                  the University policies and guidelines; and

                               ●  Perform  other  relevant  duties  related  to  this  designation  that  may  be

                                  assigned by higher authorities from time to time

                           l.  Designated Faculty Researchers. The faculty researchers of the University

                              shall perform the following duties:


                               ●  Prepare and submit proposals for funding;

                               ●  Implement researches aligned with the university agenda;

                               ●  Submit  progress  and  terminal  reports  of  ongoing  and  completed

                                  researches respectively;

                               ●  Publish research results in internationally-refereed or ISI/Scopus/ indexed

                                  journals;

                               ●  Coordinate with beneficiaries in the utilization of research outputs;]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[●  Present  research  results  in  appropriate  fora  except  those  intended  for

                                  patent application;

                               ●  Apply significant technologies or discoveries for patent following the rules

                                  on IP protection and application;

                               ●  Help in the formulation of policies and guidelines relevant to research;

                               ●  Coordinate with the Extension Services for the dissemination of research

                                  results or technologies to the community; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                  higher authorities.

                           m.  Research Assistant. The research assistant of the Research Center shall

                              perform the following duties:

                               ●  Assists project leaders in the implementation of research projects and/or


                                  other research-related activities;

                               ●  Assist in the analysis, and writing of outputs; and

                               ●  Perform other tasks that may be assigned by higher authorities.

                           n.  College/Campus/RDE Unit Research Coordinators.  The college/campus/


                              RDE unit research coordinators of the University shall perform the following

                              duties:

                               ●  Coordinate all research activities of their respective college/campus to the

                                  Research Center;

                               ●  Monitor and evaluate the researches of their respective college/campus

                                  and submit progress reports;

                               ●  Plan and implement activities that will lead towards the improvement of the

                                  faculty research competencies in their respective college/campus;

                               ●  Attend  the  meetings  called  for  by  the  Center  on  matters  relevant  to

                                  research;

                               ●  Submit  reports  required  by  the  Research  Center  for  monitoring  and

                                  evaluation purposes;]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[●  Recommend technologies for possible patent application to the Director of

                                  Knowledge Management Center; and

                               ●  Perform other relevant duties that may be assigned from time to time by

                                  higher authorities.


               Article  3.  Research  Center  Resources

                       Section 1. Manpower Resources

                          a.  Director for Research.  The Research Center shall be headed by a doctorate

                              degree  holder.  The  Director  for  Research  shall  likewise  be  a  prominent

                              researcher of the University. He/she should have contributed to all parameters

                              of the Major Final Output for Research Services (MFO3) in the last two years


                              prior to his/her designation, and preferably has a contribution to the Key Results

                              Area for Research Capability and Output (KRA3).

                          b.  Support Staff. The support staff comprising the center should be of different

                              disciplines related to the thrusts of the University. They shall be selected using

                              the  evaluation  system  stated  in  Sections  1  to  5  of  Rule  VIII  (Terms  and

                              Conditions of Employment) of the University Code. All support staff shall be


                              selected based on the qualifications set by the Civil Service Commission.

                          c.  Designated Faculty Researchers.  Designated faculty researchers shall be

                              selected  based  on  their  research  experience  and  expertise.  The  minimum

                              requirement shall be a Master’s degree. He/she must have the expertise or

                              academic  background  to  undertake  a  research  project  as  demonstrated  by


                              his/her contribution to the MFO3 and KRA2 in the last 5 years. They shall have

                              a maximum of 6 units of teaching load, comprising 25% of their workload. The

                              majority or 75% of their workload shall be devoted to research-related activities

                              that have contributed to MFO3 and KRA2. DFRs are entitled to overload pay.

                              They shall be exempted from conducting extension activities. They shall be

                              selected based on the need for their expertise as determined by the University]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[research thrust.  Any faculty member can apply as DFR subject to evaluation

                              of qualifications, availability of laboratory space, and need of expertise. Their

                              performance  shall  be  evaluated  on  a  bi-annual  basis  by  the  Director  for

                              Research  in  terms  of  accomplishment  of  their  targets.  The  retention  of  the


                              designation  will  be  based  on  their  accomplishments  and  subject  to  the

                              recommendation of the OVPRE and final approval of the University President.

                          d.  College/Campus Research Coordinators. The College/ Campus Research

                              Coordinators must possess the following qualifications:

                              ●  Must have at least a Master’s Degree

                              ●  Must have at least one (1) completed research

                              ●  Must hold a permanent or temporary position

                              ●  Must have no administrative or criminal case

                       Section 2. Facilities. The Center provides support for the faculty researchers in terms


               of its major research facilities and laboratories. The Central Experiment Station is comprised

               of four (4) hectares. It houses automated greenhouses, net houses, and the mixed orchard

               garden.  It  also  serves  as  an  experimental  site  for  various  research  projects  and  field

               laboratories.

                       The Multidisciplinary Research Building (MRB) houses the majority of the laboratories

               of various specialties such as engineering and electronics, microbiology, genetics, molecular

               biology, vaccinology, parasitology, chemistry, and other fields intended to be used for research


               by  faculty  members  and  students  of  the  University.  Experts  (ideally  Designated  Faculty

               Researchers) in the particular discipline shall be assigned to head a specific laboratory and

               shall coordinate closely with the head of TSD who is in charge of the Research Laboratories.

               They shall be the ones to monitor the utilization of the equipment by the researchers including

               the personnel and software. The building has a statistical laboratory; languages; humanities,


               and social sciences units. The MRB also has a Researcher's Lounge where experts of various

               disciplines shall converge to discuss ideas and formulate initial research plans and a modern

               Conference Room where research seminars, lectures, or professorial chairs can be held.]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[The guidelines for the use of facilities and equipment of the Center’s services shall is

               found in Appendix No.1)

                 Section 3. Finance

                       a.  Sources of Funds. Financial resources are generated through grants, donations,

                          bilateral  agreements  and  collaborations  with  government  and  non-government

                          agencies  private  institutions,  foreign  funding  institutions  and  other  research

                          agencies and councils. There are two major classifications of fund sources: the

                          internal and external funds. The internal funds come from the general appropriation


                          allocation (GAA) of the Philippine government. The Center also generates fund

                          from various income generating projects of the University and a portion of which is

                          allocated for the conduct of the University’s research activities. On the other hand,

                          the external funds can come from government agencies such as Department of

                          Agriculture (DA), Department of Science and Technology (DOST), Commission on

                          Higher Education (CHED), and others: private individuals and institutions both in

                          the Philippines and abroad; foreign government, and non-government agencies


                          such  as  United  States  Agency  for  International  Development  (USAID),  United

                          Nations (UN) and others.

                       b.  Handling of Research Funds.  All research funds are handled by the Finance

                          Management Office in coordination with the Office of the Director for Research.

                          Books of Accounts are kept by the Accounting Department under the supervision


                          of  the  Vice  President  for  Administrative  and  Support  Services.  Personnel  is

                          assigned  at  the  Accounting  Department  to  handle  documents  of  all  research

                          projects of the University to expedite processing.

                                     External research grants are treated as trust funds. Funds are released

                          to the Accounting Department by project allotment whereby project/study leaders

                          handle  the  processing  of  papers  to  release  the  fund  meant  for  their  research

                          projects/studies. Research funds allocated  from the income generating projects]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[are also handled by the Accounting Department and managed by the Director for

                          Research.

                       c.  Management of Research Funds. Research funds shall be reported in terms of

                          obligation or liquidation. The Accounting Department monitors the expenditures in


                          accordance with the items in the budget and sub-allotment. Payrolls, vouchers,

                          request for supplies and materials and other obligations of the projects shall be

                          paid through the Accounting Department with approval from the Vice President for

                          Administrative and Support Services following the accounting and auditing rules

                          and  regulations.  As  with  any  government  agency,  expenditures  incurred  in  the

                          implementation of research programs in State Universities and Colleges (SUCs)


                          shall be subjected to auditing procedures prescribed by the Commission on Audit

                          (COA).  The  internal  audit  which  is  under  the  supervision  of  the  Office  of  the

                          President and a representative from COA shall conduct the auditing.


               Article  4.  System  of  Making  Research  and  Development  Plans  and  Research

               Opportunities in the University

                       Section 1. Research and Development Planning Process.  The Research Center

               conducts  research  in  accordance  with  the  University’s  research  agenda  in  line  with  the

               regional, national, and global thrusts.


                       Research planning involves the assessment of the external and internal environments

               and anchoring the results of the analysis with the University’s vision and mission.

                       The external environment refers to the ecological, economic, legal, political, social and

               technological factors that affect the University while the internal environment considers the

               institutional capacity, structure, support, and systems affecting the organization.

                       The  assessment  of the  environment  leads  to  the  analysis  of  the  opportunities  and

               threats (external analysis) as well as its strengths and weaknesses (internal analysis) which


               then leads to evaluation of the gaps in research that should be filled and hence, help plan the

               University's future directions.]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[Section 2. Research Opportunities

                       Section 2.1.  CvSU Research and Creative works Grant. Cavite State University

                       (CvSU) supports the research, development and creative activities of faculty members

                       through the CvSU Research and Creative works Grant.  The grant is intended to bolster


                       the  research  capacity  through  procuring/upgrading  equipment,  supplies  (e.g.

                       glassware, chemicals, media, among others), software and other requirements which

                       in the long run will build the current faculty strengths and establish the reputation of the

                       laboratories/research  centers.  Researches  that  are  in  line  with  the  institutional,

                       regional, national and global thrusts are encouraged. These include creative works or

                       scientific queries that are curiosity- driven (involving basic research), problem-based


                       (applied  research)  or  investigations  along  the  interface  of  traditional  disciplines.

                       Proposals  with  innovative  and  creative  approaches  in  addressing  the  research

                       problem/subject under study and of multidisciplinary and collaborative nature shall be

                       given high priority.

                       This grant will also support high quality creative works, enhancing the overall quality of artistic

                       production of the university. Artistic disciplines include: visual arts (painting, drawing, sculpture,


                       ceramics, and textiles), performing arts (dance, music, theatre), film, video, performance art,

                       architecture, design, creative writing, interdisciplinary arts, media and digital/electronic arts, and

                       new and innovative artistic practices.

                       Overall, this aims to support scholarly pursuits, nurture creativity and innovation and

                       promote a research culture in the University. Eventually, it is envisioned that through

                       the CvSU Research and Creative works Grant, the University’s research and creative

                       works  performance  shall  soar  through  increased  publication,  copyright,  and  patent


                       certification.  The  knowledge  and  arts  created  and  the  technology  developed  shall

                       eventually be cascaded to the community, consistent with the aspirations of becoming

                       a global University in the near future.

                              As a Level 4 AACCUP-accredited HEI, CvSU’s academic standing is measured

                       by the quality of researches and instruction performance; with the weight of research


                       and instruction among the highest in the parameters evaluated and of equal value.

                       This  metric  recognizes  the  synergism  of  research  and  instruction  in  achieving]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[academic  excellence.  To  sustain  an  upward  trajectory  as  a  relevant  HEI,  more


                       research  and  creative  outputs  and  a  continually  innovating  quality  instruction  are

                       expected.

                          Section 2.1.1. Objectives of the CvSU Research Grant:

                              1.  To encourage the conduct of quality researches in line with institutional,

                                regional, national and global thrusts;


                              2.  To provide financial support for the conduct of researches and creative works;

                              3.  To  build  the  faculty  strengths  and  reputation  of  the  laboratories/centers

                                created;


                              4.  To enhance the overall quality of creative/artistic production of the university;

                              5.  To promote a research culture in the University; and

                              6.  To improve the research performance of the University.

                          Section  2.1.2.  Amount  of  Grant.  A  maximum  of  P200,000.00  grant  shall  be


                          awarded per research project  or  a  maximum  of  P100,000.00  per  creative  works

                          project.  A  higher  amount  may  be  granted  based  on  justifiable  reasons  and  the

                          soundness of the proposal. Once all legal and documentary requirements  were

                          accomplished, 70% of the total amount of grant shall be released to the proponent.

                              In the case of projects with a duration of more than one year, release of grant


                          money shall annually depend on its yearly budgetary requirement. The remaining

                          balance shall only be released after liquidating the released funds; submission of

                          progress reports and financial status report; presented the research status during

                          CvSU  Research  Review  or  special  activities  devoted  in  the  monitoring  and

                          evaluation of implemented researches.

                              In  cases  when  a  faculty  researcher  would  be  able  to  carry  out  small-scale

                          researches with a minimal amount such as those that utilize secondary data, basic


                          interviews and surveys, with existing laboratory supplies and materials, and others,

                          a faculty researcher is entitled to request an amount no more than P10,000 (Small-

                          scale CRCG).]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[Section 2.1.3 Eligibility of the Proponent.  Any faculty, non-faculty or research


                          staff  (temporary  or  permanent)  may  submit  proposals.  The  researcher  must

                          possess the following qualifications:

                              1.  Academic  qualification.  The  proponent  must  have  the  expertise  or


                                 academic  background  to  undertake  the  research  project.  For

                                 multidisciplinary  researches,  the  co-proponents  must  similarly  have  the

                                 expertise for the research undertaking. A publication whether as primary or

                                 contributing author on a related discipline as the research being proposed

                                 in a refereed or international journal is an advantage but not a requirement.

                                 For  creative  works,  the  creative  achievements  of  the  applicant  will  be

                                 considered, and the project must meet peer standards of excellence and


                                 be suitable for public performance or publication.

                              2.  Track  record  of  successful  completion  of  research  projects.  The

                                 proponent must have  a  record  of completing  former researches/creative

                                 works whether or not these were funded by the University or by external

                                 agencies. Proof of completion includes terminal report and/or publication.

                                 Those with pending submissions to the Research Center as well as those


                                 with overdue projects will not be given funding until they have submitted all

                                 requirements  due  from  them.  In  the  case  of  Designated  Faculty

                                 Researchers and Professor Level, they are allowed to handle 2 ongoing

                                 researches  internally  funded  by  the  university.  They  are  not  allowed  to

                                 handle more than 2 projects if they have overdue projects funded by the

                                 University.


                              The Research Center, Office of the Vice President for Research, and Extension,

                       and/or the Office of the University President may also directly solicit proposals from

                       qualified faculty and staff as the need arises.

                       Section  2.2.  Faculty  and  Students  Research  Capability  Enhancement  Fund

                       (FSRCEF). Cavite State University (CvSU) grants funding for student researches such

                       as  undergraduate  thesis,  design  projects,  case  studies  and  other  researches  of  a

                       similar nature that are part of a student's degree requirement for graduation and hence,]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[has  corresponding  credit.  A  student  to  be  eligible  for  the  grant  must  have  a  duly


                       approved proposal which is under a faculty member's approved research project. As

                       with the CvSU Research and Creative works Grant, it is intended to strengthen the

                       research capability of the researchers, which in this case are the students. Similarly,

                       these researches should be in line with the institutional, regional, national and global

                       thrusts  and  must  be  approved  by  the  thesis  advisory  committee  of  the  respective


                       college/campus.

                          Section 2.2.1. Objectives of the FSRCEP

                              1.  To encourage the conduct of quality researches in line with institutional,

                                 regional, national and global thrusts;

                              2.  To provide financial support to students for the conduct of researches that


                                 are anchored into an approved research proposal of a faculty member;

                              3. To identify studies with potential for intellectual property rights; and

                              4.  To  disseminate  faculty  research  outputs  through  the  monitoring  and

                                 evaluation system of the Research Center.

                          Section 2.2.3. Amount of Grant.  A maximum amount of P 25,000 grant money


                          shall be given per research study regardless of the number of researchers. A higher

                          amount may be granted based on justifiable reasons and the soundness of the

                          proposal. Once all documentary requirements are accomplished, the grant shall be

                          released to the proponent.

                              The process of proposal preparation and submission of proposals is similar to the

                       CRCG.

                       Section 2.3. Undergraduate and Graduate Thesis Grant. This funding is for students


                       who wish to avail of funding support for their thesis but could not because there is no

                       faculty  research  project  to  anchor  their  thesis  into.  Undergraduate  thesis,  design

                       projects,  case  studies,  and  other  researches  of  a  similar  nature  that  are  part of  a

                       student's degree requirement for graduation and have corresponding credit need some

                       form  of  financial  support  and  therefore,  must  be  considered  for  funding.  Similarly,


                       graduate students of the university are also in need of financial support to complete

                       their master's thesis or doctoral dissertation can avail of this funding support because]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[while these students can seek grants from external sources such as CHED or DOST,


                       these grant-giving bodies are very selective and the evaluation process take some

                       time.

                          Section 2.3.1. Objectives of the Undergraduate and Graduate Thesis Grant

                              1. To  encourage  the  conduct  of  quality  researches  in  line  with  institutional,

                                regional, national and global thrusts;


                              2. To provide financial support to qualified students  for the conduct  of  their

                                thesis;

                              3.  To identify studies with potential for intellectual property rights; and

                              4.  To  disseminate  student  research  outputs  through  the  monitoring  and

                                 evaluation system of the Research Center.


                          Section  2.3.2.  Amount  of  Grant.  A  maximum  amount  of  Php  20,000.00  grant

                          money per undergraduate student per study will be given while Php 35,000 for

                          master's thesis and Php 45,000 for a doctoral dissertation will be granted. A lower

                          amount may be granted depending on the objectives of the study as determined

                          by the Research Center. Moreover, a higher amount may be granted based on


                          justifiable reasons and soundness of the proposal. The source of the funds will be

                          the income of the University.

                       Section 2.4. College/Campus Research Fund. The College/RDE research funds are

                       allotted by the RDE unit as maintenance, operating, and other expenses (MOOE). The

                       college research fund comes from the ten percent allocation for research as described

                       in  the  CHED  Memorandum  Order  No.  20  Series  of  2011.  At  least  20%  of  the

                       college/campus research fund shall be allotted to the conduct of R and D projects.


                       Section  2.5.  External  Research  Grants.  Cavite  State  University  also  receives

                       research  grants  and  support  from  several  government  institutions  as  well  as  non-

                       government  organizations  (NGOs),  and  private  partners.  Some  of  the  government

                       funding agencies that provide grant-in-aids for researches  at CvSU include CHED,

                       DOST, and DA-BAR. Externally-funded R and D projects may be accommodated in a


                       foundation. These need not pass the usual government purchasing and accounting

                       process.  Further,  the  project  leader  and  staff  are  allowed  to  implement  the  project]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[during  official  working  hours  and  allowed  to  use  the  university  facilities.  A  certain


                       amount of the project’s fund is given to the University.

               Article 5. Preparation, Submission, Evaluation; Approval of Proposal; Implementation;

               and Monitoring and Evaluation of Research Programs/Projects

                  Section 1. Preparation and Submission of Research Proposal

                       Section  1.1  Preparation  of  the  research  proposal.  Preparation  of  the  research


                       proposal can be initiated by the Research Center when external funding agencies or

                       private institutions call for submission of proposals or when other agencies ask for help

                       on certain issues that necessitates research investigation. The Research Center may

                       seek the help of researchers in the University in the preparation of the proposals as

                       well as external experts.

                              The Research Center also calls for submission of proposals for funding by the


                       University under the CRCG, and RRG. Proposals then undergo an evaluation process.

                       In  the  event  that  proposals  are  qualified  for  funding  by  an  external  agency,  the

                       proponent can then choose a preferred funding institution.

                              The proposal submitted may be a research activity of the College where the

                       researcher belongs to or it could be a collaborative undertaking involving other units in

                       the University or elsewhere. At any rate, these activities must be coordinated with the


                       Research Center to ensure that the proposals are in line with the University’s research

                       agenda.

                              The proponents shall submit research proposals using the prescribed format

                       (with attachments). All proposals submitted for internal funding should be endorsed by

                       the College/Campus Dean or Unit Head. Prior to submission, all proposals should have

                       been pre-evaluated by the proponent using the Evaluation Checklist of Harmonized

                       Gender  and  Development  Guidelines  (HGDG)  for  Program/Project  Development.


                       Figure  2  shows  the  flowchart  for  the  submission,  approval,  implementation  and

                       monitoring and evaluation of R&D Proposals.]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[Figure 2. Flowchart for submission, approval, implementation and monitoring and evaluation

                                                   of R & D Proposals]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[Section  1.1.1.  Classification  of  Projects.  Proposals  on  any  of  the  following

                           projects (as defined by DOST-PCAARRD) may be classified as:

                              1.  Fundamental/Basic Research. It refers to experimental or theoretical work

                                  undertaken  primarily  to  acquire  new  knowledge  on  underlying


                                  phenomenon  and  observable  facts.  This  can  either  be  fundamental

                                  research  or  oriented  basic  research.  The  former  includes  researches

                                  without immediate or specific application while the latter is geared to come

                                  up with basic information toward the solution of a specific problem that has

                                  not been solved before.

                              2.  Applied Research. It refers to investigation undertaken in order to utilize


                                  data/information gathered from fundamental/basic researches or to acquire

                                  new  knowledge  directed  primarily  towards  a  specific  practical  aim  or

                                  objective with direct benefit to society.

                           Section 1.1.2. Eligibility of the Proponent. Any faculty, non-faculty or research

                           staff (temporary or permanent) is eligible and encouraged to submit proposals.

                           The researcher must possess the following qualifications:


                              a.  Academic  qualification.  The  proponent  must  have  the  expertise  or

                                  academic  background  to  undertake  the  research  project.  For

                                  multidisciplinary  researches,  the  co-proponents  must  similarly  have  the

                                  expertise for the research undertaking. A publication whether as primary or

                                  contributing author on a related discipline as the research being proposed

                                  in a refereed or international journal is an advantage but not a requirement.

                              b.  Track record of successful completion of research projects. The proponent


                                  must have a record of completing former researches whether or not these

                                  were funded by the University or by external agencies. Proof of completion

                                  includes  terminal  report  and/or  publication.  Those  with  pending

                                  submissions to the Research Center as well as those with overdue projects]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[will not be given funding nor will their proposals be endorsed to external

                                  funding agencies until they have submitted all the requirements.

                                      Job Order (J.O) faculty and non-faculty or research staff may also be

                                  part  of  the  project  proponent  as  project  staff  as  long  as  they  meet  the


                                  following qualifications listed above.

                              c.  The  number  of  CRG/RG-funded  research  projects  to  be  handled  by  a

                                  faculty  member  as  project  leader  shall  not  exceed  two  (2).  DFRs  and

                                  faculty members with Professor rank may be a project leader ofmore than

                                  2  research  projects.  The  number  of  externally-funded  projects

                                  implemented by a faculty member shall not exceed three (3).


                                      The Research Center and/or Office of the Vice President for Research,

                                  and Extension may also directly solicit proposals from qualified faculty and

                                  staff as the need arises. Solicited or commissioned proposals are subject

                                  to review for its improvement.

                      Section 1.2 Submission of Proposals. The Research Center requires that proposals

                      shall  be  submitted  in  two  (2)  printed  copies/electronic  copies  duly  signed  by  the


                      College/Campus Dean or Unit Head.

                              All proposals together with the necessary attachments must be submitted to:

                              The Director

                              Research Center


                              Cavite State University

                              Don Severino delas Alas Campus

                              Indang, Cavite


                              Phone: (046) 862-1654

                              An electronic  copy  of t h e  proposal and  its  attachments  may  be sent via
                       email  at: cvsurcmande_proposal@cvsu.edu.ph.


                              Prior  to  submission,  all  proposals  should  have  been  pre-evaluated  by  the
                       proponent using the HGDG Program/Project Development Evaluation Checklist.]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[Only those proposals with complete attachments and which conformed to the
                       prescribed format shall be evaluated.


                 Section 2. Evaluation and Approval of Proposal

                      Section 2.1. Pre-Screening of Proposals. The College/Campuses Coordinators shall

                      facilitate the pre-screening of research proposals to determine the completeness of the

                      submitted requirements, conformity with the format, non-duplication, non-plagiarism,


                      and  consistency  with  the  approved  University  research  agenda.  For  commodity-

                      specific proposals (i. e. kaong, coffee), the concerned Commodity RDE Center shall

                      be furnished with the title, objectives, and expected outputs of the proposals who will in

                      turn give feedback and determine if there is duplication of research. The proponents

                      shall also provide the HGDG Program/Project Development Evaluation Checklist.  For

                      proposals requiring revisions, the proponent shall be notified with the results and shall


                      be given ample time to integrate the required revisions.

                           Section 2.1.1. Evaluation by the Research Center Monitoring and Evaluation

                           Division.  The  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Division  shall  check  the  submitted

                           proposals  and  required  documents.  For  proposals  requiring  revisions  and  with

                           incomplete requirements, the proponent shall be notified with the results and shall

                           be given ample time to integrate the required revisions and requirements.


                       Section 2.2. Evaluation by the Responsible Conduct of Research Unit (RCRU).

                       Proposals shall then be forwarded to the appropriate committee of the Responsible

                       Conduct  of  Research  Unit  (if  necessary)  for  evaluation.  It  is  the  discretion  of  the

                       Research Center to identify the needed review of the proposals. The functions of each

                       committee under the RCRU are described in Article 2.

                       Section  2.3.  Evaluation  by  the  Technical  Reviewers  (TR).  After  the  proponent

                       complies with the requirements in Sections 2.1 and 2.2, the proposals will be forwarded


                       to  the  TR  to  review  the  technical  merits  of  the  proposal.  A  research  proposal

                       presentation  will  be  scheduled.  Quantitative  evaluation  of  the  proposal  shall  be

                       evaluated using the following criteria:]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[a.  Research quality and scientific merit/relevance (50%)

                                ●  Clarity of the rationale

                                ●  Rationality and attainability of set objectives

                                ●  Appropriateness of the methodology

                                ●  Overall coherence of writeup

                           b.  Innovativeness/creativity (20%)

                                ●  Inventiveness of the project being proposed

                                ●  Potential intellectual property right that can be derived

                           c.  Sustainability of research and long-term impact (20%)

                                ●  Potential impact of the expected research results

                                ●  Potential benefit to the community

                           d.  Soundness of targets/deliverables (10%)

                                ●  Feasibility in terms of time period

                                ●  Area requirement and cost

                                ●  Training and technical qualification of the proponents

                                ●  Budget proposed for the research

                              The TR shall also provide a qualitative evaluation of the proposal indicating the

                       comments and suggestions on the title, duration, rationale, objectives, methodology

                       and other parts of the proposal.


                              In  the  case  of  Small-scale  CRG,  the  research  may  not  undergo  proposal

                       evaluation, however it is encouraged that the project leader seeks the suggestions and

                       comments of his peers. An ERB certificate, or appropriate RCRU evaluation, certificate

                       of  non-duplication,  and  plagiarism  results  must  be  submitted  to  the

                       college/campus/RDE unit coordinator who will in turn submit to the Research Center

                       prior to the conduct of the study.

                              Proponents shall be notified of the results of the review whether their proposal


                       passed or needs revision. If it needs revision, the proponent shall be  fifteen days to]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[revise the proposal. Proposals that did not meet the deadline are less prioritized in the

                       allotment of funds and may be required to undergo re-evaluation and presentation.

                              For  research  proposals  for  funding  by  the  college/campus/RDE  unit,  the

                       College/Campus/RDE Unit shall ensure that the proposals have undergone a technical


                       review process.

                       Section 2.4. Evaluation by the Research and Extension Council. The Director for

                       Research shall then endorse the qualified research proposals to the R and E Council.

                       The Council shall then endorse proposals for funding to the University President For

                       final approval.

                              Qualified  Proposals  recommended  by  the  College/Campus/RDE  unit


                       dean/director  to  the  Director  for  Research  shall  also  be  endorsed  to  the  R  and  E

                       Council who in turn endorse to the University President for final approval.

                              Small-scale CRG also needs to be recommended by the Director for Research

                       to  the  R  and  E  Council  who  in  turn  endorses  its  final  approval  by  the  University

                       President.

                       Section  2.5.  Evaluation  of  College/Campus/RDE  unit-funded  proposals.  The


                       College/Campus/RDE  Unit  may  conduct  the  call  for  proposal  for  funding  by  their

                       college/campus/unit. They must ensure that the proposals have undergone a review

                       process. The Research Center shall recommend at least one technical reviewer to

                       evaluate the technical merits of the proposal. Similarly, the HGDG evaluation checklist,

                       ERB  certificate,  plagiarism  results,  and  certificate  of  no  duplication  of  previously

                       conducted research shall be submitted to the Research Center along with the final

                       proposal. All proposals for funding by the units shall be endorsed to the Director for


                       Research by the college/campus/RDE unit dean/director who in turn recommends to

                       the VP for R and E Council and the council then endorse to the University President

                       for final approval.

                              The coordinator shall submit the list of approved researches and final proposals

                       to the Research Center.]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[Section 2.6. Budget Allocation. Upon the approval of the Research and Extension

                       Council, all researches whether funded by the University or by external sources are

                       endorsed by the VP for Research and Extension to the University President for final

                       approval and budget allocation. Researches seeking external funds must conform to


                       the requirements and procedures of the funding agency. For proposals requiring cash

                       counterpart funds, an approval from the Director for Research, VP for R and E and

                       Budget  Office  shall  be  secured.  The  researchers  shall  be  the  one  responsible  for

                       communicating with external funding agencies regarding the status of their submitted

                       proposals. Moreover, the researchers are required to submit to the Research Center a

                       copy of the approved memorandum of agreement, photocopy of the check voucher or


                       other records of fund transfer as well as the final approved copy of the proposal.

                       Section 2.7. Endorsement of Proposal. Research proposals that passed the review

                       shall be recommended by the Director for Research to the Vice President for Research

                       and Extension, who shall then endorse them to the President for final approval.

                              For proposals submitted to external funding agencies, they must pass through

                       the Research Center and OVPRE before its endorsement by the University President.


                       Section 2.8. Processing of Research Funds. The Research Center shall prepare the

                       contract for signature of the proponent and all authorities concerned.

                              The Research Center shall facilitate the processing of the project fund. Under

                       the  CvSU  Research  Grant  and  RRG,  the  release  of  funds  shall  depend  on  the

                       approved line-item budget.

                              In the case of Small-scale CRG, a one-time release of fund shall be given to


                       the faculty researcher.

                              For proposals approved for funding by the college/campus/RDE unit, the R and

                       D coordinator shall be responsible for the processing of funds and follow the usual

                       procurement process of the university.

                       Section  3.  Implementation  of  Research  Program/Project.  After  approval  of  the

               proposal for funding, the project proponent/s must attend a pre-implementation meeting to be]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[aware of their duties and obligations (Appendix No. 2 Responsibilities of the Program/Project

               Personnel) during the period of implementation.

                       Section 3.1. Hiring/Appointment of Personnel and Professional Services. Upon

                       the  approval  of  the  proposal,  the  proponent  or  the  appointed  project  leader  is


                       authorized  to  hire  the  necessary  project  staff  or  experts  required  to  conduct  and

                       complete the deliverables of the project. The hired or appointed staff must be paid for

                       the services they rendered; provided that the terms, conditions, and salary rates are

                       strictly in accordance with the approved line-item budget of the project and following

                       the accounting and auditing rules and regulations of the University.

                       Section 4. Monitoring and Evaluation of Research Projects.  To ensure efficient


               and effective project implementation, monitoring and evaluation of all researches implemented

               by the university shall be conducted by the Center.

                       Section 4.1. Progress Reports. Proponents of all CvSU-funded research projects are

                       required to submit two (2) hard copies/electronic copy of their semi-annual and annual

                       reports duly endorsed by the Campus/College Dean or Unit Head. The proponent shall

                       also prepare their semi-annual financial report.


                       Section 4.2. On-site/Field Monitoring. If necessary, on-site or field monitoring shall

                       be  conducted  to  validate  the  progress  reports  submitted  by  the  proponent.  The

                       schedule  shall  be  set  by  the  Research  M&E  Division.  In  the  case  of

                       College/Campus/RDE unit-funded researches, the R and D coordinator will conduct

                       the on-site monitoring. The assistance of the Research Center may be tapped. The

                       coordinator shall furnish the M and E Division of the results of the on-site monitoring.

                       Section 4.3. Semi-Annual/Annual Review. Semi-annual review and/or annual review


                       are conducted to determine the continuation or termination of a research project. The

                       number of reviews to be conducted annually shall depend on the number of on-going

                       projects. Schedule of which shall be set by the Research Center. Selected members

                       of  R  and  E  Council;  technical  experts  of  the  university  and/or  experts  from  other

                       institutions shall be invited as evaluators during the review.]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[During  the  review, proponents  shall  present  the  progress and  plans  for  the

                       continuation  of  the  implementation  of  the  project.  Evaluators  shall  provide  their

                       comments/suggestions/ recommendations on the progress report and presentation.

                       The  M&E  division  shall  document,  integrate/consolidate  the  given  comments  and


                       suggestions. The same shall provide the proponents with  a copy of the review results

                       for their guidance. For ongoing researches, the proponents are expected to address

                       the suggestions of the evaluators. This will be reviewed in the next research review.

                              The Research Center reserves the right to discontinue the project anytime upon

                       due consultation with the proponent and the technical expert and upon the approval of


                       the President if there is a violation of the contract or if the soundness of the research

                       becomes questionable.

                           Section 4.3.1. Conduct of Research Review. One major activity to facilitate the

                           monitoring  and  evaluation  of  researches  is  the  holding  of  the  CvSU  Research

                           Review. It involves the evaluation of all recognized researches such as those that

                           have  been  given  funding  through  CRG  including  Small-scale  CRG,  FSRCEP,

                           Thesis  grant,  college/campus/RDE  unit-funded  researches,  and  those  that  are


                           funded by the Department of Science and Technology, Department of Agriculture,

                           Commission on Higher Education, and other external funding agencies, that are

                           either completed or ongoing during the particular year under review. During these

                           reviews, researchers present the progress/highlights of the researches. Evaluators

                           of on-going researches may consist of members from the R and E Council, faculty

                           researchers  from  the  University,  and  experts/  technical  specialists  from  other


                           research  and  development  institutions  (RDIs),  if  necessary.  Evaluators  of

                           completed researches are experts/technical specialists from R and D consortia,

                           other HEIs, and RDIs.

                                The mechanics, scope and guidelines in conducting the Research Review

                           are found in Appendix No. 3 (Mechanics and Guidelines of In-house Review).]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[Section 5. Budget Realignment. Requests for realignment of the budget shall only

               be  entertained  at  least  three  (3)  months  before  the  project  is  completed.  Requests  for

               realignment shall be submitted to the Research Center and shall be supported by the following

               documents:


                       a. Request    letter   duly   endorsed   by   the   Research    Coordinator    and

                         Campus/College/RDE Administrator/Dean/Director, Director for Research and VP

                         for R and E

                       b. Latest financial report

                       c.  Budget realignment vis-à-vis approved/released budget

                       d.  Justification for realignment

                       Section 6. Project Extension. Requests for extension of the project shall only be

               entertained at least three (3) months before the completion date.  Requests for extension shall

               be submitted to the University President and shall be supported by the following documents:

                       a.  Request letter duly endorsed by the Research Coordinator and Campus/College/


                          RDE Administrator/Dean/Director for Research and VP for R and E

                       b.  Latest financial report

                       c.  Revised Work Plan

                       d.  Justification for extension

                       There shall be no additional budget that shall be released for project extension. A

               project proponent shall only be allowed once to request for project extension. However, for

               extreme and justifiable reasons another extension may be allowed.



                       Section 7. Change in project title, objectives and activities.  Any change in the

               project  title  and  activities/workplan,  which  do  not  affect  project  deliverables  shall  be

               communicated to the University President, endorsed by the Director for Research and Vice

               President  for  Research  and  Extension.  However,  any  change  in  the  project  title  and

               activities/workplan, which does not affect the project deliverables shall be reviewed by the]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[Research Center and endorsed for approval to the University President. In either case, the

               proponent is required to submit a justification for such change.

                 Section 8. Project Completion/Termination

                       Section 8.1. Liquidation and inventory of supplies and materials. All supplies and


                       materials  acquired  during  the  implementation  as  indicated  in  the  LIB  shall  be

                       acknowledged using supply office form (ARE, MR something like this). These shall be

                       attached to the liquidation report (Appendix No. 4).

                              All unexpended funds shall be returned to the Cashier’s Office and an official

                       receipt shall be properly issued.


                       Section 8.3. Submission of Terminal Report. Not more than thirty (30) days after

                       the completed project was evaluated, five (5) copies/electronic copy of the Terminal

                       Report together with the Financial Report (with supporting documents) duly endorsed

                       by the Research Coordinator and Campus/College/RDE Administrator/Dean/Director

                       shall be submitted to the Research Center.

                              The terminal report will be evaluated, once the project passed the review, a

                       Certificate of Acceptability shall be issued to the proponent.


                 Section 9. Dissemination of Research Outputs

                       Section 9.1. Publication. All researches implemented by the University shall publish

                       an  article  publication  in  a  refereed  journals  such  as  the  CvSU  Research

                       Journal/Philippine  Coffee  Journal/other  University-level-administered  research

                       journals,  or  in  any  internationally-refereed  or  ISI/Scopus-indexed  journals.  The

                       guidelines set by the KMC regarding publication of scientific journals must be followed.

                       Section  9.2.  Paper  Presentation.  The  research  paper  may  be  presented  in  any


                       regional, national, or international research conference, fora, seminar, or meeting as

                       long as full acknowledgement shall be given to the University. The presentation should

                       not prejudice the proprietary/confidential nature of the information for the purposes of

                       IP protection.]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[Article 6. Incentives and Award

                       Section 1. Workload. Workload points shall be given to a faculty member as incentive

               for conducting research projects/activities based on the guidelines set in the Unified Workload

                                                                      th
               System approved by the Board of Regents during its 70  Regular Meeting held on March 24,

               2017.  It  covers  the  core  (e.g.  instruction,  research  and  extension)  and  strategic  (e.g.

               administrative assignments and other services) functions of a faculty member (Appendix No.

               5). Overload pay can be paid to a faculty member whose research workload exceeds their

               regular workload.

                       Section 2. Honorarium.  Faculty or staff is entitled to receive honoraria for research

               activities from externally-funded projects or activities provided that it is clearly indicated in the


               approved  line-item  budget  (LIB),  Memorandum  of  Agreement  (MOA),  or  certificate  of

               compensation.

                       Project leaders of externally-funded R&D projects without honorarium (e.g. institutional

               development grant; in kind grants; conduct of training, workshop, conference and etc.) shall

               be  entitled  to  receive  honorarium  under  the  indirect  cost  or  admin  cost  of  the  project’s

               approved LIB depending on the rules being followed by funding agency. The project leader


               shall receive 30% of the total amount of indirect cost or the amount specified in the LIB.

                       No honorarium from the University’s fund is given to a researcher in accordance with

               DBM Budget Circular 2007-1 Approved on April 23, 2007. Furthermore, all R&D activities with

               honorarium shall be excluded from the computation of work overload pay of the researcher.

                       Section  3.  Best  Research  Paper  and  Best  Poster  Paper.  Every  year,  the  Best

               Research Paper and Best Poster Paper is selected from among the completed researches.

               The selection is done during the CvSU Research Review. The criteria and mechanics are


               found in Appendix No. 6 (Mechanics, Guidelines AIHR).

                        Section 4. Publication Incentive.  A monetary and certificate of recognition shall be

                  given to faculty and staff who published research articles in scientific journals based on the

                Guidelines for Granting Incentives for Publication of Faculty and Staff (Appendix 7) approved

                  during the 63rd Regular Meeting of the CvSU’s Board of Regents held on March 19, 2015.


                      The publication fee may be charged to the project funds, provided that the payment of]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[the  fee  is  within  the  duration  of  the  project.  The  procedural  guidelines  of  this  incentive  is

               detailed in the operations manual of KMC.

                       Section  5.  Funding  for  Paper  Presentation.  The  University  provides  financial

               assistance  for  paper  presentations  in  scientific  meetings.  Priority  is  given  to  researches


               implemented  by  the  University.  Poster  Paper  presentation  may  be  accommodated  if  the

               symposium/scientific  meeting  requires  oral  presentation  “by  invitation  only”,  for  example,

               NAST and NRCP scientific meetings.

                       The  expenses  may  be  charged  to  the  project  funds,  provided  that  the  date  of

               presentation of paper/poster is within the duration of the project. The procedural guidelines of

               this incentive are detailed in the operations manual of KMC.


                       Section 6. Citation Award.  This award is given to a faculty member for the number

               of times the research article is cited by other refereed journal articles provided that CvSU is

               the recognized institutional affiliation of the author/s. The source of data on the number of

               citations is through the Scopus, Web of Science, and Google Scholar Citations. The article

               should not be cited by an article in predatory journals (as described in the Beal’s list). The

               guidelines set by the KMC regarding of citation awards must be followed.


                       Section 7. Outstanding Researcher Award. This award recognizes the exemplary

               performance  of faculty  and  staff  to  promote  excellence  in  research.  The  guidelines  in  the

               selection of the Outstanding Researcher is detailed in the revised CvSU PRAISE.

                       Section 8. Research Utilization Award. This award intends to encourage the conduct

               of researches that are utilized by the industry and other beneficiaries. Assists project leaders

               in the conduct of experiments and/ laboratory activities.

                       In order to be qualified, the utilized output has been attested by the DBM-CHED as


               indicated  in  the  MARC.  The  amount  of  award  shall  not  be  less  than  P30,000.00.00  per

               research output.

                       Section 9. Professorial Chair Award. This award is given to faculty members who

               demonstrate outstanding performance in two out of three work areas of the faculty: teaching,

               research or creative work, and extension. The guidelines for this award are detailed in CvSU


               Sikhay  Professorial  Chair  (SPC)  Award.  The  amount  of  award  shall  not  be  less  than

               P100,000.00 per awardee. Continuity of the award will be subject to availability of funds.]]></page></pages></Search>