<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="59"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.6.            The system of student evaluation and


                        grading is defined, understood and


                        disseminated to:

                        I.6.2.  faculty;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Narrative on Virtual Teachers'




                    Orientation and Capability




                    Enhancement Seminar Workshop



                    held on September 9, 2022]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                                        235-7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph



                            Faculty Orientation and Capability Enhancement Training

                                                  September 9, 2022


                  Faculty  Orientation  and  Capability  Enhancement  Training  was  held  at
                  Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus,  September  9,  2022,  through

                  Webex Meeting.

                        The program started with an opening remark of Prof. Gil D. Ramos, campus

                  administrator, and summary topic such as CvSU - Tanza at Glance, introduction
                  to key officials and support personnel, calendar of activities and grading system,

                  library  orientation,  gender  and  development  in  the  workplace  and  campus
                  extension services and classroom netiquette. It was followed by discussing the

                  test construction, Table of Specifications (TOS), rubrics preparation.


                        Meanwhile,  Prof.  Mildred  A.  Sebastian,  chairperson  of  the  teacher

                  education  department,  discussed  the  content  of  course  syllabus  and  module

                  preparation. It was followed by breakout sessions per department.

                        Furthermore, Ms. Charmaine T. Banag, faculty member under information

                  technology, oriented all faculty members about the CvSU Learning Management
                  System (LMS), its procedure, and imperative feature. Besides, a short tutorial

                  was presented to broaden the knowledge of all participants.

                        In addition, an open forum was conducted to answer the questions of the

                  teaching personnel and to inform them about the upcoming school year 2022-
                  2023.


                        The virtual orientation ended with the closing remark of Mr. Ritch M. Banate,

                  chairperson of department of management.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Introduction of Faculty per Department

































                   Ms. Noemi A. Perida, Campus Registar, discussing the Policies and Grading System]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Library orientation presented and discussed by Ms. Roselyn C. Baltar, Campus librian

































                         Ms. Debbie Rose B. Fabian, HRDO Coordinator, disscusses HR Policies
                                                  including online DTR]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Mr. Roman P. Jacinto III discussing the Gender and Development in the workplace

































                             Ms. Estelita A. Villa, discussing the Campus Extension Services]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Ms. Maria Cristina C. Tagle, discussing the Classroom Netiquette
































                 Ms. Gerry Mae T. Silvero, discussing TOS and Test Construction and rubrics preparation]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Prof. Mildred Sebastian discussing the content of course syllabus
































                                   Ms. Charmaine T. Banag, introducing the CvSU LMS]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[CvSU Tanza Faculty


























               Prepared by:                                                     Certified Correct:



               FATIMA M. DIAZ                                                   MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN

               Facilitator, SDS                                                 Head, Curriculum and Instruction
               Date prepared: September 10, 2022]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Narrative on Virtual Teachers'




                    Orientation and Capability




                    Enhancement Seminar Workshop



                    held on September 2-3, 2021]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                         CvSU TANZA FACULTY ORIENTATION AND RE-ORIENTATION 2021
                                                   September 2, 2021

               Cavite State University – Tanza Campus held the Faculty Orientation and Re-Orientation on
        September 2, 2021 thru Zoom. The program started with the AVP of the CvSU Tanza Campus

        facilities and its development through the years. It was followed by the opening remarks of  the
        campus administrator, Prof. Gil D. Ramos and the introduction of key officials, support personnel,

        and faculty per department.
               Meanwhile, Ms. Noemi A. Perida, Campus Registrar, discussed the academic policies and

        grading  system  and  the  discussion  of  HR  Policies  including  online  DTR  by  the  Campus  HR

        Coordinator, Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag.
               Furthermore,  Ms.  Maria  Cristina  C.  Tagle,  GAD  Coordinator,  tackled  Gender  and

        Development in the Workplace followed by an AVP of the Campus Extension Services lead by the
        campus Extension Coordinator, Mr. Ritch M. Banate.

               In  addition,  a  discussion  about  the  Classroom  Management  in  the  Online  World:  Proper
        Netiquette  in  the  Teaching  and  Learning  Process  was  discussed  by  Mr.  Mark  Joel  C.  Sibulo,

        Department of Arts and Sciences Chaiperson.

               Also,  an  open  forum  was  conducted  to  answer  the  questions  of  the  faculty  about  the
        discussed topics. During the open forum, various questions were raised by the key officials and

        the department chairperson.

               The  virtual  orientation  ended  with  the  presentation  of  e-certificates  for  the  resource
        speakers.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                                        235-7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph



                                 Faculty Orientation and Capability Enhancement

                                                September 2 to 3, 2021



                  Two days Faculty Orientation and Capability Enhancement Webinar was

                  held at Cavite State University – Tanza Campus, September 2 to 3, 2021,
                  through online Webex.


                        The program started with a summary using online quiz regarding previous
                  topic such as CvSU at Glance, introduction to key officials, gender development

                  and  campus  extension  services.  It  was  followed  by  discussing  the  test
                  construction,  Table  of  Specifications  (TOS),  content  of  written  examinations,

                  rubrics preparation and other activities.


                        Meanwhile, Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, chairperson of the department of

                  education,  discussed  the  content  of  course  syllabus,  laboratory  report,  and

                  learning guide.

                        “Learning  guide  is  the  best  materials  and  easy  to  use,  through  this,

                  students will work on their own based on the tasks that the instructor assigned
                  to them,” she added.


                        Moreover,  Ms.  Charmaine  T.  Banag,  faculty  member  under  information

                  technology,  oriented  all  faculty  members  about  the  CvSU  Learning

                  Management  System,  its  procedure, and  imperative  feature.  Besides, a  short
                  tutorial was presented to broaden the knowledge of all participants.


                        Furthermore,  Mr.  Mark  Joel  S.  Sibulo,  chairperson  of  the  department  of

                  arts and sciences, discussed the proper attire, grading system, and netiquettes

                  that  need  to  consider  during  online  class;  and  each  department  conducted  a
                  break out session to deliberate a sample draft of course syllabus, objectives of

                  the department and establish rapport with each member.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[In addition, an open forum was conducted to answer the questions of the

                  teaching  personnel  and  to edify them about  the  upcoming  school  year 2021-
                  2022.  During  the  open  forum,  various  questions  were  raised  by  the  faculties

                  and were answered by Prof. Mildred Sebastian, chairperson of the department

                  of education and other key officials.

                        The  virtual  orientation  ended  with  the  closing  statement  of  Ms.  Debbie
                  Rose Banag, HR Coordinator, gave welcome statements about the newly hired

                  faculty  with  emphasis  that  despite  the  pandemic,  Cavite  State  University  -

                  Tanza Campus will continue serving and providing quality education throughout
                  the semester.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Prepared by:                                                     Certified Correct:





               IVORY P. MOJICA                                                  MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN

               Facilitator, ISPS                                                Head, Curriculum and Instruction
               Date prepared: September 4, 2021]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Narrative on  Teachers' Capability




                    Enhancement Seminar Workshop




                    held on February 3, 2020]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Minutes of the CvSU T3 Meeting]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[1                                  Republic of the Philippines
           2                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
           3                      Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
           4                              235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
           5                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph
           6
           7                    T3 COORDINATORS AND DEPARTMENT CHAIRS MEETING
           8                               NOVEMBER 6, 2020 I 9:00AM I ZOOM
           9
          10   Present:                                           Absent:
          11   Prof. Noel A. Sedigo                               Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis
          12   Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo
          13   Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian
          14   Ms. Lilian O. Sidamon
          15   Ms. Shane C. Hayag
          16   Ms. Rocesvalle J. Caipang
          17   Mr. Mikael Florenz P. Nuestro
          18   Ms. April G. Gile
          19   Prof. Arlene L. Estrada
          20   Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio
          21   Prof. Cristza D.O. Manlapig
          22   Ms. Mark Joseph C. Sibulo
          23   Ms. Erika Joyce S. Senaris
          24   Mr. Ritch M. Banate
          25
          26       The meeting was called to order at 9:00 a.m. via Zoom arranged by Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, Campus
          27   Administrator, T3 Campuses.
          28
          29           Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo, T3 campus secretary facilitated the roll call of attendance. She
          30   likewise presented the agenda as follows:
          31
          32       1.  Faculty performance monitoring
          33       2.  Updates on faculty and students concerns
          34
          35   FACULTY PERFORMANCE MONITORING
          36
          37       Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, pointed out the eight areas to be considered in monitoring the faculty
          38   performance which will also serve as the basis for rehiring or termination of the same. These are the
          39   number of syllabus submitted on time, number of attendance/participation on meetings, on time
          40   submission of midterm exams with TOS or rubrics, active participation in accreditation preparation,
          41   on time submission of modules or learning guides, classroom observation ratings, SET ratings, and  on
          42   time  submission  of  final  examinations.  Prof.  Sedigo  likewise  requested  the  campus  secretary  to
          43   prepare  a  matrix  for  the  above-mentioned  areas  and  facilitate  the  monitoring  of  the  faculty
          44   performance. Dr. Demetillo agreed on the matter.
          45
          46   UPDATES ON FACULTY AND STUDENTS CONCERNS
          47
          48       Prof. Sedigo requested all department chairs to report feedbacks of the faculty and students on
          49   the conduct of online classes and midterm examinations.
          50
          51   TANZA CAMPUS
          52]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[53         Mr. Ritch Banate, management department chair reported that all faculty members were able to
          54   submit their rubrics and midterm examinations with TOS on time. He said that the only concern was
          55   for Ms. Cumayas for being strict but in the end, she also gave considerations for working students.
          56
          57        Mr. Mark Joel Sibulo, arts and sciences department chair also informed the campus administrator
          58   that all faculty members under his department had submitted the midterm examinations with TOS
          59   on time. He informed Prof. Sedigo on the reported cheating instances of the students, however, Prof.
          60   Sedigo replied that it was already expected and was already considered as normal in this time of new
          61   normal.
          62
          63       Ms. Erika Joyce Senaris, information technology department chair started that likewise all faculty
          64   members under her department had submitted the midterm exams on time.
          65
          66       Prof. Mildred Sebastian, teacher education department chair also affirmed that all faculty under
          67   her department had submitted midterm exams on time. No concerns reported for both faculty and
          68   students aside from some faculty had initiated more requirements for the students to comply but
          69   was already addressed.
          70
          71   GEN. TRIAS CITY CAMPUS
          72
          73       Ms. April Gile, management department chair, reported that all had able to submit their midterm
          74   examinations except for Mr. Antonio Pellanes who failed to submit some of his midterm exams and
          75   there are some complaints that he only had met some of his class once and also failed to upload
          76   reading materials and activities during the period and Ms. Galecia who who submitted her midterm
          77   exams late.
          78
          79       Ms. Roncevalle Caipang, arts and sciences department chair stated that all faculty had submitted
          80   their midterm exams with TOS including Dr. Kim who was reportedly not conducting classes to the
          81   students. Prof. Sedigo requested Ms. Caipang to talk to Dr. Kim to address the matter.
          82
          83       Mr. Mikael Florenz Nuestro, information technology department chair, conveyed to Prof. Noel that
          84   all faculty members had also submitted except for Mr. Felix. Mr. Nuestro tried to reach out for Ms.
          85   Felix for several times but did not respond to the messages being sent. Mr. Felix also failed to upload
          86   modules and activities and the exams made for the students were cannot be accessed. Prof. Sedigo
          87   informed Mr. Nuestro that all information on Mr. Felix are all noted and be addressed.
          88
          89   TRECE MARTIRES CITY CAMPUS
          90
          91        Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio, information technology department chair confirmed that all had also
          92   submitted except for Ms. Riel who failed to submit on time but had already promised to  do so.
          93   According to Mr. Villavicencio some student had difficulty in coping up with their classes particularly
          94   the BSIT second year since they have 13 subjects and most of the faculty had only uploaded their
          95   reading  materials  and  activities  and  seldom  conducted  an  online  class.  Prof.  Sedigo  advised  Mr.
          96   Villavicencio  to  encouraged  faculty  members  to  upload  power  point  with  video  and  audio
          97   presentations that students can at least listen to faculty’s explanation on the subject matter.
          98
          99        Ms. Cristza Manlapig, management department chair stated that all faculty members from her
        100    department had submitted the all rubrics and midterm exams on time and that no concerns both for
        101    faculty and students was reported.
        102
        103         Ms. Arlene Estrada, arts and sciences department chair reported that under her department, all
        104    faculty members had submitted their rubrics and midterm examination with TOS on time.
        105]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[106         Prof. Sedigo stated the office will issue a memo to explain for that those faculty members with
        107    student’s concerns and who failed to submit midterm examination on time. He further reiterated to
        108    all  campus  coordinators  that  they  may  require  their  faculty  members  to  submit  monthly
        109    accomplishment report.
        110
        111    OTHER MATTERS
        112
        113         Prof. Sedigo encouraged all faculty members to conduct research and to present the same in the
        114    University Research In-House review. He likewise congratulated Ms. Caipang who just successfully
        115    presented her completed research paper in the recently conducted University Research In-House
        116    Review. Likewise, Prof. Sedigo was also congratulated by all for winning third place in his research
        117    presentation during also in the said event.
        118
        119         Prof. Sedigo also reminded everyone to continue preparing all documents and other materials
        120    needed in the upcoming T3 Accreditation.
        121
        122    No further matter was discussed.
        123
        124    The meeting adjourned at 11:55 a.m.
        125
        126    Prepared by:                                       Noted by:
        127
        128
        129    JESSIE ANNE T. DEMETILLO, PhD                      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
        130    Campus Secretary                                   Campus Administrator
        131
        132
        133
        134
        135
        136
































        137]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-18-20


               To             :      ALL Campus Coordinators, Accreditation Task Force Chairs,
                                     Program Coordinators, Area Coordinators and IT Faculty
                                     Members





               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      CvSU T3 Accreditation Task Force Meeting

               Date           :       24 September 2020


               Please attend the CvSU T3 Accreditation Task Force Meeting on 25 September 2020,
               Friday at 3 o’clock in the afternoon via Zoom.

               For your compliance.

               Thank you.]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-17-20


               To             :      ALL Campus Coordinators, Department Chairs, Program
                                     Coordinators, Area Coordinators and IT Faculty Members





               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      CvSU T3 Accreditation Orientation

               Date           :       14 September 2020


               Please attend the CvSU T3 Accreditation Orientation on 16 September 2020, Wednesday
               at 1 o’clock in the afternoon via Zoom.

               For your compliance.

               Thank you.]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-11-20


               To             :      ALL T3 KEY OFFICIALS





               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF ZOOM MEETING

               Date           :       August 11, 2020


                       Please attend the T3 Key Officials Zoom Meeting tomorrow, Wednesday, 12 August

               2020 at 1 o’clock in the afternoon.


                       The following agenda are to be discussed:

                         1.  Presentation Virtual Schedule of Faculty and Students (Please prepare)

                         2.  Final Course Syllabi

                         3.  Updates on the Student Registration (Preparation and Schedule)

                         4.  Updates on Google Classroom Orientation Schedule

                         5.  Liaison Officer Updates

                         6.  Other Matters


                       Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum

               No. OCA-10-20


               To             :      ALL SKELETAL WORKFORCE MEMBERS
                                     (FACULTY AND STAFF)





               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF ZOOM MEETING

               Date           :       August 9, 2020


                       Please attend the T3 Skeletal Workforce Meeting tomorrow, Monday, 10 August 2020


               at 9 o’clock in the morning.

                       The following agenda are to be discussed:

                         1.  Faculty Loading

                         2.  Faculty Recommendation

                         3.  Virtual Schedule of Faculty and Students


                         4.  Final Course Syllabi

                         5.  Updates on the Student Registration (Preparation and Schedule)

                         6.  Updates on Google Classroom Orientation Schedule

                         7.  Liaison Officer Updates

                         8.  Other Matters

                       Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-09-20


               To             :      ALL SKELETAL WORKFORCE MEMBERS
                                     (FACULTY AND STAFF)





               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF ZOOM MEETING

               Date           :      2 August 2020


                       Please attend the T3 Skeletal Workforce Meeting tomorrow, 03 August 2020 at 1

               o’clock in the afternoon.

                       The following agenda are to be discussed:

                         1.  Final Faculty Loading


                         2.  Faculty Recommendation

                         3.  Virtual Schedule of Faculty and Students

                         4.  Final Course Syllabi

                         5.  Updates on the Student Registration (Preparation and Schedule)

                         6.  Updates on Google Classroom Orientation Schedule

                         7.  Liaison Officer Updates


                         8.  Other Matters

                       Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-08-20


               To             :      ALL SKELETAL WORKFORCE MEMBERS
                                     (FACULTY AND STAFF)





               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF ZOOM MEETING

               Date           :      29 July 2020


                       Please attend the T3 Skeletal Workforce Meeting today, 29 July 2020 at 1 o’clock in

               the afternoon.

                       Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-07-20


               To             :      ALL T3 KEY OFFICIALS, PERMANENT AND TEMPORARY
                                     FACULTY MEMBERS, AND STAFF





               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF T3 ACADEMIC COUNCIL ZOOM MEETING

               Date           :      29 June 2020


                       Please join and participate in the T3 Scheduled Academic Council Zoom Meeting on

               Tuesday, 30 June 2020 at 2 o’clock in the afternoon.

                       Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-06-20


               To             :      ALL T3 FACULTY AND STAFF




               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF MEETING (ZOOM)

               Date           :      26 May 2020


                       Please join and participate in the T3 Scheduled Zoom Meeting on Wednesday, 27

               May 2020 at 1 o’clock in the afternoon.


                       The following agenda are to be discussed:

                         1.  Health Protocols

                         2.  Syllabus and Module Preparation

                         3.  Final Workload Assignment

                         4.  Submission of requirements (Grades, teaching portfolio, etc.)


               Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[1                                  Republic of the Philippines
           2                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
           3                     Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
           4                              235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
           5                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph
           6
           7                           T3 KEY OFFICIALS SCHEDULED ZOOM MEETING
           8
           9                                          May 27, 2020
          10
          11                                    MINUTES OF THE MEETING
          12
          13
          14       Present: All Faculty and Staff
          15
          16       The meeting was called to order at 1:30 p.m. via Scheduled Zoom Meeting arranged by Mr. Keno
          17   A. Villavicencio, IT Department Chair, Trece Martires City Campus.
          18
          19           The meeting started with an opening prayer led by Mr. Luke P. Ty, guidance coordinator of CvSU
          20   Trece Martires City Campus.
          21
          22           Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo, T3 campus secretary, facilitated the roll call of attendance, and all
          23   were present. She likewise presented the agenda as follows:
          24
          25       1.  Health Protocols
          26       2.  Syllabus and Module Preparations
          27       3.  Final Workload Assignment
          28       4.  Submission of requirements (Grades, teaching portfolio, etc.)
          29
          30       Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, informed everyone to comply with the health protocols inside the campus
          31   strictly. The security guards were oriented to check every employee's temperature coming in and
          32   reminded them to use alcohol to sanitize their hands and of the visitors upon entering the campus
          33   premises. Likewise the so-called social distancing should be strictly imposed. Further, he emphasized
          34   that  each  campus  will  undergo  an  immediate  disinfection  with  the  help  of  the  campus  utility
          35   personnel.
          36
          37       Each faculty member is advised by Prof. Sedigo to prepare the course syllabus as early as now. He
          38   reminded all department chairs to give all faculty loads so that they can prepare course syllabi and
          39   modules, which is due on July 30, 2020. Mr. Luke Ty presented a lecture on how to design course
          40   syllabi and modules applicable in today's new normal environment. The approach is blended, online,
          41   and modular.
          42
          43       Prof.  Sedigo  suggested  to  the  faculty  to  be  clear  about  the  references.  References  must  be
          44   coordinated with the campus librarian for listing and acquisition of books. Ms. Villarante, the campus
          45   librarian, agreed and added that references, particularly electronic references, will be incorporated
          46   into the campus e-library.
          47
          48       Ms. Noemi Perida clarifies if possible to allow second-year students (HM and IT) to apply for
          49   graduation or  proceed  for  a  BS  degree. Prof.  Sedigo  responded  with, "yes  they  can."  He  further
          50   reminded everyone that T3 Campuses would not be having midyear classes for 2020. Ms. Feranail
          51   added that the students in the following semesters could take those subjects scheduled for midyear
          52   class 2020.
          53]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[54       Regarding workload, Mr. Ritch Banate and Prof. Arlene Estrada confirmed that they had already
          55   given the subjects to be taught by each of the faculty members under their departments. Likewise,
          56   all other department chairs also assured that they already distributed subjects to the respective
          57   faculty members under their department.
          58
          59       Prof. Sedigo announced to submit requirements or faculty portfolios before the deadline to avoid
          60   the  salary  delay.  He  likewise  asked  why  most  of  Trece  Campus  faculty  members  have  not  yet
          61   submitted their grading sheets. Some answered that they still need to get their student files and
          62   records from the campus to do so.
          63
          64       Also, Prof. Sedigo reminded the department chairs and HR coordinators to finalize the number of
          65   faculty to be hired this First Semester AY 2020-2021 and in as much as possible consider those with
          66   masters’ degree and as well as doctors’ degree. This is in consideration for bolstering the faculty
          67   profile of the campuses and also for long term considerations.
          68
          69   No further matter was discussed.
          70
          71   The meeting adjourned at 2:30 p.m.
          72
          73   Prepared by:                                       Noted by:
          74
          75
          76   JESSIE ANNE T. DEMETILLO, PhD                      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
          77   Campus Secretary                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-04-20


               To             :      ALL T3 KEY OFFICIALS AND STAFF




               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF MEETING (ZOOM)

               Date           :      05 May 2020


                       Please join and participate in the T3 Scheduled Zoom Meeting on Monday, 11 May

               2020 at 1 o’clock in the afternoon.


               Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[1                                  Republic of the Philippines
           2                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
           3                     Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
           4                              235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
           5                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph
           6
           7                           T3 KEY OFFICIALS SCHEDULED ZOOM MEETING
           8
           9                                          May 11, 2020
          10
          11                                    MINUTES OF THE MEETING
          12
          13
          14       Present: All T3 Key Officials
          15
          16       The meeting was called to order at 1:30 p.m. via Scheduled Zoom Meeting arranged by Mr. Keno
          17   A. Villavicencio, IT Department Chair, Trece Martires City Campus.
          18
          19           The meeting started with an opening prayer led by Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo, Arts and Sciences
          20   Department Chair of the CSU Tanza Campus.
          21
          22           Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo, T3 campus secretary, facilitated the roll call of attendance, and all
          23   were present. She likewise presented the agenda as follows:
          24
          25       1.  Midyear Classes
          26       2.  Crisis Management Officer
          27       3.  Work Load and Teaching Assignment
          28       4.  Realignment of Budget
          29       5.  Grades and Teaching Portfolio
          30       6.  Health Protocols
          31
          32   MIDYEAR CLASSES
          33       Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, the campus coordinator, consulted the body to decide whether to have
          34   midyear classes or not. The body agreed not to hold midyear classes this 2020 for T3 Campuses. Prof.
          35   Feranil said that summer subjects could be taken during the next semesters instead if there would
          36   take no midyear classes for T3. According to Prof. Sedigo, the midyear period will be devoted to the
          37   faculty to have training and seminars to prepare for the new normal classes this coming First Semester
          38   AY 2020.
          39
          40   CRISIS MANAGEMENT OFFICER
          41       Prof. Sedigo appointed Ms. Lontoc, T3 nurse to be the T3 Crisis Management Officer. This ensures
          42   the safety for everyone reporting in the T3 campuses once Enhanced Community Quarantine is lifted
          43   and for the strict compliance with the Department of Health's health protocols. Ms. Lontoc added
          44   that she already ordered the necessary materials and equipment needed for the three campuses,
          45   such  as  face  masks,  alcohol,  temperature  scanner,  etc.  Further,  Prof.  Sedigo  requested  that
          46   disinfection for each campus shall be done prior to the reporting of the skeletal force.
          47
          48   WORKLOAD AND TEACHING ASSIGNMENT
          49       Prof. Sedigo asked Prof. Feranil about the status of the Workload and Teaching. Prof. Feranil said
          50   that she already distributed the loads to the respective department chairs; however, none of the
          51   department chairs submitted the accomplished load assignments.
          52]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[53       Prof. Sedigo calls the attention of Mr. Keno Villavicencio, IT Department Chair, to canvass for
          54   Learning  Management  System  Seminars  in  preparation  for  a  blended  teaching  approach.  Mr.
          55   Villavicencio  responded  that  he  already  had  contacts  for  MIS  and  need  to  finalize  the  proposal
          56   content still.
          57
          58       Ms. Jelyn Digma suggested that face to face approach can be adopted only for students who do
          59   not have internet access.
          60
          61       Ms. Arlene Estrada said that it is better if the University can develop one uniform module that
          62   can be used systemwide.
          63
          64   REALIGNMENT OF BUDGET
          65       Prof. Sedigo instructed the Budget Officers to realign the budget, such as the budget for seminars,
          66   trainings, conferences, accreditation, to budget for equipment and other things necessary for the new
          67   normal classes.
          68
          69   GRADES AND TEACHING PORTFOLIO
          70       Prof. Sedigo reminded all to submit the grades and teaching portfolio on time to avoid delay on
          71   salaries, especially for the faculty with a contract of service status. He instructed all department chairs
          72   to check all the requirements of faculty upon submission.
          73
          74   HEALTH PROTOCOLS
          75       Dr. Demetillo, T3 Secretary, presented some of the health protocols and preventive measures
          76   against COVID 19 to the T3 campuses key officials. Prof. Sedigo advised Ms. Lontoc to facilitate the
          77   purchase  request  of  alcohol,  masks,  temperature  scanners,  foot  disinfectant  mats,  etc.  for  T3
          78   campuses.  He  likewise  instructed  the  campus  coordinators  to  help  monitor  in  ensuring  the
          79   compliance of the mentioned health protocols. Ms. Lontoc responded and she said that she will do it
          80   immediately.
          81
          82   OTHER MATTERS
          83       Prof.  Sedigo  reminded  HR  coordinators  to  prepare  a  recommendation  letter  to  rehire  non-
          84   teaching personal with a contract about to end.
          85
          86       No further matter was discussed.
          87
          88       The meeting adjourned at 2:45 p.m.
          89
          90   Prepared by:                                       Noted by:
          91
          92
          93   JESSIE ANNE T. DEMETILLO, PhD                      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
          94   Campus Secretary                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-03-20


               To             :      ALL CONCERNED T3 KEY OFFICIALS
                                     (T3 Secretary, Campus Coordinators, Department Chairs,
                                     Research & Extension Coordinators, MIS Coordinators,
                                     Curriculum & Instruction Head, OSAS Coordinators, OJT
                                     Coordinators, Registrar, HR Officers, & Ms. Belleth Hosmillo)




               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               Subject        :      NOTICE OF MEETING (ZOOM)

               Date           :      18 APRIL 2020


                       Please join and participate in the T3 Scheduled Zoom Meeting on Monday, 20 April


               2020 at 1 o’clock in the afternoon.

               Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[1                                  Republic of the Philippines
           2                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
           3                     Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
           4                              235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
           5                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph
           6
           7                                    MINUTES OF THE MEETING
           8
           9                           T3 KEY OFFICIALS SCHEDULED ZOOM MEETING
          10                                          April 20, 2020
          11
          12       Present:  T3  Secretary,  Campus  Coordinators,  Department  Chairs,  Research,  and  Extension
          13   Coordinators,  MIS  Coordinators,  Curriculum  and  Instruction  Head,  OSAS  Coordinators,  OJT
          14   Coordinators, Registrar, HR Officers, and Ms. Belleth Hosmillo.
          15
          16       The meeting was called to order at 1:30 p.m. via Scheduled Zoom Meeting arranged by Mr. Keno
          17   A. Villavicencio, IT Department Chair, Trece Martires City Campus.
          18
          19           Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo, T3 campus secretary, facilitated the roll call of attendance, and all
          20   were present. She likewise presented the agenda as follows:
          21
          22       1.  T3 Alternative Work Arrangement
          23       2.  Students’ Grades and Status
          24       3.  Grades and Requirements
          25
          26   T3 ALTERNATIVE WORK ARRANGEMENT
          27
          28       Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, the campus administrator, said that T3 campuses would create a skeletal
          29   workforce  who  will  report  to  their  respective  campuses  as  soon  as  the  Enhanced  Community
          30   Quarantine  is  lifted.  Included  in  the  skeletal  workforce  are  the  regular  faculty  members  with
          31   designations and all the non- teaching personnel. On the other hand, all faculty members with a
          32   service status contract will be working from home.
          33
          34      Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo agreed that she would prepare the proposed skeletal workforce with
          35   Alternative Work Assignments for submission and approval of the Office of the Vice President for
          36   Academic Affairs and Office of the President.
          37
          38      Prof. Sedigo also advised the faculty and staff that the end of the semester on April 30, 2020, was
          39   already approved. However, faculty members on the contract of service status will still be on service
          40   and be receiving their salaries until June 14, 2020.
          41
          42
          43      Prof. Sedigo advised the faculty that grades for the Second  Semester, AY 2019-2020, will only be
          44   SATISFACTORY, NO GRADE OR DROPPED.
          45
          46      Prof. Cristza de Ocampo asked about the grades that will be given to the OJT student who has not
          47   started their second phase of the OJT practicum.
          48
          49      Prof. Sedigo answered that in as long as the student had started their first phase OJT program and
          50   had their MOA or MOU, it is acceptable to give a grade of SATISFACTORY. For OJT, EDP, and Thesis
          51   requirements, only  a  narrative  report will  be  submitted  by  the  students  as  compliance  with  the
          52   requirement.
          53
          54      Mr. Comiso asked Prof. Sedigo if the submission of grades and portfolio is online.]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[55
          56      Prof. Sedigo responded with Yes.
          57
          58      Prof. Estrada made a follow-up question to Prof. Sedigo if OJT, EDP, and Thesis narrative reports
          59   will also be submitted online.
          60
          61      Prof. Sedigo also responded with a Yes.
          62
          63      Prof. Sedigo consulted, and the body agreed to have no mid-year classes for the T3 campuses this
          64   2020. He said that First Semester AY 2020 would start in August, and thus faculty members without
          65   designation will be reporting only in August 2020. Further, he confirmed that there is still a graduation
          66   plan, and it will right after when the COVID is over.
          67
          68      All faculty members are required to submit the teaching portfolio containing the following to their
          69   respective department chairs to avoid delay of salary: grading sheet, class record, attendance sheet,
          70   teaching materials, supplemental materials, etc. The deadline for submission is on June 11, 2020.
          71
          72   No further matter was discussed.
          73
          74   The meeting adjourned at 2:30 p.m.
          75
          76   Prepared by:                                       Noted by:
          77
          78
          79   JESSIE ANNE T. DEMETILLO, PhD                      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
          80   Campus Secretary                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-01-20


               To             :      ALL T3 KEY OFFICIALS



               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               Subject        :      NOTICE OF MEETING

               Date           :      19 February 2020


                       Please come for a meeting on Wednesday, 26 February 2020 at 12:00 p.m. at the

               Reading Room, CvSU - Trece Campus, Trece Martires City, Cavite

                       The following agenda are to be discussed:

                   1.  Office Performance Commitment and Review (OPCR)

                   2.   T3 Operational Plan 2020

                   3.  Accreditation/Application for Certificate of Program Completion (CoPC)


                   4.  Calendar of Activities, Second Semester, AY 2019-2020

                   5.  Assignment of IMDU Committee per Campus

                   6.  Midterm Examination Schedule (March 23-28, 2020)

                   7.  University Games/Foundation Day/other-related activities

                   8.  Students’ Insurance/Masterlist of enrolled students(Billing)

                   9.  PDS/SALN (March 16, 2020)


                   10. Flexi-Time

                   11. Other Matters

               Your attendance is required.

               Thank you.]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[1                                  Republic of the Philippines
           2                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
           3                     Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
           4                              235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
           5                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph
           6
                                                             nd
           7                      T3 KEY OFFICIALS MEETING (2   Semester, SY 2019-2020)

           8
           9                                    MINUTES OF THE MEETING
          10              CvSU - Trece Martires City Campus Reading Room, Trece Martires City, Cavite
          11                                        February 26, 2020
          12
          13       Present: ALL T3 KEY OFFICIALS
          14
          15       The meeting was called to order at 11:00 a.m. at the CvSU Trece Martires City Campus’ Reading
          16   Room.
          17
          18           It started with an opening prayer led by Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo, a faculty member of the CvSU
          19   Tanza Campus.
          20
          21           Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo, T3 campus secretary, facilitated the roll call of attendance and
          22   presented the Agenda of the meeting as follows:
          23
          24   AGENDA
          25       1.  Office Performance Commitment and Review (OPCR)
          26       2.  T3 Operational Plan 2020
          27       3.  Accreditation/Application for Certificate of Program Compliance (CoPC)
          28       4.  Calendar of Activities, Second Semester, AY 2019-2020
          29       5.  Assignment of IMDU Committee per Campus
          30       6.  Midterm Examination Schedule (March 23-28, 2020)
          31       7.  University Games/Foundation Day/other-related activities
          32       8.  Students’ Insurance/Masterlist of enrolled students(Billing)
          33       9.  PDS/SALN (March 16, 2020)
          34       10. Flexi-Time
          35       11. Other Matters (request for car service – Tanza; solid waste management - Gentri; solidarity -
          36           Trece)
          37
          38   OFFICE PERFORMANCE COMMITMENT AND REVIEW (OPCR) and T3 OPERATIONAL PLAN 2020
          39       Prof.  Noel  A.  Sedigo,  the  campus  coordinator,  reminded  the  campus  secretary  and  campus
          40   coordinators to review the campus' Office Performance Commitment and Review (OPCR) and the T3
          41   Operational Plan to be submitted to the main campus while waiting for the new format.
          42
          43   ACCREDITATION/APPLICATION FOR CERTIFICATE OF PROGRAM COMPLIANCE (CoPC)
          44       Prof.  Sedigo  instructed  all  the  campus  coordinators  and  the  curriculum  and  instruction
          45   coordinator to prepare and subject all the degree/program offerings of T3 campuses to COPC by June
          46   2020. Further, he said to realign and prepare a budget of P26,000 per program for the application
          47   fee. The following degree programs per campus are to be applied for COPC:  Trece: IT, HM and BM;
          48   Tanza: BM, HM, IT and Educ; and Gen. Trias: Tourism, Psychology, and OFAD. He also requested Ms.
          49   Feranil to prepare the Task Force Committee to prepare the documents and reminded all to be honest
          50   in preparing the documents to be presented to the accreditors.
          51]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[52       Ms. Arlene Estrada reminded all that the schedule for AACCUP accreditation would be in August
          53   2020, and she likewise presented the Committee Task Force for each area.
          54
          55   CALENDAR OF ACTIVITIES, SECOND SEMESTER, AY 2019-2020
          56       Prof. Sedigo presented the Calendar of Activities, Second Semester 2020, and reminded all to be
          57   always prepared for the upcoming activities and deadlines of compliances.
          58
          59       Prof. Sedigo requested Prof. Feranil (Trece Campus), Prof. Sebastian (Tanza Campus) and Dr.
          60   Manarpiis (Gentri Campus) to prepare the IMDU Committee Campus immediately to be submitted to
          61   the Office of the University President for approval. And, they all agreed with Prof. Sedigo.
          62
          63       As  to  midterm  examination,  Prof.  Sedigo  reminded  all  faculty  to  prepare  and  submit  their
          64   midterm examinations with TOS to their respective Department Chairs at least two weeks before the
          65   scheduled exam for review and approval before reproduction.
          66
          67       The University Games and as well as Foundation Day are yet to be rescheduled per campus.
          68   However,  for T3 campuses,  it  was agreed  to  have a  temporary  schedule  for the  foundation  day
          69   celebrations and solidarity programs as follows: Trece: May 6, 2020; Tanza: May 7, 2020, and Gentri:
          70   May 8, 2020.
          71
          72       Prof. Noel A. Sedigo calls the attention of Ms. Mary Ann L. Anonas, T3 registrar, and the rest of
          73   the registrar aid to do the counterchecking of the Master List to ensure correct billing as to the
          74   number of the enrolled students. Ms. Anonas said she had already done the counterchecking of the
          75   master  list.  She  even  visited  the  Gen.  Trias  City  campus  to  ensure  the  records'  accuracy  to  be
          76   submitted at the main campus. Likewise, all OSAS Head and CSG advisers are requested to process
          77   the students' insurance as soon as possible.
          78
          79       Prof. Sedigo also reminded the permanent, temporary, and casual faculty and staff to submit PDS
          80   and SALN to the HR Coordinator to be submitted on or before March 16, 2020, at the main campus.
          81
          82       As per Prof. Sedigo, Flexi-time is still up, and the use of biometrics is always encouraged. He
          83   requested Dr. Demetillo to prepare a letter to ask the qualified T3 personnel to allow Flexi-time
          84   because of the other designations they have. Prof. Sedigo also informed Ms. Hosmillo to request a
          85   new biometric for Trece Campus since it is no longer working.
          86
          87       Mr. Laynes reiterated  that Gentri Campus  could hardly impose  the solid waste management
          88   program since they are occupying three locations. The guards could barely monitor the students'
          89   activities in disposing of their garbage.
          90       Prof. Sedigo reminds Ms. Manlapig to remind the canteen owners about garbage disposal and
          91   Ms. Lontoc, Mr. Cajigas, and Mr. Laynes to monitor solid waste management for each campus.
          92
          93       Mr. Cajigas requested for a truck and driver to pick up the chairs in Las Pinas donated by the
          94   concerned foundation. Prof. Sedigo asked John to coordinated the said request to the main campus.
          95
          96   No further matter was discussed.
          97
          98   The meeting adjourned at 2:15 p.m.
          99
        100    Prepared by:                                       Noted by:
        101
        102
        103    JESSIE ANNE T. DEMETILLO, PhD                      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
        104    Campus Secretary                                   Campus Administrator]]></page></pages></Search>