<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="81"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.7.            The following activities are undertaken


                        to ensure quality in the process of


                        curriculum development:

                        I.7.1.         participative planning and


                                       designing:


                                        I.7.1.2.  faculty;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[C  v  S  U    B o  a  r d    o f   R e  g e  n  t s   R e  s  o l u  t i o n
                      CvSU Board of Regents Resolution

                                f o r   t h e   A p p r o v  a l   o f   P r o  p  o s  a  l s
                           for the Approval of Proposals





                       Bachelor of Secondary Education
                        B  a c  h e  l o r   o f   S e  c  o n  d  a r  y   E d  u  c a  t i o n


                                                                     M
                                                                         a
                                                                 d

                                                            a
                                                              n
                                                                                           i
                                                                                          t
                                                                                               s
                                                                                             c
                                                                                       a
                                                                             h
                                                                            t
                                                                                   m
                                                                                e
                                 r
                              o
                                    i

                      m
                      major in English and Mathematics
                             j
                          a
                                      n
                                                    i
                                                  l
                                                        h
                                                     s
                                          E

                                                g
                                             n]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                               Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                       Indang, Cavite
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
                                       OFFICE OF THE UNIVERSITY PRESIDENT


               OFFICE MEMORANDUM
               NO.: BOR-PHDR-01-2021

               TO      :      DR. MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, VPAA
                              Concerned Deans/Campus Administrators

               SUBJECT:       Implementation of Board Approved/Confirmed Proposals

               DATE  :        22 June 2021



                   1.  Please be informed that the following proposals were approved/confirmed during the
                                            th
                                    th
                       Combined 86  and 87  Regular Meeting of the Board of Regents held on 18 June
                       2021:

                                                              Action of the BOR
                                     Proposal                 and comments /       Board Resolution No.
                                                                suggestions
                        a.  Curriculum enhancements for the
                           following academic programs:

                           •   Bachelor of Science in Applied    Approved        Resolution No. 12-a, s. 2021
                               Mathematics
                           •   BS in Psychology                  Approved        Resolution No. 12-b, s. 2021
                           •   Bachelor of Arts in English       Approved        Resolution No. 12-c, s. 2021
                               Language Studies
                           •   BS Biology                        Approved        Resolution No. 12-d, s. 2021
                           •   BS Agriculture                    Approved        Resolution No. 12-e, s. 2021
                           •   BS Business Management            Approved        Resolution No. 12-f, s. 2021
                           •   BS Development Management         Approved        Resolution No. 12-g, s. 2021
                           •   BS Fisheries                      Approved        Resolution No. 12-h, s. 2021
                                                             subject to renaming
                                                             of the program (using
                                                              Aquatic instead of
                                                                 Fisheries)
                           •   Bachelor of Secondary Education   Approved        Resolution No. 12-i, s. 2021
                               major in English, Mathematics,
                               Filipino, Science, Social Studies
                           •   BS in Tourism Management          Approved        Resolution No. 12-j, s. 2021
                           •   BS Hospitality Management         Approved        Resolution No. 12-k, s. 2021
                           •   BS Criminology                    Approved        Resolution No. 12-l, s. 2021
                           •   BS Industrial Security            Approved       Resolution No. 12-m, s. 2021
                               Management
                           •   Master of Arts in Education major   Approved      Resolution No. 12-n, s. 2021
                               in Guidance and Counseling
                           •   Master in Business Administration   Approved      Resolution No. 12-o, s. 2021
                               without Thesis
                           •   Doctor of Philosophy in           Approved        Resolution No. 12-p, s. 2021
                               Management
                        b. Authority to hire twenty (20) academic   Approved     Resolution No. 13, s. 2021
                           personnel for the following positions
                           who will be assigned at the College of]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                               Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                       Indang, Cavite
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
                           Medicine effective First Semester, AY
                           2021-2022
                        c. Proposal to Operate CvSU Maternity    Approved         Resolution No. 9, s. 2021
                           and Lying-in Clinic
                        d. Graduation of 384 students, Midyear   Confirmed       Resolution No. 19, s. 2021
                           January 2021

                   2.  The Vice President is expected to conduct thorough monitoring on the implementation
                       of the above-mentioned approved proposals.

                   3.  The proponents are required to submit the status of implementation to the Office of the
                       Board Secretary two (2) weeks before the schedule of the succeeding Board meeting.

                   4.  Thank you.




                                                           DR. HERNANDO D. ROBLES, CEO VI
                                                                      University President









               CC:     Office of the Board Secretary
                       Records Office
                       File]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[PROPOSED BACHELOR OF



                         SECONDARY EDUCATION



                                                     (BSEd)


                                       major in English]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[PROPOSAL:             Revision of Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) major in
                                     English

               PROPONENT:            College of Education

               RATIONALE:
                       The need to improve the quality of our education and provide corresponding access to
               Filipino students is deeply rooted in our 1987 Constitution, Batas Pambansa 232 and RA 7722.
                       Sizable  resources  were  allotted  by  our  government  to  implement  various  education-
               related programs to achieve this end the recent of which is the adoption of the shift from expert
               knowledge transmission to learner competency building or outcome-based education through
               CMO  no.  46 s  2012.  This mandate  requires  the  review  and  refocusing  of  the  different  HEI’s
               curricular offerings to be a par with the prescribed international standard.
                       It has long recognized that the most crucial factor in the quality education is the quality of
               pre-service teacher education which it has been providing for more than two decades. It has
               also embraced the important function and responsibility of providing the necessary training to
               future teachers as part of their professional development.
                       Cavite State University through the College of Education established in 1992 as School
               of  Education  started  to  offer  Bachelor  of  Elementary  Education  (BEEd)  and  Bachelor  of
               Secondary  Education  (BSEd).  In  2005,  CMO  No.  30  series  of  2004  also  known  as  Revised
               Policies and Standards for Undergraduate Teacher Education Curriculum was implemented and
               the College started to offer the current curriculum in education. Through the Teacher Education
               Department  of  the  College  of  Education  in  coordination  with  the  other  campuses  offerings
               education programs, the University is working on producing quality graduates in education.
                       Recent developments point to the need to expand the courses offered by the Teacher
               Education  Department  by  offering  additional  major  fields  specifically  Filipino,  Social  Studies,
               MAPEH,  Science  and  Values  Education.  This  is  in  consonance  with  the  needs  of  both
               elementary and secondary schools in their K to 12 program.
                       These imperatives coupled with the recent issuances on different CMO’s that are related
               to teacher education make it necessary to redirect and revise its current curricular offerings to
               make it attuned to demand and needs of its clienteles, hence this proposal.


               OBJECTIVES:
               1.  To produce quality education graduates of Cavite State University
               2.  To respond to the new teacher education curricula based on CMO 75, series of 2017
               3.  To standardize the education programs in the main and other campuses of the Cavite State
                   University


               STRATEGIES
               1.  Curriculum Review Committee Formed
                          The University Curriculum Review Committee was formed by the Vice President for
                   Academic Affairs (VPAA) through a Memorandum No. PHDR-77-17 dated April 25, 2017 to
                   review and revise the current curricular offerings of the university. A meeting was called by
                   the VPAA to orient the coordinators of the terms of reference of program coordinators at
                   S.L. Lasap Hall on June 15, 2017.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[The university coordinators and faculty members of the College of Education-main
                   campus, CvSU Naic, Cavite City, Imus, Silang, Gen. Trias, Bacoor, Tanza, and Carmona
                   held  Curriculum  Review  for  BSHRM,  BSTM,  DHRM,  BEE,  BSE  and  TCP  Programs  at
                   Hostel Tropicana on September 27, 2017 under the leadership of Dr. Editha G. Reyes, the
                   former  dean  of  the  College  of  Education.  Most  of  the  curricular  revisions  of  different
                   programs were based on the draft copies of Commission on Higher Education Order. The
                   final copies of the CMOs were released on December 28, 2018.
                          The participants from the Teacher Education Department were:
                          Dr. Lumine R. Crisostomo          Program Coordinator, BSE
                          Dr. Jane Reyes                    Program Coordinator, BEE
                          Prof. Julie S. Guevara           TED faculty
                          Ms. Edelyn D. Sabilla            TED faculty
                          Ms. Karen Lynn G. Macawile       TED faculty
                          Mrs. Richel Diokno                   TED faculty
                          Likewise,  following  program  coordinators  and  faculty  members  participated  the
                   curricular revisions:
                          Dr. Ligaya P. Antiojo            Naic
                          Ms. Roselyn A. Ymana             Silang
                          Ms. Cristel M. Belaro            Silang
                          Mr. Lambert M. Diokno            Cavite City
                          Ms. Jocelyn B, Siochi            Carmona
                          Mr. Euvard Ross R. Corpuz        Imus
                          Mr. Glenn Bryan A, Creencia      Gen. Trias City
                          Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian         Tanza
                          Mr. Christian Mark G. Lorenzana  Bacoor
                          Mr. Rostum B. Gulmatico, Jr.     Silang
                          Mr. Victoriano P. Barliso, Jr.   Gen. Trias City
                          Mr. Ernesto A. Gutierrez, Jr.    Naic
                          Similarly, The Committee on Curriculum Review and Development was formed by
                   the Dr. Cecilia B. Banaag, dean of the College of Education on January 23, 2018 to review
                   and revise the existing Teacher Education curricula based on CMO Nos. 75, 76, 77 and 78,
                   series of 2017.

               2.  Workshop Conducted
                          The  initial  meeting  of  the  committee  was  conducted  on  January  29,  2018  and
                   attended by the following:
                        Prof. Jason R. Maniacop             Chair, CEd Committee on Curriculum Review and
                                                           Development
                        Dr. Lumine R. Crisostomo           Program Coordinator, BSE
                        Dr. Jane J. Reyes                  Program Coordinator, BEE
                        Dr. Florencio R. Abanes            Committee Member
                        Dr. Isaias A. Banaag               Committee Member]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[On  February  1,  2018,  the  workshop  on  curriculum  review  and  development  was
                   conducted and attended by the following:
                        Dr. Cecilia B. Banaag              Dean, College of Education
                        Prof. Jason R. Maniacop             Chair, CEd Committee on Curriculum Review and
                                                           Development
                        Dr. Lumine R. Crisostomo           Program Coordinator, BSE
                        Dr. Jane J. Reyes                  Program Coordinator, BEE
                        Dr. Florencio R. Abanes            Committee Member
                        Dr. Isaias A. Banaag               Committee Member
                        Dr. Myleen P. Legaspi              Technical Staff
                        Ms. Karen G. Macawile              Technical Staff
                        Ms. Richel P. Diokno               Technical Staff
                        Ms. Edelyn D. Sabilla              Technical Staff

                        The  outputs  of  the  workshop  were  new  program  offerings,  namely:  Bachelor  of
                   Secondary  Education  major  in  Social  Studies,  Science,  and  Filipino,  Bachelor  of  Early
                   Childhood  Education  (BECEd),  Bachelor  of  Special  Needs  Education  (BSNEd)  and
                   Bachelor  of  Technology  and  Livelihood  Education  (BTLEd)  major  in  Home  Economics.
                   These were based on the CHED Memorandum Order Numbers 75,76, 77 and 78, series of
                   2017.

               3.  Presentation of Curricula to the Stakeholders
                          The developed curricula for the three programs were presented to the stakeholders on
                   February 13, 2018 for consultation, critiquing, comments suggestions and recommendation.
                   Present  were  representatives  of  faculty  members,  students,  parents  and  alumni  of  the
                   different campuses as well as from the main campus. Representative from Department of
                   Education and the community were also present.

               4.  Presentation to the College Academic Council
                          The  proposal  was  subjected  to  a  deliberation  and  consultation  with  College  of
                   Education Academic Council on February 20, 2018.

               5.  Presentation to the University Academic Council
                          Outputs of the curriculum review will be presented to the university academic council
                   for approval and subsequent endorsement to CHED and Board of Regents.

               6. Submission to CHED for Review and Approval

               7. Submission to the Board of Regents for Review and Approval


               PERIOD OF IMPLEMENTATION
                      The new curriculumum for Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) major in English be
               implemented  on  the  first  semester  of  school  year  2018-2019  upon  approval  of  the  Board  of
               Regents.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[PROGRAM SPECIFICATION

               Degree Name: Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) Major in English

               Program Goals:
                       The BSEd degree program aims to develop highly motivated and competent teachers
               specializing in the content and pedagogy for secondary education.

               PROGRAM OBJECTIVES
                   A.  Program Educational Objectives
                     1.  Articulate and discuss the latest developments in the specific field of practice.
                     2.  Demonstrate mastery of subject matter/discipline.
                     3.  Facilitate learning using a wide range of teaching methodologies and delivery modes
                         appropriate to specific learners and their environments.
                     4.  Develop innovative curricula, instructional plans, teaching approaches, and resources
                         for diverse learners.
                     5.  Apply skills in the development and utilization of ICT to promote quality, relevant and
                         sustainable educational practices.
                     6.  Demonstrate a variety of thinking skills in planning, monitoring, assessing and
                         reporting learning processes and outcomes.
                     7.  Practice professional and ethical teaching standards sensitive to the local, national
                         and global realities.
                     8.  Pursue lifelong learning for personal and professional growth through varied
                         experiential and field-based opportunities.

                   B.  Program/Student Outcomes
                     1.  possess broad knowledge of language and literature for effective learning;
                     2.  use English as a glocal language in a multi-lingual context as it applies to the teaching
                         of language and literature;
                     3.  acquire extensive reading background in language, literature and allied fields;
                     4.  demonstrate proficiency in oral and written communication;
                     5.  show competence in employing innovative language and literature teaching
                         approaches, methodologies, and strategies;
                     6.  use technology in facilitating language learning and teaching;
                     7.  inspire students and colleagues to live relevant and transformative changes to
                         improve learning and teaching language and literature; and
                     8.  display skills and abilities to be reflective and research-oriented language and
                         literature teachers.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[CURRICULUM

                       The Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) major in English will be composed of the
               following courses:

                          General Education        :                            45 units
                               Core                :       33 units
                               Electives           :           9 units
                               Mandated            :           3 units
                          Professional Education  :                             42 units
                               Theories and Concepts:      12 units
                              Methods and Strategies:      18 units
                              Experiential Learning
                                   Courses         :       12 units
                          Major Courses            :                            63 units
                          Elective Courses         :                              6 units
                          Mandated Courses         :                            14 units
                              PE                   :       8
                              NSTP                 :       6
                          Institutional Mandated  :                               6 units

                                TOTAL              :                              176 units



               ADMISSION AND RETENTION POLICIES

               1. Admission Policies
                    a. A high school GPA of not lower than 85.
                    b. Passing the University Entrance Test with a score of not lower than the set standard for
                        courses with board examination.
                    c. Passing an interview with the Department Chairperson or the Campus Dean.

               2. Retention Policies
                    a.  A  first  year  cumulative  GPA  of  2.5  or  better  with  no  failing  grade  including  grades  in
                        NSTP.
                    b. Passing the Standardized Aptitude Test for Teachers (SATT) before second year with a
                        score equivalent to 70 percentile.
                    c. A second year and third year cumulative GPA of 2.25 or better with no grade lower than
                        3.0 including NSTP.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[3. Transferee and Shiftee
                    a. Transferee  from  other  schools  and  shiftee  from  other  courses  within  the  university
                        system shall be admitted to education program if they have a cumulative GPA of 2.0 or
                        better and with no grade lower than 3.0.
                    b. They are also governed by the retention policies stated above.
                    c. SATT should only be given after completing the minimum number of units per major field
                        including those grades that are credited from previous school or program.
                    d. No transferee or shiftee shall be admitted at the third year level.
                    e. Passing an interview with the Department Chairperson or the Campus Dean.

               4. Other Provisions
                   a. Computation of cumulative GPA shall be based on a minimum number of units per major
                       field per year level.
                    b.  This  policy  shall  cover  only  the  teacher  education  programs  of  the  Cavite  State
                      University System.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[CURRICULUM COMPONENTS]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[BACHELOR OF SECONDARY EDUCATION (BSEd)
                                                      Major in English

                                            Courses                                    No. of      Total Units
                                                                                       Units
               A. General Education Courses (CMO No. 20 s. 2013 & CMO No.                              45
                  4, s. 2018)
                  1. Art Appreciation                                                    3
                  2. Ethics                                                              3
                  3. Mathematics in the Modern World                                     3
                  4. Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas                    3
                  5. Purposive Communication                                             3
                  6. Science, Technology and Society                                     3
                  7. The Contemporary World                                              3
                  8. Understanding the Self                                              3
                  9. Life and Works of Rizal                                             3
                  10. Gender and Society                                                 3
                  11. Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino                               3
                  12. Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino                                             3
                  13. Retorika / Masining na Pagpapahayag                                3
                  14. Panitikang Panlipunan                                              3
                  15. World Literature                                                   3
               B. Professional Education Courses                                                       42
               Foundation Courses/ Theories and Concepts                                          12
               1. Child and Adolescent Learner and Learning Principles                   3
               2. The Teaching Profession                                                3
               3. The Teacher and The Community, School Culture and                      3
                     Organizational Leadership
               4. Foundation of Special and Inclusive Education                          3
               Pedagogical Content Knowledge                                                      18
               1. Facilitating Learner-Centered Teaching                                 3
               2. Assessment in Learning 1                                               3
               3. Assessment in Learning 2                                               3
               4. Technology for Teaching and Learning 1                                 3
               5. The Teacher and The School Curriculum                                  3
               6. Building and Enhancing New Literacies Across                           3
                   the Curriculum
               Experiential Learning                                                              12
               1. Field Study 1 – Observations of Teaching-Learning in Actual            3
                  School Environment
               2. Field Study 1 – Participation and Teaching Assistantship               3
               3. Teaching Internship                                                    6
               C. Major Courses                                                                        63
               1. Introduction to Linguistics                                            3
               2. Language, Culture, and Society                                         3
               3. Structure of English                                                   3
               4. Principles and Theories of Language                                    3
                   Acquisition and Learning
               5. Language Programs and Policies in                                      3
                   Multilingual Societies]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[6. Language Learning Materials Development                                3
               7. Teaching and Assessment of Literature                                  3
                    Studies                                                              3
               8. Teaching and Assessment of the Macro skills                            3
               9. Teaching and Assessment of Grammar                                     3
               10. Speech and Theater Arts                                               3
               11. Language Education Research                                           3
               12. Children Literature and Adolescent Literature                         3
               13. Mythology and Folklore                                                3
               14. Survey of Philippine Literature in English                            3
               15. Survey of Afro-Asian Literature                                       3
               16. Survey of English and American Literature                             3
               17. Contemporary, Popular, and Emergent
                      Literature                                                         3
               18. Literary Criticism                                                    3
               19. Technical Writing                                                     3
               20. Campus Journalism                                                     3
               21. Technology for Teaching and Learning 2
                     (Technology in Language Education)                                  3
               D. Cognate/Elective Courses                                                              6
               1. Stylistics and Discourse Analysis                                      3
               2. English for Specific Purposes                                          3
               E. Mandated Courses                                                                     14
               1. Movement Enhancement                                                   2
               2. Fitness Exercises                                                      2
               3. Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness I                       2
               4. Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness II                      2
               5. National Service Training Program 1                                    3
               6. National Service Training Program 2                                    3
               F. Institutional Mandated Courses                                                        6
               1. Competency Appraisal 1                                                 3
               2. Competency Appraisal 2                                                 3
               3. Institutional Orientation 1                                            (1)
                                                                                         TOTAL      176 units]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[COMPARISON OF PROPOSED AND


                                      EXISTING CURRICULUM]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[BACHELOR OF SECONDARY EDUCATION (BSEd)
                                                      major in English

                                                                              NO. OF UNITS
                                COURSES                       CMO # 75, s.       Existing        Proposed
                                                                  2017
                                                                   36                               45
                                                               (based on                         (based on
               A. GENERAL EDUCATION COURSES                    CMO 20, s.           57          CMO 20, s.
                                                              2013 & CMO                       2013 & CMO
                                                               4, s. 2018)                       4, s. 2018)
               B. PROFESSIONAL/FUNDAMENTAL                                          51
                   COURSES
                    A. Theory/Concept Courses                      42               12              42
                    B. Methods/Strategies Courses                                   27
                    C. Field Study Courses                                          12
               C. Major Courses                                    63               69              63
               D. Cognate/Elective Courses                         6                                 6
               E. Mandated Courses                                 14               14              14
                    A. Physical Education                          8                8                8
                    B. NSTP                                        6                6                6
               F. Institutional Mandated Courses
                   (Competency Appraisal and Institutional         0                6                6
                   Orientation)


                                                   TOTAL          161              197              176




                                                   SUMMARY OF UNITS

                                                                                     Offering
                                      COURSES
                                                                                CMO # 75, s. 2017
                                                                                        36
               I. General Education Courses                                (based on CMO 20, s. 2013 &
                                                                                 CMO 4, s. 2018)
               II. Professional Education Courses                                       42
                    A. Foundation Courses/Theories and Concepts                         12
                    B. Pedagogical Content Knowledge                                    18
                    C. Experiential Learning                                            12
               III. Major Courses                                                       63
               IV. Cognate/Elective Courses                                              6
               V. Mandated Courses                                                      14
                    A. Physical Education                                                8
                    B. NSTP                                                              6
               VI. Institutional Mandated Courses (Competency                            6
                   Appraisal and Institutional Orientation)
                                                                TOTAL                   176]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[BREAKDOWN OF COURSES]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Indang, Cavite

               Curriculum:                  BACHELOR OF SECONDARY EDUCATION (BSEd)
                                            major in English
               Number of Years:             Four (4) years
               Responsible College:         College of Education


                                               BREAKDOWN OF COURSES

                   I.  GENERAL EDUCATION COURSES (CMO No. 20 s. 2013 & CMO No. 4, s. 2018)

                 Course                         Course Title                      Lecture     Lab.     Credit
                  Code                                                             Hours     Hours     Units
               GNED 01       Art Appreciation                                         3         0        3
               GNED 02       Ethics                                                   3         0        3
               GNED 03       Mathematics in the Modern World                          3         0        3
               GNED 04       Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas         3         0        3
               GNED 05       Purposive Communication                                  3         0        3
               GNED 06       Science, Technology and Society                          3         0        3
               GNED 07       The Contemporary World                                   3         0        3
               GNED 08       Understanding the Self                                   3         0        3
               GNED 09       Life and Works of Rizal                                  3         0        3
               GNED 10       Gender and Society                                       3         0        3
               GNED 11       Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino              3         0        3
               GNED 12       Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino                                   3         0        3
               GNED 13       Retorika / Masining na Pagpapahayag                      3         0        3
               GNED 14       Panitikang Panlipunan                                    3         0        3
               GNED 15       World Literature                                         3         0        3
                                                                         TOTAL                             45


                   II.  PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION COURSES

                   A.  Foundation Courses/ Theories and Concepts
                             Child and Adolescent Learners and Learning
               EDUC 50                                                                3         0        3
                             Principles
               EDUC 55       The Teaching Profession                                  3         0        3
                             The Teacher and The Community, School Culture
               EDUC 60                                                                3         0        3
                             and Organizational Leadership
               EDUC 65       Foundation of Special and Inclusive Education            3         0        3
                                                                         TOTAL                             12
                   B.  Pedagogical Content Knowledge
               EDUC 70       Facilitating Learner-Centered Teaching                   3         0        3
               EDUC 75       Assessment in Learning 1                                 3         0        3
               EDUC 80       Assessment in Learning 2                                 3         0        3
               EDUC 85       Technology for Teaching and Learning 1                   3         0        3
               EDUC 90       The Teacher and The School Curriculum                    3         0        3]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Building and Enhancing New Literacies Across the
               EDUC 95                                                                3         0        3
                             Curriculum
                                                                         TOTAL                             18
                   C.  Experiential Learning
                             Field Study 1 - Observations of Teaching-Learning        3         0        3
               EDFS 21
                             in Actual School Environment
                             Field Study 2 - Participation and Teaching               3         0        3
               EDFS 22
                             Assistantship
                                                                                      0        40        6
               EDFS 23       Teaching Internship
                                                                                            hrs/week
                                                                         TOTAL                             12


                   III.  MAJOR COURSES

               BSEE 21       Introduction to Linguistics                              3         0        3
               BSEE 22       Language, Culture, and Society                           3         0        3
               BSEE 23       Structure of English                                     3         0        3
                             Principles and Theories of Language Acquisition
               BSEE 24                                                                3         0        3
                             and Learning
                             Language Programs and Policies in Multilingual
               BSEE 25                                                                3         0        3
                             Societies
               BSEE 26       Language Learning Materials Development                  3         0        3
               BSEE 27       Teaching and Assessment of Literature Studies            3         0        3
               BSEE 28       Teaching and Assessment of the Macro Skills              3         0        3
               BSEE 29       Teaching and Assessment of Grammar                       3         0        3
               BSEE 30       Speech and Theater Arts                                  3         0        3
               BSEE 31       Language Education Research                              3         0        3
               BSEE 32       Children and Adolescent Literature                       3         0        3
               BSEE 33       Mythology and Folklore                                   3         0        3
               BSEE 34       Survey of Philippine Literature in English               3         0        3
               BSEE 35       Survey of Afro-Asian Literature                          3         0        3
               BSEE 36       Survey of English and American Literature                3         0        3
               BSEE 37       Contemporary, Popular, and Emergent Literature           3         0        3
               BSEE 38       Literary Criticism                                       3         0        3
               BSEE 39       Technical Writing                                        3         0        3
               BSEE 40       Campus Journalism                                        3         0        3
                             Technology for Teaching and Learning 2
               BSEE 41                                                                3         0        3
                             (Technology in Language Education)
                                                                         TOTAL                             63

                   IV. ELECTIVE COURSES

               BSEE 110      Stylistics and Discourse Analysis                        3         0        3
               BSEE 111      English for Specific Purposes                            3         0        3
                                                                         TOTAL                              6]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[V.  MANDATED COURSES

               FITT 1        Movement Enhancement                                     2         0        2
               FITT 2        Fitness Exercises                                        2         0        2
               FITT 3        Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness I         2         0        2
               FITT 4        Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness II        2         0        2
               NSTP 1        National Service Training Program 1                      3         0        3
               NSTP 2        National Service Training Program 2                      3         0        3
                                                                         TOTAL                             14

                   VI. INSTITUTIONAL MANDATED COURSES

               EDUC 197      Competency Appraisal 1                                   3         0        3
               EDUC 198      Competency Appraisal 2                                   3         0        3
               CVSU 101      Institutional Orientation 1                              1         0        (1)
                                                                         TOTAL                              6

                                      TOTAL NUMBER OF UNITS                                              176]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[COURSE DESCRIPTIONS]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[GENERAL EDUCATION COURSES (CMO No. 20, series of 2013 & CMO No. 4, s. 2018

                   Course Code       GNED 01
                   Course Title      Art Appreciation
                   Course            Nature, function and appreciation of the arts in contemporary society
                   Description
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       GNED 02
                   Course Title      Ethics
                   Course            Principles of ethical behavior in modern society, and in interaction with
                   Description       the environment and other shared resources.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Title      GNED 03
                   Course Title      Mathematics in the Modern World
                   Course            Nature of mathematics, appreciation of its practical, intellectual and
                   Description       aesthetic dimensions, and application of mathematical tools in daily life.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       GNED 04
                   Course Title      Mga Babasahing Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas
                   Course            Mga piling primaryang sanggunian ukol sa iba’t-ibang yugto ng
                   Description       kasaysayan ng Pilipinas, pagsusuri at interpretasyon.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       GNED 05
                   Course Title      Purposive Communication
                   Course            Writing,  speaking  and  presenting  to  different  audiences  for  various
                   Description       purposes.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Course Code       GNED 06
                   Course Title      Science, Technology, and Society
                   Course            Interactions  between  science  and  technology  and  social,  cultural,
                   Description       political and economic contexts which shape and are shaped by them;
                                     specific  examples  throughout  human  history  of  scientific  and
                                     technological developments.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       GNED 07
                   Course Title      The Contemporary World
                   Course            Globalization and its impact on individuals, societies, and communities
                   Description       challenges, and responses.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       GNED 08
                   Course Title      Understanding the Self
                   Course            Nature of identity; factors and forces that affect the development and
                   Description       maintenance of personal identity
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       GNED 09
                   Course Title      Life and Works of Rizal
                   Course            Life, works and writings of Rizal with emphasis on his principles, ideals,
                   Description       and teaching, towards the development and progress of this country.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite      GNED 04  - Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas

                   Course Code       GNED 10
                   Course Title      Gender and Society
                   Course            Gender  as  a  social  construction,  its  role  in  and  impact  on  different
                   Description       facets of societal life.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Course Code       GNED 11
                   Course Title      Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino
                   Course            Isang  praktikal  na  kursong  nagpapalawak  at  nagpapalalim  sa
                   Description       kontekstwalisadong  komunikasyon  sa  wikang  Filipino  ng  mga
                                     mamamayang Pilipino sa kani-kanilang mga komunidad sa partikular,
                                     at sa buong lipunang Pilipino sa pangkalahatan. Nakatuon ang kursong
                                     ito  sa  makrokasanayang  pakikinig  at  pagsasalita,  gayundin  sa
                                     kasanayan sa paggamit ng iba’t ibang tradisyonal at modernong midya
                                     na  makabuluhan  sa  kontekstong  Pilipino  sa  iba’t  ibang  antas  at
                                     larangan.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       GNED 12
                   Course Title      Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino
                   Course            Isang  maagwat  na  kursong  nagpapalawak  at  nagpapalalim  sa
                   Description       kasanayan  sa  malalim  at  mapanuring  pagbasa,  pagsulat,  at
                                     pananaliksik  sa  wikang  Filipino  sa  iba’t-ibang  larangan,  sa  konteksto
                                     ng kontemporaryong sitwasyon at mga pangangailangan ng bansa at
                                     ng mga mamamayang Pilipino.  Partikular na nakatuon ang kursong ito
                                     sa  makrokasanayang  pagbasa  at  pagsulat,  gamit  ang  mga
                                     makabuluhang  panananaliksik  sa  wikang  Filipino,  bilang  lunsaran  ng
                                     pagpapalawak  at  pagpapalalim  sa  kasanayan,  kakayahan  at
                                     kamalayan  ng  mga  estudyante  na  malikhain  at  mapanuring
                                     makapagdalumat o “makapag-teorya” sa wikang Filipino, batay sa mga
                                     piling lokal at dayuhang konsepto at teorya na akma sa konteksto ng
                                     komunidad at bansa.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite      GNED 11 – Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino

                   Course Code       GNED 13
                   Course Title      Retorika / Masining ng Pagpapahayag
                   Course            Pag-aaral ng mga prinsipyo ng masining na pagpapahayag sa Filipino.
                   Description       Nakatuon  ito  sa  malayang  pagtuklas  at  pagpapakita  ng  sariling
                                     kakayahan at talino sa pasulat at pasalitang pagpapahayag.  Lilinang
                                     ang  kursong  ito  ng  mga  kasanayan  sa  pasalita  at  pasulat  na
                                     pagpapahayag  ng  mga  mag-aaral  bilang           isang   indibidwal,
                                     mamamayan ng isang bansa at bahagi ng isang global na komunidad.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite      GNED 11 - Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino
                                     GNED 12 - Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Course Code       GNED 14
                   Course Title      Panitikang Panlipunan
                   Course            Isang kurso sa pag-aaral at paglikha ng panitikang Filipino na nakatuon
                   Description       sa  kabuluhang  panlipunan  ng  mga  tekstong  literari  sa  iba’t  ibang
                                     bahagi ng kasaysayan ng bansang Pilipinas. Sinasaklaw nito ang mga
                                     isyung  panlipunan  na  tinalakay  ng  mga  akdang  Filipino  tulad  ng
                                     kahirapan, malawak na agwat ng mayayaman at mahirap, reporma sa
                                     lupa,   globalisasyon,   pagsasamantala     sa   mga  manggagawa,
                                     karapatang  pantao,  isyung  pangkasarian,  sitwasyon  ng  mga  pangkat
                                     minorya at / o marhinalisado, at iba pa.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       GNED 15
                   Course Title      World Literature
                   Course            A  survey  of  world  literature  including  short  stories,  poetry,  novels,
                   Description       drama, and non-fiction.  Emphasis is on the exploration and discussion
                                     of human and moral qualities revealed through literature.
                   Course Credit     3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite


                  PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION COURSES (CMO No. 75, s. 2017)

                   Course Code       EDUC 50
                   Course Title      The Child and Adolescent Learners and Learning Principle
                   Course            This  course  focuses  on  child  and  adolescent  development  with
                   Description       emphasis  on  current  research  and  theory  on  biological,  linguistic,
                                     cognitive,  social  and  emotional  dimensions  of  development.  Further,
                                     this  includes  factors  that  affect  the  progress  of  development  of  the
                                     learners and shall include appropriate pedagogical principles for each
                                     developmental level.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Course Code       EDUC 55
                   Course Title      The Teaching Profession
                   Course            This course deals with the teacher as a person and as a professional
                   Description       within  the  context  of  national  teacher  standards  and  global  teachers’
                                     standards  and  educational  philosophies.  It  will  include  professional
                                     ethics,  core  values,  awareness  of  professional  rights,  privileges  and
                                     responsibilities  as  well  as  the  teachers’  roles  in  the  society  as  a
                                     transformative agent of change.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       EDUC 60
                   Course Title      The  Teacher  and  the  Community,  School  Culture  and
                                     Organizational Leadership
                   Course            This course focuses on society as a context upon which the schools
                   Description       have  been  established.  Educational  philosophies  that  are  related  to
                                     society as a foundation of schools and schooling shall be emphasized.
                                     Further,  principles  and  theories  on  school  culture,  and  organizational
                                     leadership  shall  be  included  to  prepare  prospective  teachers  to
                                     become school leaders and managers.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite


                   Course Code       EDUC 65
                   Course Title      Foundation of Special and Inclusive Education
                   Course            This course shall deal  with philosophies, theories and legal bases of
                   Description       special  needs  and  inclusive  education,  typical  and  atypical
                                     development  of  children,  learning  characteristics  of  students  with
                                     special educational needs (gifted and talented, learners with difficulty
                                     seeing,  learners  with  difficulty  hearing,  learners  with  difficulty
                                     communicating,  learners  with  difficulty  walking/moving,  learners  with
                                     difficulty  remembering  and  focusing,  learners  with  difficulty  with  self-
                                     care)  and  strategies  in  teaching  and  managing  these  learners  in  the
                                     regular class.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Course Code       EDUC 70
                   Course Title      Facilitating Learner-Centered Teaching
                   Course            This  course  explores  the  fundamental  principles,  processes  and
                   Description       practices  anchored  on  learner-centeredness  and  other  educational
                                     psychologies  as  these  apply  to  facilitate  various  teaching-learning
                                     delivery modes to enhance learning,
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       EDUC 75
                   Course Title      Assessment of Learning 1
                   Course            This  is  a  course  that  focuses  on  the  principles,  development  and
                   Description       utilization  of  conventional  assessment  tools  to  improve  the  teaching-
                                     learning process.  It emphasizes on the use of assessment of, as, and
                                     for, in measuring knowledge, comprehension and other thinking skills
                                     in the cognitive, psychomotor or affective domains.  It allows students
                                     to go through the standard steps in test construction and development
                                     and the application in grading systems.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       EDUC 80
                   Course Title      Assessment of Learning 2
                   Course            This  is  a  course  that  focuses  on  the  principles,  development  and
                   Description       utilization  of  alternative  forms  of  assessment  in  measuring  authentic
                                     learning.    It  emphasizes  on  how  to  assess  process-  and  product-
                                     oriented learning outcomes as well as affective learning.  Students will
                                     experience  how  to  develop  rubrics  and  other  assessment  tools  for
                                     performance-based and product-based assessment.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Course Code       EDUC 85
                   Course Title      Technology for Teaching and Learning 1
                   Course            This is an introductory course that explores basic knowledge, skills and
                   Description       values in the use of technology for teaching and learning.  It includes
                                     ICT  policies  and  safety  issues,  media  and  technology  in  various
                                     content areas, learning theories and principles in the use of design of
                                     learning lessons, teaching-learning experiences and assessment tasks
                                     that  utilize  appropriate  traditional  and  innovative  technologies  with
                                     social, ethical and legal responsibility in the use of technology tools and
                                     resources.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       EDUC 90
                   Course Title      The Teacher and the Curriculum
                   Course            This  course  includes  the  fundamental  concepts  and  principles  in
                   Description       curriculum  and  curriculum  development  as  a  foundation  to  engage
                                     prospective  teachers  as  curricularists.    The  more  active  role  of  the
                                     teacher in planning., implementing and evaluating school-curriculum as
                                     well as in managing school curriculum change vis-à-vis various context
                                     of teaching-learning and curricular reforms shall be given emphasis.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code       EDUC 95
                   Course Title      Building and Enhancing Literacy Across Curriculum
                   Course            This  course  introduces  the  concepts  of  new  literacies  in  the  21
                                                                                                          st
                   Description       century as an evolving social phenomena and shared cultural practices
                                     across  learning  areas.    The  21   century  literacies  shall  include  (a)
                                                                      st
                                     globalization  and  multi-cultural  literacy,  (b)  social  literacy,  (c)  media
                                     literacy, (d) financial  literacy,  (e) cyber literacy/digital  literacy, (f) eco-
                                     literacy  and  (g)  arts  and  creativity  literacy.    Field  based-
                                     interdisciplinary  explorations  and  other  teaching  strategies  shall  be
                                     used in this course.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours
                   Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Course Code       EDFS 21
                   Course Title      Field Study 1 – Observation of Teaching-Learning in Actual School
                                     Environment

                   Course            This is the first experiential course which will immerse a future teacher to
                   Description       actual  classroom  situation  and  learning  environment  where  direct
                                     observation  of  teaching  and  learning  episodes  that  focuses  on  the
                                     application  of  educational  theories  learned  in  content  and  pedagogy
                                     courses will be made.  Observations on learners’ behavior, motivation,
                                     teachers’ strategies of teaching, classroom management, assessment in
                                     learning  among  others  shall  be  given  emphasis.    A  portfolio  shall  be
                                     required in the course.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite      All professional and major/specialization subjects

                   Course Code       EDFS 22
                   Course Title      Field Study 2 – Participation and Teaching Assistantship
                   Course            This is course is a continuation of Field Study 1.  It is school based and
                   Description       allows a pre-service student to participate and assist in a limited actual
                                     teaching-learning  activities  that  relate  to  assessment  of  learning,
                                     preparation  of  instruction  materials,  preparation  of  the  bulletin  boards,
                                     and  other  routines  in  the  classroom.    A  portfolio  which  will  contain
                                     sample lesson or learning plans and demonstration teaching of at least
                                     one subject content area will be required.  An action research shall be
                                     encouraged to start in this course and conclude during the internship.
                   Course Credits  3 units
                   Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite      All professional subjects and major subjects

                   Course Code       EDFS 23
                   Course Title      Teaching Internship
                   Course            This  course  is  a  one-semester  full  time  teaching  internship  in  basic
                   Description       education schools using a clinical approach under the mentorship of a
                                     cooperating teacher.  Teaching internship shall be done both in the in-
                                     campus or off-campus if possible.  No academic courses shall be taken
                                     together with Teaching Internship.  A teaching portfolio shall be required
                                     and the completion of the Action Research.
                   Course Credits  6 units
                   Contact Hours     40 hours per week full time (no academic units allowed)
                   Prerequisite      Field Study 1 & 2]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[MAJOR COURSES

                  Course Code        BSEE 21
                  Course Title       Introduction to Linguistics
                  Course             Provides  an  overview  of  linguistics  as  a  discipline,  its  development,
                  Description        levels  of  structure,  and  its  significance  to  English  language  teaching.
                                     (EK1, ES1)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       All Content Courses

                  Course Code        BSEE 22
                  Course Title       Language, Culture and Society
                  Course             Explores  the  inextricable  link  between  and  among  language,  culture,
                  Description        and  society  and  its  implications  to  the  development  of  English  as  a
                                     global language and the ways by which it is learned and taught. (EK1,
                                     EA2)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 21 – Introduction to Linguistics

                  Course Code        BSEE 23
                  Course Title       Structures of English
                  Course             Develops  the  ability  to  use  the  phonological,  lexical,  syntactic,  and
                  Description        semantic structures of English with ease and explain the form, meaning,
                                     and use of their elements. (EK1, ES1)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 21 – Introduction to Linguistics


                  Course Code        BSEE 24
                  Course Title       Principles and Theories of Language Acquisition and Learning
                  Course             Examines principles, factors, and contexts of language acquisition and
                  Description        learning based on theories and research findings. (EK1, EA2)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 22 – Language, Culture and Society]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Course Code        BSEE 25
                  Course Title       Language Programs and Policies in Multilingual Societies
                  Course             Provides  a survey  of  local  and  international  basic  education  language
                  Description        programs  and  policies  that  account  for  issues  and  considerations
                                     relevant to the engagement of teachers in school settings. (EK1, ES2,
                                     EA2)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 24 – Principles and Theories of Language Acquisition and
                                     Learning

                  Course Code        BSEE 26
                  Course Title       Language Learning Materials Development
                  Course             Develops the application of the principles, methods, and approaches of
                  Description        translations and adaptation of various texts. (EK2, EK3, ES1, ES2, EA2)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 24 – Principles and Theories of Language Acquisition and
                                     Learning
                                     EDUC 85 – Technology in Language Education

                  Course Code        BSEE 27
                  Course Title       Teaching and Assessment of Literature Studies
                  Course             Develops the application of the principles, methods, and approaches of
                  Description        translations and adaptation of various texts. (EK2, EK3, ES1, ES2, EA2)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 38 – Literary Criticism

                  Course Code        BSEE 28
                  Course Title       Teaching and Assessment of the Macroskills
                  Course             Explores the nature of reading and the theoretical bases, principles, and
                  Description        methods  and  strategies  in  teaching  and  assessing  reading.  It  aims  to
                                     familiarize  students  with  various  strategies  for  pre-reading,  during
                                     reading, and post reading. (ES2)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 22 – Language, Culture and Society]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Course Code        BSEE 29
                  Course Title       Teaching and Assessment of Grammar
                  Course             The  course  engages  the  learners  in  understanding  the  distinctions
                  Description        between and among four types: functional, descriptive, prescriptive, and
                                     pedagogic. Aside from the emphasis on how teaching and assessment
                                     vary considering the four types, the course also provides opportunities to
                                     discover the role of grammar in achieving communicative competence.
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 23 – Structures of English

                  Course Code        BSEE 30
                  Course Title       Speech and Theater Arts
                  Course             Examines the process of oral communications and the various forms of
                  Description        speech arts from public speaking and group discussions to debate, oral
                                     interpretations and dramatics. (EK 2)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 23 – Structures of English

                  Course Code        BSEE 31
                  Course Title       Language Education Research
                  Course             Develops skills in applying principles and approaches in research to find
                  Description        answers to questions in language learning and teaching.   (EK1, ES2,
                                     EA2)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 24 - Principles and Theories of Language Acquisition and
                                     Learning

                  Course Code        BSEE 32
                  Course Title       Children and Adolescent Literature
                  Course             Provides a survey of the categories and types of the world’s literature for
                  Description        children and adolescents. (EK3)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 24 - Principles and Theories of Language Acquisition and
                                     Learning]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Course Code        BSE-E 33
                  Course Title       Mythology and Folklore
                  Course             Explores mythology and folklore from different countries to gain insight
                  Description        into people’s origin, desires, fears, instincts, and needs.    (EK 3).
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 22 – Language, Culture and Society

                  Course Code        BSEE 34
                  Course Title       Survey of Philippine Literature in English
                  Course             Enable  students  to  analyze  the  growth  and  development  of  Philippine
                  Description        Literature in English from 1900 to the present along socio-cultural events
                                     as shown in representative works. (EK3)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 32 – Children and Adolescent Literature

                  Course Code        BSEE 35
                  Course Title       Survey of Apro-Asian Literature
                  Course             Surveys selected  literary  texts  from  Asia  and  Africa,  particularly  India,
                  Description        China,  Japan,  the  countries  in  the  southeast  region  in  Asia,  and  the
                                     African nations south of Sahara along socio-historical, philosophical, and
                                     literary underpinnings. (EK3)
                  Course Credits     3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite       BSEE 32 – Children and Adolescent Literature

                  Course Code         BSEE 36
                  Course Title        Survey of English and American Literature
                  Course              Engages students in a historical survey of literary works produced by
                  Description         understanding English and American literatures from its beginnings to
                                      the 21st Century. (EK3)
                  Course Credits      3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite        BSEE 32 – Children and Adolescent Literature

                  Course Code         BSEE 37
                  Course Title        Contemporary, Popular, and Emergent Literature
                  Course              Focuses on critical issues in contemporary and popular literature and
                  Description         genres. (EK3)
                  Course Credits      3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite        BSEE 32 – Children and Adolescent Literature]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Course Code         BSEE 38
                  Course Title        Literary Criticism
                  Course              Provides students with opportunities to study the basic approaches to
                  Description         literary  theory  and  criticism  and  their  application  to  selected  literary
                                      works. (EK1)
                  Course Credits      3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisites       BSEE 32 – Children and Adolescent Literature
                                      BSEE 33 – Mythology and Folklore
                                      BSEE 34 – Survey of Philippine Literature
                                      BSEE 35 – Survey of Apro-Asian Literature
                                      BSEE 36 – Survey of English and American Literature
                                      BSEE 37 – Contemporary, Popular, and Emergent Literature

                  Course Code         BSEE 39
                  Course Title        Technical Writing
                  Course              Develops technical and scientific writing skills across disciplines. (EK2,
                  Description         EK3, ES1, EA1)
                  Course Credits      3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite        BSEE 23 – Structures of English

                  Course Code         BSEE 40
                  Course Title        Campus Journalism
                  Course              Develops  skills  and  applies  principles  and  strategies  in  writing  for
                  Description         traditional and new media. (EK1, EK2, EK3, ES1, ES3, EA1, EA2)
                  Course Credits      3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite        BSEE 39 – Technical Writing]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Course Code         BSEE 41
                  Course Title        Technology for Teaching and Learning 2 (Technology in
                                      Secondary Language Education)
                  Course              TTL  2  is  a  3-unit  course  which  will  focus  on  the  application,  design,
                  Description         production,   utilization,   and   evaluation   of   Information   and
                                      Communications Technology (ICT) materials for teaching and learning
                                      in  Secondary  Language  (English  and  Filipino)  Education  Programs.
                                      The  major  requirement  for  this  course  is  an  ICT-Integrated  and
                                      Project-based Learning Plan aligned to the K to 12 Curriculum. All the
                                      learning  activities  and  course  requirements  will  revolve  around  the
                                      student-teacher developed Learning Plan.
                  Course Credits      3 units
                  Contact Hours
                  Prerequisite        EDUC 75 Assessment in Learning 1
                                      EDUC 80 Assessment in Learning 2
                                      EDUC 85 Technology for Teaching and Learning 1


                  MANDATED COURSES

                  Course Code          FITT 1
                  Course Title         Movement Enhancement
                  Course               This  course  provides  training  in  different  patterns  and  core
                  Description          engagement  in  conjunction  with  principles  of  healthy  eating  and
                                       physically active life.  Students will be able to adapt and transfer the
                                       movement  competency  in  different  contexts  (i.e.  use  of  training
                                       equipment).
                  Course Credit        2 units
                  Contact Hours        2 hours/week
                  Prerequisite         None

                   Course Code         FITT 2
                   Course Title        Fitness Exercises
                   Course              This course provides experiences in core stability, strength and
                   Description         mobility training.  It includes goal setting exercise progression
                                       and regression and periodic assessment for the development of
                                       various fitness components.
                   Course Credit       2 units
                   Contact Hours       2 hours/week
                   Prerequisite        FITT 1 - Movement Enhancement]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Course Code         FITT 3
                   Course Title        Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness I
                   Course              This  course  will  provide  physical  activities  for  the  purpose  of
                   Description         optimizing health and fitness.  Students will choose from a menu of
                                       course offering in dance, sports and outdoor activities.
                   Course Credit       2 units
                   Contact Hours       2 hours/week
                   Prerequisite         FITT 1 - Movement Enhancement

                   Course Code         FITT 4
                   Course Title        Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness II
                   Course              This  course  will  provide  physical  activities  for  the  purpose  of
                   Description         optimizing  health  fitness.    Students  will  choose  from  a  menu  of
                                       course offering in dance, outdoor adventure activities.
                   Course Credit       2units
                   Contact Hours       2 hours/week
                   Prerequisite        FITT 1 - Movement Enhancement

                   Course Code         NSTP 1
                   Course Title        CWTS/LTS/ROTC
                   Course              A comprehensive program that gives emphasis on citizenship training
                   Description         and still patriotism, moral virtues, respect for the rights of civilians and
                                       adherence to the constitution.
                   Course Credit       3 units
                   Contact Hours       3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite        None

                   Course Code         NSTP 2
                   Course Title        CWTS/LTS/ROTC
                   Course              A  comprehensive  program  that  focuses  on  the  transfer  of  learned
                   Description         technology  to  client  barangay/community.  A  partnership  among
                                       student,  school  facilitators  and  barangay  coordinators  toward
                                       improvement, growth and change in the community.
                   Course Credit       3 units
                   Contact Hours       3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite        NSTP 1]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[INSTITUTIONAL MANDATED COURSES

                   Course Code          EDUC 197
                   Course Title         Competency Appraisal 1
                   Course               Review classes for professional education courses.
                   Description
                   Course Credits       3
                   Contact Hours        3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code          EDUC 198
                   Course Title         Competency Appraisal 2
                   Course               The course provides review classes for specialization/ major
                   Description          courses and general education courses.
                   Course Credits       3
                   Contact Hours        3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code          CVSU 101
                   Course Title         Institutional Orientation 1
                   Course               Cavite State University, its rules and regulations
                   Description
                   Course Credits       (1)
                   Contact Hours        1 hour/week
                   Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[SUMMARY OF REVISION]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[SUMMARY OF REVISION

               I.  In compliance with CHED Memorandum no. 75, series 2017

                                                                              NO. OF UNITS
                                COURSES                       CMO # 75, s.
                                                                  2017           Existing        Proposed
                                                                   36                               45
                                                               (based on                         (based on
               A. GENERAL EDUCATION COURSES                    CMO 20, s.           57          CMO 20, s.
                                                              2013 & CMO                       2013 & CMO
                                                               4, s. 2018)                       4, s. 2018)
               B.  PROFESSIONAL/FUNDAMENTAL                        42               51              42
                    COURSES
                    A. Theory/Concept Courses                                       12
                    B. Methods/Strategies Courses                                   27
                    C. Field Study Courses                                          12
               C. Major Courses                                    63               62              63
               D.  Cognate/Elective Courses                        6                                 6
               E. Mandated Courses                                 14               14              14
                    A. Physical Education                          8                8                8
                    B. NSTP                                        6                6                6
               F. Institutional Mandated Courses
                   (Competency Appraisal & Institutional            -               6                6
                   Orientation))
                                                   TOTAL          161              190              176

               II.  Added/deleted/changed in the proposed curriculum
                   a.  Deleted Courses
                       ENGL 1        Study and Thinking Skills in English
                       MATH 1        Basic Mathematics
                       HUMN 11       Music, Arts Education and Appreciation
                       PHSC 1        Physical Science Including Earth Science
                       SOSC 1        Society and Culture with Family Planning
                       SOSC 2        General Psychology
                       ENGL 7        Writing in the Discipline
                       FILI 7        Pagbasa at Pagsulat Tungo sa Pananaliksik
                       STAT 1        Elementary Statistics
                       BIOL 1a       General Biology 1
                       SOSC 3        Philippine History, Geography & Institution
                       ITEC 3        Information & Communication Technology
                       LITT 1        Philippine Literature
                       LITT 2        World Literature
                       ENGL 6        Speech Communication
                       FILI 8        Masining na Pagpapahayag
                       SOSC 5        Philippine Government, Politics & Constitution]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[BTCH 1        Introduction to Biotechnology
                       EDUC 99a      Seminar 1
                       EDUC 99b      Seminar 2
                       EDUC 99c      Seminar 3
                       CURR 21       Curriculum Development
                       TEAC 21       Principles of Teaching 1
                       TEAC 22       Principles of Teaching 2
                       EDUC 37       Child and Adolescent Development
                       ECON 2        General Economics with TAR
                       EDTC 22       Instructional Media Resources
                       EDFS 23       Field Study 3
                       EDFS 24       Field Study 4
                       EDFS 25       Field Study 5
                       EDFS 26       Field Study 6
                       HUMN 6        Social Philosophy 1
                       ENGL 3        Developmental Reading
                       EDUC 40       Social Dimensions of Education
                       ENGL 70       Language Curriculum for Secondary School
                       ENGL 80       The Teaching of Speaking
                       ENGL 85       The Teaching of Listening and Reading
                       ENGL 95       Preparation and Evaluation of Instructional Materials
                       ENGL 100      Teaching of Literature
                       ENGL 60       Language and Literature Assessment
                       ENGL 105      Creative Writing
                       ENGL 120      Remedial Instruction in English
                       ENGL 130      English for Special Purposes
                       ENGL 140      Introduction to Stylistics
                       ENGL 145      Translation and Editing of Text

                   b.  Added Courses
                       GNED 01       Art Appreciation
                       GNED 02       Ethics
                       GNED 03       Mathematics in the Modern World
                       GNED 04       Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas
                       GNED 05       Purposive Communication
                       GNED 06       Science, Technology and Society
                       GNED 07       The Contemporary World
                       GNED 08       Understanding the Self
                       GNED 09       Life and Works of rizal
                       GNED 10       Gender and Society
                       GNED 11       Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino
                       GNED 12       Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino
                       GNED 13       Retorika / Masining na Pagpapahayag
                       GNED 14       Panitikang Panlipunan
                       EDUC 50       Child and Adolescent Learner and Learning Principles]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[EDUC 60       The Teacher and The Community, School Culture and Organizational
                                     Leadership
                       EDUC 65       Foundation of Special and Inclusive Education
                       EDUC 90       The Teacher and the School Curriculum
                       EDUC 95       Building and Enhancing New Literacies Across the Curriculum
                       BSEE 22       Language, Culture and Society
                       BSEE 24       Principles and Theories of Language Acquisition and Learning
                       BSEE 25       Language Programs and Policies in Multilingual Societies
                       BSEE 26       Language Learning Materials Development
                       BSEE 27       Teaching and Assessment of Literature Study
                       BSEE 28       Teaching and Assessment of the Macro skills
                       BSEE 29       Teaching and Assessment of Grammar
                       BSEE 32       Children and Adolescent Literature
                       BSEE 34       Survey of Philippine Literature in English
                       BSEE 37       Contemporary, Popular and Emergent Literature in English
                       BSEE 39       Technical Writing
                       BSEE 41       Technology for Teaching and Writing 2 (Technology in Language
                                     Education)

                   c.  Replaced Courses

                       FROM                                       TO
                       Course Code           Course Title         Course Code           Course Title

                       ENGL 50          Introduction to Applied    BSEE 21      Introduction to Linguistics
                                                     Linguistics
                       ENGL 125       Structure of English        BSEE 23       Structure of English
                                                                                                                           Language
                       ENGL 55         Afro-Asian Literature      BSEE 35       Survey of Afro-Asian
                                                                                                                           Literature
                       ENGL 75        English and American        BSEE 36       Survey of English and
                                                   Literature                        American Literature

                   d.  Changed Course Titles

                       FROM                                       TO
                       Course Code            Course Title        Course Code             Course Title

                       FILI 6             Komunikasyon sa         GNED 11         Kontekstwalisadong
                                       Akademikong Filipino                                       Komunikasyon sa Filipino
                       EDTC 21        Introduction to Educational   EDUC 85      Technology for Teaching and
                                             Technology                                                       Learning 1
                       ASSE  21       Assessment of Learning 1    EDUC 75         Assessment in Learning 1
                       ASSE  22       Assessment of Learning 2    EDUC 80         Assessment in Learning 2
                       ENGL 90        Language Research               BSEE 31          Language Education
                                                                                   Research
                       ENGL 135      Speech and Stage Art         BSEE 30         Speech and Theater Arts
                       EDFS 27        Practice Teaching           EDFS 23         Teaching Internship]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[e.  Courses with Modified Subject Codes and Titles

                       FROM                                       TO
                       Course Code          Course Title          Course Code         Course Title

                       SOSC 6          Rizal’s Life, Works and    GNED 09        Life and Works of Rizal
                                          Writings
                       EDUC 39       The Teaching Profession      EDUC 55        The Teaching Profession
                       EDUC 38         Facilitating Learning      EDUC 70        Facilitating Learner-Centered
                                                                                         Teaching
                       EDFS 27       Practice Teaching            EDFS 23        Teaching Internship
                       ENGL 65       Literary Criticism           BSEE 38        Literary Criticism
                       ENGL 110      Mythology and Folklore       BSEE 33        Mythology and Folklore
                       ENGL 115      Campus Journalism            BSEE 40        Campus Journalism]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[PROPOSED BACHELOR OF



                        SECONDARY EDUCATION



                                                    (BSEd)



                                 major in Mathematics]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[PROPOSAL:             Revision of Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd)
                                     major in Mathematics
               PROPONENT:            College of Education

               RATIONALE:
                       The need to improve the quality of our education and provide corresponding access to
               Filipino students is deeply rooted in our 1987 Constitution, Batas Pambansa 232 and RA 7722.
                       Sizable  resources  were  allotted  by  our  government  to  implement  various  education-
               related programs to achieve this end the recent of which is the adoption of the shift from expert
               knowledge transmission to learner competency building or outcome-based education through
               CMO  no.  46 s  2012.  This mandate  requires  the  review  and  refocusing  of  the  different  HEI’s
               curricular offerings to be a par with the prescribed international standard.
                       It has long recognized that the most crucial factor in the quality education is the quality of
               pre-service teacher education which it has been providing for more than two decades. It has also
               embraced the important function and responsibility of providing the necessary training to future
               teachers as part of their professional development.
                       Cavite State University through the College of Education established in 1992 as School of
               Education started to offer Bachelor of Elementary Education (BEEd) and Bachelor of Secondary
               Education (BSEd). In 2005, CMO No. 30 series of 2004 also known as Revised Policies and
               Standards for Undergraduate Teacher Education Curriculum was implemented and the College
               started to offer the current curriculum in education. Through the Teacher Education Department
               of the College of Education in coordination with the other campuses offerings education programs,
               the University is working on producing quality graduates in education.
                       Recent developments point to the need to expand the courses offered by the Teacher
               Education  Department  by  offering  additional  major  fields  specifically  Filipino,  Social  Studies,
               MAPEH, Science and Values Education. This is in consonance with the needs of both elementary
               and secondary schools in their K to 12 program.
                       These imperatives coupled with the recent issuances on different CMO’s that are related
               to teacher education make it necessary to redirect and revise its current curricular offerings to
               make it attuned to demand and needs of its clienteles, hence this proposal.


               OBJECTIVES:
               1.  To produce quality education graduates of Cavite State University
               2.  To respond to the new teacher education curricula based on CMO 75, series of 2017
               3.  To standardize the education programs in the main and other campuses of the Cavite State
                   University

               STRATEGIES
               1.  Curriculum Review Committee Formed
                          The University Curriculum Review Committee was formed by the Vice President for
                   Academic Affairs (VPAA) through a Memorandum No. PHDR-77-17 dated April 25, 2017 to
                   review and revise the current curricular offerings of the university. A meeting was called by
                   the VPAA to orient the coordinators of the terms of reference of program coordinators at S.L.
                   Lasap Hall on June 15, 2017.
                          The university coordinators and faculty members of the College of Education-main
                   campus, CvSU Naic, Cavite City, Imus, Silang, Gen. Trias, Bacoor, Tanza, and Carmona held
                   Curriculum  Review  for  BSHRM,  BSTM,  DHRM,  BEE,  BSE  and  TCP  Programs  at  Hostel]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Tropicana on September 27, 2017 under the leadership of Dr. Editha G. Reyes, the former
                   dean of the College of Education. Most of the curricular revisions of different programs were
                   based on the draft copies of Commission on Higher Education Order. The final copies of the
                   CMOs were released on December 28, 2018.
                          The participants from the Teacher Education Department were:
                          Dr. Lumine R. Crisostomo                Program Coordinator, BSE
                          Dr. Jane J. Reyes                       Program Coordinator, BEE
                          Prof. Julie S. Guevara                  TED faculty
                          Ms. Edelyn D. Sabilla                   TED faculty
                          Ms. Karen Lynn G. Macawile              TED faculty
                          Mrs. Richel Diokno                      TED faculty
                          Likewise,  following  program  coordinators  and  faculty  members  participated  the
                   curricular revisions:
                          Dr. Ligaya P. Antiojo                   Naic
                          Ms. Roselyn A. Ymana                    Silang
                          Ms. Cristel M. Belaro                   Silang
                          Mr. Lambert M. Diokno                   Cavite City
                          Ms. Jocelyn B. Siochi                   Carmona
                          Mr. Euvard Ross R. Corpuz               Imus
                          Mr. Glenn Bryan A. Creencia             Gen. Trias City
                          Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian                Tanza
                          Mr. Christian Mark G. Lorenzana         Bacoor
                          Mr. Rostum B. Gulmatico, Jr.            Silang
                          Mr. Victoriano P. Barliso, Jr.          Gen. Trias City
                          Mr. Ernesto A. Gutierrez, Jr.           Naic
                          Similarly, The Committee on Curriculum Review and Development was formed by the
                   Dr. Cecilia B. Banaag, dean of the College of Education on January 23, 2018 to review and
                   revise the existing Teacher Education curricula based on CMO Nos. 75, 76, 77 and 78, series
                   of 2017.

               2.  Workshop Conducted
                          The initial meeting of the committee was conducted on January 29, 2018 and
                   attended by the following:
                        Prof. Jason R. Maniacop                   Chair, CEd Committee on Curriculum
                                                                         Review and Development
                        Dr. Lumine R. Crisostomo                  Program Coordinator, BSE
                        Ms. Jane J. Reyes                         Program Coordinator, BEE
                        Dr. Florencio R. Abanes                   Committee Member
                        Dr. Isaias A. Banaag                      Committee Member

                              On February 1, 2018, the workshop on curriculum review and development was
                   conducted and attended by the following:
                        Dr. Cecilia B. Banaag                     Dean, College of Education
                        Prof. Jason R. Maniacop                    Chair, CEd Committee on Curriculum
                                                                  Review and Development]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Dr. Lumine R. Crisostomo                  Program Coordinator, BSE
                        Dr. Jane J. Reyes                         Program Coordinator, BEE
                        Dr. Florencio R. Abanes                   Committee Member
                        Dr. Isaias A. Banaag                      Committee Member
                        Dr. Myleen P. Legaspi                     Technical Staff
                        Ms. Karen G. Macawile                     Technical Staff
                        Ms. Richel P. Diokno                      Technical Staff
                        Ms. Edelyn D. Sabilla                     Technical Staff

                        The  outputs  of  the  workshop  were  revised  program  offerings,  namely  Bachelor  of
                   Secondary Education (BSEd) major in: English, Mathematics and Science; and new program
                   offering, namely Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) major in: Values Education, Araling
                   Panlipunan, and Filipino.  These were based on the CHED Memorandum Order Number 75,
                   series of 2017.

               3.  Presentation of Curricula to the Stakeholders
                       The developed curricula for the three programs were presented to the stakeholders on
                   February 13, 2018 for consultation, critiquing, comments suggestions and recommendation.
                   Present were representatives of faculty members, students, parents and alumni of the
                   different campuses as well as from the main campus. Representatives from Department of
                   Education and the community were also present.

               4.  Presentation to the College Academic Council
                          The proposal will be subjected to a deliberation and consultation with College of
                   Education Academic Council on February 20, 2018.

               5.  Presentation to the University Academic Council
                          Outputs of the curriculum review will be presented to the university academic council
                   for approval and subsequent endorsement to CHED and Board of Regents.

               6. Submission to CHED for Review and Approval

               7. Submission to the Board of Regents for Review and Approval

               PERIOD OF IMPLEMENTATION
                   The new curriculumum for Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) major in Mathematics
               be implemented on the first semester of school year 2018-2019 upon approval of the Board of
               Regents.

               PROGRAM SPECIFICATION

               Degree Name: Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) Major in Mathematics

               Program Goals:
                       The BSEd degree program aims to develop highly motivated and competent teachers
               specializing in the content and pedagogy for secondary education.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Program Educational Objectives:
                    1.  Articulate and discuss the latest developments in the specific field of practice.
                    2.  Demonstrate mastery of subject matter/discipline.
                    3.  Facilitate learning using a wide range of teaching methodologies and delivery modes
                        appropriate to specific learners and their environments.
                    4.  Develop innovative curricula, instructional plans, teaching approaches, and resources
                        for diverse learners.
                    5.  Apply skills in the development and utilization of ICT to promote quality, relevant and
                        sustainable educational practices.
                    6.  Demonstrate a variety of thinking skills in planning, monitoring, assessing and reporting
                        learning processes and outcomes.
                    7.  Practice professional and ethical teaching standards sensitive to the local, national and
                        global realities.
                    8.  Pursue lifelong learning for personal and professional growth through varied
                        experiential and field-based opportunities.

               Program/Student Outcomes:
                       The Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) Major in Mathematics intends to produce
               graduates who:
                   1.  Exhibit competence in mathemetical concepts and procedures;
                   2.  Exhibit proficiency in relating mathematics to other curricular areas;
                   3.  Manifest  meaningful  and  comprehensive  pedagogical  content  knowlegde  (TCK)  of
                       mathematics;
                   4.  Demonstrate  competence  in  designing,  constructing,  and  utilizing  different  forms  of
                       assessment in mathematics;
                   5.  Demonstrate proficiency  in problem solving   by solving and creating routine and non-
                       routine problems with different level of complexity;
                   6.  Use effectively appropriate approaches, methods, and techniques mathematics including
                       technological tools; and
                   7.  Appreciate mathematics as an opportunity for creative work, moments of enlightenment,
                       discovery and gaining insights of the world.

               CURRICULUM
                       The Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSEd) major in Mathematics will be composed of
               the following courses:

                          General Education        :                            45 units
                               Core                :       33 units
                               Electives           :           9 units
                               Mandated            :           3 units
                          Professional Education:                               42 units
                               Theories and Concepts:      12 units
                              Methods and Strategies:      18 units
                              Experiential Learning]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Courses         :       12 units
                          Major Courses            :                            63 units
                          Mandated Courses         :                            14 units
                              PE                   :       8
                              NSTP                 :       6
                          Institutional Mandated:                                 6 units

                              TOTAL                :                              170 units

               ADMISSION AND RETENTION POLICIES

               1. Admission Policies
                    a. A high school GPA of not lower than 85.
                    b. Passing the University Entrance Test with a score of not lower than the set standard for
                        courses with board examination.
                    c. Passing an interview with the Department Chairperson or the Campus Dean.

               2. Retention Policies
                    a. A first year cumulative GPA of 2.5 or better with no failing grade including grades in NSTP.
                    b. Passing the Standardized Aptitude Test for Teacher (SATT) before second year with a
                        score equivalent to 70 percentile.
                    c. A second year and third year cumulative GPA of 2.25 or better with no grade lower than
                        3.0 including NSTP.

               3. Transferee and Shiftee
                    a. Transferee from other schools and shiftee from other courses within the university system
                        shall be admitted to education program if they have a cumulative GPA of 2.0 or better,
                        and with no grade lower than 3.0.
                    b. They are also governed by the retention policies stated above.
                    c. SATT should only be given after completing a minimum number of units per major field
                        including those grades that are credited from previous school or program.
                    d. No transferee or shiftee shall be admitted at the third year level.
                    e. Passing an interview with the Department Chairperson or the Campus Dean.

               4. Other Provisions
                   a. Computation of cumulative GPA shall be based on a minimum number of units per major
                      field per year level.
                   b. This policy shall cover only the teacher education programs of the Cavite State University
                     System.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[CURRICULUM COMPONENTS]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[BACHELOR OF SECONDARY EDUCATION (BSEd)
                                                   Major in Mathematics

                                       Courses                               No. of Units         Total Units
                 A. General Education Courses (CMO No. 20 s. 2013                                     45
                       & CMO N0. 4, s. 2018)
                 1. Art Appreciation                                              3
                 2. Ethics                                                        3
                 3. Mathematics in the Modern World                               3
                 4. Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas              3
                 5. Purposive Communication                                       3
                 6. Science, Technology and Society                               3
                 7. The Contemporary World                                        3
                 8. Understanding the Self                                        3
                 9. Life and Works of Rizal                                       3
                 10. Gender and Society                                           3
                 11. Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa                           3
                       Filipino
                 12. Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino                                       3
                 13. Retorika/Masining na Pagpapahayag                            3
                 14. Panitikang Panlipunan                                        3
                 15. World Literature                                             3
                 B. Professional Education Courses                                                    42
                 Foundation Courses/ Theories and Concepts                                      12
                 1. Child and Adolescent Learner and Learning                     3
                      Principles                                                  3
                 2. The Teaching Profession                                       3
                 3. The Teacher and The Community, School
                 4.  Culture and Organizational Leadership                        3
                 5. Foundation of Special and Inclusive Education
                 Pedagogical Content Knowledge                                                  18
                 1. Facilitating Learner-Centered Teaching                        3
                 2. Assessment in Learning 1                                      3
                 3. Assessment in Learning 2                                      3
                 4. Technology for Teaching and Learning 1                        3
                 5. The Teacher and The School Curriculum                         3
                 6. Building and Enhancing New Literacies Across the              3
                     Curriculum
                 Experiential Learning                                                          12
                 1. Field Study 1 – Observations of Teaching-Learning             3
                     in Actual School Environment
                 2. Field Study 2 – Participation and Assistantship               3
                 3. Teaching Internship                                           6
                 C. Major Courses                                                                     63
                 1.History of Math                                                3
                 2.College & Advanced Algebra                                     3
                 3.Trigonometry                                                   3
                 4. Plane & Solid Geometry                                        3
                 5. Logic & Set Theory                                            3
                 6. Elementary Statistics & Probability                           3]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[7. Calculus 1 with Analytic Geometry                             4
                 8. Calculus 2                                                    4
                 9. Calculus 3                                                    3
                 10. Modern Geometry                                              3
                 11. Mathematics of Investment                                    3
                 12. Number Theory                                                3
                 13. Linear Algebra                                               3
                 14. Advanced Statistics                                          3
                 15. Problem Solving, Mathematical Investigation                  3
                       & Modeling
                 16. Principles & Strategies in Teaching                          3
                       Mathematics
                 17. Abstract Algebra                                             3
                 18. Research in Mathematics                                      4
                 19. Technology for Teaching and Learning 2*                      3
                       (Instrumentation & Evaluation in
                        Mathematics)
                 20. Assessment & Evaluation in Mathematics                       3
                 D. Mandated Courses                                                                  14
                 1. Movement Enhancement                                          2
                 2. Fitness Exercises                                             2
                 3. Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness I              2
                 4. Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness II             2
                 5. CWTS/ LTS/ ROTC                                               3
                 6. CWTS/ LTS/ ROTC                                               3
                 E. Institutional Mandated Courses                                                     6
                 1. Competency Appraisal 1                                        3
                 2. Competency Appraisal 2                                        3
                 3. Institutional Orientation 1                                   (1)
                                                                                      TOTAL        170 units]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[COMPARISON OF PROPOSED



                                                          AND



                             EXISTING CURRICULUM]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[BACHELOR OF SECONDARY EDUCATION (BSEd)
                                                  Major in Mathematics

                                                                              NO. OF UNITS
                                                              CMO # 75, s.
                                COURSES
                                                              2017 & CMO         Existing        Proposed
                                                               #4, s. 2018
                                                                                                      45
                                                                                                  (based on
                 I. GENERAL EDUCATION COURSES                       36               57          CMO 75, s.
                                                                                                2017 & CMO
                                                                                                 4, s. 2018)
                 II.   PROFESSIONAL/FUNDAMENTAL                     42               51
                    COURSES
                     A. Theory/Concept Courses                      12               12               42
                     B. Methods/Strategies Courses                  27               27
                     C. Field Study Courses                         12               12
                 III. Major Courses                                 63               62               63
                 IV. Mandated Courses                               14               14               14
                     A. Physical Education                                           8                8
                     B. NSTP                                                         6                6
                 V. Institutional Mandated Courses
                     (Competency Appraisal &                         -               6                6
                     Institutional Orientation)
                                                    TOTAL          155              190              170

                                                  SUMMARY OF UNITS

                                                                                      Offering
                                      COURSES                                  CMO # 75, s. 2017 &
                                                                                  CMO #4, s.2018
                 I. General Education Courses                                            45
                 II. Professional Education Courses                                      42
                     A. Foundation Courses/Theories and Concepts                         12
                     B. Pedagogical Content Knowledge                                    18
                     C. Experiential Learning                                            12
                 III. Major Courses                                                      63
                 IV. Mandated Courses                                                    14
                     A. Physical Education                                                8
                     B. NSTP                                                              6
                 IV. Institutional Mandated Courses (Competency                           6
                     Appraisal & Institutional Orientation)
                                                                TOTAL                    170]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[BREAKDOWN OF COURSES]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Indang, Cavite

               Curriculum:                  BACHELOR OF SECONDARY EDUCATION (BSEd)
                                            major in Mathematics
               Number of Years:             Four (4) years
               Responsible College:         College of Education


                                               BREAKDOWN OF COURSES

                   I.     GENERAL EDUCATION COURSES (CMO No. 20 s. 2013)

                  Course                        Course Title                      Lecture      Lab.     Credit
                    Code                                                           Hours      Hours     Units
                 GNED 01      Art Appreciation                                        3         0         3
                 GNED 02      Ethics                                                  3         0         3
                 GNED 03      Mathematics in the Modern World                         3         0         3
                 GNED 04      Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng                  3         0         3
                              Pilipinas
                 GNED 05      Purposive Communication                                 3         0         3
                 GNED 06      Science, Technology and Society                         3         0         3
                 GNED 07      The Contemporary World                                  3         0         3
                 GNED 08      Understanding the Self                                  3         0         3
                 GNED 09      Life and Works of Rizal                                 3         0         3
                 GNED 10      Gender and Society                                      3         0         3
                 GNED 11      Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino             3         0         3
                 GNED 12      Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino                                  3         0         3
                 GNED 13      Retorika/Masining na Pagpapahayag                       3         0         3
                 GNED 14      Panitikang Panlipunan                                   3         0         3
                 GNED 15      World Literature                                        3         0         3
                                                                        TOTAL                               45

                   II.    PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION COURSES

                    A.  Foundation Courses/ Theories and Concepts
                              Child and Adolescent Learner and Learning
                 EDUC 50                                                               3         0         3
                              Principles
                 EDUC 55      The Teaching Profession                                  3         0         3
                              The Teacher and The Community, School Culture
                 EDUC 60                                                               3         0         3
                              and Organizational Leadership
                 EDUC 65      Foundation of Special and Inclusive Education            3         0         3
                                                                          TOTAL                             12]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[B.  Pedagogical Content Knowledge
                 EDUC 70      Facilitating Learner-Centered Teaching                   3         0         3
                 EDUC 75      Assessment in Learning 1                                 3         0         3
                 EDUC 80      Assessment in Learning 2                                 3         0         3
                 EDUC 85      Technology for Teaching and Learning 1                   3         0         3
                 EDUC 90      The Teacher and The School Curriculum                    3         0         3
                              Building and Enhancing New Literacies Across the
                 EDUC 95                                                               3         0         3
                              Curriculum
                                                                          TOTAL                             18
                    C.  Experiential Learning
                              Field Study 1 – Observations of Teaching-Learning        3         0        3
                 EDFS 21
                              in Actual School Environment
                              Field Study 2 – Participation and Teaching               3         0        3
                 EDFS 22
                              Assistantship
                                                                                       0        40        6
                 EDFS 23      Teaching Internship                                             hrs/wee
                                                                                                 k
                                                                          TOTAL                             12

                   III. MAJOR COURSES

                 BSEM 21      History of Math                                          3         0         3
                 BSEM 22      College & Advanced Algebra                               3         0         3
                 BSEM 23      Trigonometry                                             3         0         3
                 BSEM 24      Plane & Solid Geometry                                   3         0         3
                 BSEM 25      Logic & Set Theory                                       3         0         3
                 BSEM 26      Elementary Statistics & Probability                      3         0         3
                 BSEM 27      Calculus 1 with Analytic Geometry                        4         0         4
                 BSEM 28      Calculus 2                                               4         0         4
                 BSEM 29      Calculus 3                                               3         0         3
                 BSEM 30      Modern Geometry                                          3         0         3
                 BSEM 31      Mathematics of Investment                                3         0         3
                 BSEM 32      Number Theory                                            3         0         3
                 BSEM 33      Linear Algebra                                           3         0         3
                 BSEM 34      Advanced Statistics                                      3         0         3
                              Problem Solving, Mathematical Investigation &
                 BSEM 35                                                               3         0         3
                              Modeling
                 BSEM 36      Principles & Strategies in Teaching Mathematics          3         0         3
                 BSEM 37      Abstract Algebra                                         3         0         3
                 BSEM 38      Research in Mathematics                                  4         0         4
                              Technology for Teaching and Learning 2*
                 BSEM 39                                                               3         0         3
                              (Instrumentation & Evaluation in Mathematics)
                 BSEM 40      Assessment & Evaluation In Mathematics                   3         0         3
                                                                          TOTAL                             63]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[IV. MANDATED COURSES

                 FITT 1       Movement Enhancement                                     2         0         2
                 FITT 2       Fitness Exercises                                        2         0         2
                 FITT 3       Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness I         2         0         2
                 FITT 4       Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness II        2         0         2
                 NSTP 1       CWTS / LTS/ ROTC                                         3         0         3
                 NSTP 2       CWTS / LTS/ ROTC                                         3         0         3
                                                                          TOTAL                             14

                   V. INSTITUTIONAL MANDATED COURSES

                 EDUC 197     Competency Appraisal 1                                   3         0         3
                 EDUC 198     Competency Appraisal 2                                   3         0         3
                 CvSU 101     Institutional Orientation 1                              1         0        (1)
                                                                          TOTAL                              6

                                                      TOTAL NUMBER OF UNITS                               170]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[COURSE DESCRIPTIONS]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[GENERAL EDUCATION COURSES (CMO No. 20, series of 2013)

                    Course Code       GNED 01
                    Course Title      Art Appreciation
                    Course            Nature, function and appreciation of the arts in contemporary society
                    Description
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code       GNED 02
                    Course Title      Ethics
                    Course            Principles of ethical behavior in modern society, and in interaction with
                    Description       the environment and other shared resources.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Title      GNED 03
                    Course Title      Mathematics in the Modern World
                    Course            Nature  of  Mathematics,  appreciation  of  its  practical,  intellectual  and
                    Description       aesthetic dimensions, and application of mathematical tools in daily life.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code       GNED 04
                    Course Title      Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas
                    Course            Mga  piling  primaryang  sanggunian  ukol  sa  iba’t-ibang  yugto  ng
                    Description       kasaysayan ng Pilipinas, pagsusuri at interpretasyon.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code       GNED 05
                    Course Title      Purposive Communication
                    Course            Writing,  speaking  and  presenting  to  different  audiences  for  various
                    Description       purposes.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Course Code       GNED 06
                    Course Title      Science, Technology, and Society
                    Course            Interactions  between  science  and  technology  and  social,  cultural,
                    Description       political, and economic contexts which shape and are shaped by them;
                                      specific  examples  throughout  human  history  of  scientific  and
                                      technological developments.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code       GNED 07
                    Course Title      The Contemporary World
                    Course            Globalization and its impact on individuals, societies, and communities,
                    Description       challenges, and responses.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code       GNED 08
                    Course Title      Understanding the Self
                    Course            Nature of identity; factors and forces that affect the development and
                    Description       maintenance of personal identity.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code       GNED 09
                    Course Title      Life and Works of Rizal
                    Course            Life, works, and writings of Rizal with emphasis on his principles, ideals,
                    Description       and teaching, towards the development and progress of this country.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite      GNED 04 – Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas

                    Course Code       GNED 10
                    Course Title      Gender and Society
                    Course            Gender as a social construction, its role in and impact on different facets
                    Description       of societal life.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[Course Code       GNED 11
                    Course Title      Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino
                    Course            Isang  praktikal  na  kursong  nagpapalawak  at  nagpapalalim  sa
                    Description       kontekstwalisadong  komunikasyon  sa  wikang  Filipino  ng  mga
                                      mamamayang Pilipino sa kani-kanilang mga komunidad sa partikular, at
                                      sa buong lipunang Pilipino sa pangkalahatan. Nakatuon ang kursong ito
                                      sa makrokasanayang pakikinig at pagsasalita, gayundin sa kasanayan
                                      sa  paggamit  ng  iba’t-ibang  tradisyonal  at  modernong  midya  na
                                      makbuluhan sa kontekstong Pilipino sa iba’t-ibang antas at larangan.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code       GNED 12
                    Course Title      Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino
                    Course            Isang  maagwat  na  kursong  nagpapalawak  at  nagpapalalim  sa
                    Description       kasanayan  sa  malalim  at  mapanuring  pagbasa,  pagsulat,  at
                                      pananaliksik sa wikang Filipino sa iba’t-ibang larangan, sa konteksto ng
                                      kontemporaryong sitwasyon at mga pangangailangan ng bansa at ng
                                      mga mamamayang Pilipino.  Partikular na nakatuon ang kursong ito sa
                                      makrokasanayang pagbasa at pagsulat, gamit ang mga makabuluhang
                                      panananaliksik sa wikang Filipino, bilang lunsagan ng pagpapalawak at
                                      pagpapalalim  sa  kasanayan,  kakayahan  at  kamalayan  ng  mga
                                      estudyante na malikhain at mapanuring makapagdalumat o “makapag-
                                      teorya”  sa  wikang  Filipino,  batay  sa  mga  piling  lokal  at  dayuhang
                                      konsepto at teorya na akma sa konteksto ng komunidad at bansa.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite      GNED 11 - Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino

                    Course Code       GNED 13
                    Course Title      Retorika / Masining ng Pagpapahayag
                    Course            Pag-aaral ng mga prinsipyo ng masining na pagpapahayag sa Filipino.
                    Description       Nakatuon  ito  sa  malayang  pagtuklas  at  pagpapakita  ng  sariling
                                      kakayahan at talino sa pagsulat at pasalitang pagpapaphayag.  Lilinang
                                      ang  kursong  ito  ng  mga  kasanayan  sa  pasalita  at  pasulat  na
                                      pagpapahayag ng mga mag-aaral bilang isang indibidwal, mamamayan
                                      ng isang bansa at bahagi ng isang global na komunidad.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite      GNED 11 - Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino
                                      GNED 12 – Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[Course Code       GNED 14
                    Course Title      Panitikang Panlipunan
                    Course            Isang kurso sa pag-aaral at paglikha ng panitikang Filipino na nakatuon
                    Description       sa kabuluhang panlipunan ng mga tekstong literari sa iba’t ibang bahagi
                                      ng kasaysayan ng bansang Pilipinas. Sinasaklaw nito ang may isyung
                                      panlipunan  na  tinalakay  ng  mga  akdang  Filipino  tulad  ng  kahirapan,
                                      malawak  na  agwat  ng  mayayaman  at  mahirap,  reporma  sa  lupa,
                                      globalisasyon,  pagsasamantala  sa  mga  manggagawa,  karapatang
                                      pantao, isyung pangkasarian, sitwasyon ng mga pangkat minorya at / o
                                      marhinalisado, at iba pa.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code       GNED 15
                    Course Title      World Literature
                    Course            A survey of world literature including short stories, poetry, novels, drama,
                    Description       and non-fiction.  Emphasis is on the exploration and discussion of human
                                      and moral qualities revealed through literature.
                    Course Credit     3 units
                    Contact Hours     3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION COURSES (CMO No. 75, s. 2017)

                    Course Code               EDUC 50
                    Course Title              The Child and Adolescent Learners and Learning Principle
                    Course Description        This course focuses on child and adolescent development with
                                              emphasis  on  current  research  and  theory  on  biological,
                                              linguistic,  cognitive,  social  and  emotional  dimensions  of
                                              development.  Further,  this  includes  factors  that  affect  the
                                              progress  of  development  of  the  learners  and  shall  include
                                              appropriate  pedagogical  principles  for  each  developmental
                                              level.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code               EDUC 55
                    Course Title              The Teaching Profession
                    Course Description        This  course  deals  with  the  teacher  as  a  person  and  as  a
                                              professional within the context of national teacher standards and
                                              global teachers’ standards and educational philosophies. It will
                                              include  professional  ethics,  core  values,  awareness  of
                                              professional  rights,  privileges  and  responsibilities  as  well  as
                                              teachers’  roles  in  the  society  as  a  transformative  agent  of
                                              change.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code               EDUC 60
                    Course Title              The  Teacher  and  the  Community,  School  Culture  and
                                              Organizational Leadership
                    Course Description        This  course  focuses  on  society  as  a  context  upon  which  the
                                              schools have been established. Educational philosophies that
                                              are  related  to  the  society  as  a  foundation  of  schools  and
                                              schooling shall be emphasized. Further, principles and theories
                                              on  school  culture,  and  organizational  leadership  shall  be
                                              included  to  prepare  prospective  teachers  to  become  school
                                              leaders and managers.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[Course Code               EDUC 65
                    Course Title              Foundation of Special and Inclusive Education
                    Course Description        This  course  shall  deal  with  philosophies,  theories  and  legal
                                              bases  of  special  needs  and  inclusive  education,  typical  and
                                              atypical  development  of  children,  learning  characteristics  of
                                              students  with  special  educational  needs  (gifted  and  talented,
                                              learners  with  difficulty  seeing,  learners  with  difficulty  hearing,
                                              learners  with  difficulty  communicating,  learners  with  difficulty
                                              walking/moving,  learners  with  difficulty  remembering  and
                                              focusing, learners with difficulty with self-care) and strategies in
                                              teaching and managing these learners in the regular class.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code               EDUC 70
                    Course Title              Facilitating Learner-Centered Teaching
                    Course Description        This course explores the fundamental principles, processes and
                                              practices  anchored  on  learner-centeredness  and  other
                                              educational  psychologies  as  these  apply  to  facilitate  various
                                              teaching-learning delivery modes to enhance learning.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code               EDUC 75
                    Course Title              Assessment in Learning 1
                    Course Description        This is a course that focuses on the principles, development and
                                              utilization  of  conventional  assessment  tools  to  improve  the
                                              teaching-learning  process.  It  emphasizes  on  the  use  of
                                              assessment  of,  as,  and  for  in  measuring  knowledge,
                                              comprehension  and  other  thinking  skills  in  the  cognitive,
                                              psychomotor  or  affective  domain.  It  allows  students  to  go
                                              through the standard steps in test construction and development
                                              and the application in grading systems.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[Course Code               EDUC 80
                    Course Title              Assessment in Learning 2
                    Course Description        This is a course that focuses on the principles, development and
                                              utilization  of  alternative  forms  of  assessment  in  measuring
                                              authentic learning. It emphasizes how to assess process and
                                              product-oriented  learning  outcomes  as  well  as  affective
                                              learning. Students will experience how to develop rubrics and
                                              other  assessment  tools  for  performance-based  and  product-
                                              based assessment.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code               EDUC 85
                    Course Title              Technology for Teaching and Learning 1
                    Course Description        This is an introductory course that explores basic knowledge,
                                              skills  and  values  in  the  use  of  technology  for  teaching  and
                                              learning. It includes ICT polices and safety issues, media and
                                              technology  in  various  content  areas,  learning  theories  and
                                              principles  in  the  use  of  design  of  learning  lessons,  teaching-
                                              learning  experiences  and  assessment  tasks  that  utilize
                                              appropriate  traditional  and  innovative  technology  with  social,
                                              ethical, and legal responsibility in the use of technology tools
                                              and resources.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code               EDUC 90
                    Course Title              The Teacher and the Curriculum
                    Course Description        The course includes the fundamental concepts and principles in
                                              curriculum  and  curriculum  development  as  the  foundation  to
                                              engage prospective teachers as curricularists. The more active
                                              role  of  the  teacher  in  planning,  implementing  and  evaluating
                                              school-curriculum  as  well  as  managing  school  curriculum
                                              change  vis-à-vis  various  context  of  teaching-learnng  and
                                              curricular reforms shall be given emphasis.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Course Code               EDUC 95
                    Course Title              Building  and  Enhancing  New  Literacies  Across  the
                                              Curriculum
                                                                                                           st
                    Course Description        This course introduces the concepts of new literacies in the 21
                                              century as an evolving social phenomena and shared cultural
                                                                                    st
                                              practices across learning area. The 21  century literacies shall
                                              include  (a)  globalization  and  multi-cultural  literacy,  (b)  social
                                              literacy,  (c)  media  literacy,  (d)  financial  literacy,  (e)  cyber
                                              literacy/digital literacy, (f) eco-literacy, and (g) arts and creativity
                                              literacy.  Field-based  interdisciplinary  exploration  and  other
                                              teaching strategies shall be used in this course.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours
                    Prerequisite

                    Course Code               EDFS 21
                    Course Title              Field Study 1 – Observations of Teaching-Learning in
                                              Actual School Environment

                    Course Description        This is the first experiential course which will immerse a future
                                              teacher to actual classroom situation and learning environment
                                              where direct observation of teaching and learning episodes that
                                              focuses  on  the  application  of  educational  theories  learned  in
                                              content and pedagogy courses will be made.  Observations on
                                              learners’ behavior, motivation, teachers’ strategies of teaching,
                                              classroom management, assessment in learning among others
                                              shall be given emphasis.  A portfolio shall be required  in the
                                              course.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite              All professional and major/specialization subjects]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[Course Code               EDFS 22
                    Course Title              Field Study 2 – Participation and Teaching Assistantship
                    Course Description        This course is a continuation of Field Study 1.  It is school based
                                              and allows a pre-service student to participate and assist in a
                                              limited  actual  teaching-learning  activities  that  relate  to
                                              assessment  of  learning,  preparation  of  instruction  materials,
                                              preparation  of  the  bulletin  boards,  and  other  routines  in  the
                                              classroom.    A  portfolio  which  will  contain  sample  lesson  or
                                              learning  plans  and  demonstration  teaching  of  at  least  one
                                              subject content area will be required.  An action research shall
                                              be encouraged to start in this course and conclude during the
                                              internship.
                    Course Credits            3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite              All professional subjects and major subjects


                    Course Code               EDFS 23
                    Course Title              Teaching Internship
                    Course Description        This course is a one-semester full time teaching  internship in
                                              basic  education  schools  using  a  clinical  approach  under  the
                                              mentorship of a cooperating teacher.  Teaching internship shall
                                              be done both in the in-campus or off-campus if possible.  No
                                              academic  courses  shall  be  taken  together  with  Teaching
                                              Internship.    A  teaching  portfolio  shall  be  required  and  the
                                              completion of the Action Research.
                    Course Credits            6 units
                    Contact Hours             40 hours per week full time (no academic units allowed)
                    Prerequisite              EDFS 21- Observations of Teaching-Learning in Actual
                                                                School Environment
                                              EDFS 22 - Participation and Teaching Assistantship]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[MAJOR COURSES

                     Course Code              BSEM 21
                     Course Title             History of Mathematics
                     Course Description       This  course  presents  the  humanistic  aspects  of  mathematics
                                              which provides the historical context and timeline that led to the
                                              present understanding and applications of the different branches
                                              of mathematics.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             None

                     Course Code              BSEM 22
                     Course Title             College & Advanced Algebra
                     Course Description       The course builds the students’ knowledge on properties of the
                                              real number system, operations on different types of algebraic
                                              expressions,  and  solution  of  various  types  of  equations  and
                                              inequalities.    The  course  also  covers  the  prerequisites  to
                                              trigonometry and calculus, specifically transcendental and non-
                                              transcendental  functions,  including  the  characteristics  of  their
                                              graphs and applications.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             None

                     Course Code              BSEM 23
                     Course Title             Trigonometry
                     Course Description       The  course  introduces  students  to  circular  and  trigonometric
                                              functions,  trigonometric  identities,  and  to  the  polar  coordinate
                                              system.  The  students  then  apply  concepts  in  these  topics  to
                                              applications in problem solving.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 22 - College & Advanced Algebra]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[Course Code              BSEM 24
                     Course Title             Plane & Solid Geometry
                     Course Description       The course covers topics on Euclidean Geometry. The topics are
                                              discussed  using  both  the  deductive  and  inductive  methods  to
                                              conjecture  definitions,  corollaries,  postulates  and  theorems  on
                                              plane and solid geometry.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 22 - College & Advanced Algebra

                     Course Code              BSEM 25
                     Course Title             Logic and Set Theory
                     Course Description       The course is a study of mathematical logic which covers topics
                                              such  as  propositions,  logical  operators,  rules  of  replacement,
                                              rules of inference, algebra of logic and quantifiers. It also includes
                                              a discussion of elementary theory of sets such as fundamental
                                              concepts of sets, set theorems and set operations.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             None

                     Course Code              BSEM 26
                     Course Title             Elementary Statistics & Probability
                     Course Description       The course equips the students with the basic statistical tools to
                                              understand various phenomena. The topics on mean, variance,
                                              sampling, and estimation eventually allow the students to be able
                                              to perform hypothesis testing on real-life problems from different
                                              fields. The course includes applications and data analysis with
                                              computations carried out using SPSS.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             None]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[Course Code              BSEM 27
                     Course Title             Calculus 1 with Analytic Geometry
                     Course Description       The course equips the students with knowledge and skills needed
                                              to be able to determine limits of functions, to differentiate, and to
                                              integrate  algebraic,  exponential,  logarithmic,  and  trigonometric
                                              functions  in  one  variable.  It  also  includes  exposure  to  ore
                                              challenging problems covering continuity and areas of regions.
                     Course Credits           4 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 22 - College & Advanced Algebra,
                                              BSEM 23 - Trigonometry
                                              BSEM 24 – Plane and Solid Geometry

                     Course Code              BSEM 28
                     Course Title             Calculus 2
                     Course Description       The course aims to further develop the students’ understanding
                                              of differential and  integral calculus. It covers the methods and
                                              techniques  of  integration,  indeterminate  forms,  and  improper
                                              integrals of algebraic and transcendental functions.
                     Course Credits           4 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 27 - Calculus 1 with Analytic Geometry

                     Course Code              BSEM 29
                     Course Title             Calculus 3
                     Course Description       The course aims to provide the students with an understanding
                                              of the applications of differentiation and integration in sequences,
                                              infinite series, power series, as well as of multiple integration for
                                              functions in several variables, Moreover, students will be able to
                                              apply these concepts to problem solving.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 28 - Calculus 2]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[Course Code              BSEM 30
                     Course Title             Modern Geometry
                     Course Description       The  course  is  an  enrichment  of  the  course  on  Euclidean
                                              Geometry. It discusses the properties and applications of other
                                              types  of  geometries  such  as  finite  geometry,  non-Euclidean
                                              geometry, and projective geometry.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 24 - Plane & Solid Geometry
                                              BSEM 25 - Logic & Set Theory

                     Course Code              BSEM 31
                     Course Title             Mathematics of Investment
                     Course Description       The course introduces students with a basic understanding of the
                                              applications of mathematical concepts and skills in economics,
                                              business and accounting. It includes determining the time value
                                              of money using simple and compound interest and discounting,
                                              variation of annuities, amortization stocks and bonds, and sinking
                                              fund..
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSE 22 - College & Advanced Algebra

                     Course Code              BSEM 32
                     Course Title             Number Theory
                     Course Description       The  course  is  a  study  of  the  properties  of  numbers  and  their
                                              proofs.  It  presents  the  students  with  different  methods  of
                                              mathematical proving. It focuses on the discussion of the set of
                                              integers  that  including  Unique  Prime  Factorization,  Divisibility
                                              Rules,  Euclidean  Algorithm,  Linear  Congruence,  and  Linear
                                              Diophantine Equations.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 22 - Advanced Algebra
                                              BSEM 25 - Logic & Set Theory]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[Course Code              BSEM 33
                     Course Title             Linear Algebra
                     Course Description       The  course  provides  a  basic  understanding  of  vector  spaces,
                                              including  the  study  of  matrices,  their  properties  and  matrix
                                              operations. It also covers the applications of matrices in systems
                                              of linear equations and linear transformations.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 25 - Logic & Set Theory

                     Course Code              BSEM 34
                     Course Title             Advanced Statistics
                     Course Description       The  course  deals  with  non-parametric  statistics.  It  covers  the
                                              topics  on  test  of  association  such  as  Spearman  Rho,  Phi
                                              coefficient,  Contingency  coefficient,  biserial  and  test  of
                                              differences  such  as  Mann-Whitney  U,  Wilcoxon.  It  includes
                                              applications  and  data  analysis  with  computations  carried  out
                                              using SPSS.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 26 - Elementary Statistics & Probability

                     Course Code              BSEM 35
                     Course Title             Problem Solving, Mathematical Investigation & Modeling
                     Course Description       The  course  deepens  and  further  enhances  the  students’
                                              understanding  of  real-life  applications  of  mathematics  through
                                              investigating, pattern finding, testing and justifying conjectures,
                                              and making generalizations.
                     Course Credits           3 units
                     Contact Hours
                     Prerequisite             BSEM 22 - Advanced Algebra
                                              BSEM 24 - Plane and Solid Geometry
                                              BSEM 25 - Logic & Set Theory]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[Course Code              BSEM 36

                     Course Title             Principles and Strategies in Teaching Mathematics
                     Course Description       The  course  deals  with  the  applications  of  the  principles,  the
                                              strategies in teaching, and philosophical foundations of teaching
                                              mathematics.  These  are  then  applied  in  lesson  planning  and
                                              microteaching.
                     Course Credits           3 units

                     Contact Hours

                     Prerequisite

                      Course Code             BSEM 37
                      Course Title            Abstract Algebra
                      Course Description      The  course  is  a  study  of  basic  algebraic  structures  such  as
                                              groups,  rings,  integral  domains  and  fields.  It  provides  a  basic
                                              understanding of relations focusing on isomorphism. It aims to
                                              enhance the students’ skills in constructing mathematical proofs,
                                              and  develop  their  symbolic  thinking  and  appreciation  of
                                              mathematical structures.
                      Course Credits          3 units
                      Contact Hours
                      Prerequisite            BSEM 25 - Logic & Set Theory

                      Course Code             BSEM 38
                      Course Title            Research in Mathematics
                      Course Description      The course aims to prepare prospective mathematics teachers to
                                              undertake an undergraduate research project.  It gives teachers
                                              the  opportunity  to  conduct  researches  that  address  problems,
                                              issues, and concerns in mathematics teaching and learning. It
                                              also showcases their research skills through the application of the
                                              mathematical  content  and  processes  they  have  learned
                                              previously.
                      Course Credits          4 units
                      Contact Hours
                      Prerequisite            BSEM 34 - Advanced Statistics]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[Course Code             BSEM 39
                      Course Title            Technology for Teaching and Learning 2
                                              (Instrumentation & Technology in Mathematics)
                      Course Description      TTL  2  is  a  3-unit  course  which  will  focus  on  the  application,
                                              design, production, utilization, and evaluation of Information and
                                              Communications  Technology  (ICT)  materials  for  teaching  and
                                              learning  in  Mathematics  Education  Programs.  The  major
                                              requirement  for  this  course  is  an  ICT-integrated  and  Project-
                                              based Learning Plan aligned to the K to 12 Curriculum. All the
                                              learning activities and course requirements will revolve around
                                              the student-teacher developed Learning Plan.
                      Course Credits          3 units
                      Contact Hours
                      Prerequisite            EDCU 75 - Assessment of Learning Courses 1
                                              EDCU 80 - Assessment of Learning Courses 2
                                              EDUC 85 - Technology for Teaching and Learning 1

                      Course Code             BSEM 40
                      Course Title            Assessment and Evaluation in Mathematics
                      Course Description      The  course  deals  with  traditional  and  authentic  assessment
                                              methods  for  evaluating  mathematics  learning.  It  covers  the
                                              purposes  of  instruction  and  assessment,  the  relationship  of
                                              assessment  to  content  and  performance  standards,  and
                                              discussions on the issues and trends in assessment specifically
                                              in mathematics teaching.
                      Course Credits          3 units
                      Contact Hours
                      Prerequisite            BSEM 34 - Advanced Statistics


                   MANDATED COURSES

                    Course Code              FITT 1
                    Course Title             Movement Enhancement
                    Course Description       This  course  provides  training  in  different  m  patterns  and  core
                                             engagement in conjunction with principles of healthy eating and
                                             physically active life.  Students will be able to adapt and transfer
                                             the  movement  competency  in  different  contexts  (i.e.  use  of
                                             training equipment).
                    Course Credit            2 units
                    Contact Hours            2 hours/week
                    Prerequisite             None]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[Course Code              FITT 2
                    Course Title             Fitness Exercises

                    Course Description       This course provides experiences in core stability, strength
                                             and  mobility  training.    It  includes  goal  setting  exercise
                                             progression and regression and periodic assessment for the
                                             development of various fitness components.
                    Course Credit            2 units
                    Contact Hours            2 hours/week
                    Prerequisite             FITT 1 – Movement Enhancement

                    Course Code              FITT 3
                    Course Title             Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness I
                    Course Description       This  course  will  provide  physical  activities  for  the  purpose  of
                                             optimizing health and fitness.  Students will choose from a menu
                                             of course offering in dance, sports and outdoor activities.
                    Course Credit            2 units
                    Contact Hours            2 hours/week
                    Prerequisite             FITT 1 – Movement Enhancement

                    Course Code              FITT 4
                    Course Title             Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness II
                    Course Description       This course will provide physical activities for the purpose of
                                             optimizing health fitness.  Students will choose from a menu
                                             offering in dance, outdoor adventure activities.
                    Course Credit            2 units
                    Contact Hours            2 hours/week
                    Prerequisite             FITT 1 – Movement Enhancement


                    NSTP 1 and 2

                    Course Code               NSTP 1
                    Course Title              CWTS/LTS/ROTC
                    Course Description        A  comprehensive  program  that  gives  emphasis  on  citizenship
                                              training and still patriotism, moral virtues, respect for the rights of
                                              civilians and adherence to the constitution.
                    Course Credit             3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite              None]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[Course Code               NSTP 2
                    Course Title              CWTS/LTS/ROTC
                    Course Description        A comprehensive program that focuses on the transfer of learned
                                              technology to client barangay/community. A partnership among
                                              student,  school  facilitators  and  barangay  coordinators  toward
                                              improvement, growth and change in the community.
                    Course Credit             3 units
                    Contact Hours             3 hours/week
                    Prerequisite              NSTP 1 - CWTS/LTS/ROTC



                   INSTITUTIONAL MANDATED COURSES

                   Course Code                EDUC 197
                   Course Title               Competency Appraisal 1
                   Course Description         Review classes for professional education courses.
                   Course Credits             3 units
                   Contact Hours              3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code                EDUC 198
                   Course Title               Competency Appraisal 2
                   Course Description         The course provides review classes for specialization/ major
                                              courses and general education courses.
                   Course Credits             3 units
                   Contact Hours              3 hours/week
                   Prerequisite

                   Course Code                CvSU 101
                   Course Title               Institutional Orientation 1
                   Course Description         Cavite State University, its rules and regulations.
                   Course Credits             (1)
                   Contact Hours              1 hour/week
                   Prerequisite]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[SUMMARY OF REVISION]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[SUMMARY OF REVISION

               I.  In compliance with CHED Memorandum no. 75, series 2017


                                                                              NO. OF UNITS
                                   COURSES                    CMO # 75, s.       Existing        Proposed
                                                                   2017
                     A.  GENERAL EDUCATION                          36               57               45
                         COURSES
                     B.  PROFESSIONAL/                                               51
                         FUNDAMENTAL COURSES
                          A. Theory/Concept Courses                 42               12               42
                          B. Methods/Strategies Courses                              27
                          C. Field Study Courses                                     12
                     C. Major Courses                               63               62               63
                     D. Mandated Courses                            14               14               14
                          A. Physical Education                      8               8                8
                          B. NSTP                                    6               6                6
                     E. Institutional Mandated Courses
                          (Competency Appraisal &                                    6                6
                          Institutional Orientation)
                                                    TOTAL          155              190              170


               II.  Added/deleted/changed in the proposed curriculum
                   a.  Deleted Courses
                       ENGL 1        Study and Thinking Skills in English
                       MATH 1        Basic Mathematics
                       HUMN 11       Music, Arts Education and Appreciation
                       PHSC 1        Physical Science Including Earth Science
                       SOSC 1        Society and Culture with Family Planning
                       SOSC 2        General Psychology
                       ENGL 7        Writing in the Discipline
                       FILI 7        Pagbasa at Pagsulat Tungo sa Pananaliksik
                       STAT 1        Elementary Statistics
                       BIOL 1a       General Biology 1
                       SOSC 3        Philippine History, Geography & Institution
                       ITEC 3        Information & Communication Technology
                       LITT 1        Philippine Literature
                       LITT 2        World Literature
                       ENGL 6        Speech Communication
                       FILI 8        Masining na Pagpapahayag
                       SOSC 5        Philippine Government, Politics & Constitution]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[BTCH 1        Introduction to Biotechnology
                       EDUC 99a  Seminar 1
                       EDUC 99b  Seminar 2
                       EDUC 99c      Seminar 3
                       MATH 8        Introduction to Analytic Geometry
                       MATH 50       Foundations of Mathematics
                       CURR 21       Curriculum Development
                       TEAC 21       Principles of Teaching 1
                       TEAC 22       Principles of Teaching 2
                       EDUC 37       Child and Adolescent Development
                       ECON 2        General Economics with TAR
                       EDTC 22       Instructional Media Resources
                       EDFS 23       Field Study 3
                       EDFS 24       Field Study 4
                       EDFS 25       Field Study 5
                       EDFS 26       Field Study 6
                       HUMN 6        Social Philosophy 1
                       ENGL 3        Developmental Reading
                       EDUC 40       Social Dimensions of Education
                       MATH 140  Seminar Technology in Mathematics
                       MATH 150  Seminar in Problem Solving in Mathematics

                   b.  Added Courses
                       GNED 01       Art Appreciation
                       GNED 02       Ethics
                       GNED 03       Mathematics in the Modern World
                       GNED 04       Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas
                       GNED 05       Purposive Communication
                       GNED 06       Science, Technology and Society
                       GNED 07       The Contemporary World
                       GNED 08       Understanding the Self
                       GNED 11       Panitikang Panlipunan
                       GNED 12       Gender and Society
                       EDUC 50       Child and Adolescent Learner and Learning Principles
                                     History of Math
                       EDUC 60       The Teacher and The Community, School Culture and
                                     Organizational Leadership
                       EDUC 65       Foundation of Special and Inclusive Education
                       EDUC 90       The Teacher and the School Curriculum
                       EDUC 95       Building and Enhancing New Literacies Across the Curriculum
                       BSEM 21       History of Math]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[BSEM 29       Calculus 3
                       BSEM 39       Technology for Teaching and Learning 2
                                             (Instrumentation & Evaluation in Mathematics)
                       BSEM 25       Logic & Set Theory
                       BSEM 36       Principles & Strategies in Teaching Mathematics
                       BSEM 40       Assessment & Evaluation in Mathematics


                   c.  Replaced Courses

                       FROM                                       TO
                       MATH 5     Plane Trigonometry              BSEM 23     Trigonometry
                       MATH 6     Advanced Algebra                BSEM 22     College and Advanced
                                                                                Algebra
                       MATH 155a   Plane Geometry                 BSEM 24     Plane and Solid Geometry
                       MATH 110  Mathematical Probability  BSEM 26              Elementary Statistics and
                                                                                Probability
                       MATH 155      Calculus 1                   BSEM 27     Calculus 1 with Analytic
                                                                                Geometry
                       MATH 135  Mathematical                     BSEM 35       Problem Solving,
                                             Investigations & Modeling          Mathematical Investigation
                                                                                & Modelling

                   d.  Changed Course Titles

                       FROM                                              TO
                       FILI 6       Komunikasyon sa Akademikong          GNED 10    Kontekstwalisadong
                                       Filipino                                          Komunikasyon sa
                                                                                         Filipino
                       EDTC 21   Introduction to Educational             EDUC 85    Technology for
                                     Technology                                                        Teaching and
                                                                                         Learning 1
                       ASSE 21    Assessment of Learning 1               EDUC 75    Assessment in
                                                                                         Learning 1
                       ASSE 22    Assessment of Learning 2               EDUC 80    Assessment in
                                                                                         Learning 2]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[e.  Courses with Modified Subject Codes

                       FROM                                       TO
                       Course Code          Course Title          Course Code         Course Title
                       SOSC 6          Rizal’s Life, Works and   GNED 09         Life and Works of Rizal*
                                       Writings
                       EDUC 39       The Teaching Profession  EDUC 55        The Teaching Profession
                       EDUC 38      Facilitating Learning         EDUC 70        Facilitating Learner-
                                                                                  Centered Teaching
                       EDFS 27       Practice Teaching            EDFS 23         Teaching Internship
                       MATH 106    Modern Geometry                BSEM 30         Modern Geometry
                       MATH 111  Abstract Algebra                 BSEM 37         Abstract Algebra
                       STAT 4        Advanced Statistics          BSEM 34         Advanced Statistics
                       MATH 80       Linear Algebra               BSEM 33         Linear Algebra
                       MATH 105      Number Theory                BSEM 32       Number Theory
                       MATH 145      Research in Mathematics  BSEM 35             Research in Mathematics
                       MATH 160  Calculus II                      BSEM 28       Calculus 2
                       BMGT 21a  Mathematics of                   BSEM 31       Mathematics of
                                     Investment                                   Investment]]></page></pages></Search>