<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="22"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.5.            The institution ensures transparency in


                        the development/revision of guidelines


                        and procedures for the student council/

                        government.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY-TANZA CAMPUS
                                                           CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT

                                           Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                                    -




             September 19, 2022


             PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
             Campus Administrator
             This Campus

                                               Thru: MS. MELONA I. SAQUIN
                                                         Head, OSAS


             Dear Sir!

             Good day!


             As we start our obligation as the newly elected officers of the highest student body of this institution,
             we are respectfully submitting the Constitution and By-laws of the Central Student Government
             which will govern the Campus’ student council for Academic Year 2022-2023.



             Attached is the said document for your approval. Thank you and stay safe!


             Respectfully yours,


             JAN ANGELA L. CATINDIG
             President, CSG

             Noted by:


             MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
             Senior Adviser


                  JOHNNY RICK S. APELLANES
             Junior Adviser

             Recommending Approval:

             MELONA I. SAQUIN
             Head, OSAS

                                                                                  Approved by:




                                                  PROF.  GIL D.  RAMOS
                                   Administrator, Cavite State University – Tanza Campus]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CENTRAL STUDENT


                                            GOVERNMENT




























                                     CONSTITUTION



                                                        AND



                                               BY-LAWS





















                          1     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                        Tanza Campus
                                       Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                      (046) 850 – 5088
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                           CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT


                                              CONSTITUTION AND BY-LAWS

                                                         PREAMBLE


                              We, the students of Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                       (CvSU-TC),  imploring  the  aid  of  Almighty  God,  in  order  to  establish  a
                       nationalistic,  democratic,  autonomous,  and  representative  Central
                       Student Government that shall truly reflect the needs, ideas, and goals of
                       the  CvSU-TC  SSG  student,  protect  and  promote  students’  rights,
                       interests,  and  welfare  contributions  to  the  furtherance  of  academic
                       excellence  and  academic  freedom,  affirm  dynamic  and  responsible
                       student leadership, attain a high degree of moral, social and intellectual
                       growth and strength the common ties that bind us, ordain and promulgate
                       this Constitution and By-Laws.

                                                          ARTICLE I
                                     NAME AND DOMICILE OF THE ORGANIZATION

                   SECTION 1         The Student Council of the Cavite State University- Tanza Campus
                                     shall be known as Cavite State University- Tanza Campus Central
                                     Student  Government,  herein  and  thereafter  known  as  CvSU-TC
                                     CSG.


                   SECTION 2         The office of the CvSU-TC CSG shall be located at the Cavite
                                     State University-Tanza Campus, Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas,
                                     Tanza, Cavite.


                                                          ARTICLE II
                                     DECLARATION OF PRINCIPLES AND POLICIES

                   SECTION 1         The CvSU-TC CSG is a nationalist, democratic, autonomous, and
                                     representative  Student’s  Council.  Power  and  authority  shall
                                     emanate from the student constituency.












                          2     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[SECTION 2         The  CvSU-TC  CSG  believes  that  education  should  promote  the
                                     total  and  well-rounded  development  of  every  student  in  order  to
                                     realize a humane existence for all. Thus, it shall enhance critical
                                     thinking including the ability to make an informed judgment, free of
                                     dogmas and myths.


                   SECTION 3         The  CvSU-TC  CSG  shall  protect  and  promote  the  student’s
                                     interests, rights, and welfare.



                   SECTION 4         The CvSU-TC CSG shall be the vanguard of the  mechanism by
                                     which  students  could  properly  involve  themselves  in  the
                                     management  of  their  activities  and  in  the  enhancement  of  their
                                     education.


                   SECTION 5         The CvSU-TC CSG shall develop among the student a sense of
                                     service  and  responsibility  so  that  they  will  utilize  educational
                                     opportunities to the maximum for the unity and welfare of the CvSU
                                     Tanza Campus community.



                   SECTION 6         The CvSU-TC CSG shall serve as an active forum for the ideas and
                                     sentiments of the students.



                   SECTION 7         The  CvSU-TC  CSG  shall  seek,  generate  and  support  education
                                     reforms along with nationalistic, humanistic, and scientific methods
                                     for the full development of the human potential to respond to social
                                     realities and to promote academic freedom.


                   SECTION 8         The CvSU-TC CSG shall at all times uphold this Constitution and
                                     By-Laws




                                                         ARTICLE III
                                                        MEMBERSHIP


                   SECTION 1         All bonafide undergraduate students  of Cavite State University  –
                                     Tanza Campus are members of the constituency represented by
                                     the CvSU-TC CSG.












                          3     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[ARTICLE IV
                                                      BILL OF RIGTHS




                   SECTION          Students shall have the right to information on matters affecting them.
                   1

                   SECTION          Students  shall  have  the  unabridged  right  to  form  organizations  or
                   2                associations in conformity with the rules and regulations adopted by
                                   the college.


                   SECTION          Students  shall  have  the  right  to  enjoy  the  freedom  of  speech,
                   3                expression, and of the press.


                   SECTION          Students shall have the right to exercise freedom of religious beliefs,
                   4                faith, and spiritual practices.


                   SECTION          Students  shall  have  the  right  to  undertake  research  publish  and
                   5                discuss  findings  and  recommendations  in  accordance  with  the
                                   principles of academic freedom.


                   SECTION          Students  shall  have  the  right  to  peaceably  for  the  redress  of
                   6                grievances and seek speedy action thereof.


                   SECTION          Students shall have the right to appeal any decisions affecting their
                   7                rights, interests, and welfare.


                   SECTION          Students shall have the right to enjoy the fullest adequate facilities
                   8                and services provided by the College.


                   SECTION          Students shall have the right to due process of law.
                   9

                   SECTION          Students  shall  not  be  subjected  to  exploitation,  involuntarily
                   10               servitude, harassment, or cruel and/or unusual punishment.

                   SECTION          Students shall have the right to exercise freedom of ideological and
                   11               political beliefs.

                   SECTION          Students shall have the right to vote in  any  matters affecting their
                   12               rights, interest, and welfare.

                                                         ARTICLE V
                                    DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF STUDENTS




                          4     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[SECTION          Every student shall observe at all times the law of the land, the rules
                   1                and regulations of the College, and uphold this Constitution and By-
                                   Laws.


                   SECTION          Every student shall assist College authorized person in disseminating
                   2                the  rules  and  regulations  of  the  College  and  instructing  fellow
                                   students and other members of the community.

                   SECTION          Every  student  shall  help  promote  an  academic  atmosphere
                   3                conducive to peace and harmony among various constituencies of
                                   the College.
                   SECTION          Every student shall exercise his/her rights and responsibility with due
                   4                regard for the right of his fellow students and other members of the
                                   Cavite State University – Tanza Campus community.


                   SECTION          Every student shall elect his/her respective class officers.
                   5

                   SECTION          Every  student  shall  pay  the  required  fees  levied  by  the  CvSU-TC
                   6                CSG.

                                                         ARTICLE VI
                         CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY – TANZA CAMPUS CENTRAL STUDENT
                                                       GOVERNMENT

                   SECTION          Cavite State University – Tanza Campus Student Government (CvSU
                   1                –  TC  CSG)  shall  have  the  power  to  implement  all  policies  and
                                   resolutions  concerning  the  right,  interests,  and  welfare  of  the
                                    students.

                   SECTION          The  CvSU-TC  CSG  shall  be  composed  of  its  President,  Vice-
                   2                President,  Secretary,  Treasurer,  Auditor,  Public  Relation  Officer
                                   (PRO), and each representative from each course, from each entire
                                    student constituency.

                                    a.) The Elected President of each student organization’s course will
                                       automatically serve as a representative of their respective course
                                       and organization.


                   SECTION          The CvSU-TC CSG President or his/her authorized representative/s
                   3                shall  be  the  rightful  representative/s  of  the  entire  student
                                   constituency.

                   SECTION          The  CvSU-TC  CSG  shall  consider  the  General  Principles  of
                   4                cooperation and maintenance of order and discipline in the pursuit of
                                   purpose and objective of the organization.






                          5     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[SECTION          The  CvSU-TC  CSG  shall  plan,  approve,  and  implement  programs
                   5                and projects within its area of jurisdiction.

                   SECTION          The CvSU-TC CSG shall enforce rules and policies formulated by the
                   6                University Consultative Assembly.

                   The  CvSU-
                   TC CSG
                   SECTION          The CvSU-TC CSG shall allocate funds provided for its campus and
                   7                administer  them  for  the  implementation  of  projects  relevant  to  the
                                   needs of its constituency.



                   SECTION          All elected and appointed officials of the CvSU – TC CSG shall hold
                   8                the office for one (1) academic year or until such time that a new set
                                   of officers shall have been sworn to office.



                   SECTION          The general management of the affairs and properties shall be vested
                   9                in the CvSU – TC CSG.



                                                         ARTICLE VII
                     DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY – TANZA
                      CAMPUS CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT (CvSU-TC CSG) OFFICERS


                   SECTION 1        the President

                                   (a) He/She shall be the chief executive of the organization and shall
                                       have the duty to supervise its affairs.
                                   (b) He/She shall guide all the elected officials.
                                   (c) He/She shall preside during the regular meeting of the CvSU-TC
                                       CSG.
                                   (d) He/She shall have the authority to create any committee, as it may
                                       deem necessary in approval of all the advisers.
                                   (e) He/She shall have the power to appoint members of the council
                                       and other different committees.
                                   (f)  He/She shall have the power to call special/emergency meetings
                                       whenever necessary.
                                   (g) He/She shall represent the CvSU-TC CSG in different meetings,
                                       etc.
                                   (h) He/She  shall  lead  the  members  in  carrying  out  activities  in
                                       attaining the purpose and objectives of the organization.
                                   (i)  He/She  shall  have  the  power  to  direct  and  supervise  the
                                       implementation of any activity that CvSU-TC CSG may undertake.
                                   (j)  He/She shall have the power to appropriate funds in conformity
                                       with the approved budget allocations.






                          6     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[(k) He/she  shall  have  the  power  to  enforce  a  provision  of  the
                                       Constitutions  and  By-Laws  and  all  rules  and  regulations  of  the
                                       CvSu-TC CSG.
                                   (l)  He/She shall ensure the proper implementation of the CvSU-TC
                                       CSG Constitution and By-Laws.












                   SECTION 2        the Vice – President

                                   (a) He/She  shall  perform  the  function  and  duty  of  the  President  in
                                       case of the latter’s absence and/or disability.
                                   (b) He/She shall carefully monitor the performance of other officers.
                                   (c) He/She  shall  take  charge  of  the  planning  of  activities  of  the
                                       Student Council.
                                   (d) He/She shall handle a committee to be assigned by the CvSU-TC
                                       CSG.
                                   (e) He/She  shall,  together  with  the  president,  enforce  policies  and
                                       guidelines formulated by the Central Student Government.
                                   (f)  He/She  shall  perform  other  functions  and  duties  as  may  be
                                       assigned by the President from time to time.



                   SECTION 3        the Secretary

                                   (a) He/She shall compose all letters/reports in accordance with the
                                       specifications of content given by the President.
                                   (b) He/She shall prepare, sign, send and file all the communication
                                       pertaining to the CvSU-TC CSG.
                                   (c) He/She  shall  post  the  memoranda  and  see  to  it  that
                                       announcements are known upon the notification of the President.
                                   (d) He/She  shall  keep  the  full  minutes  of  all  the  meetings  of  the
                                       Central Student Government meetings and consultative assembly
                                       meetings and certify its correctness.
                                   (e) He/She shall prepare and serve due notice of all meetings of the
                                       Central Student Government meetings and consultative assembly
                                       in accordance with this Constitution and By-Laws.
                                   (f)  He/she  shall  act  as  a  custodian  and  maintain  all  records  and
                                       documents of the CvSu-TC CSG and consultative assembly.
                                   (g) He/She  shall  perform  other  functions  and  duties  as  may  be
                                       assigned by the President from time to time.
                                   (h) He/She may appoint an assistant secretary if necessary.








                          7     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[SECTION 4        the Treasurer

                                   (a) He/She shall act as a custodian of all records and funds of the
                                       CvSU-TC CSG.
                                   (b) He/She shall be responsible for prompt collection of all fees levied
                                       by the CvSU-TC CSG.
                                   (c) He/She  shall  exercise  supervision  and  coordination  with  all
                                       classroom treasurers.
                                   (d) He/She shall receive and disburse funds on behalf of the Student
                                       Council as authorized by the President, provided, however, that
                                       all disbursement be supported by the necessary documents which
                                       shall be kept as part of his/her record.
                                   (e) He/She  shall  complete  accounts  and  records  of  all  funds  and
                                       financial transactions of the CvSU-TC CSG.
                                   (f)  He/She  shall  prepare  the  monthly  financial  statement  of  the
                                       CvSU-TC CSG.
                                   (g) He/She shall, together with the President, sign all the instruments,
                                       checks, and orders for the payments of money against the funds
                                       or credits in the current savings account of the CvSU-TC CSG.
                                   (h) He/She  shall  perform  other  functions  and  duties  as  may  be
                                       assigned by the President from time to time.





                   SECTION 5        the Business Manager

                                   (a) He/She  shall  examine  all  records  of  the  finances  of  CvSU-TC
                                       CSG.
                                   (b) He/She  shall  coordinate  with  the  treasurer  with  regard  to  the
                                       financial status of the council.
                                   (c) He/She  shall  determine  whether  the  financial  position  of  the
                                       CvSU-TC CSG is clearly presented in its statement of account to
                                       be presented by him/her.
                                   (d) He/She shall ascertain whether all funds due to CvSU-TC CSG
                                       have been properly recorded and whether all disbursements of
                                       funds and/or use of property have been duly authorized and duly
                                       accounted for.
                                   (e) He/She  shall  submit  to  the  adviser  and  coordinator  a  financial
                                       report after every activity it undertakes.
                                   (f)  He/She shall submit a report of CvSU-TC CSG to the Dean at the
                                       end of every semester.
                                   (g) He/She  shall  evaluate  the  work  of  the  treasurer  and
                                       recommended  to  the  President  the  adaptation  of  corrective
                                       procedures  to  improve  internal  control  or  fund  receipts  and
                                       disbursements.
                                   (h) He/She  shall  perform  other  functions  and  duties  as  maybe
                                       assigned by the President from time to time.






                          8     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[SECTION 6        the Public Relation Officer

                                   (a) He/She shall serve as coordinator of the activities of the Central
                                       Student Government and shall see to it that the activities do not
                                       conflict with other important activities of the entire constituency.
                                   (b) He/She shall be responsible for disseminating information to other
                                       organizations,  clubs,  or  committees  and  to  all  other  members
                                       pertinent to the Central Student Government.
                                   (c) He/She  shall  perform  other  functions  and  duties  as  may  be
                                       assigned by the President from time to time.

                   SECTION 7        the Senators (4 members)

                                    (a) They shall serve as the head of the different committee, which
                                       includes:
                                             I.   Environmental Management Committee, whose duty is
                                                  to:
                                                    i.   To encourage students to dispose of solid waste
                                                         properly and responsibly.
                                                    ii.   To    produce      activities    that    promote
                                                         environmental literacy.
                                                   iii.   To ensure students comply with the “Garbage in,
                                                         Garbage out Policy” of the University.
                                                   iv.   To  encourage  students  to  engage  in  the
                                                         productive use of recyclable waste.
                                            II.   Sports and Recreation Management committee, whose
                                                  duty is to:
                                                    i.   To motivate the students to participate in sports
                                                         and recreational activities.
                                                    ii.   To  outsource  funds  to  acquire  more  sports
                                                         equipment.
                                                   iii.   To produce recreational events that will amplify
                                                         the  student’s  involvement  and  commitment  to
                                                         the university’s mission and vision.
                                                   iv.   To     encourage       and     promote       global
                                                         competitiveness by providing support to student-
                                                         athletes.
                                            III.   Consultative and Support Committee, whose duty is to:
                                                    i.   To  become  a  bridge  of  communication  for  the
                                                         students to the campus administrator.
                                                    ii.   To ensure that the Central Student Government
                                                         office  is  able  to  support  the  campus
                                                         administrative function.
                                                   iii.   To  develop  a  medium  where  students  can
                                                         promote  agendas  that  could  be  used  for  their
                                                         advantages and best benefits.
                                                   iv.   To create connections that will help the student
                                                         with their needs.




                          9     Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[(b) They shall perform other functions and duties as may be assigned
                                       by the President from time to time.





                                                         ARTICLE VIII
                                                COMMISSION ON ELECTION

                  SECTION 1          The Commission on Election (COMELEC) shall be composed of
                                     three (3) commissioners all of whom be appointed by OSA. The
                                     OSA Coordinator shall act as the chairperson.

                  SECTION 2          All commissioners shall have the following qualifications:

                                            a.  He/she shall be a bonafide student at CvSU-Tanza
                                                Campus
                                            b.  He/she shall have a GPA of at least 2.5 for the last
                                                semester
                                            c.  He/she shall have no pending cases
                                            d.  An incumbent officer shall in this case be chosen or
                                                elected as a member of the COMELEC

                  SECTION 3          The COMELEC shall have the following functions:


                                            a.  For the practical organization of the entire election,
                                                including screening, campaign procedures, polling
                                                procedures, vote counts, and announcement of
                                                results.
                                            b.  To promulgate rules and regulations implementing the
                                                provisions of CvSU-TC CSG Student Organization
                                                Election Code or other laws which the Commission is
                                                required to enforce and administer.
                                            c.  To pass the verdict on election complaints concerning
                                                election returns and qualifications of candidates for
                                                elective positions.
                                            d.  To take such other measures that may deem proper
                                                upon consultation with the OSA Head.
                                            e.  To report the results of the election to the OSA and to
                                                the entire college constituents.

                SECTION 4            The Commission may recommend the removal or may take
                                     disciplinary action against any candidate for violating or
                                     disregarding any of its orders, directives, and/or decisions.

                SECTION 5            No suspension of sentence for violation of the laws or rules and
                                     regulations concerning elections shall be meted out without the
                                     recommendation of the commission.

                          10    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[SECTION 6            All the decisions of the COMELEC sitting en banc shall be final.

                SECTION 7            The campaign shall end one day before the election.

                SECTION 8            The members of the COMELEC shall set the guidelines and
                                     manners regarding the election-related protest.


                                                         ARTICLE IX
                                                   SYSTEM OF ELECTION

                SECTION 1            There shall be a definite system to be observed in the election of
                                     certain officers and members of the CvSU- TC CSG.


                SECTION 2            The system shall be as follows:

                                     a)  The election exercises shall be held within the period
                                         specified above
                                     b)  The CvSU- TC officials shall be elected in a manner provided
                                         by a section of article respectively of this Constitution and
                                         By-Laws.

                SECTION 3            Qualifications of the Candidacy (CvSU- TC CSG)

                                     Candidates must meet all the requirements by the deadline to
                                     be eligible to participate in the election which is to be verified by
                                     the COMELEC:




                                     A)  President

                                         1.  He/ she must be a junior or senior officially enrolled
                                            student of CvSU- Tanza Campus. He must present the
                                            original and a photocopy of his/ her registration form. A
                                            student who is not officially enrolled shall give a
                                            promissory note stating that he shall pay the remaining
                                            amount of the 50% required upon enrollment payment
                                            one month (30 days) after the date of the declaration of
                                            winners. The note will be attached to his/ her application
                                            form. Failure to pay shall mean a vacancy in his/ her
                                            position.
                                         2.  He/ she shall obtain a certificate of good moral character.
                                         3.   He/ she must be a full-time student and a registered
                                            member of the organization for at least a year.
                                         4.  He/ she must be an officer of any other organizations and
                                            clubs.



                          11    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[5.  He/ she shall have a GPA of 2.5 and must not have
                                            failing grades in any subjects for the last semester.
                                         6.  He/ she must not be a working student while in office. A
                                            working student who is engaged in work outside of
                                            College. Examples include:
                                                       ●  Student Assistant
                                                       ●  Fast food/ restaurant crew
                                                       ●  SK Chairman
                                                       ●  SK Councilor
                                                       ●  Department store staff
                                         7.  For a transferee and returning student, he must be a
                                            resident of CvSU- Tanza Campus for one year or two
                                            consecutive semesters.

                                     B)  Vice President

                                         1.  He/ she must be a junior or senior officially enrolled
                                            student of CvSU- Tanza Campus. He must present the
                                            original and a photocopy of his/ her registration form. A
                                            student who is not officially enrolled shall give a
                                            promissory note stating that he shall pay the remaining
                                            amount of the 50% required upon enrollment payment
                                            one month (30 days) after the date of the declaration of
                                            winners. The note will be attached to his/ her application
                                            form. Failure to pay shall mean a vacancy of his/ her
                                            position.
                                         2.  He/ she shall obtain a certificate of good moral character.
                                         3.   He/ she must be a full-time student and a registered
                                            member of the organization for at least a year.
                                         4.  He/ she must be an officer of any other organizations and
                                            clubs.
                                         5.  He/ she shall have a GPA of 2.5 and must not have
                                            failing grades in any subjects for the last semester.
                                         6.  He/ she must not be a working student while in the office.
                                            A working student who is engaged in work outside of
                                            College. Examples include:
                                                       ●  Student Assistant
                                                       ●  Fast food/ restaurant crew
                                                       ●  SK Chairman
                                                       ●  SK Councilor
                                                       ●  Department store staff
                                         7.  For a transferee and returning student, he must be a
                                            resident of CvSU- Tanza Campus for one year or two
                                            consecutive semesters.

                          12    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[C)  Secretary

                                         1.  He/ she must be a junior or senior officially enrolled
                                            student of CvSU-Tanza Campus. He must present the
                                            original and a photocopy of his/ her registration form. A
                                            student who is not officially enrolled shall give a
                                            promissory note stating that he shall pay the remaining
                                            amount of the 50% required upon enrollment payment
                                            one month (30 days) after the date of the declaration of
                                            winners. The note will be attached to his/ her application
                                            form. Failure to pay shall mean a vacancy of his/ her
                                            position.
                                         2.  He/ she shall obtain a certificate of good moral character.
                                         3.   He/ she must be a full-time student and a registered
                                            member of the organization for at least a year.
                                         4.  He/ she must be an officer of any other organizations and
                                            clubs.
                                         5.  He/ she shall have a GPA of 2.5 and must not have
                                            failing grades in any subjects for the last semester.
                                         6.  He/ she must not be a working student while in office. A
                                            working student who is engaged in work outside of
                                            College. Examples include:
                                                       ●  Student Assistant
                                                       ●  Fast food/ restaurant crew
                                                       ●  SK Chairman
                                                       ●  SK Councilor
                                                       ●  Department store staff

                                         7.  For a transferee and returning student, he must be a
                                            resident of CvSU-Tanza Campus for one year or two
                                            consecutive semesters.

                                     D)  Treasurer

                                         1.  He/ she must be a junior or senior officially enrolled
                                            student of CvSU- Tanza Campus. He must present the
                                            original and a photocopy of his/ her registration form. A
                                            student who is not officially enrolled shall give a
                                            promissory note stating that he shall pay the remaining
                                            amount of the 50% required upon enrollment payment
                                            one month (30 days) after the date of the declaration of
                                            winners. The note will be attached to his/ her application




                          13    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[form. Failure to pay shall mean a vacancy in his/ her
                                            position.
                                         2.  He/ she shall obtain a certificate of good moral character.
                                         3.   He/ she must be a full-time student and a registered
                                            member of the organization for at least a year.
                                         4.  He/ she must be an officer of any other organizations and
                                            clubs.
                                         5.  He/ she shall have a GPA of 2.5 and must not have
                                            failing grades in any subjects for the last semester.
                                         6.  He/ she must not be a working student while in office. A
                                            working student who is engaged in work within the
                                            outside of the College. Examples include:
                                                       ●  Student Assistant
                                                       ●  Fast food/ restaurant crew
                                                       ●  SK Chairman
                                                       ●  SK Councilor
                                                       ●  Department store staff
                                         7.  For a transferee and returning student, he must be a
                                            resident of CvSU-Tanza Campus for one year or two
                                            consecutive semesters.


                                     E)  Business Manager

                                         1.  He/ she must be a sophomore, junior or senior officially
                                            enrolled student of CvSU-Tanza Campus. He must
                                            present the original and a photocopy of his/ her
                                            registration form. A student who is not officially enrolled
                                            shall give a promissory note stating that he shall pay the
                                            remaining amount of the 50% required upon enrollment
                                            payment one month (30 days) after the date of the
                                            declaration of winners. The note will be attached to his/
                                            her application form. Failure to pay shall mean a vacancy
                                            of his/ her position.
                                         2.  He/ she shall obtain a certificate of good moral character.
                                         3.   He/ she must be a full-time student and a registered
                                            member of the organization for at least a year.
                                         4.  He/ she must be an officer of any other organizations and
                                            clubs.
                                         5.  He/ she shall have a GPA of 2.5 and must not have
                                            failing grades in any subjects for the last semester.






                          14    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[6.  He/ she must not be a working student while in the office.
                                            A working student who is engaged in work outside of
                                            College. Examples include:
                                                       ●  Student Assistant
                                                       ●  Fast food/ restaurant crew
                                                       ●  SK Chairman
                                                       ●  SK Councilor
                                                       ●  Department store staff
                                         7.  For a transferee and returning student, he must be a
                                            resident of CvSU-Tanza Campus for one year or two
                                            consecutive semesters.

                                     F)  Public Relations Officer

                                         1.  He/ she must be a freshman, sophomore, junior or senior
                                            officially enrolled student of CvSU-Tanza Campus. He
                                            must present the original and a photocopy of his/ her
                                            registration form. A student who is not officially enrolled
                                            shall give a promissory note stating that he shall pay the
                                            remaining amount of the 50% required upon enrollment
                                            payment one month (30 days) after the date of the
                                            declaration of winners. The note will be attached to his/
                                            her application form. Failure to pay shall mean a vacancy
                                            in his/ her position.
                                         2.  He/ she shall obtain a certificate of good moral character.
                                         3.   He/ she must be a full-time student and a registered
                                            member of the organization for at least a year.
                                         4.  He/ she must be an officer of any other organizations and
                                            clubs.
                                         5.  He/ she shall have a GPA 2.5/ 80 % high school GPA
                                            and must not have failing grades in any subjects for the
                                            last semester.
                                         6.  He/ she must not be a working student while in office. A
                                            working student who is engaged in work within the
                                            outside of the College. Examples include:
                                                       ●  Student Assistant
                                                       ●  Fast food/ restaurant crew
                                                       ●  SK Chairman
                                                       ●  SK Councilor
                                                       ●  Department store staff

                                         7.  For a transferee and returning student, he/she must be a
                                            resident of CvSU-Tanza Campus for one year or two
                                            consecutive semesters.

                          15    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[G)  Senators

                                            1.  They must be a freshman, sophomore, junior, or
                                                senior officially enrolled student of CvSU-Tanza
                                                Campus. They must present the original and a
                                                photocopy of his/her registration form. A student who
                                                is not officially enrolled shall give a promissory note
                                                stating that he shall pay the remaining amount of the
                                                50% required upon enrollment payment one month
                                                (30 days) after the date of the declaration of winners.
                                                The note will be attached to his/ her application form.
                                                Failure to pay shall mean a vacancy in his/ her
                                                position.
                                            2.  They shall obtain a certificate of good moral character.
                                            3.  They must be a full-time student and a registered
                                                member of the organization for at least a year.
                                            4.  They must be an officer of any other organizations
                                                and clubs.
                                            5. They shall have a GPA of 2.5/ 80 % high school GPA
                                                and must not have failing grades in any subjects for
                                                the last semester.
                                            6.  They must not be a working student while in the office.
                                                A working student who is engaged in work outside of
                                                College. Examples include:
                                                       ●  Student Assistant
                                                       ●  Fast food/ restaurant crew
                                                       ●  SK Chairman
                                                       ●  SK Councilor
                                                       ●  Department store staff

                                            7.  For a transferee and returning student/s, they must be
                                                a resident of CvSU-Tanza Campus for one year or
                                                two consecutive semesters.


                                                          ARTICLE X
                         ACCOUNTABILITY OF CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY-TANZA STUDENT
                                                 GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS

                 SECTION 1           All elected and appointed officials of the CvSU-TC CSG shall at
                                     all times be accountable to the studentry whom they should serve
                                     with  utmost  responsibility,  integrity,  loyalty,  efficiency,  and
                                     patriotism.


                          16    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[SECTION 2           All elected and appointed official of the CvSU-TC CSG may be
                                     removed from the office on the grounds of culpable violation of
                                     this constitution and Bylaws, betrayal, bribery and graft and
                                     corruption and other high crimes.

                 SECTION 3           Judgments in case of conviction shall not extend further than
                                     removal from holding any office within the organization.

                SECTION 4            Officers resigned or removed from office shall be replaced
                                     through a special plebiscite to be here within one month after
                                     the occurrence of vacancy. The COMELEC mandated to
                                     promulgate rules or regulation concerning the conduct of special
                                     election.




                                                         ARTICLE XI
                                                          MEETINGS

                SECTION 1            The schedule of the meeting:
                                     a)  General meeting shall take place a week before and a day
                                         after a project and/or activity.
                                     b)  Special and emergency meetings are held whenever
                                         necessary.

               SECTION 2             The order of the meeting shall be:
                                     a)  Calling the meeting to order by the Secretary
                                     b)  Calling the role by another Secretary
                                     c)  Evaluation of the development on previous matters taken by
                                         the President
                                     d)  Unfinished business
                                     e)  Report of the treasurer
                                     f)  Announcement
                                     g)  Adjournment

               SECTION 3             The officers shall follow the formal/order.

               SECTION 4             The President whenever necessary may call emergency
                                     meetings provided that reasonable notice is served upon the
                                     officers/members.






                          17    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[SECTION 5             All meetings shall be held at the place, time and date designated
                                     by the President. The notification of which shall be made by the
                                     PRO and Secretary.

               SECTION 6             Two-thirds (2/3) of the quorum should always be followed.

               SECTION 7             Certain fines shall be given for any absence and tardiness in
                                     each meeting. A 15 minutes grace period will be given for the
                                     late and;
                                     a)  16-30 minutes late will be fined Php 20.00;
                                     b)  31 minutes and above will be declared as absent and will be
                                         fined Php 100.00.

               SECTION 8             In any case, if an officer is in need to be absent in an official
                                     meeting, he/she shall provide a valid reason, with proof of
                                     evidence, which includes:
                                     a)  Bad Health Condition;
                                     b)  Emergency Situations, in which other officers will vote if the
                                         situation is indeed an emergency.


                                                         ARTICLE XII
                                                        TERMINATION

               SECTION 1             3 consecutive absences from an official meeting will result in
                                     removal from the position.

               SECTION 2             The removed officer shall surrender the CSG Uniform, CSG I.D.,
                                     and if available, funds or collection money.

               SECTION 3             The remaining CSG officers will nominate candidates for the
                                     vacant position which will then be approved by the president.


                                                         ARTICLE XIII
                                                   GENERAL PROVISION

               SECTION 1             The CvSU-TC CSG may adopt an official seal which shall both,
                                     be truly reflective and symbolic of the ideas, principles and
                                     aspirations of the whole studentry.

               SECTION 2             The name of the CvSU-TC CSG shall not be used for immoral or
                                     unlawful purposes.


                          18    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[SECTION 3             All Student Organizations shall be recognized by the CvSU-TC
                                     CSG and shall submit a copy of their respective plan of
                                     programs and budgets attached to the previously accomplished
                                     programs and budgets, semestral financial statements to be
                                     handled by the CvSU-TC CSG Vice–President.

               SECTION 4             All students’ organizations shall extend support to the CvSU-TC
                                     CSG in the implementation and realization of its objectives.

               SECTION 5             The CvSU-TC CSG shall ensure a medium for informing its
                                     constituency of all its activities and projects.

               SECTION 6             General Election shall be held before the closing of the second
                                     semester.

               SECTION 7             All elected officials of the CvSU- TC CSG shall in no case hold
                                     more than one (1) position in any class or non-class
                                     organization.

               SECTION 8             All elected officials of the CvSU- TC CSG shall wear its CSG
                                                      nd
                                     uniform every 2  week of the month. Failure to comply will be
                                     fined Php 50.00.

                                                         ARTICLE XIV
                                                  AMENDMENTS/REVISION

               SECTION 1             The CvSU-Tanza Campus Central Student Government upon a
                                     vote of three-fourths (3/4) of all its members may propose
                                     amendments to or revisions of this Constitutions and Bylaws.
               SECTION 2             Any amendment to or revision of this Constitution and Bylaws
                                     shall be valid when ratified by majority of the members of the
                                     Constituency in a student plebiscite duly called for the purpose.

                                                         ARTICLE XV
                                                         EFFECTIVITY

               SECTION 1             This constitution and Bylaws shall take effect immediately upon
                                     its ratification by a majority of the votes cast by the students at a
                                     Campus- wide Plebiscite duly called for its purpose.






                          19    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[JAN ANGELA L. CATINDIG
                                                           President


                                                    MA. ALTHEA L. BATILO
                                                         Vice-President


                                                 KAYLA ROSE I. MAGPANTAY
                                                           Secretary


                                                 JENNELYN M. VALDERAMA
                                                           Treasurer


                                                 RUTH MARIANNE A. PALMA
                                                       Business Manager


                                                    FIDEL JR. A. SEVERINO
                                                             P.R.O.


                       JULIE CLAIRE C. ANDRES                               CIARA MAE D. DEUNA
                                 Senator                                               Senator


                       HAROLD D. PILANDE                                  JOHNTHEL R. JALBUENA
                                  Senator                                              Senator


                       Noted by:                                         Recommending Approval:


                       MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                               MELONA I. SAQUIN
                       Senior Adviser for CSG                                                   Head, OSAS


                       JOHNNY RICK S. APELLANES
                       Junior Adviser

                       Approved by:


                                                     PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
                                     Administrator, Cavite State University – Tanza Campus



                          20    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus
                                Central Student Government Constitution and By-Laws]]></page></pages></Search>