<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="172"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.6.            There is a mechanism to facilitate the


                        teaching-learning process.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph





                                ACADEMIC AFFAIRS POST ECQ PLAN USING THE
                                      FLEXIBLE LEARNING ARRANGEMENT*



                       COVID-19 is a worldwide pandemic impacting every aspect of society, including Higher
               Education Institutions (HEIs). The implementation of Enhanced Community Quarantine (ECQ)
               in various regions in the country poses issues and challenges among HEIs wherein faculty,
               students and administrators need to face.  Classes in all levels were suspended – face-to-face
               teaching  and  learning  stopped  including  all  other  online  learning  activities  since  not  all
               students  and  faculty  had  reliable  internet  connection  at  home.  Temporary  closure  affects
               40,819 students, 1508 teaching and 590 non-teaching staff of Cavite State University.

                       In  response  to  the  threats of  this  global  COVID-19 pandemic,  the  Commission on
               Higher  Education  (CHEd) has  recommended  the  implementation  of  a  flexible  system  for
               the reopening    of   classes   of   colleges   and   universities   in   the   country   for
               school year 2020-2021 (Manila Times, 05 May 2020). CHED Chairperson De Vera explained
               that  “under  a  flexible  learning  system, schools  adjust  the  learning  process  based  on  the
               location of the students and the structure of the learning system. It includes online and offline
               activities.”

                       Given the unprecedented challenges of this global pandemic to HEIs,  Cavite State
               University has quite significantly initiated plans to reshape the learning management system
               that will address the needs and situations of its thousands of students ensuring the highest
               degree possible of inclusion and equity in education.

                       The following outlines the post ECQ plan of Academic Affairs for the undergraduate
               and  graduate  students  in  the  Main  and  Satellite  Campuses  using  the  flexible  learning
               arrangement to be implemented effective upon approval:


                                      FLEXIBLE LEARNING ARRANGEMENT

                       Cavite State University shall implement the  Flexible learning arrangement which
               will permit the 1) redesigning of the syllabi to fit to the alternative modes of learning, 2)
               the  use  of  both  digital  and  non-digital  modes  of  teaching  and  learning  and  3)
               adjustment  on  the  schedules  for  flexible  learning.  This  learning  system  will  provide
               learners  with  choices  about  when,  where  and  how  learning  occurs  using  a  range  of
               technologies and available materials to support the teaching and learning process.

               _____________________________

               *  Prepared  by  the  Office  of  the  Vice  President  for  Academic  Affairs  and  approved  by  virtue  of
               Administrative Council Resolution No. 13, series of 2020 dated May 10, 2020


                                                       Page 1 of 9]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph



                   I.     Adjustment of Academic Calendar


                          1.  Midyear Term 2020

                                1.1  Registration Period   –      June 22-23, 2020
                                1.2  Beginning of Classes –       June 24, 2020
                                1.3  Final Examination     –      July 27 – 29, 2020
                                1.4  Last Day of Submission/
                                        Uploading of Grades -     July 31, 2020

                              Note: A separate Special Guidelines for Midyear Term 2020 may be proposed taking into
                              consideration the following:
                              a.  Provisions on items II-XII should be specifically designed more applicable to the needs and
                                  situation of the students who will be directly affected by the Post ECQ Plan.
                              b.  Strict re-implementation of CHED-COVID-2019 Advisory No. 2, s. March 2020
                              c.  Learning management system that integrates flexible learning arrangement (use of digital
                                  and non-digital learning modes) with limited provision for face to face learning mode
                              d.  Stricter  health  protocols  for  students  and  employees  and  other  support  mechanisms
                                  stipulated in CSC MC10, s 2020

                          2.  First Semester, 2020 – 2021

                                2.1  Registration Period   –      August 3 - 28, 2020
                                2.2  Beginning of Classes -       September 7, 2020
                                2.3  Christmas Break       -      December 21, 2020 – January 3, 2021
                                2.4  Final Examination     -      January 11 - 16, 2021 (Graduating)
                                                                  January 18 – 23, 2021 (Non Graduating)
                                2.5  Last Day of Submission/
                                        Uploading of Grades-      January 23, 2021 (Graduating)
                                                                  January 30, 2021 (Non Graduating)

                          3.  Second Semester, 2020 - 2021

                                3.1  Registration Period   –      February 1-12, 2021
                                3.2  Beginning of Classes -       February 15, 2021
                                3.3  Final Examination     -      June 7 -11, 2021 (Graduating)
                                                                  June 14- 19, 2021 (Non Graduating)
                                3.4  Last day of Submission/
                                          Uploading of Grades-    June 17, 2021 (Graduating)
                                                                  June 28, 2021 (Non Graduating)

                          4.  Midyear Term 2021

                                1.1  Registration Period   –      June 21 – 25, 2021
                                1.2  Beginning of Classes –       June 28, 2021
                                1.3  Final Examination     –      August 2-5, 2021
                                1.4  Submission of Grades -       August 6, 2021


                                                       Page 2 of 9]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph




                   II.    Class Size

                          1.   The minimum number of students to open a class as stipulated in the CvSU
                               Manual of Operation (2009) shall be followed. Should the class size fall below
                               the  minimum  number,  the  Department  Chairperson  should  be  informed
                               immediately to decide whether to dissolve the class or to maintain  it as a
                               special class approved by the College Dean/Campus Administrator.
                          2.   The  maximum  class  size  of  forty  (40)  students  shall  be  observed.  To
                               implement protocol on physical/social distancing, class shall be divided into
                               two groups/batches for alternate class arrangement.
                          3.   The maximum number of students per class session shall be 20


                   III.   Schedule of Classes, Class Meetings, and Room Assignments

                          1.   Schedule of classes for First and Third Year Students shall be every Monday,
                               Tuesday, and Wednesday while classes for Second Year and Fourth Year
                               Students shall be every Thursday, Friday and Saturday. Other year levels
                               shall be scheduled for three consecutive days or in any days of the week.
                               Other adjustments may be done, if necessary.
                          2.   Class meetings shall be done through alternate class arrangement i.e. face to
                               face or remote/distance mode.
                          3.   If possible, students should only come to university once a week for face to
                               face classes.
                          4.   During class meetings, the first batch of the class shall be taught using face
                               to face while the second batch shall be doing the assigned task/s through
                               remote/distance mode and vice versa.
                          5.   Homeroom assignments shall be implemented except for laboratory classes.
                               All colleges/departments offering the courses/programs shall be responsible
                               for homeroom assignment of their respective students.
                          6.   Protocol  on  physical/social  distancing  shall  be  strictly  implemented  during
                               face to face and laboratory classes


                   IV.    Class Attendance

                          1.   The University Policy on class attendance shall be implemented for face to
                               face class meetings.


                   V.     Academic Load

                          1.   The university policy on academic load shall be waived for AY 2020-2021.
                          2.   A student may be allowed to enroll more than the maximum allowable credit
                               units not to exceed 26 units.


                                                       Page 3 of 9]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                   VI.    First Day of Classes

                          1.   During  the  first  day  of  classes,  students  shall  be  provided  with  a  copy  of
                               course syllabus.
                          2.   Faculty  members  should  discuss  the  content  of  the  course  syllabus
                               particularly the course objectives, course content, instructional approaches,
                               learning  activities,  learning  resources  and  location,  course  requirements,
                               bases for evaluating students’ performance and technology to be used.
                          3.   Faculty members should orient the students about the class groupings and
                               discuss the procedure for alternate class arrangement;
                          4.   Faculty members shall create a class directory that includes home address,
                               e-mail  address,  social  media  account,  mobile  number  and  others  in
                               preparation  for  distance/remote  learning  mode.  Faculty  members  shall
                               comply with the Philippine Data Privacy Act of 2012 or RA 10173 in handling
                               the personal information of the students.
                          5.   Faculty members shall conduct a survey on students’ internet connectivity and
                               available gadgets that can be used to access learning materials and submit
                               course requirements/outputs online.
                          6.   Faculty  members  are  encouraged  to  provide  advanced  copy  of  learning
                               materials to be used for the entire semester.

                   VII.   Modes of Teaching and Learning

                                 Classes shall be conducted on a flexible learning arrangement using varied
                          online and offline modes of learnings, e.g. blended modes of teaching, distance
                          learning, online learning including but not limited to the following:


                          1.  Synchronous Physical/ Face to Face Components
                                1.1  Face to face classes/tutoring
                                1.2  Conduct of Laboratory Classes

                          2.  Synchronous Electronic Components
                                2.1  Video/Audio Conferencing
                                2.2  Online Classes
                                2.3  Instant Messaging

                          3.  Asynchronous Components
                                3.1  On-line self-paced learning content (modules, learning guide, etc)
                                3.2  E-mail, discussion forums
                                3.3  Handouts/Articles/Books
                                3.4  Audio/Video clips
                                3.5  Chatting
                                3.6  Other electronic/computer-based instruction

                          Note: The use of Open Educational Resources (OERs) is recommended. Depending
                          on the nature of the programs, the college/campus may also adopt other alternative
                          learning modes most suitable to either lecture or laboratory classes.

                                                       Page 4 of 9]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph



                   VIII.   NSTP, PE, RLE, Courses with Laboratory and similar courses

                          1.  Colleges/Departments offering NSTP, PE, RLE, laboratory courses and other
                              similar courses shall explore options to deliver these courses through face to
                              face and remote/distance learning.
                          2.  Develop/Use available video recordings to demonstrate  experiments, sports
                              activities and similar activities.
                          3.  As  much  as  possible,  use  online  and  offline  (pre-recorded)  instructional
                              resources to demonstrate/design projects.
                          4.  Modify the scope and direction of design projects to avoid utilizing any on-
                              campus resources, such as the machine shops access, assembly spaces, and
                              laboratories.

                   IX.    Assessment and Evaluation of Students’ Performance

                          1.  Examination may be administered in any mode accessible to all students.
                          2.  Assessment/evaluation  for  remote/distance  mode  shall  be  conducted  using
                              alternative strategies including but not limited to the following:
                                      2.1   Question-based assessment
                                            2.1.1  Open-book or “take home” assessment
                                            2..1.2  Series of Quizzes
                                            2.1.3  Student-developed quiz questions
                                      2.2   Project-based assessment
                                            2.2.1  Development of video presentations/demonstration
                                            2.2.2  Annotated anthology or bibliography
                                            2.2.3  Fact Sheet
                                             2.2.4    Peer-  and  self-review  activity/case  analysis/  critique
                                                    paper
                                            2.2.5  e-Portfolio
                                            2.2.6  Term paper
                          3.  Should an exam be conducted online, plan to offer a “trial quiz” first, prior to
                              the launch of the actual examination.
                          4.  Ask students to sign an honor system pledge

                  X.     Monitoring of Classes and Evaluation of Faculty Performance

                          1.  All  faculty  members  shall  include  the  Department  Chairperson/Dean  in  the
                              course  site/class  account  to  be  created by  faculty  for  their  remote/distance
                              classes.    The  Department  Chairperson/Dean  can  open  the site  anytime  for
                              monitoring purposes.
                          2.  For  off-line  activities,  faculty  members  shall  submit  their  portfolio  to  the
                              concerned Department Chairperson before midterm and before the end of the
                              term.  All  activities  and  sample  outputs  of  the  students  shall  be  part  of  the
                              portfolio.  Portfolio  may  be submitted  to  the  Department  Chairperson  in  any
                              mode, i.e. soft or hard copy.


                                                       Page 5 of 9]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                          3.  Student evaluation of teachers (SET) shall be done online using Google Survey
                              Form or in any mode accessible to the students.

                  XI.    Safety and security practices during face to face classes and conduct of extra-
                         or co-curricular activities

                          The following shall be strictly observed to help protect the students, faculty and
                          employees inside the university:

                          1.  Wearing of school ID;
                          2.  Wearing of face mask;
                          3.  Physical/social distancing;
                          4.  Suspension of wearing of school uniforms (to discourage the students from
                              repeatedly wearing uniforms which could also be of help to stop the spread of
                              the virus); and
                          5.  Suspension of extra- or co-curricular activities that will gather up to 10 people.

                   XII.   Flexible Learning Arrangement for the Graduate School

                              For graduate students, all flexible arrangements for undergraduate students
                       shall be adopted by the Graduate School except for the following:
                       1.  Academic Calendar

                              Saturdays following the established dates for registration, start of class, final
                              examination  and  submission  of  grades  shall  be  set  as  schedule  for  the
                              aforementioned academic activities for the Graduate School.
                       2.  Class Size

                              A maximum class size of twenty (20) for the Master’s level and fifteen (15) for
                              the Doctorate level shall be observed for graduate classes.  Classes with more
                              than the maximum number of students shall be split into two sections.
                       3.  Schedule of Classes

                              Saturdays as days of holding classes for the Graduate School shall remain.

                       4.  Academic Load

                              The academic load as set forth by the Graduate School academic policy shall
                              be followed.
                       5.  Comprehensive Examination

                              Pursuant to the CvSU Academic Policies and Guidelines in Light of Covid-19
                              Pandemic, the Graduate School and Open Learning College (GS-OLC) will
                              administer the comprehensive examination online or through any other mode
                              available  for  eligible  Master  and  PhD  students.  Below  outlines  the  general
                              guidelines in taking the comprehensive examination:
                                                       Page 6 of 9]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph




                               5.1   Modes of Delivery

                                            The  comprehensive  examination  will  have  two  modes  of
                                     delivery: (1) online – to be administered this June and (2) sit-down – to
                                     be administered starting September. Based on the urgency of taking
                                     the  examination,  graduate  students  will  be  categorized  into:  (1)
                                     Category 1 students  - Graduating Non-thesis MBA students who will
                                     be advised to take the online examination this June and (2) Category
                                     2 students – All other Master and PhD students who will be advised to
                                     take the sit-down examination on September.

                                      5.1.1  Sit-down comprehensive examination

                                                   The usual sit-down examination will be administered in
                                            compliance  with  the  set minimum health  protocols  like  social
                                            distancing and wearing of masks.

                                    5.1.2   Online comprehensive examination

                                                   The  online  comprehensive  examination  is  a  four-day
                                            long  examination  that  will  be  administered  on  June,  2020.  A
                                            student will be given sets of questions covering 3 to 4 subjects
                                            per day depending on their respective programs.

                                                   The  questions  will  be  sent  to  the  examinee  email  at
                                            around 8:00 am of the examination date. Submission of answers
                                            will  be  on  or  before  12:00  midnight  of  the  next  day.  Late
                                            submissions will not be considered for checking.

                                                   Answer sheets will be collected by GS-OLC thru email
                                            and forwarded to faculty members email for checking.

                              5.2      Development of Examination

                                           Concerned faculty members will be requested to make suitable
                                     questions for online mode of examination delivery.  The following are
                                     suggested in crafting the examination questions:

                                     5.2.1  Faculty  members  may  consider  giving  questions  to  assess
                                            higher  levels  of  learning  domains.  Questions  should  elicit
                                            analysis and critical thinking among the examinees.

                                     5.2.2  Faculty members may consider setting a minimum number of
                                            words for the examinees’ answers. By doing so, examinees will
                                                       Page 7 of 9]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                            be  obliged  to  integrate  what  they  know  and  express  them
                                            concisely in their own words.

                                     5.2.3  Faculty  members  may  require  the  examinees  to  cite  their
                                            references  used  in  their  answers  to  prompt  examinees  to  do
                                            further research.

                                            Deadline  for  the  submission  of  the  examination  questions  by
                                     concerned  faculty  members  is  on  May  30,  2020.  Submission  is  thru
                                     gs.olc@cvsu.edu.ph.


                              5.3    Checking of Comprehensive Examination

                                     5.2.1  Faculty  members  will  be  given  a month  to  check  the  answer
                                            sheets.  Faculty  members  may  use  a  plagiarism  checker  app
                                            (e.g.  Turnitin)  to  evaluate  the originality  of  the  answers at  an
                                            acceptable rate of 25 % as set by the University’s Knowledge
                                            Management Center (KMC). [For inquiries how to have a Turnitin
                                            account,  please  email  KMC  at  mfccruzada@cvsu.edu.ph.]
                                            Deadline  of  submission  of  results  is  on  July  21,  2020.
                                            Submission  is  thru  gs.olc@cvsu.edu.ph  using  an  electronic
                                            Comprehensive Examination Result form. Electronic forms will
                                            be provided by GS-OLC.


                               5.4   Student Guide for the Online Examination:


                                            The  comprehensive  examination  for  Master  of  Business
                                     Administration (professional track) is a four-day long examination that
                                     will be administered on June 6, 13, 20, and 27, 2020. Students will be
                                     given sets of questions covering 3 to 4 subjects per day depending on
                                     their respective programs.

                                     1.  Using Google account, register using the online information form.
                                         Access Link : http://tiny.cc/gsolc-onlinecompre.

                                         An  email  from  the  Graduate  School  and  Open Learning  College
                                         (GS-OLC)  with  a  subject  “GSOLC  Online  Comprehensive
                                         Examination (First/Second/Third/Fourth Day)” will be sent at around
                                         8:00 am of the examination date. The email will include instructions,
                                         sets of questions and official answer sheets.

                                     2.  Answer  the  questions  using  the  official  answer  sheets.  Type
                                         answers on a separate sheet for each subject. Save answers in
                                                       Page 8 of 9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                         PDF  format  with  a  file  name:  SUBJECT  CODE,  underline,  and
                                         student number (eg. BA201_201512345.pdf).

                                     3.  Attach answer sheets to a reply email.  Reply to the email sent by
                                         the GS-OLC. Submit answers on or before 12:00 midnight of the
                                         next  day  of  the  examination  date.  Late  submissions  will  not  be
                                         considered for checking.

                                     4.  Wait for the result of the online comprehensive examination after
                                         28-30 days of the last date of examination. Result will be sent to
                                         through email. In case of failed remarks, contact GS-OLC via email
                                         or contact number 0909-3007-560 for further instructions.

                                     5.  Answers will be subjected to a plagiarism checker app to evaluate
                                         the originality of answers. All inquiries shall be sent through email
                                         at gs.olc@cvsu.edu.ph.

                           Note  :  For  the  separate  guidelines  on  the  Regular  Semester  (First  Semester  to
                           commence in September 07, 2020, the University may fully go on a regular flexible
                           learning  arrangement  taking  into  consideration  the  most  immediate  support
                           mechanisms for the students, faculty and personnel such as but not limited to the
                           following:
                           1.  Learning management system (connectivity in the University and Campuses,
                              contextual learning and flexible learning; and related modes of learning)
                           2.  Capacity building for faculty on digital and non-digital teaching modes
                           3.  Support mechanisms and safer facilities to students and employees stipulated in CSC
                              MC10, s 2020


               References:

               De Vera, J,P. 2020. Re-shaping higher education in the Philippines delivered in a e-skewala
               webinar on May 08, 2020

               ABS-CBN News Article, 03 May 2020: “Colleges, universities should consult students on next
               academic year: CHED”

               The Manila Times, 05 May 2020, CHED pushes rolling of school opening














                                                       Page 9 of 9]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Presentation during the 2020

                                               Faculty Orientation]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Documentation of Faculty Orientation


          and Capability Enhancement Seminar



                                Workshop]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                                    (046) 414-3949
                                   Phase 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph



                                                                         23 August 2021

               DR. HERNANDO D. ROBLES
               President
               This University
                                                                                        A-210826-2276
               Dear Dr. Robles:                                                         ED
                                                                                        08-26-21
                       Good day.

                       CvSU-Tanza  Campus  will  conduct  the  Virtual  Teachers’  Orientation  and  Capability
               Enhancement Seminar Workshop on September 2-3, 2021 from 1:00pm to 5:00pm via Zoom. The
               said activity aims to provide our faculty members with additional information and enhance different
               ways on flexible learning modality of education delivery with the aid of ICT and new technologies.

                       In line with this, I would like to request permission to conduct the said activity. Attached is
               the activity proposal for your reference.

                       I am hoping that this request will merit your approval. Thank you very much.


                                                                  Respectfully yours,


                                                                  GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                                                                  Campus Administrator


               Recommending Approval:


               MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Vice President for Academic Affairs

                                                                  Approved:


                                                                  HERNANDO D. ROBLES, EdD CEO VI
                                                                  President


                          O - 2024
                          ED
                          09-01-21]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                                    (046) 414-3949
                                   Phase 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


               Title:   Virtual Teachers’ Orientation and Capability Enhancement Seminar Workshop


               Rationale

                       The Higher Education 4.0 trends and future perspectives for teaching and learning are
               equally affected by the rapid changes we are facing today. These trends are significant to meet
               the future needs and challenges in education through the pervasive application of Information and
               Communication Technology (ICT).  In addition, the emergence of COVID-19 pandemic and the
               imminent presence of different COVID-19 variants (Delta) brought unforeseen disruptions in
               the lives of people all over the world.  The Philippine higher education institutions (HEIs) are
               no exemption in facing such critical situations.  To ensure the continuity of learning among
               tertiary students while avoiding and/or limiting the risks of infection in the community, HEIs
               explored and shifted to other innovative learning modalities that transmigrate the conduct of
               classes  from  traditional  to  flexible  learning  modalities,  which  gave  students  the  option  to
               choose the most convenient delivery modes to them.  This flexible learning modality emerged
               during the First Semester of Academic Year 2020–2021 where it was used for the conduct of
               lecture classes, leaving behind the conduct of laboratory classes that require a more rigid
               training for students in face-to-face classes.

                       As CvSU Tanza increases its enrolment during the First Semester of AY 2021 – 2022, from
               1,154 students last year now caters a projected 1700 enrollees, thus compelling the campus to
               hire additional faculty members. With this, there is an urgent need to conduct faculty orientation
               and re-orientation and further explore other innovative flexible learning modalities that suit the
               capacity, capability, and connectivity of our teachers and learners.

               Objectives
                       The activity aims to provide our faculty members with additional information and enhance
               different ways on  flexible  learning  modality of education delivery  with  the aid of  ICT and new
               technologies.


               Implementation
                       The Campus Administrator together with all faculty members will attend the said activity on
               September 2 – 3, 2021 from 1:00pm to 5:00pm via Zoom/WebEx.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Program of Activities

               Day 1: Faculty Orientation and Re-Orientation (September 2, 2021)
                                         Activity                                     In-Charge
                 Registration
                 Prayer                                                    Mr. Crisostomo Sibulo
                                                                           Faculty, DAS
                 National Anthem                                           Audio Visual Presentation
                 CvSU-Tanza at a Glance                                    Ms. Joyce Erika S. Senaris
                                                                           Chair, DIT
                 Opening Remarks                                           Prof. Gil D. Ramos
                                                                           Campus Administrator
                 Introduction of Key Officials and Support Personnel       Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                                                           Coordinator, OSAS
                 Introduction of Faculty per Department                    Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                                           HR Coordinator, CvSU Tanza
                 Presentation of Academic Calendar, Policies and Grading   Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                     System                                                Campus Registrar
                 HR Policies including online DTR                          Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                                           HR Coordinator, CvSU Tanza
                 Gender and Development in the Workplace                   Ms. Maria Cristina C. Tagle
                                                                           GAD Coordinator
                 Campus Extension Services                                 Mr. Ritch M. Banate
                                                                           Extension Coordinator
                 Classroom Management in the Online World: Proper          Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                     Netiquette in the Teaching and Learning Process       Chair, DAS

               Day 2: Capability Enhancement Training (September 3, 2021)
                                         Activity                                     In-Charge
                 Prayer                                                    Mr. Crisostomo Sibulo
                 Recap of Previous Activities                              Ms. Mary Joy Angelique R. Mojica
                                                                           Faculty, TED
                 Test Construction, Table of Specification and Rubrics     Ms. Gerry Mae T. Silvero
                     Preparation                                           Faculty, TED
                 Syllabus and Module Preparation                           Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                                           Chair, TED
                 Breakout Sessions                                         Per Department
                        Session 1: DAS
                        Session 2: DIT
                        Session 3: DOM
                        Session 4: TED
                    University Vision and Mission, Goals and Objectives
                    Department Objectives
                    Program Educational Objectives
                    Course Syllabus Format
                 Introduction to the CvSU LMS                              Ms. Charmaine T. Banag
                                                                           Faculty Member, DIT
                 Closing Remarks                                           Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                                           HR Coordinator, CvSU Tanza

               Working Committee
                 Activity in Charge                              Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                                                 Mr. Ritch M. Banate
                                                                 Ms. Joyce Erika S. Senaris
                                                                 Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Program Layout and                              Ms. Charmaine T. Banag
                 Certificates Preparation                        Ms. Haizel Anne M. Costa
                 Technical Requirements                          Mr. Jeffrey M. Delgado
                                                                 Mr. Joseph O. Sabaybay
                 Registration/ Attendance and Evaluation         Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                                 Ms. Mary Joy Angelique R. Mojica
                 Documentation in Charge                         Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                                                 Mr. Erwin M. Regio
                                                                 Mr. Johnny Rick S. Apellanes
                                                                 Mr. Charles Vincent V. Pitagan
                                                                 Ms. Ivory P. Mojica
                 In Charge of Ceremonies                         Ms. Rein R. Origosa
                                                                 Mr. Audreyson H. Borilla
                 Overall in Charge                               Prof. Gil D. Ramos


               Prepared by:


               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
               Head, Curriculum and Instruction



                                                   Approved:


                                                   GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                     Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                               235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                        www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                         TANZA FACULTY ORIENTATION 2020
                                                   September 3, 2020

                       Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus  conducted  a  virtual  faculty
               orientation on September 3, 2020 thru Zoom to help all the newly hired and rehired

               faculty and staff of the campus make a smooth and enjoyable transition to the new

               normal of education and to prove that a crisis cannot impair its academic functions.
               The program started with a prayer led by Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo and followed by the

               AVP of CvSU at a Glance which featured the humble beginnings of the University

               and its vision of becoming a global University.
                       Meanwhile, Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3 Campus Administrator, welcomed all the

               faculty members and staff with gratitude as he witnessed the untiring support and
               whole-hearted dedication of faculty and staff to continue the semester despite the

               current situation of the academic community.
                       Furthermore,  the  old  and  new  faculty  members  were  introduced  by  their

               respective department chairpersons. Each department chairpersons provided a brief

               background of their educational attainment, specializations, and accomplishments.
                       Moreover,  Prof.  Mildred  A.  Sebastian,  Chairperson  of  Teacher  Education

               Department,  presented  the  academic  calender.  This  was  followed  by  academic
               policies and grading system discussed by Ms. Noemi A. Perida.

                       After that, the discussion of HR Policies and Gender and Development was
               led by Tanza campus’ HR and GAD Coordinator, Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag.

                       In addition, Ms. Loran Camille Villarante, T3 Librarian, tackled the CvSU e-

               Library System and Open Education Resources. It was followed by the discussion of
               Mr. Luke Ty about netiquettes in handling online classes.

                       The virtual orientation ended with the closing statement of Mr. Cris Albert P.
               Cajigas, Tanza Campus Coordinator, who said that as the University embraced the

               first semester of the Academic Year 2020 – 2021 under the new normal context, the

               administration,  faculty  members  and  the  students  should  embraced  altogether  to]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[continually  uplift  the  CvSU’s  tenets  of  Truth,  Service  and  Excellence,  despite  the

               paralyzing effect of the COVID-19 pandemic.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Teachers’ Capability Enhancement Seminar
                                                     Workshop


        7:00 – 8:00 AM     Registration
        8:01 – 8:30 AM     Opening Program
                           Prayer                                 Mr. Mark Joel Sibulo
                                                                  Chair, Department of Arts and Sciences
                           National Anthem
                           Welcome Remarks                        Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                                  Administrator, T3 Campuses
                           Inspirational Message                  Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro
                                                                  Vice President, Academic Affairs
                           Levelling of Expectations and Objectives   Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas
                                                                  Coordinator, Tanza Campus
                           Introduction of Participants           Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                                  Local HR, Tanza Campus
        8:31 – 9:15 AM     Discussion of CvSU Vision and Mission    Mr. Mark Joel Sibulo
                              and T3 Campuses Goals               Chair, Department of Arts and Sciences

        9:16 – 9:45 AM     Discussion on Program Educational      Mr. Ritch M. Banate
                              Objectives and Program Outcomes     Chair, Department of Management
                              BS Business Management
                              BS Information Technology
                              BS Tourism Management
                              BS Hospitality Management
                              BS Psychology
                              Bachelor of Secondary Education
                              Bachelor of Elementary Education

        9:46 – 10:15 AM    Teaching Strategies and Classroom      Prof. Noel B. Manarpiis
                              Management                          Teacher Education Department Chair, General Trias
                                                                    City Campus
        10:16 – 11:00 AM   Integration of Gender-Fair Language in   Prof. Arlene L. Estrada
                              Course Syllabi Preparation          GAD Coordinator, T3 Campuses

        11:01 – 12:00 PM   Discussion on the Code of Conduct and   Ms. Shaine C. Hayag
                              Ethical Standards for Public Officials   HR Coordinator, General Trias City Campus
                              and Employees (RA 6713)

        12:00 – 1:00 PM    Lunch Break

        1:00 – 1:30 PM     Technology –Aided Education            Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio
                                                                  Department of Information Technology Chair,
                                                                   Trece Martires City Campus
        1:31 – 2:00 PM     Course Syllabus                        Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                                  Chair, Teacher Education Department
        2:01 – 2:30 PM     Test Construction and Table of         Ms. Gerry Mae Silvero
                              Specifications (TOS)                Instructor, Teacher Education Department

        2:31 – 3:00 PM     Rubrics Preparation                    Ms. Ivory Mojica
                                                                  Instructor, Teacher Education Department
        3:01 – 5:30 PM     Workshop

        5:31 – 5:45 PM     Distribution of Certificates           Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                                  Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas
        5:46 – 5:55 PM     Closing Remarks                        Ms. Joyce Erika S. Senaris
                                                                  Chair, Department of Information Technology
        5:56 – 6:00 PM     CvSU Hymn                              Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                                                  Coordinator, OSAS

                                          Angelika Cumayas and Audreyson Borilla
                                                  Masters of Ceremonies]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          414-3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                 TANZA CAMPUS

                          TEACHER’S CAPABILITY ENHANCEMENT SEMINAR
                                                 February 13, 2020

                       Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus  held  a  capability

               enhancement seminar for teachers at Hostel Tropicana of Cavite State

               University–Main Campus on February 13, 2020. This was conducted to

               provide the faculty members with an additional credential that will certify

               their competence to teach their course effectively. Besides, the training

               aimed to empower faculty members for them to strengthen their sound

               educational  principles  and  the  capacity  and  willingness  to  transform

               others and one’s self. The program started with a prayer led by Mr. Mark

               Joel C. Sibulo and followed by the AVP of the National Anthem.

                       Meanwhile,  Prof.  Noel  A.  Sedigo,  T3  Campus  Administrator,

               welcomed all the faculty members with confidence as he is certain that

               the  training  will  eventually  gear  them  towards  excellence.  He  firmly

               believed that this training will harness the full potential of faculty members

               in delivering quality instruction to their students.

                       Moreover, Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo, Chairperson of the Department

               of Arts and Sciences, presented the CvSU Vision and Mission, and T3

               Campus Goals.  This was followed  by  the presentation  of  Mr.  Ritch  M.

               Banate,  Chairperson  of  the  Department  of  Management  on  program

               educational objectives and outcomes of the various programs offered by

               the Campus.

                       After  that,  the  training  on  teaching  strategies  and  classroom

               management was facilitated by Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis. During the training,]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[each faculty member learned effective ways on how to manage their class

               and teaching strategies that will help them deliver quality instruction.

                       Furthermore, Prof. Arlene L. Estrada, GAD Coordinator, discussed

               the integration of gender-fair language on course syllabi which is really

               vital to ensure gender-responsive and sensitive instruction. In connection

               with this, Ms. Shaine C. Hayag, HR Coordinator of CvSU – General Trias

               Campus discussed the code of conduct and ethical standards for public

               officials and employees to ensure that employees always observed the

               mandates.

                       Additionally, Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio, DIT Chairperson of CvSU –

               Trece Martires City Campus facilitated the training on technology-aided

               education which was followed by the training on course syllabus facilitated

               by Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, TED Chairperson.

                       Also, Ms. Gerry Mae T. Silvero, tackled test construction, and table

               of specifications. It was followed by the discussion of Ms. Ivory Mojica

               about  rubrics  preparation.  A  workshop  was  conducted  right  after  their

               presentations for the faculty members to create their own exam with TOS

               and sample rubrics where they presented it for enhancement.

                       The seminar was ended with the closing statement of Ms. Joyce

               Erika S. Senaris, DIT Chairperson, who said that as an educator, it is the

               obligation of faculty members to continuously enrich their capability  as

               change is inevitable as well as the dimension of education. It was a great

               opportunity  to  expose  the  faculty  members  to  various  enhancement

               training  that  will  ensure  their  preparedness  and  be  able  to  fill  in  the


               demands of higher education.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[PHOTO DOCUMENTATION






































                   Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis during his talk about teaching strategies and
                                              classroom management





































                 Prof. Arlene A. Estrada during her talk about integration of gender-fair
                                            language on course syllabi]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Ms. Shaine Hayag during her talk about the code of conduct and ethical
                                 standards for public officials and employees



































                     Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio during her talk about technology-aided
                                                      education]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian received her Certificate of Recognition for
                   being the resource person in the Course Syllabus which is awarded
                          by Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas (Campus Coordinator) and
                                 Prof. Noel A. Sedigo (Campus Administrator)]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Ms. Ivory Mojica received her certificate of recognition awarded by
                            Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas (Campus Coordinator) and
                                 Prof. Noel A. Sedigo (Campus Administrator)]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Ms. Gerry Mae T. Silvero received her certificate of recognition awarded
                          by Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas (Campus Coordinator) and
                                 Prof. Noel A. Sedigo (Campus Administrator)]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Faculty members during the workshop




































                  Faculty members together with their Campus Administrator after the
                                                 successful training]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Parents and Students Orientation


                                First Semester, 2022-2023]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY

                                          TANZA CAMPUS





                             Parents and Students


                            Virtual Orientation and


                                 September 16, 2022 (1:00-5:00 P.M)
                           Re-orientation Program
                                              via FB Live]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY

 TANZA CAMPUS





 Parents and Students


 Virtual Orientation and


 September 16, 2022 (1:00-5:00 P.M)
 Re-orientation Program
 via FB Live]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



                         PARENTS’ AND STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION AND
                                        RE-ORIENTATION PROGRAM 2022
                                                 September 16, 2022



                         The  Cavite  State  University-Tanza  Campus  conducted  the  virtual
               parents and student orientation and re-orientation last September 12, 2022,
               1:00pm-4:00pm via FB live. The implementing guidelines on the limited face-
               to-face  classes,  academic  policies  and  grading  system,  student  code  of
               conduct  and  other  student  services,  learning  delivery  modes,  orientation
               about  the  Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  of  the  University,  and
               orientation on the library system are some of the topics discussed during the
               program.

























                             Activity banner posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook page]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph






















                          Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro, Vice President for Academic Affairs, giving her
                                             welcome remarks to the participants
























                                           Introduction to the Campus’ key officials and support personnel]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                            Introduction to the faculty members of the Teacher Education Department
























                            Introduction to the faculty members of the Department of Management]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                                     The University academic calendar for S.Y 2022-2023, presented by the
                                                    Campus Registrar, Ms. Noemi A. Perida
























                              Discussion on the academic policies and grading system of the University]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph























                   Discussion on the student programs and service provided by the Office of Student
                         Affairs and Services, presented by Ms. Melona I. Saquin, OSAS Head




































                                        Discussion on the student code of conduct]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and Children Act, Anti-
                  bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on Drug Abuse and Drug
                  Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442 vilification against Person with
                                                          Disability





























                 Presentation on the CvSU Learning Management System (LMS) and flexible learning delivery
                                modes, presented by the MIS officer, Ms. Charmaine T. Banag]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

























                         Library orientation presented by the Campus’ Librian, Ms. Roselyn C. Baltar
























                               Mr. Gerard Advincula, program host, facilitating the open forum]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



               Prepared by:                                                     Certified Correct:


               FATIMA M. DIAZ                                                   MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Facilitator, ISPS                                                Head, OSAS
               Date prepared: September 19, 2022


                                                                                Noted:


                                                                                GIL D. RAMOS
                                                                                Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[Parents and Students Orientation


                                First Semester, 2021-2022]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


               02 September 2021


               DR. HERNANDO D. ROBLES
               President                                                            A-210907-2363
               This University                                                      ED
                                                                                    09-07-2021

               Dear Sir:

               The Cavite State University-Tanza will hold its Parents and Students Virtual Orientation and
               Re-orientation Program on September 10, 2021. This aims to inform parents and students
               about  academic  policies  and  grading  system,  student  code  of  conduct,  Netiquette  during
               flexible learning, learning delivery modes and orientation about the Learning Management
               System (LMS) of the University. This activity will be conducted via Cisco Webex and thru FB
               live.

               In this regard, we would like to seek your approval to allow us to conduct the said activity.
               Attached is the activity proposal for your reference.

               Thank you very much for your usual support.

               Respectfully yours,



               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, OSAS


               Recommending Approval:


               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Dean, OSAS



               MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Vice President for Academic Affairs




                                                        Approved:


                                         HERNANDO D. ROBLES, EdD, CEO VI
                                               for:  University President


             O - 2067
             ED
             09-09-2021]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



               Title:              Parents and Students Virtual Orientation and Re-orientation Program 2021

               Proponent:    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus, Office of Student Affairs and Services

               Target Participants:   Parents and students of CvSU-Tanza


               Rationale:

                       This coming semester marks the second year of the implementation of flexible learning

               in universities and colleges. In this regard, the Cavite State University-Tanza Campus will

               conduct a virtual parents and student virtual orientation and re-orientation on September 10,

               2021. The academic policies and grading system, student code of conduct, Netiquette during

               flexible learning, learning delivery modes and orientation about the Learning Management


               System  (LMS)  of  the  University,  are  some  of  the  topics  that  will  be  discussed during  the

               program.

               Objectives:

                   1.  To formally introduce the key officials, old and new faculty members and employees;

                   2.  inform the parents and students about the calendar of activities for school year 2021-

                       2022;


                   3.  discuss the academic policies and grading system;

                   4.  conduct orientation about the Student Code of Conduct;

                   5.  present video presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and

                       Children Act, Anti-bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on

                       Drug Abuse and Drug Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442

                       vilification against Person with Disability;

                   6.  conduct orientation about Netiquette during flexible learning; and


                   7.  discuss the Learning Delivery Modes and Learning Management System (LMS) of the

                       University.]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


               Implementation:


                   1.  All students must register by filling out the Google Form before the day of the activity.

                       Parents are also encourage to register.

                   2.  Campus key officials are required to join the virtual meeting room during the orientation

                       program.

                   3.  Cisco Webex Meet will be used as the platform for the orientation and the program will


                       be aired through FB Live.

                   4.  An activity evaluation form through Google Form will be sent to the participants after

                       the orientation program.

               Participants:

                       The participants of the proposed activity are students, parents and faculty members.



               Working Committee:


                Activity In-charge                            Melona I. Saquin
                                                              Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                                              Mildred A. Sebastian
                Program Lay-out and Posting                   Gerry Mae T. Silvero
                                                              Mary Joy Angelique R. Mojica
                Technical Requirements                        Joseph O. Sabaybay
                                                              Jeffrey M. Delgado
                Screening of Questions                        Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                              JR Apellanes
                                                              Maria Kristina Galicha
                Registration/Evaluation                       Jed de Silva
                                                              Rein Ortigosa
                                                              Jessica Avon Quezada
                Certificates                                  Joyce Erika S. Senaris
                                                              Charles Pitagan
                Documentation                                 Ivory Mojica
                                                              Erwin Regio
                                                              John Daniel V. Cap-atan]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
               Programme:

                     “Parents and Students Virtual Orientation and Re-orientation Program 2021”
                                          September 10, 2021 (1:00-5:00 P.M)


                1:00 -1:05 P.M     Prayer                                     Mr. Crisostomo Sibulo
                                                                              Faculty, DAS

                1:06 -1:10 P.M     National Anthem                            AVP

                1:11 -1:15 P.M     CvSU-Tanza at a Glance                     AVP

                1:16-1:20 P.M      Introduction of Campus Key Officials and   AVP
                                   Faculty Members
                1:21 -1:35 P.M     Inspirational Message                      Prof. Gil D. Ramos
                                                                              Campus Administrator
                                   Presentation of Students per Program
                  1:36 -2:15 P.M  and their Registration Advisers and         Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                                   Academic Policies and Grading System       Campus Registrar

                  2:16 -2:40 P.M  Scholarships and Student Financial          Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                   Assistance                                 Head, OSAS/ Scholarship
                                                                              Coordinator
                  2:41 -3:30 P.M  Student Code of Conduct and Netiquette      Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                   during Flexible Learning                   Department
                                                                              Chairperson/Guidance and
                                                                              Counselling
                  3:31 -3:50 P.M  Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the
                                   Anti-violence   Against   Women      and
                                   Children Act, Anti-bullying Act, R.A 7877 or
                                   Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on  AVP
                                   Drug  Abuse  and  Drug  Prevention  and
                                   Control,  HIV  Aids  Awareness  and  R.A
                                   9442  vilification  against  Person  with
                                   Disability;

                  3:51 -4:30 P.M  Flexible  Learning  Delivery  Modes  and  Ms. Charmaine T. Banag
                                   CvSU  Learning  Management  System  MIS Officer
                                   (LMS)
                  4:31-4:55 P.M    Open Forum                                 ---

                  4:56-5:00 P.M    Closing Remarks                            Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                                              Instruction and Curriculum
                                                                              Development
                                                                              Coordinator/Department
                                                                              Chairperson, TED

                                          CvSU Hymn                           AVP


                                          Mr. Audreyson H. Borilla
                                            Master of Ceremonies]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                              TANZA CAMPUS






                            Parents and Students






                          Virtual Orientation and



                         September 10, 2021 (1:00-5:00 P.M)
                          Re-orientation Program
                                            via FB Live]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
         TANZA CAMPUS






 Parents and Students






 Virtual Orientation and



 September 10, 2021 (1:00-5:00 P.M)
 Re-orientation Program
 via FB Live]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                            PARENTS’ AND STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION AND

                                          RE-ORIENTATION PROGRAM 2021
                                                   September 10, 2021




                       The  academic  year  2021-2022  was  the  second  year  of  the
               implementation of flexible learning in universities and colleges. Cavite State
               University-Tanza Campus conducted the virtual parents and student virtual
               orientation  and  re-orientation  on  September  10,  2021  via  FB  live.  The

               academic policies and grading system, student code of conduct, Netiquette
               during flexible learning, learning delivery modes and orientation about the
               Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  of  the  University,  are  some  of  the
               topics discussed during the program.
























                             Activity banner posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook page


                       Registration announcement posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook Page]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

























                        The Vice President for Academic Affairs, Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro, giving her
                                             welcome remarks to the participants






















                          Prof. Gil D. Ramos, Campus Administrator, giving his inspiration message]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                 to the students and parents.























                                Introduction to the Campus key officials and support personnel
























                   Discussion on the academic policies and grading system of the University, presented by the]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



































                                                    Campus Registrar, Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                  Discussion on the scholarships and student financial assistance program, presented by the
                                             OSAS Head, Ms. Melona I. Saquin]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                  Discussion on the netiquette during flexible learning, presented by Mr. Mark Joel C.
                                      Sibulo, the guidance facilitator of the Campus
























                Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and Children Act, Anti-
                  bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on Drug Abuse and Drug
                  Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442 vilification against Person with
                                                          Disability]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                 Orientation on the CvSU Learning Management System (LMS), presented by the MIS officer,
                                                  Ms. Charmaine T. Banag

































                               Prof. Gil D. Ramos and other participants during the open forum





               Prepared by:                                                     Certified Correct:


               JOYCE ERIKA S. SENARIS                                           MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Facilitator, ISPS                                                Head, OSAS
               Date prepared: September 16, 2021

                                                                                Noted:


                                                                                GIL D. RAMOS
                                                                                Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[Parents and Students Orientation


                                First Semester, 2020-2021]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                     T3 STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION 2020
                                                  September 21, 2020

               Cavite State University – T3 Campuses held the Students’ Virtual Orientation on September
        21, 2020 thru Facebook live stream. The program started with the AVP of the T3 campuses, CvSU

        Tanza, Gen. Trias City, and Trece Martires City Campuses facilities and its development through
        the  years. It was followed  by the  introduction  of T3 key  officials, support  personnel, faculty per

        department and students class adviser per program.
               Meanwhile,  Ms.  Mary  Ann  L.  Anonas,  T3  Campus  Registrar,  discussed  the  academic

        policies  and  grading  system  followed  by  the  discussion  of  different  scholarship  offered  in  the

        University and other external agencies.
               Furthermore, Ms. Loran Camille Villarante oriented the students about the CvSU e-Library

        System Open Education Resources and Creative Commons.
               In addition, an open forum was conducted to answer the questions of the students and to

        enlighten them about the “new normal” academic set-up of T3 Campuses. During the open forum,
        various questions were raised by the students and were answered by Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3

        Campus Administrator, and other key officials.

               The virtual orientation ended with the closing statement of Prof. Sedigo with his emphasis
        that despite the pandemic, T3 Campuses will continue serving and providing quality education and

        ensuring that no students will be left behind.





        Prepared by:                                                             Certified Correct:


        JOYCE ERIKA S. SENARIS                                                   MELONA I. SAQUIN

        Facilitator, ISPS                                                        OSAS Head

        Date pr  epared: September 25, 2020



                                                                                Noted:

                                                                                GIL D. RAMOS
                                                                                Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[21 September 2020
                                                        1:00 PM




        Prayer
        National Anthem

        Introduction of T3 Key Officials and Support Services

        Introduction of Faculty per Department
        Introduction of Students per Program and their          Lilian O. Sidamon (Trece)
        Registration Advisers                                   Shaine C. Hayag (Gen. Trias)
                                                                Mildred A. Sebastian (Tanza)
                                                                Campus Coordinators

        Academic Policies and Grading System                    Mary Ann L. Anonas (Trece)
                                                                Registrar I, T3 Campuses
        Student Norm and Conduct in the New Normal              Lilian O. Sidamon (Trece)
                                                                Office of Student Affairs and Services Head
        Scholarships                                            Melona I. Saquin (Tanza)
                                                                Office of Student Affairs and Services Head

        Orientation to CvSU e-Library System, Open              Lora Camille A. Villarante
        Education Resources and Creative Commons                Librarian I, T3 Campuses

        Open Forum                                              Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                                Mary Ann L. Anonas
                                                                Rogelyn P. Alarca
                                                                Noemi A. Perida
                                                                Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                                Shaine C. Hayag
                                                                Melona I. Saquin
                                                                Lora Camille A. Villarante
        Announcements

        CvSU Hymn



                                             Mr. John Daniel V. Cap-atan
                                               In-Charge of Ceremonies]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[Parents and Students Virtual Orientation

                            on the CvSU – T3 Campuses


                               Implementation of Flexible


                                  Learning Delivery Mode


                                First Semester, 2020-2021]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[udents'Orientation
                                      St


                                First Semester, 2019-2020]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                            (CvSU)
                                               DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

                                                           Indang, Cavite
                                                415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806

                                                        www.cvsu.edu.ph



                              OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS



               OFFICE MEMORANDUM
               No. 32 s. 2021


               TO             :      ALL COLLEGE DEANS
                                     ALL CAMPUS ADMINISTRATORS
                                     ALL FACULTY MEMBERS
                                     ALL OTHER CONCERNED



               FROM           :      MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
                                     Vice President for Academic Affairs


               SUBJECT      :        FACULTY EVALUATION

               DATE           :      November 10, 2021


                   1.  In line with the evaluation of faculty members on their teaching effectiveness, please be
                       informed of the following:

                                                                              Person Who
                                          Instrument to     Schedule of                          Record
                           Purpose                                                 Will
                                            be Used        Administration                         Keeper
                                                                               Administer
                        Evaluation of                                        Person in-
                        teaching
                                                                   th
                        effectiveness    VPAA-QF-16-       Every 11  to      charge (to be
                                                                             designated by
                                         Faculty
                                                             th
                        during flexible   Evaluation       13  week of the   the College       OVPAA
                        learning for                       semester
                        internal         Form                                Dean/ Campus
                                                                             Administrator)
                        promotion*
                                         QCE of the
                        Evaluation of    NBC No. 461-
                        teaching         Instrument for    Any time after    Individual        OVPAA
                                                           midterm
                        effectiveness    Instruction/      examination       Faculty
                        for NBC 461*     Teaching
                                         Effectiveness
                           *Approved by CvSU PMT
                                                         Page 1 of 2]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[2.  For VPAA-QF-16- FACULTY EVALUATION FORM

                       2.1    All college deans/ campus administrators shall assign a person-in-charge per
                              department who will conduct the online faculty evaluation.

                       2.2    The link for the VPAA-QF-16 will be sent by this office to all colleges and
                              campuses to be shared by the designated person-in-charge to the students.

                       2.3    To facilitate the evaluation, person-in-charge will join the online class of the
                              teacher to administer the evaluation instrument by sharing the link to the
                              students.


                       2.4    Before the evaluation, it is expected that the instrument and process of
                              evaluation were thoroughly explained to the students.

                   3.  For QCE of the NBC No. 461 – Instrument for Instruction/Teaching Effectiveness


                       3.1    The link for the NBC No. 461 shall be sent likewise by this office to all colleges
                              and campuses to be shared by faculty members to the students.

                       3.2    Faculty members shall then share the link to their students any time after
                              midterm examination.

                       3.3    Before the evaluation, it is expected as well that the instrument and the process
                              of evaluation were thoroughly explained to the students.

                    4.  Attached are the instruments for your reference.

                    5.  For your guidance and dissemination.

                    6.   Thank you.































                                                         Page 2 of 2]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[The QCE of the NBC No. 461
                                     Instrument for Instruction/Teaching Effectiveness


                            Rating Period:______________________ to ______________________


               Name of Faculty: ________________________ Academic Rank: _________________

                Evaluators:

                           O  Self                             O   Peer
                           O  Student                          O   Supervisor

                Instruction: Please evaluate the faculty using the scale below. Encircle your rating.

                  Scale     Descriptive Rating                  Qualitative Description
                                                 The  performance  almost  always  exceeds  the  job
                    5          Outstanding
                                                 requirements.  The Faculty is an exceptional role model
                                                 The    performance  meets  and  often  exceeds  the  job
                    4       Very Satisfactory
                                                 requirements
                    3          Satisfactory      The performance meets job requirements
                                                 The  performance  needs  some  development  to  meet  job
                    2              Fair
                                                 requirements.
                    1             Poor           The faculty fails to meet job requirements


                 A. Commitment                                                          Scale
                      Demonstrates  sensitivity  to  students’  ability  to  attend  and
                  1.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      absorb content information.
                      Integrates sensitively his/her learning objectives with those of
                  2.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      the students in a collaborative process.
                  3.   Makes self available to students beyond official time    5    4    3    2    1

                      Regularly  comes  to  class  on  time,  well-groomed  and  well-
                  4.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      prepared to complete assigned responsibilities.
                      Keeps accurate records of students’ performance and prompt
                  5.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      submission of the same.
                                                                 Total Score

                 B. Knowledge of Subject                                                Scale
                      Demonstrates  mastery  of  the  subject  matter  (explain  the
                  1.  subject  matter  without  relying  solely  on  the  prescribed   5   4   3   2   1
                      textbook).

                      Draws and share information on the state on the art of theory
                  2.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      and practice in his/her discipline.
                      Integrates  subject  to  practical  circumstances  and  learning
                  3.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      intents/purposes of students.
                      Explains  the  relevance  of  present  topics  to  the  previous
                  4.  lessons,  and  relates  the  subject  matter  to  relevant  current   5   4   3   2   1
                      issues and/or daily life activities.

                      Demonstrates  up-to-date  knowledge  and/or  awareness  on
                  5.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      current trends and issues of the subject.
                                                                  Total Score]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[C. Teaching for Independent Learning                                   Scale

                     Creates teaching strategies that allow students to practice using
                  1.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                     concepts they need to understand (interactive discussion).
                     Enhances student self-esteem and/or gives due recognition to
                  2.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                     students’ performance/potentials.
                     Allows students to create their own course with objectives and
                  3.  realistically  defined  student-professor  rules  and  make  them   5   4   3   2   1
                     accountable for their performance

                     Allows  students  to  think  independently  and  make  their  own
                  4.  decisions and holding them accountable for their performance   5   4   3   2   1
                     based largely on their success in executing decisions.
                     Encourages  students  to  learn  beyond  what  is  required  and
                  5.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                     help/guide the students how to apply the concepts learned
                                                                  Total Score

                 D. Management of Learning                                              Scale

                      Creates  opportunities  for  intensive  and/or  extensive
                  1.  contribution of students in the class activities (e.g. breaks class   5   4   3   2   1
                      into dyads, triads or buzz/task groups).
                      Assumes roles as facilitator, resource person, coach, inquisitor,
                  2.  integrator,  referee  in  drawing  students  to  contribute  to   5   4   3   2   1
                      knowledge and understanding of the concepts at hands.
                      Designs and implements learning conditions and experience
                  3.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      that promotes healthy exchange and/or confrontations.
                      Structures/re-structures   learning   and   teaching–learning
                  4.                                                            5    4    3    2    1
                      context to enhance attainment of collective learning objectives.
                     Use of Instructional Materials ((audio/video materials: fieldtrips,
                  5.  film showing, computer aided instruction and etc.) to reinforces   5   4   3   2   1
                     learning processes.
                                                                  Total Score



               Legend for the Formula/Equation:
                            ts    =  Total Score
                            hps  =  Highest Possible Score
                            %     =  Percentage


                Signature of Evaluator     :

                Name of Evaluator          :
                Position of Evaluator       :
                Date                                 :]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                              Department of Management


                                        CLASSROOM OBSERVATION REPORT
                                            Second Semester, AY 2021-2022


                        Name of Faculty                                CRITERIA                        Total
                                                                                                      Points
              Permanent                                   A           B           C          B
              Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      24         25          25          24          98
              Fabian, Debbie Rose b.                      24         25          25          24          98
              Saquin, Melona I.                           25         24          25          24          98
              Job Order
              Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.                   21         21          23          24          90
              Bergado, Marjorie                           21         21          22          20          84
              Carpina, Daniel V.                          22         22          22          23         89.2
              De Silva, Jan Edizon J.                     24         23          22          21         89.2
              Galicha, Maria Kristina A.                  21         21          22          22         86.4
              Mabalay, Christofer A.                      22         21          21          22          86
              Son, Kristina D.                            22         23          22          23          90
              Quezada, Jessica Avon C.                    21         21          21          22         85.2

             Legend

              A. Commitment                                    C. Teaching for Independent Learning
              B. Knowledge of Subject                          D. Management of Learning



             Prepared by:


             RITCH M. BANATE
             Department Chairperson


             Noted:


             GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
             Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                              Department of Management


                                        CLASSROOM OBSERVATION REPORT
                                             First Semester, AY 2021-2022


                        Name of Faculty                                CRITERIA                        Total
                                                                                                      Points
              Permanent                                   A           B           C          B
              Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      24         24          25          23          96
              Fabian, Debbie Rose b.                      24         25          24          25          98
              Saquin, Melona I.                           24         25          24          24         96.8
              Job Order
              Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.                   23         23          22          22         89.6
              Delas Alas, Keith Angelica A.               20         21          20          20         80.8
              De Silva, Jan Edizon J.                     22         23          21          23         88.8
              Galicha, Maria Kristina A.                  20         21          22          22         85.6
              Mabalay, Christofer A.                      20         20          21          21         82.4
              Son, Kristina D.                            22         22          23          22         89.2
              Quezada, Jessica Avon C.                    23         22          21          20         85.2

             Legend

              A. Commitment                                    C. Teaching for Independent Learning
              B. Knowledge of Subject                          D. Management of Learning



             Prepared by:


             RITCH M. BANATE
             Department Chairperson


             Noted:


             GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
             Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                              Department of Management


                                        CLASSROOM OBSERVATION REPORT
                                            Second Semester, AY 2020-2021


                        Name of Faculty                                CRITERIA                        Total
                                                                                                      Points
              Permanent                                   A           B           C          B
              Banag Debbie Rose T.                        23         25          24          24          96
              Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      25         23          24          23         94.8
              Saquin, Melona I.                           24         25          24          24         96.8
              Job Order
              Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.                   23         21          23          22         89.2
              Carpina, Daniel V.                          20         21          22          23         86.8
              Cumayas, Angelika A.                        22         21          22          22         87.2
              De Silva, Jan Edizon J.                     23         23          22          21         88.4
              Galicha, Maria Kristina A.                  20         20          22          23          86
              Quezada, Jessica Avon C.                    20         20          20          21         81.2

             Legend

              A. Commitment                                    C. Teaching for Independent Learning
              B. Knowledge of Subject                          D. Management of Learning



             Prepared by:


             RITCH M. BANATE
             Department Chairperson


             Noted:


             GIL D. RAMOS,  MAHisto
             Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                              Department of Management


                                        CLASSROOM OBSERVATION REPORT
                                             First Semester, AY 2020-2021


                        Name of Faculty                                CRITERIA                        Total
                                                                                                      Points
              Permanent                                   A           B           C          B
              Banag Debbie Rose T.                        24         25          23          24         95.6
              Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      25         24          24          25          98
              Saquin, Melona I.                           25         24          25          23         96.8
              Job Order
              Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.                   22         21          21          22          86
              Cumayas, Angelika A.                        20         21          22          21         84.4
              De Silva, Jan Edizon J.                     22         21          22          20         84.8
              Galicha, Maria Kristina A.                  19         18          20          23         81.2

             Legend

              A. Commitment                                    C. Teaching for Independent Learning
              B. Knowledge of Subject                          D. Management of Learning



             Prepared by:


             RITCH M. BANATE
             Department Chairperson


             Noted:


             NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
             Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                              Department of Management


                                        CLASSROOM OBSERVATION REPORT
                                            Second Semester, AY 2019-2020


                        Name of Faculty                                CRITERIA                        Total
                                                                                                      Points
              Permanent                                   A           B           C          B
              Banag Debbie Rose T.                        25         23          24          25         97.2
              Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      24         24          24          24          96
              Saquin, Melona I.                           25         24          25          24          98
              Job Order
              Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.                   22         22          22          22          88
              Carpina, Daniel V.                          21         20          22          22         85.6
              Cumayas, Angelika A.                        22         21          21          22          86
              De Silva, Jan Edizon J.                     20         22          23          22         87.6
              Galicha, Maria Kristina A.                  21         20          19          22          82

             Legend

              A. Commitment                                    C. Teaching for Independent Learning
              B. Knowledge of Subject                          D. Management of Learning



             Prepared by:


             RITCH M. BANATE
             Department Chairperson


             Noted:


             NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
             Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="132"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="133"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="134"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="135"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="136"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="137"><![CDATA[STUDENT EVALUATION FOR TEACHERS




                             Second Semester, 2021-2022]]></page><page Index="138"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                         (CvSU)
                                            DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS
                                                        Indang, Cavite
                                             415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph



                          OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS


              OFFICE MEMORANDUM
              No. 9, s. 2022

              TO            :       ALL COLLEGE DEANS AND CAMPUS ADMINISTRATORS


              FROM          :       MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, Ph.D.
                                    Vice President for Academic Affairs


              SUBJECT       :       STUDENT EVALUATION OF TEACHERS

              DATE          :       April 19, 2022
              ____________________________________________________________________________

                  1.  Please be informed that the Office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs will
                     be conducting evaluation of faculty thru the Student Evaluation of Teacher (SET)

                     instrument on April 25 to 28, 2022. The same instrument was made available in
                     Google form thru the following links created for the purpose:

                            Main Campus                  https://forms.gle/er5N9TWuz7TNZbCf6

                            GS and OLC                   https://forms.gle/rNWswYvgNGhBK2SA8
                            Bacoor Campus                https://forms.gle/QRV4zVEFH9SjisFM9

                            Carmona Campus               https://forms.gle/PGk5MSViDtroH3UR9
                            Cavite City Campus           https://forms.gle/a8WAe3Qq9SkHqCJx8

                            Gen.Trias Campus             https://forms.gle/wCZVM8ULZBqPdBXe9

                            Imus Campus                  https://forms.gle/zXkEB1hwUyQEhZdaA
                            Naic Campus                  https://forms.gle/dWNU62Me5HjLEHyp9

                            Rosario Campus               https://forms.gle/QSFgqTu4macHFWjt6
                            Silang Campus                https://forms.gle/LPwDuQzs4B86z4uTA

                            Tanza Campus                 https://forms.gle/kraC8xr9PoDoMqKKA

                            Trece Martires Campus        https://forms.gle/pcA4s782GWcAerpY8]]></page><page Index="139"><![CDATA[2.  Kindly  double  check  on  the  link  the  names  of  the  faculty  members  from  your

                     respective college/campus to ensure its completeness.
                  3.  All  college  deans/campus  administrators  shall  assign  a  person-in-charge  per

                     department who will conduct the online faculty evaluation.
                  4.  To  facilitate  the  evaluation,  person-in-charge  will  join  the  online  class  of  the

                     teacher to administer the evaluation instrument by sharing the link to the students.

                  5.  Before the evaluation, it is expected that the instrument and process of evaluation
                     were thoroughly explained to the students.

                  6.  We will appreciate it very much if the forms will be accomplished not later than
                     April 28, 2022.

                  7.  For your guidance and dissemination

                  8.  Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="140"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                           (CvSU)
                                              DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS
                                                          Indang, Cavite
                                               415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph



                             OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS


               June 22, 2022


               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Campus Administrator, CvSU-Tanza Campus
               This University


               Dear Prof. Ramos:

                       This is to provide you the official final result of the Student Evaluation for Teachers
                                                      nd
               (SET) of the CvSU-Tanza Campus for 2  Sem. AY 2021-2022 for your reference.

                       Thank you very much.


               Truly yours,


               MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="141"/><page Index="142"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                   CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                 (CvSU)

                                                                    DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

                                                                                Indang, Cavite

                                                                    415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
                                                                             www.cvsu  .edu.ph


                                                   OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS

                                                                   SUMMARY LIST OF SET RATINGS
                                                                      for the 2  Sem. AY 2021-2022
                                                                              nd

               COLLEGE/CAMPUS:              CvSU-Tanza Campus

               Part I: General Evaluation of the Faculty                                                                                     Rating



                                                            I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
                                                Sample
                  Name of Faculty                                         Organization   III. Teacher-  IV. Teaching   Management   and Support   to Students
                                                 Size                                                                            Numerical        Adjectival



        Addangna, Teresa O.                       34        4.86      4.89      4.89      4.86      4.82      4.85      4.84        4.86       Very Satisfactory
        Advincula, Audrey Gerard D.                6        4.87      4.80      4.87      4.77      4.83      4.83      4.80        4.82       Very Satisfactory
        Ampon, Mary Dean P.                       78        4.52      4.57      4.53      4.47      4.54      4.50      4.56        4.53       Very Satisfactory
        Apellanes, Johnny Rick S,                 181       4.44      4.50      4.34      4.43      4.46      4.45      4.51        4.45       Very Satisfactory
        Baculod, Jonell M.                        20        4.07      4.11      3.97      4.14      4.09      4.15      3.98        4.07       Very Satisfactory
        Balano, Gabriel G.                        152       4.65      4.60      4.50      4.60      4.61      4.58      4.58        4.59       Very Satisfactory
        Banag, Charmaine T.                       18        4.01      4.09      3.94      3.96      3.98      4.10      4.07        4.02       Very Satisfactory
        Banate, Ritch M.                          31        4.95      4.94      4.92      4.94      4.92      4.92      4.93        4.93       Very Satisfactory
        Banate, Sharmaine M.                      31        4.90      4.86      4.87      4.84      4.84      4.89      4.92        4.87       Very Satisfactory
        Bergado, Marjorie C.                      49        4.76      4.80      4.77      4.73      4.75      4.72      4.76        4.75       Very Satisfactory
        Bonifacio, Janine B.                      36        4.86      4.84      4.72      4.74      4.76      4.85      4.83        4.80       Very Satisfactory
        Borilla, Audreyson H.                     72        4.72      4.74      4.73      4.68      4.68      4.72      4.69        4.71       Very Satisfactory
        Bueza, Aries C.                           87        4.67      4.61      4.65      4.61      4.59      4.60      4.66        4.63       Very Satisfactory
        Caballero, Jackielyn S.                   147       4.75      4.74      4.74      4.76      4.74      4.78      4.77        4.75       Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="143"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
    CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 (CvSU)

 DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

 Indang, Cavite

  415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
 www.cvsu  .edu.ph


 OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS

 SUMMARY LIST OF SET RATINGS
 for the 2  Sem. AY 2021-2022
 nd

 COLLEGE/CAMPUS:    CvSU-Tanza Campus

 Part I: General Evaluation of the Faculty               Rating



 I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
 Sample
 Name of Faculty   Organization   III. Teacher-  IV. Teaching   Management   and Support   to Students
 Size                                        Numerical       Adjectival



 Addangna, Teresa O.   34   4.86   4.89   4.89   4.86   4.82   4.85   4.84   4.86   Very Satisfactory
 Advincula, Audrey Gerard D.   6   4.87   4.80   4.87   4.77   4.83   4.83   4.80   4.82   Very Satisfactory
 Ampon, Mary Dean P.   78   4.52   4.57   4.53   4.47   4.54   4.50   4.56   4.53   Very Satisfactory
 Apellanes, Johnny Rick S,   181   4.44   4.50   4.34   4.43   4.46   4.45   4.51   4.45   Very Satisfactory
 Baculod, Jonell M.   20   4.07   4.11   3.97   4.14   4.09   4.15   3.98   4.07   Very Satisfactory
 Balano, Gabriel G.   152   4.65   4.60   4.50   4.60   4.61   4.58   4.58   4.59   Very Satisfactory
 Banag, Charmaine T.   18   4.01   4.09   3.94   3.96   3.98   4.10   4.07   4.02   Very Satisfactory
 Banate, Ritch M.   31   4.95   4.94   4.92   4.94   4.92   4.92   4.93   4.93   Very Satisfactory
 Banate, Sharmaine M.   31   4.90   4.86   4.87   4.84   4.84   4.89   4.92   4.87   Very Satisfactory
 Bergado, Marjorie C.   49   4.76   4.80   4.77   4.73   4.75   4.72   4.76   4.75   Very Satisfactory
 Bonifacio, Janine B.   36   4.86   4.84   4.72   4.74   4.76   4.85   4.83   4.80   Very Satisfactory
 Borilla, Audreyson H.   72   4.72   4.74   4.73   4.68   4.68   4.72   4.69   4.71   Very Satisfactory
 Bueza, Aries C.   87   4.67   4.61   4.65   4.61   4.59   4.60   4.66   4.63   Very Satisfactory
 Caballero, Jackielyn S.   147   4.75   4.74   4.74   4.76   4.74   4.78   4.77   4.75   Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="144"><![CDATA[I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   IV. Teaching   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
                                                Sample                                                                                       Rating
                  Name of Faculty                                         Organization   III. Teacher-             Management   and Support   to Students
                                                 Size                                                                            Numerical        Adjectival



        Cap-atan, John Daniel V.                  29        3.92      3.79      3.48      3.72      3.79      3.69      3.58        3.71         Satisfactory
        Carpina, Daniel V.                        83        4.72      4.74      4.67      4.65      4.65      4.62      4.62        4.67       Very Satisfactory
        Costa, Haizel Anne m.                     19        4.58      4.54      4.54      4.56      4.58      4.58      4.60        4.57       Very Satisfactory
        Culvera, Ryan Jay O.                      72        3.95      3.93      3.90      3.90      3.84      3.90      3.93        3.91         Satisfactory
        Darvin, Rogelio M.                        27        4.83      4.75      4.75      4.73      4.75      4.79      4.77        4.77       Very Satisfactory
        De Silva, Jan Edizon J.                   106       4.44      4.50      4.50      4.48      4.44      4.45      4.46        4.47       Very Satisfactory
        De Torres, John Paul P.                   31        4.50      4.46      4.35      4.37      4.42      4.52      4.46        4.44       Very Satisfactory
        Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                    44        4.59      4.63      4.64      4.59      4.58      4.58      4.59        4.60       Very Satisfactory
        Escalante, Christian B.                   124       4.88      4.87      4.85      4.87      4.85      4.85      4.89        4.86       Very Satisfactory
        Fabian, Debbie Rose B.                    27        4.23      4.32      4.04      4.32      4.24      4.26      4.07        4.21       Very Satisfactory
        Feranil, Edison E.                         2        4.10      4.40      4.40      4.00      4.30      4.40      4.50        4.30       Very Satisfactory
        Galicha, Maria Kristina P.                58        4.56      4.67      4.54      4.64      4.53      4.64      4.72        4.61       Very Satisfactory
        Gote, Fahad T.                            44        4.62      4.63      4.64      4.62      4.61      4.60      4.65        4.62       Very Satisfactory
        Jacinto, Roman P. III                     85        4.12      4.12      4.08      4.11      4.09      4.16      4.20        4.12       Very Satisfactory
        Lopez, Jhollie Anne D.                    33        4.78      4.76      4.75      4.67      4.68      4.73      4.78        4.74       Very Satisfactory
        Lumagui, Grace T.                         16        4.66      4.64      4.64      4.65      4.64      4.63      4.66        4.64       Very Satisfactory
        Mabalay, Christofer A.                    68        3.77      3.72      3.69      3.80      3.83      3.76      3.89        3.78         Satisfactory
        Macapundag, Muhaimin P.                   28        4.01      4.12      4.04      4.11      4.09      4.09      4.18        4.09       Very Satisfactory
        Marcelino, Anacleto Q.                     4        4.50      4.50      4.50      4.50      4.50      4.50      4.20        4.46       Very Satisfactory
        Mojica, Ivory P.                          83        4.35      4.32      4.28      4.37      4.36      4.32      4.38        4.34       Very Satisfactory
        Mojica, Lenardo G.                        70        3.08      2.82      2.89      2.79      2.83      2.77      2.84        2.86        Unsatisfactory
        Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.             51        4.51      4.51      4.46      4.47      4.49      4.40      4.47        4.47       Very Satisfactory
        Obon, Ana Marie C.                        29        4.39      4.31      4.28      4.29      4.32      4.30      4.19        4.30       Very Satisfactory
        Ortigosa, Rein R.                         58        4.93      4.93      4.90      4.88      4.85      4.91      4.92        4.90       Very Satisfactory
        Peñaflorida, Efren G. Jr.                 68        4.50      4.47      4.42      4.42      4.45      4.40      4.50        4.45       Very Satisfactory
        Pitagan, Charles Vincent B.               40        4.71      4.69      4.73      4.72      4.77      4.73      4.73        4.72       Very Satisfactory
        Quezada, Jessica Avon C.                  29        4.30      4.37      4.36      4.33      4.32      4.43      4.53        4.38       Very Satisfactory
        Ramos, Lavie Mae A.                       46        4.77      4.77      4.76      4.73      4.72      4.78      4.80        4.76       Very Satisfactory
        Regio, Erwin M.                           20        3.13      3.18      3.16      3.20      3.21      3.11      3.05        3.15         Satisfactory
        Samantila, Mariz B.                       25        4.31      4.46      4.43      4.28      4.32      4.45      4.47        4.39       Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="145"><![CDATA[I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   IV. Teaching   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
 Sample                                                  Rating
 Name of Faculty   Organization   III. Teacher-  Management   and Support   to Students
 Size                                        Numerical       Adjectival



 Cap-atan, John Daniel V.   29   3.92   3.79   3.48   3.72   3.79   3.69   3.58   3.71   Satisfactory
 Carpina, Daniel V.   83   4.72   4.74   4.67   4.65   4.65   4.62   4.62   4.67   Very Satisfactory
 Costa, Haizel Anne m.   19   4.58   4.54   4.54   4.56   4.58   4.58   4.60   4.57   Very Satisfactory
 Culvera, Ryan Jay O.   72   3.95   3.93   3.90   3.90   3.84   3.90   3.93   3.91   Satisfactory
 Darvin, Rogelio M.   27   4.83   4.75   4.75   4.73   4.75   4.79   4.77   4.77   Very Satisfactory
 De Silva, Jan Edizon J.   106   4.44   4.50   4.50   4.48   4.44   4.45   4.46   4.47   Very Satisfactory
 De Torres, John Paul P.   31   4.50   4.46   4.35   4.37   4.42   4.52   4.46   4.44   Very Satisfactory
 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.   44   4.59   4.63   4.64   4.59   4.58   4.58   4.59   4.60   Very Satisfactory
 Escalante, Christian B.   124   4.88   4.87   4.85   4.87   4.85   4.85   4.89   4.86   Very Satisfactory
 Fabian, Debbie Rose B.   27   4.23   4.32   4.04   4.32   4.24   4.26   4.07   4.21   Very Satisfactory
 Feranil, Edison E.   2   4.10   4.40   4.40   4.00   4.30   4.40   4.50   4.30   Very Satisfactory
 Galicha, Maria Kristina P.   58   4.56   4.67   4.54   4.64   4.53   4.64   4.72   4.61   Very Satisfactory
 Gote, Fahad T.   44   4.62   4.63   4.64   4.62   4.61   4.60   4.65   4.62   Very Satisfactory
 Jacinto, Roman P. III   85   4.12   4.12   4.08   4.11   4.09   4.16   4.20   4.12   Very Satisfactory
 Lopez, Jhollie Anne D.   33   4.78   4.76   4.75   4.67   4.68   4.73   4.78   4.74   Very Satisfactory
 Lumagui, Grace T.   16   4.66   4.64   4.64   4.65   4.64   4.63   4.66   4.64   Very Satisfactory
 Mabalay, Christofer A.   68   3.77   3.72   3.69   3.80   3.83   3.76   3.89   3.78   Satisfactory
 Macapundag, Muhaimin P.   28   4.01   4.12   4.04   4.11   4.09   4.09   4.18   4.09   Very Satisfactory
 Marcelino, Anacleto Q.   4   4.50   4.50   4.50   4.50   4.50   4.50   4.20   4.46   Very Satisfactory
 Mojica, Ivory P.   83   4.35   4.32   4.28   4.37   4.36   4.32   4.38   4.34   Very Satisfactory
 Mojica, Lenardo G.   70   3.08   2.82   2.89   2.79   2.83   2.77   2.84   2.86   Unsatisfactory
 Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.   51   4.51   4.51   4.46   4.47   4.49   4.40   4.47   4.47   Very Satisfactory
 Obon, Ana Marie C.   29   4.39   4.31   4.28   4.29   4.32   4.30   4.19   4.30   Very Satisfactory
 Ortigosa, Rein R.   58   4.93   4.93   4.90   4.88   4.85   4.91   4.92   4.90   Very Satisfactory
 Peñaflorida, Efren G. Jr.   68   4.50   4.47   4.42   4.42   4.45   4.40   4.50   4.45   Very Satisfactory
 Pitagan, Charles Vincent B.   40   4.71   4.69   4.73   4.72   4.77   4.73   4.73   4.72   Very Satisfactory
 Quezada, Jessica Avon C.   29   4.30   4.37   4.36   4.33   4.32   4.43   4.53   4.38   Very Satisfactory
 Ramos, Lavie Mae A.   46   4.77   4.77   4.76   4.73   4.72   4.78   4.80   4.76   Very Satisfactory
 Regio, Erwin M.   20   3.13   3.18   3.16   3.20   3.21   3.11   3.05   3.15   Satisfactory
 Samantila, Mariz B.   25   4.31   4.46   4.43   4.28   4.32   4.45   4.47   4.39   Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="146"><![CDATA[I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   IV. Teaching   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
                                                Sample                                                                                       Rating
                  Name of Faculty                                         Organization   III. Teacher-             Management   and Support   to Students
                                                 Size                                                                            Numerical        Adjectival



        Sanchez, Micah M.                         37        4.85      4.76      4.83      4.81      4.75      4.73      4.80        4.79       Very Satisfactory
        Saquin, Melona I.                         51        4.74      4.79      4.73      4.72      4.70      4.77      4.78        4.75       Very Satisfactory
        Sebastian, Mildred A.                     40        4.34      4.25      4.36      4.27      4.40      4.29      4.31        4.32       Very Satisfactory
        Senaris, Joyce Erika S.                   18        4.82      4.77      4.77      4.82      4.83      4.77      4.79        4.80       Very Satisfactory
        Serrano, Con Marvin B.                    35        4.70      4.70      4.75      4.74      4.71      4.75      4.74        4.73       Very Satisfactory
        Sibulo, Crisistomo M.                     62        4.54      4.55      4.43      4.44      4.45      4.60      4.54        4.51       Very Satisfactory
        Sibulo, Mark Joel C.                       5        4.68      4.48      4.56      4.48      4.60      4.48      4.76        4.58       Very Satisfactory
        Silvero, Gerry Mae T.                     76        4.84      4.85      4.84      4.84      4.86      4.84      4.86        4.85       Very Satisfactory
        Son, Kristina D.                          61        4.48      4.51      4.38      4.54      4.45      4.49      4.46        4.47       Very Satisfactory
        Tagle, Maria Cristina C.                  62        4.47      4.50      4.48      4.46      4.43      4.46      4.50        4.47       Very Satisfactory
        Villa, Estelita A.                        17        4.02      4.18      4.18      4.09      4.15      4.24      4.26        4.16       Very Satisfactory


               Recorded by:                                Prepared by:                               Noted:


               JEFFERSON G. RODRIGUEZ                      ANTONIO V. CINTO                           MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Technical Staff, OVPAA                      Technical Staff, OVPAA                     VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="147"><![CDATA[I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   IV. Teaching   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
 Sample                                                  Rating
 Name of Faculty   Organization   III. Teacher-  Management   and Support   to Students
 Size                                        Numerical       Adjectival



 Sanchez, Micah M.   37   4.85   4.76   4.83   4.81   4.75   4.73   4.80   4.79   Very Satisfactory
 Saquin, Melona I.   51   4.74   4.79   4.73   4.72   4.70   4.77   4.78   4.75   Very Satisfactory
 Sebastian, Mildred A.   40   4.34   4.25   4.36   4.27   4.40   4.29   4.31   4.32   Very Satisfactory
 Senaris, Joyce Erika S.   18   4.82   4.77   4.77   4.82   4.83   4.77   4.79   4.80   Very Satisfactory
 Serrano, Con Marvin B.   35   4.70   4.70   4.75   4.74   4.71   4.75   4.74   4.73   Very Satisfactory
 Sibulo, Crisistomo M.   62   4.54   4.55   4.43   4.44   4.45   4.60   4.54   4.51   Very Satisfactory
 Sibulo, Mark Joel C.   5   4.68   4.48   4.56   4.48   4.60   4.48   4.76   4.58   Very Satisfactory
 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.   76   4.84   4.85   4.84   4.84   4.86   4.84   4.86   4.85   Very Satisfactory
 Son, Kristina D.   61   4.48   4.51   4.38   4.54   4.45   4.49   4.46   4.47   Very Satisfactory
 Tagle, Maria Cristina C.   62   4.47   4.50   4.48   4.46   4.43   4.46   4.50   4.47   Very Satisfactory
 Villa, Estelita A.   17   4.02   4.18   4.18   4.09   4.15   4.24   4.26   4.16   Very Satisfactory


 Recorded by:              Prepared by:               Noted:


 JEFFERSON G. RODRIGUEZ       ANTONIO V. CINTO           MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
 Technical Staff, OVPAA          Technical Staff, OVPAA         VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="148"><![CDATA[STUDENT EVALUATION FOR TEACHERS




                                First Semester, 2021-2022]]></page><page Index="149"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                           (CvSU)
                                              DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS
                                                          Indang, Cavite
                                               415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph



                             OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS


               December 3, 2022


               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Campus Administrator, CvSU-Tanza Campus
               This University


               Dear Prof. Ramos:

                       This is to provide you the official result of the Student Evaluation for Teachers (SET)
                                                st
               of the CvSU-Tanza Campus for 1  Sem. AY 2021-2022 for your reference.

                       Thank you very much.


               Truly yours,


               MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="150"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                   CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                 (CvSU)

                                                                    DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

                                                                                Indang, Cavite

                                                                    415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
                                                                             www.cvsu  .edu.ph


                                                   OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS

                                                                   SUMMARY LIST OF SET RATINGS
                                                                      for the 1  Sem. AY 2021-2022
                                                                              st

               COLLEGE/CAMPUS:              CvSU-Tanza Campus

               Part I: General Evaluation of the Faculty                                                                                     Rating



                                                            I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Rapport   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
                                                Sample
                  Name of Faculty                                         Organization   III. Teacher-  Student   IV. Teaching   Management   and Support   to Students
                                                 Size                                                                            Numerical        Adjectival



        Addangna, Teresa O.                       20        4.46      4.56      4.53      4.49      4.58      4.39      4.52        4.50       Very Satisfactory
        Advincula, Audrey Gerard D.               39        4.78      4.77      4.79      4.78      4.83      4.78      4.78        4.79       Very Satisfactory
        Ampon, Mary Dean P.                       90        4.65      4.64      4.63      4.63      4.62      4.62      4.71        4.65       Very Satisfactory
        Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.                 40        3.96      4.01      4.04      3.95      3.98      3.89      4.05        3.98         Satisfactory
        Baculod, Joneil M.                        27        4.67      4.77      4.68      4.72      4.75      4.67      4.65        4.70       Very Satisfactory
        Balano, Gabriel G.                         9        4.82      4.82      4.89      4.78      4.84      4.89      4.91        4.85       Very Satisfactory
        Banag, Charmaine T.                       25        4.30      4.37      4.28      4.35      4.31      4.34      4.38        4.33       Very Satisfactory
        Banate, Ritch M.                          61        4.78      4.79      4.74      4.75      4.67      4.71      4.66        4.73       Very Satisfactory
        Banate, Sharmaine M.                      33        4.86      4.90      4.90      4.85      4.85      4.87      4.88        4.87       Very Satisfactory
        Bonifacio, Janine B.                      31        4.70      4.72      4.59      4.67      4.59      4.67      4.70        4.66       Very Satisfactory
        Borilla, Audreyson H.                     70        4.69      4.73      4.70      4.65      4.65      4.67      4.66        4.68       Very Satisfactory
        Bueza, Aries C.                           27        4.36      4.43      4.56      4.30      4.40      4.45      4.47        4.42       Very Satisfactory
        Caballero, Jackielyn S.                   27        4.88      4.90      4.86      4.87      4.84      4.85      4.90        4.87       Very Satisfactory
        Costa, Haizel Anne M.                     52        4.48      4.47      4.55      4.47      4.47      4.54      4.55        4.51       Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="151"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
    CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 (CvSU)

 DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

 Indang, Cavite

  415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
 www.cvsu  .edu.ph


 OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS

 SUMMARY LIST OF SET RATINGS
 for the 1  Sem. AY 2021-2022
 st

 COLLEGE/CAMPUS:    CvSU-Tanza Campus

 Part I: General Evaluation of the Faculty               Rating



 I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Rapport   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
 Sample
 Name of Faculty   Organization   III. Teacher-  Student   IV. Teaching   Management   and Support   to Students
 Size                                        Numerical       Adjectival



 Addangna, Teresa O.   20   4.46   4.56   4.53   4.49   4.58   4.39   4.52   4.50   Very Satisfactory
 Advincula, Audrey Gerard D.   39   4.78   4.77   4.79   4.78   4.83   4.78   4.78   4.79   Very Satisfactory
 Ampon, Mary Dean P.   90   4.65   4.64   4.63   4.63   4.62   4.62   4.71   4.65   Very Satisfactory
 Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.   40   3.96   4.01   4.04   3.95   3.98   3.89   4.05   3.98   Satisfactory
 Baculod, Joneil M.   27   4.67   4.77   4.68   4.72   4.75   4.67   4.65   4.70   Very Satisfactory
 Balano, Gabriel G.   9   4.82   4.82   4.89   4.78   4.84   4.89   4.91   4.85   Very Satisfactory
 Banag, Charmaine T.   25   4.30   4.37   4.28   4.35   4.31   4.34   4.38   4.33   Very Satisfactory
 Banate, Ritch M.   61   4.78   4.79   4.74   4.75   4.67   4.71   4.66   4.73   Very Satisfactory
 Banate, Sharmaine M.   33   4.86   4.90   4.90   4.85   4.85   4.87   4.88   4.87   Very Satisfactory
 Bonifacio, Janine B.   31   4.70   4.72   4.59   4.67   4.59   4.67   4.70   4.66   Very Satisfactory
 Borilla, Audreyson H.   70   4.69   4.73   4.70   4.65   4.65   4.67   4.66   4.68   Very Satisfactory
 Bueza, Aries C.   27   4.36   4.43   4.56   4.30   4.40   4.45   4.47   4.42   Very Satisfactory
 Caballero, Jackielyn S.   27   4.88   4.90   4.86   4.87   4.84   4.85   4.90   4.87   Very Satisfactory
 Costa, Haizel Anne M.   52   4.48   4.47   4.55   4.47   4.47   4.54   4.55   4.51   Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="152"><![CDATA[I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   IV. Teaching   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
                                                Sample                                                                                       Rating
                  Name of Faculty                                         Organization   III. Teacher-             Management   and Support   to Students
                                                 Size                                                                            Numerical        Adjectival



        Culvera, Ryan Jay O.                      17        4.38      4.39      4.40      4.38      4.33      4.40      4.40        4.38       Very Satisfactory
        Darvin, Rogelio M.                        15        4.15      4.27      4.01      4.23      4.21      4.09      3.88        4.12       Very Satisfactory
        De Silva, Jan Edizon J.                   52        4.09      4.18      4.15      4.13      4.12      4.18      4.21        4.15       Very Satisfactory
        De Torres, John Paul P.                   58        4.21      4.28      4.31      4.24      4.27      4.23      4.30        4.26       Very Satisfactory
        Delas Alas, Kieth Angelica A.             25        3.50      3.53      3.53      3.60      3.47      3.48      3.70        3.55         Satisfactory
        Escalante, Christian B.                   106       4.73      4.77      4.75      4.75      4.72      4.75      4.77        4.75       Very Satisfactory
        Fabian, Debbie Rose B.                    43        3.89      4.04      3.94      4.07      4.05      4.07      4.05        4.02       Very Satisfactory
        Feranil, Edison E.                        62        4.61      4.59      4.57      4.59      4.60      4.59      4.64        4.60       Very Satisfactory
        Francisco, Teofilo Jr. G.                 18        4.21      4.34      4.33      4.52      4.54      4.52      4.42        4.41       Very Satisfactory
        Galicha, Maria Kristina P.                24        4.47      4.57      4.58      4.56      4.51      4.49      4.52        4.53       Very Satisfactory
        Gote, Fahad T.                            59        4.42      4.37      4.41      4.37      4.37      4.35      4.44        4.39       Very Satisfactory
        Guban, Sarah Jane                         46        4.87      4.87      4.83      4.81      4.80      4.87      4.82        4.84       Very Satisfactory
        Ignacio, Marie Joy C.                     31        4.32      4.37      4.19      4.30      4.28      4.23      4.36        4.29       Very Satisfactory
        Jacinto, Roman III P.                     35        4.09      4.06      4.06      4.03      4.04      3.95      3.88        4.02       Very Satisfactory
        Mabalay, Christofer A.                    28        3.24      3.09      3.01      3.07      3.28      3.11      3.26        3.15         Satisfactory
        Marasigan, Gemma S.                       29        2.08      2.03      2.04      1.97      1.99      2.05      2.26        2.06        Unsatisfactory
        Marcelino, Anacleto Q.                    15        4.43      4.35      4.27      4.27      4.20      4.12      4.33        4.28       Very Satisfactory
        Mojica, Ivory P.                          91        4.41      4.33      4.41      4.44      4.40      4.43      4.55        4.42       Very Satisfactory
        Mojica, Leonardo G.                        6        3.90      3.77      3.63      3.50      3.77      3.63      3.67        3.70         Satisfactory
        Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.             88        4.73      4.78      4.72      4.74      4.71      4.74      4.73        4.74       Very Satisfactory
        Navida, Allan L.                          50        4.76      4.76      4.71      4.67      4.74      4.72      4.67        4.72       Very Satisfactory
        Ortigosa, Rein R.                         36        4.83      4.87      4.81      4.85      4.85      4.83      4.86        4.84       Very Satisfactory
        PeÃ±aflorida, Efren Jr. G.                29        4.62      4.57      4.66      4.59      4.66      4.73      4.66        4.64       Very Satisfactory
        Pitagan, Charles Vincent B.               58        4.26      4.20      4.20      4.23      4.19      4.26      4.22        4.23       Very Satisfactory
        Quezada, Jessica Avon C.                  43        3.68      3.68      3.71      3.73      3.74      3.83      3.98        3.77         Satisfactory
        Ramos, Lavie Mae A.                        5        4.60      4.60      4.44      4.56      4.56      4.56      4.56        4.55       Very Satisfactory
        Regio, Erwin M.                            8        4.13      4.10      3.95      4.10      4.18      4.08      4.18        4.10       Very Satisfactory
        Samantila, Mariz B.                       55        4.63      4.67      4.63      4.63      4.66      4.65      4.67        4.65       Very Satisfactory
        Saquin, Melona I.                         28        4.72      4.77      4.70      4.71      4.74      4.72      4.72        4.73       Very Satisfactory
        Sebastian, Mildred A.                     18        4.92      4.86      4.92      4.90      4.91      4.89      4.90        4.90       Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="153"><![CDATA[I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   IV. Teaching   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
 Sample                                                  Rating
 Name of Faculty   Organization   III. Teacher-  Management   and Support   to Students
 Size                                        Numerical       Adjectival



 Culvera, Ryan Jay O.   17   4.38   4.39   4.40   4.38   4.33   4.40   4.40   4.38   Very Satisfactory
 Darvin, Rogelio M.   15   4.15   4.27   4.01   4.23   4.21   4.09   3.88   4.12   Very Satisfactory
 De Silva, Jan Edizon J.   52   4.09   4.18   4.15   4.13   4.12   4.18   4.21   4.15   Very Satisfactory
 De Torres, John Paul P.   58   4.21   4.28   4.31   4.24   4.27   4.23   4.30   4.26   Very Satisfactory
 Delas Alas, Kieth Angelica A.   25   3.50   3.53   3.53   3.60   3.47   3.48   3.70   3.55   Satisfactory
 Escalante, Christian B.   106   4.73   4.77   4.75   4.75   4.72   4.75   4.77   4.75   Very Satisfactory
 Fabian, Debbie Rose B.   43   3.89   4.04   3.94   4.07   4.05   4.07   4.05   4.02   Very Satisfactory
 Feranil, Edison E.   62   4.61   4.59   4.57   4.59   4.60   4.59   4.64   4.60   Very Satisfactory
 Francisco, Teofilo Jr. G.   18   4.21   4.34   4.33   4.52   4.54   4.52   4.42   4.41   Very Satisfactory
 Galicha, Maria Kristina P.   24   4.47   4.57   4.58   4.56   4.51   4.49   4.52   4.53   Very Satisfactory
 Gote, Fahad T.   59   4.42   4.37   4.41   4.37   4.37   4.35   4.44   4.39   Very Satisfactory
 Guban, Sarah Jane   46   4.87   4.87   4.83   4.81   4.80   4.87   4.82   4.84   Very Satisfactory
 Ignacio, Marie Joy C.   31   4.32   4.37   4.19   4.30   4.28   4.23   4.36   4.29   Very Satisfactory
 Jacinto, Roman III P.   35   4.09   4.06   4.06   4.03   4.04   3.95   3.88   4.02   Very Satisfactory
 Mabalay, Christofer A.   28   3.24   3.09   3.01   3.07   3.28   3.11   3.26   3.15   Satisfactory
 Marasigan, Gemma S.   29   2.08   2.03   2.04   1.97   1.99   2.05   2.26   2.06   Unsatisfactory
 Marcelino, Anacleto Q.   15   4.43   4.35   4.27   4.27   4.20   4.12   4.33   4.28   Very Satisfactory
 Mojica, Ivory P.   91   4.41   4.33   4.41   4.44   4.40   4.43   4.55   4.42   Very Satisfactory
 Mojica, Leonardo G.   6   3.90   3.77   3.63   3.50   3.77   3.63   3.67   3.70   Satisfactory
 Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.   88   4.73   4.78   4.72   4.74   4.71   4.74   4.73   4.74   Very Satisfactory
 Navida, Allan L.   50   4.76   4.76   4.71   4.67   4.74   4.72   4.67   4.72   Very Satisfactory
 Ortigosa, Rein R.   36   4.83   4.87   4.81   4.85   4.85   4.83   4.86   4.84   Very Satisfactory
 PeÃ±aflorida, Efren Jr. G.   29   4.62   4.57   4.66   4.59   4.66   4.73   4.66   4.64   Very Satisfactory
 Pitagan, Charles Vincent B.   58   4.26   4.20   4.20   4.23   4.19   4.26   4.22   4.23   Very Satisfactory
 Quezada, Jessica Avon C.   43   3.68   3.68   3.71   3.73   3.74   3.83   3.98   3.77   Satisfactory
 Ramos, Lavie Mae A.   5   4.60   4.60   4.44   4.56   4.56   4.56   4.56   4.55   Very Satisfactory
 Regio, Erwin M.   8   4.13   4.10   3.95   4.10   4.18   4.08   4.18   4.10   Very Satisfactory
 Samantila, Mariz B.   55   4.63   4.67   4.63   4.63   4.66   4.65   4.67   4.65   Very Satisfactory
 Saquin, Melona I.   28   4.72   4.77   4.70   4.71   4.74   4.72   4.72   4.73   Very Satisfactory
 Sebastian, Mildred A.   18   4.92   4.86   4.92   4.90   4.91   4.89   4.90   4.90   Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="154"><![CDATA[I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   IV. Teaching   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
                                                Sample                                                                                       Rating
                  Name of Faculty                                         Organization   III. Teacher-             Management   and Support   to Students
                                                 Size                                                                            Numerical        Adjectival



        Senaris, Joyce Erika S.                   77        4.44      4.48      4.40      4.44      4.47      4.44      4.43        4.44       Very Satisfactory
        Sibulo, Crisostomo M.                     17        4.44      4.58      4.54      4.53      4.55      4.59      4.49        4.53       Very Satisfactory
        Sibulo, Mark Joel C.                       8        3.40      3.20      2.83      3.08      3.53      3.35      3.13        3.21         Satisfactory
        Silvero, Gerry Mae T.                     90        4.77      4.77      4.76      4.70      4.71      4.75      4.77        4.75       Very Satisfactory
        Son, Kristina D.                          28        4.62      4.69      4.58      4.61      4.68      4.66      4.72        4.65       Very Satisfactory
        Tagle, Maria Cristina C.                  72        4.45      4.46      4.42      4.42      4.38      4.46      4.54        4.45       Very Satisfactory
        Villa, Estelita A.                        12        4.18      4.27      4.23      4.22      4.40      4.30      4.48        4.30       Very Satisfactory

               Recorded by:                                Prepared by:                               Noted:


               JEFFERSON G. RODRIGUEZ                      ANTONIO V. CINTO                           MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Technical Staff, OVPAA                      Technical Staff, OVPAA                     VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="155"><![CDATA[I. Subject   Matter   Content   II.   Student   Rapport   IV. Teaching   Methods   V.   Presentation   VI. Classroom   VII. Sensitivity
 Sample                                                  Rating
 Name of Faculty   Organization   III. Teacher-  Management   and Support   to Students
 Size                                        Numerical       Adjectival



 Senaris, Joyce Erika S.   77   4.44   4.48   4.40   4.44   4.47   4.44   4.43   4.44   Very Satisfactory
 Sibulo, Crisostomo M.   17   4.44   4.58   4.54   4.53   4.55   4.59   4.49   4.53   Very Satisfactory
 Sibulo, Mark Joel C.   8   3.40   3.20   2.83   3.08   3.53   3.35   3.13   3.21   Satisfactory
 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.   90   4.77   4.77   4.76   4.70   4.71   4.75   4.77   4.75   Very Satisfactory
 Son, Kristina D.   28   4.62   4.69   4.58   4.61   4.68   4.66   4.72   4.65   Very Satisfactory
 Tagle, Maria Cristina C.   72   4.45   4.46   4.42   4.42   4.38   4.46   4.54   4.45   Very Satisfactory
 Villa, Estelita A.   12   4.18   4.27   4.23   4.22   4.40   4.30   4.48   4.30   Very Satisfactory

 Recorded by:              Prepared by:               Noted:


 JEFFERSON G. RODRIGUEZ       ANTONIO V. CINTO           MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
 Technical Staff, OVPAA          Technical Staff, OVPAA         VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="156"/><page Index="157"><![CDATA[STUDENT EVALUATION FOR TEACHERS




                             Second Semester, 2020-2021]]></page><page Index="158"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                   CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                 (CvSU)

                                                                    DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

                                                                                Indang, Cavite

                                                                    415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
                                                                             www.cvsu  .edu.ph


                                                   OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS

                                                                   SUMMARY LIST OF SET RATINGS
                                                                              nd
                                                                      for the 2  Sem. AY 2020-2021


               COLLEGE/CAMPUS:              CvSU-Tanza Campus


                                                 Sample                    Knowledge       Teaching for     Management                   RATING
                   NAME OF FACULTY                          Instruction
                                                   Size                    of Subject     Independence       of Learning    Numerical          Adjectival
             Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.             131          4.63          4.59             4.66             4.61           4.62         Very Satisfactory
             Banag, Charmaine T.                   50           4.30          4.17             4.18             4.21           4.22         Very Satisfactory
             Banag, Debbie Rose T.                 98           4.28          4.27             4.22             4.24           4.25         Very Satisfactory
             Banate, Ritch M.                      42           4.86          4.88             4.78             4.82           4.83         Very Satisfactory
             Borilla, Audreyson H.                 90           4.68          4.68             4.67             4.61           4.66         Very Satisfactory
             Caballero, Jackielyn S.               37           4.66          4.52             4.62             4.54           4.59         Very Satisfactory
             Cap-atan, John Daniel V.              43           3.98          4.06             4.02             4.07           4.03         Very Satisfactory
             Carpina, Daniel V.                    62           4.73          4.76             4.73             4.63           4.71         Very Satisfactory
             Costa, Haizel Anne M.                 67           4.63          4.61             4.62             4.58           4.61         Very Satisfactory
             Cumayas, Angelika M.                  43           3.88          3.99             4.07             4.13           4.02         Very Satisfactory
             De Silva, Jan Edizon J.               12           3.45          3.47             3.37             3.40           3.42           Satisfactory
             Delgado, Jeffrey M.                   48           3.72          3.78             3.75             3.65           3.72           Satisfactory
             Denzo, John Derick R.                 101          4.16          4.28             4.25             4.25           4.23         Very Satisfactory
             Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                41           4.60          4.64             4.61             4.60           4.61         Very Satisfactory
             Escalante, Christian B.               126          4.76          4.77             4.76             4.75           4.76         Very Satisfactory
             Galicha, Maria Kristina P.             7           4.40          4.40             4.40             4.31           4.38         Very Satisfactory
             Gaunia, Jonerizza L.                  64           4.46          4.53             4.48             4.47           4.48         Very Satisfactory
             Guban, Sarah Jane                     48           4.83          4.83             4.78             4.78           4.80         Very Satisfactory
             Mojica, Ivory P.                      67           3.59          3.62             3.62             3.59           3.61           Satisfactory
             Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.         15           4.64          4.64             4.67             4.68           4.66         Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="159"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
    CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 (CvSU)

 DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

 Indang, Cavite

  415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
 www.cvsu  .edu.ph


 OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS

 SUMMARY LIST OF SET RATINGS
 nd
 for the 2  Sem. AY 2020-2021


 COLLEGE/CAMPUS:    CvSU-Tanza Campus


 Sample   Knowledge   Teaching for   Management      RATING
 NAME OF FACULTY   Instruction
 Size   of Subject   Independence   of Learning   Numerical   Adjectival
 Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.   131   4.63   4.59   4.66   4.61   4.62   Very Satisfactory
 Banag, Charmaine T.   50   4.30   4.17   4.18   4.21   4.22   Very Satisfactory
 Banag, Debbie Rose T.   98   4.28   4.27   4.22   4.24   4.25   Very Satisfactory
 Banate, Ritch M.   42   4.86   4.88   4.78   4.82   4.83   Very Satisfactory
 Borilla, Audreyson H.   90   4.68   4.68   4.67   4.61   4.66   Very Satisfactory
 Caballero, Jackielyn S.   37   4.66   4.52   4.62   4.54   4.59   Very Satisfactory
 Cap-atan, John Daniel V.   43   3.98   4.06   4.02   4.07   4.03   Very Satisfactory
 Carpina, Daniel V.   62   4.73   4.76   4.73   4.63   4.71   Very Satisfactory
 Costa, Haizel Anne M.   67   4.63   4.61   4.62   4.58   4.61   Very Satisfactory
 Cumayas, Angelika M.   43   3.88   3.99   4.07   4.13   4.02   Very Satisfactory
 De Silva, Jan Edizon J.   12   3.45   3.47   3.37   3.40   3.42   Satisfactory
 Delgado, Jeffrey M.   48   3.72   3.78   3.75   3.65   3.72   Satisfactory
 Denzo, John Derick R.   101   4.16   4.28   4.25   4.25   4.23   Very Satisfactory
 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.   41   4.60   4.64   4.61   4.60   4.61   Very Satisfactory
 Escalante, Christian B.   126   4.76   4.77   4.76   4.75   4.76   Very Satisfactory
 Galicha, Maria Kristina P.   7   4.40   4.40   4.40   4.31   4.38   Very Satisfactory
 Gaunia, Jonerizza L.   64   4.46   4.53   4.48   4.47   4.48   Very Satisfactory
 Guban, Sarah Jane   48   4.83   4.83   4.78   4.78   4.80   Very Satisfactory
 Mojica, Ivory P.   67   3.59   3.62   3.62   3.59   3.61   Satisfactory
 Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.   15   4.64   4.64   4.67   4.68   4.66   Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="160"><![CDATA[Sample                    Knowledge       Teaching for     Management                   RATING
                   NAME OF FACULTY                          Instruction
                                                   Size                    of Subject     Independence       of Learning    Numerical          Adjectival
             Navida, Allan L.                      52           4.72          4.72             4.68             4.66           4.69         Very Satisfactory
             Ortigosa, Rein R.                     65           4.77          4.74             4.72             4.76           4.75         Very Satisfactory
             Peralta, Mary Giliane R.              109          4.51          4.54             4.47             4.43           4.49         Very Satisfactory
             Pitagan, Charles Vincent C.           113          3.62          3.57             3.69             3.69           3.64           Satisfactory
             Precia, Erika D.                      69           4.44          4.40             4.38             4.31           4.38         Very Satisfactory
             Quezada, Jessica Avon C.               5           4.48          4.52             4.52             4.48           4.50         Very Satisfactory
             Ramos, Gil D.                          1           2.60          3.20             3.00             3.40           3.05           Satisfactory
             Regio, Erwin M.                       172          4.59          4.63             4.56             4.57           4.59         Very Satisfactory
             Sabaybay, Joseph O.                   34           3.78          3.69             3.81             3.76           3.76           Satisfactory
             Sanchez, Micah M.                     85           4.41          4.42             4.41             4.41           4.41         Very Satisfactory
             Saquin, Melona I.                     93           4.62          4.60             4.60             4.52           4.59         Very Satisfactory
             Sebastian, Mildred A.                 25           4.72          4.82             4.86             4.82           4.80         Very Satisfactory
             Senaris, Joyce Erika S.               68           4.82          4.82             4.76             4.75           4.79         Very Satisfactory
             Sibulo, Mark Joel C.                  61           4.59          4.62             4.58             4.61           4.60         Very Satisfactory
             Silvero, Gerry Mae T.                 47           4.95          4.94             4.93             4.93           4.94         Very Satisfactory
             Tagle, Maria Cristina C.              74           4.45          4.42             4.44             4.41           4.43         Very Satisfactory

               Prepared by:                                Noted:


               JEFFERSON G. RODRIGUEZ                      MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Technical Staff, OVPAA                      VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="161"><![CDATA[Sample   Knowledge   Teaching for   Management      RATING
 NAME OF FACULTY   Instruction
 Size   of Subject   Independence   of Learning   Numerical   Adjectival
 Navida, Allan L.   52   4.72   4.72   4.68   4.66   4.69   Very Satisfactory
 Ortigosa, Rein R.   65   4.77   4.74   4.72   4.76   4.75   Very Satisfactory
 Peralta, Mary Giliane R.   109   4.51   4.54   4.47   4.43   4.49   Very Satisfactory
 Pitagan, Charles Vincent C.   113   3.62   3.57   3.69   3.69   3.64   Satisfactory
 Precia, Erika D.   69   4.44   4.40   4.38   4.31   4.38   Very Satisfactory
 Quezada, Jessica Avon C.   5   4.48   4.52   4.52   4.48   4.50   Very Satisfactory
 Ramos, Gil D.   1   2.60   3.20   3.00   3.40   3.05     Satisfactory
 Regio, Erwin M.   172   4.59   4.63   4.56   4.57   4.59   Very Satisfactory
 Sabaybay, Joseph O.   34   3.78   3.69   3.81   3.76   3.76   Satisfactory
 Sanchez, Micah M.   85   4.41   4.42   4.41   4.41   4.41   Very Satisfactory
 Saquin, Melona I.   93   4.62   4.60   4.60   4.52   4.59   Very Satisfactory
 Sebastian, Mildred A.   25   4.72   4.82   4.86   4.82   4.80   Very Satisfactory
 Senaris, Joyce Erika S.   68   4.82   4.82   4.76   4.75   4.79   Very Satisfactory
 Sibulo, Mark Joel C.   61   4.59   4.62   4.58   4.61   4.60   Very Satisfactory
 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.   47   4.95   4.94   4.93   4.93   4.94   Very Satisfactory
 Tagle, Maria Cristina C.   74   4.45   4.42   4.44   4.41   4.43   Very Satisfactory

 Prepared by:               Noted:


 JEFFERSON G. RODRIGUEZ       MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
 Technical Staff, OVPAA          VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="162"/><page Index="163"><![CDATA[STUDENT EVALUATION FOR TEACHERS




                                First Semester, 2020-2021]]></page><page Index="164"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                   CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                 (CvSU)

                                                                    DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

                                                                                Indang, Cavite

                                                                    415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
                                                                             www.cvsu  .edu.ph


                                                   OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS

                                                                   SUMMARY LIST OF SET RATINGS
                                                                              st
                                                                      for the 1  Sem. AY 2020-2021


               COLLEGE/CAMPUS:              CvSU – Tanza Campus


                                                                            PART I                                                           RATING
              NAME OF FACULTY              Sample                    Knowledge       Teaching for     Management      PART II
                                             Size      Instruction    of Subject     Independence      of Learning              Numerical          Adjectival
        Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.              1          4.00           4.00             4.00             4.00         4.00        4.00          Satisfactory
        Banag, Charmaine T.                                                                      No Rating
        Banag, Debbie Rose T.                                                                    No Rating
        Banate, Ritch M.                                                                         No Rating
        Borilla, Audreyson H.                 16          3.94           3.90             3.90             3.90         4.01        3.96          Satisfactory
        Caballero, Jackielyn S.                                                                  No Rating
        Cap-atan, John Daniel V.               1          5.00           5.00             4.80             4.80         5.00        4.95       Very Satisfactory
        Costa, Haizel Anne M.                                                                    No Rating
        Cumayas, Angelika M.                   1          1.60           1.60             1.60             1.20         1.72        1.61             Poor
        De Silva, Jan Edizon J.                2          2.20           1.70             1.60             2.10         2.61        2.26              Fair
        Delgado, Jeffrey M.                                                                      No Rating
        Denzo, John Derick R.                  1          4.00           4.00             4.00             4.20         4.33        4.19       Very Satisfactory
        Dinlasan, Jessa B.                    18          4.07           4.01             3.96             3.90         3.93        3.96          Satisfactory
        Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                 4          4.50           4.45             4.45             4.45         4.78        4.62       Very Satisfactory
        Escalante, Christian B.               10          4.76           4.78             4.78             4.70         4.77        4.76       Very Satisfactory
        Galicha, Maria Kristina P.                                                               No Rating
        Gaunia, Jonerizza L.                   1          4.20           4.40             3.80             3.80         4.11        4.08       Very Satisfactory
        Granada, Anne Mariellle A.            35          4.54           4.38             4.30             4.27         4.38        4.38       Very Satisfactory
        Guban, Sarah Jane                      6          4.93           4.90             4.77             4.87         4.90        4.88       Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="165"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
    CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 (CvSU)

 DON SEVERINO DE LAS ALAS CAMPUS

 Indang, Cavite

  415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
 www.cvsu  .edu.ph


 OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS

 SUMMARY LIST OF SET RATINGS
 st
 for the 1  Sem. AY 2020-2021


 COLLEGE/CAMPUS:    CvSU – Tanza Campus


 PART I                                                  RATING
 NAME OF FACULTY   Sample   Knowledge   Teaching for   Management   PART II
 Size   Instruction   of Subject   Independence   of Learning   Numerical   Adjectival
 Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.   1   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   Satisfactory
 Banag, Charmaine T.   No Rating
 Banag, Debbie Rose T.   No Rating
 Banate, Ritch M.   No Rating
 Borilla, Audreyson H.   16   3.94   3.90   3.90   3.90   4.01   3.96   Satisfactory
 Caballero, Jackielyn S.   No Rating
 Cap-atan, John Daniel V.   1   5.00   5.00   4.80   4.80   5.00   4.95   Very Satisfactory
 Costa, Haizel Anne M.   No Rating
 Cumayas, Angelika M.   1   1.60   1.60   1.60   1.20   1.72   1.61   Poor
 De Silva, Jan Edizon J.   2   2.20   1.70   1.60   2.10   2.61   2.26   Fair
 Delgado, Jeffrey M.   No Rating
 Denzo, John Derick R.   1   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.20   4.33   4.19   Very Satisfactory
 Dinlasan, Jessa B.   18   4.07   4.01   3.96   3.90   3.93   3.96   Satisfactory
 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.   4   4.50   4.45   4.45   4.45   4.78   4.62   Very Satisfactory
 Escalante, Christian B.   10   4.76   4.78   4.78   4.70   4.77   4.76   Very Satisfactory
 Galicha, Maria Kristina P.   No Rating
 Gaunia, Jonerizza L.    1   4.20   4.40   3.80   3.80   4.11   4.08   Very Satisfactory
 Granada, Anne Mariellle A.   35   4.54   4.38   4.30   4.27   4.38   4.38   Very Satisfactory
 Guban, Sarah Jane   6   4.93   4.90   4.77   4.87   4.90   4.88   Very Satisfactory]]></page><page Index="166"><![CDATA[PART I                                                           RATING
              NAME OF FACULTY              Sample                    Knowledge       Teaching for     Management      PART II
                                             Size      Instruction    of Subject     Independence      of Learning              Numerical          Adjectival
        Isidro, Shylla Jean S.                18          3.78           3.70             3.66             3.63         3.66        3.68          Satisfactory
        Manlapig, Ron Mariah Kristaffer        6          4.13           4.17             4.13             4.07         4.44        4.28       Very Satisfactory
        Matel, Jonna N.                        1          4.00           4.00             4.00             4.00         4.00        4.00          Satisfactory
        Mojica, Ivory P.                      26          3.11           3.01             3.04             2.94         3.12        3.07          Satisfactory
        Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.                                                            No Rating
        Navida, Allan L.                       1          3.20           3.60             3.40             3.00         3.33        3.32          Satisfactory
        Ortigosa, Rein R.                     29          4.57           4.67             4.64             4.61         4.63        4.62       Very Satisfactory
        Peralta, Mary Giliane R.                                                                 No Rating
        Pitagan, Charles Vincent C.                                                              No Rating
        Precia, Erika D.                                                                         No Rating
        Regio, Erwin M.                        2          4.00           3.80             4.00             4.00         4.03        3.99          Satisfactory
        Sabaybay, Joseph O.                    2          1.00           1.00             1.00             1.00         1.00        1.00             Poor
        Sanchez, Micah M.                      2          3.20           3.40             3.60             3.50         3.53        3.48          Satisfactory
        Saquin, Melona I.                      5          4.64           4.56             4.56             4.40         4.30        4.42       Very Satisfactory
        Sebastian, Mildred A.                  1          4.00           4.80             5.00             5.00         5.00        4.85       Very Satisfactory
        Senaris, Joyce Erika S.                                                                  No Rating
        Sibulo, Mark Joel C.                   1          4.00           4.00             4.00             4.00         4.00        4.00          Satisfactory
        Silvero, Gerry Mae T.                  6          4.57           4.63             4.47             4.43         4.63        4.58       Very Satisfactory
        Tagle, Maria Cristina C.                                                                 No Rating


               Recorded by:                                Prepared by:                               Noted:


               JEFFERSON G. RODRIGUEZ                      ANTONIO V. CINTO                           MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Technical Staff, OVPAA                      Technical Staff, OVPAA                     VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="167"><![CDATA[PART I                                                  RATING
 NAME OF FACULTY   Sample   Knowledge   Teaching for   Management   PART II
 Size   Instruction   of Subject   Independence   of Learning   Numerical   Adjectival
 Isidro, Shylla Jean S.   18   3.78   3.70   3.66   3.63   3.66   3.68   Satisfactory
 Manlapig, Ron Mariah Kristaffer    6   4.13   4.17   4.13   4.07   4.44   4.28   Very Satisfactory
 Matel, Jonna N.    1   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   Satisfactory
 Mojica, Ivory P.   26   3.11   3.01   3.04   2.94   3.12   3.07   Satisfactory
 Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique R.   No Rating
 Navida, Allan L.   1   3.20   3.60   3.40   3.00   3.33   3.32   Satisfactory
 Ortigosa, Rein R.   29   4.57   4.67   4.64   4.61   4.63   4.62   Very Satisfactory
 Peralta, Mary Giliane R.   No Rating
 Pitagan, Charles Vincent C.   No Rating
 Precia, Erika D.   No Rating
 Regio, Erwin M.   2   4.00   3.80   4.00   4.00   4.03   3.99   Satisfactory
 Sabaybay, Joseph O.   2   1.00   1.00   1.00   1.00   1.00   1.00   Poor
 Sanchez, Micah M.   2   3.20   3.40   3.60   3.50   3.53   3.48   Satisfactory
 Saquin, Melona I.   5   4.64   4.56   4.56   4.40   4.30   4.42   Very Satisfactory
 Sebastian, Mildred A.   1   4.00   4.80   5.00   5.00   5.00   4.85   Very Satisfactory
 Senaris, Joyce Erika S.   No Rating
 Sibulo, Mark Joel C.   1   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   4.00   Satisfactory
 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.   6   4.57   4.63   4.47   4.43   4.63   4.58   Very Satisfactory
 Tagle, Maria Cristina C.   No Rating


 Recorded by:              Prepared by:               Noted:


 JEFFERSON G. RODRIGUEZ       ANTONIO V. CINTO           MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
 Technical Staff, OVPAA          Technical Staff, OVPAA         VP, Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="168"><![CDATA[STUDENT EVALUATION FOR TEACHERS




                             Second Semester, 2019-2020









                         Not Applicable due to Pandemic]]></page><page Index="169"><![CDATA[STUDENT EVALUATION FOR TEACHERS




                                First Semester, 2019-2020]]></page><page Index="170"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="171"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="172"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>
