<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="24"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.6.            There is a mechanism to facilitate the


                        teaching-learning process.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph





                                ACADEMIC AFFAIRS POST ECQ PLAN USING THE
                                      FLEXIBLE LEARNING ARRANGEMENT*



                       COVID-19 is a worldwide pandemic impacting every aspect of society, including Higher
               Education Institutions (HEIs). The implementation of Enhanced Community Quarantine (ECQ)
               in various regions in the country poses issues and challenges among HEIs wherein faculty,
               students and administrators need to face.  Classes in all levels were suspended – face-to-face
               teaching  and  learning  stopped  including  all  other  online  learning  activities  since  not  all
               students  and  faculty  had  reliable  internet  connection  at  home.  Temporary  closure  affects
               40,819 students, 1508 teaching and 590 non-teaching staff of Cavite State University.

                       In  response  to  the  threats of  this  global  COVID-19 pandemic,  the  Commission on
               Higher  Education  (CHEd) has  recommended  the  implementation  of  a  flexible  system  for
               the reopening    of   classes   of   colleges   and   universities   in   the   country   for
               school year 2020-2021 (Manila Times, 05 May 2020). CHED Chairperson De Vera explained
               that  “under  a  flexible  learning  system, schools  adjust  the  learning  process  based  on  the
               location of the students and the structure of the learning system. It includes online and offline
               activities.”

                       Given the unprecedented challenges of this global pandemic to HEIs,  Cavite State
               University has quite significantly initiated plans to reshape the learning management system
               that will address the needs and situations of its thousands of students ensuring the highest
               degree possible of inclusion and equity in education.

                       The following outlines the post ECQ plan of Academic Affairs for the undergraduate
               and  graduate  students  in  the  Main  and  Satellite  Campuses  using  the  flexible  learning
               arrangement to be implemented effective upon approval:


                                      FLEXIBLE LEARNING ARRANGEMENT

                       Cavite State University shall implement the  Flexible learning arrangement which
               will permit the 1) redesigning of the syllabi to fit to the alternative modes of learning, 2)
               the  use  of  both  digital  and  non-digital  modes  of  teaching  and  learning  and  3)
               adjustment  on  the  schedules  for  flexible  learning.  This  learning  system  will  provide
               learners  with  choices  about  when,  where  and  how  learning  occurs  using  a  range  of
               technologies and available materials to support the teaching and learning process.

               _____________________________

               *  Prepared  by  the  Office  of  the  Vice  President  for  Academic  Affairs  and  approved  by  virtue  of
               Administrative Council Resolution No. 13, series of 2020 dated May 10, 2020


                                                       Page 1 of 9]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph



                   I.     Adjustment of Academic Calendar


                          1.  Midyear Term 2020

                                1.1  Registration Period   –      June 22-23, 2020
                                1.2  Beginning of Classes –       June 24, 2020
                                1.3  Final Examination     –      July 27 – 29, 2020
                                1.4  Last Day of Submission/
                                        Uploading of Grades -     July 31, 2020

                              Note: A separate Special Guidelines for Midyear Term 2020 may be proposed taking into
                              consideration the following:
                              a.  Provisions on items II-XII should be specifically designed more applicable to the needs and
                                  situation of the students who will be directly affected by the Post ECQ Plan.
                              b.  Strict re-implementation of CHED-COVID-2019 Advisory No. 2, s. March 2020
                              c.  Learning management system that integrates flexible learning arrangement (use of digital
                                  and non-digital learning modes) with limited provision for face to face learning mode
                              d.  Stricter  health  protocols  for  students  and  employees  and  other  support  mechanisms
                                  stipulated in CSC MC10, s 2020

                          2.  First Semester, 2020 – 2021

                                2.1  Registration Period   –      August 3 - 28, 2020
                                2.2  Beginning of Classes -       September 7, 2020
                                2.3  Christmas Break       -      December 21, 2020 – January 3, 2021
                                2.4  Final Examination     -      January 11 - 16, 2021 (Graduating)
                                                                  January 18 – 23, 2021 (Non Graduating)
                                2.5  Last Day of Submission/
                                        Uploading of Grades-      January 23, 2021 (Graduating)
                                                                  January 30, 2021 (Non Graduating)

                          3.  Second Semester, 2020 - 2021

                                3.1  Registration Period   –      February 1-12, 2021
                                3.2  Beginning of Classes -       February 15, 2021
                                3.3  Final Examination     -      June 7 -11, 2021 (Graduating)
                                                                  June 14- 19, 2021 (Non Graduating)
                                3.4  Last day of Submission/
                                          Uploading of Grades-    June 17, 2021 (Graduating)
                                                                  June 28, 2021 (Non Graduating)

                          4.  Midyear Term 2021

                                1.1  Registration Period   –      June 21 – 25, 2021
                                1.2  Beginning of Classes –       June 28, 2021
                                1.3  Final Examination     –      August 2-5, 2021
                                1.4  Submission of Grades -       August 6, 2021


                                                       Page 2 of 9]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph




                   II.    Class Size

                          1.   The minimum number of students to open a class as stipulated in the CvSU
                               Manual of Operation (2009) shall be followed. Should the class size fall below
                               the  minimum  number,  the  Department  Chairperson  should  be  informed
                               immediately to decide whether to dissolve the class or to maintain  it as a
                               special class approved by the College Dean/Campus Administrator.
                          2.   The  maximum  class  size  of  forty  (40)  students  shall  be  observed.  To
                               implement protocol on physical/social distancing, class shall be divided into
                               two groups/batches for alternate class arrangement.
                          3.   The maximum number of students per class session shall be 20


                   III.   Schedule of Classes, Class Meetings, and Room Assignments

                          1.   Schedule of classes for First and Third Year Students shall be every Monday,
                               Tuesday, and Wednesday while classes for Second Year and Fourth Year
                               Students shall be every Thursday, Friday and Saturday. Other year levels
                               shall be scheduled for three consecutive days or in any days of the week.
                               Other adjustments may be done, if necessary.
                          2.   Class meetings shall be done through alternate class arrangement i.e. face to
                               face or remote/distance mode.
                          3.   If possible, students should only come to university once a week for face to
                               face classes.
                          4.   During class meetings, the first batch of the class shall be taught using face
                               to face while the second batch shall be doing the assigned task/s through
                               remote/distance mode and vice versa.
                          5.   Homeroom assignments shall be implemented except for laboratory classes.
                               All colleges/departments offering the courses/programs shall be responsible
                               for homeroom assignment of their respective students.
                          6.   Protocol  on  physical/social  distancing  shall  be  strictly  implemented  during
                               face to face and laboratory classes


                   IV.    Class Attendance

                          1.   The University Policy on class attendance shall be implemented for face to
                               face class meetings.


                   V.     Academic Load

                          1.   The university policy on academic load shall be waived for AY 2020-2021.
                          2.   A student may be allowed to enroll more than the maximum allowable credit
                               units not to exceed 26 units.


                                                       Page 3 of 9]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                   VI.    First Day of Classes

                          1.   During  the  first  day  of  classes,  students  shall  be  provided  with  a  copy  of
                               course syllabus.
                          2.   Faculty  members  should  discuss  the  content  of  the  course  syllabus
                               particularly the course objectives, course content, instructional approaches,
                               learning  activities,  learning  resources  and  location,  course  requirements,
                               bases for evaluating students’ performance and technology to be used.
                          3.   Faculty members should orient the students about the class groupings and
                               discuss the procedure for alternate class arrangement;
                          4.   Faculty members shall create a class directory that includes home address,
                               e-mail  address,  social  media  account,  mobile  number  and  others  in
                               preparation  for  distance/remote  learning  mode.  Faculty  members  shall
                               comply with the Philippine Data Privacy Act of 2012 or RA 10173 in handling
                               the personal information of the students.
                          5.   Faculty members shall conduct a survey on students’ internet connectivity and
                               available gadgets that can be used to access learning materials and submit
                               course requirements/outputs online.
                          6.   Faculty  members  are  encouraged  to  provide  advanced  copy  of  learning
                               materials to be used for the entire semester.

                   VII.   Modes of Teaching and Learning

                                 Classes shall be conducted on a flexible learning arrangement using varied
                          online and offline modes of learnings, e.g. blended modes of teaching, distance
                          learning, online learning including but not limited to the following:


                          1.  Synchronous Physical/ Face to Face Components
                                1.1  Face to face classes/tutoring
                                1.2  Conduct of Laboratory Classes

                          2.  Synchronous Electronic Components
                                2.1  Video/Audio Conferencing
                                2.2  Online Classes
                                2.3  Instant Messaging

                          3.  Asynchronous Components
                                3.1  On-line self-paced learning content (modules, learning guide, etc)
                                3.2  E-mail, discussion forums
                                3.3  Handouts/Articles/Books
                                3.4  Audio/Video clips
                                3.5  Chatting
                                3.6  Other electronic/computer-based instruction

                          Note: The use of Open Educational Resources (OERs) is recommended. Depending
                          on the nature of the programs, the college/campus may also adopt other alternative
                          learning modes most suitable to either lecture or laboratory classes.

                                                       Page 4 of 9]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph



                   VIII.   NSTP, PE, RLE, Courses with Laboratory and similar courses

                          1.  Colleges/Departments offering NSTP, PE, RLE, laboratory courses and other
                              similar courses shall explore options to deliver these courses through face to
                              face and remote/distance learning.
                          2.  Develop/Use available video recordings to demonstrate  experiments, sports
                              activities and similar activities.
                          3.  As  much  as  possible,  use  online  and  offline  (pre-recorded)  instructional
                              resources to demonstrate/design projects.
                          4.  Modify the scope and direction of design projects to avoid utilizing any on-
                              campus resources, such as the machine shops access, assembly spaces, and
                              laboratories.

                   IX.    Assessment and Evaluation of Students’ Performance

                          1.  Examination may be administered in any mode accessible to all students.
                          2.  Assessment/evaluation  for  remote/distance  mode  shall  be  conducted  using
                              alternative strategies including but not limited to the following:
                                      2.1   Question-based assessment
                                            2.1.1  Open-book or “take home” assessment
                                            2..1.2  Series of Quizzes
                                            2.1.3  Student-developed quiz questions
                                      2.2   Project-based assessment
                                            2.2.1  Development of video presentations/demonstration
                                            2.2.2  Annotated anthology or bibliography
                                            2.2.3  Fact Sheet
                                             2.2.4    Peer-  and  self-review  activity/case  analysis/  critique
                                                    paper
                                            2.2.5  e-Portfolio
                                            2.2.6  Term paper
                          3.  Should an exam be conducted online, plan to offer a “trial quiz” first, prior to
                              the launch of the actual examination.
                          4.  Ask students to sign an honor system pledge

                  X.     Monitoring of Classes and Evaluation of Faculty Performance

                          1.  All  faculty  members  shall  include  the  Department  Chairperson/Dean  in  the
                              course  site/class  account  to  be  created by  faculty  for  their  remote/distance
                              classes.    The  Department  Chairperson/Dean  can  open  the site  anytime  for
                              monitoring purposes.
                          2.  For  off-line  activities,  faculty  members  shall  submit  their  portfolio  to  the
                              concerned Department Chairperson before midterm and before the end of the
                              term.  All  activities  and  sample  outputs  of  the  students  shall  be  part  of  the
                              portfolio.  Portfolio  may  be submitted  to  the  Department  Chairperson  in  any
                              mode, i.e. soft or hard copy.


                                                       Page 5 of 9]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                          3.  Student evaluation of teachers (SET) shall be done online using Google Survey
                              Form or in any mode accessible to the students.

                  XI.    Safety and security practices during face to face classes and conduct of extra-
                         or co-curricular activities

                          The following shall be strictly observed to help protect the students, faculty and
                          employees inside the university:

                          1.  Wearing of school ID;
                          2.  Wearing of face mask;
                          3.  Physical/social distancing;
                          4.  Suspension of wearing of school uniforms (to discourage the students from
                              repeatedly wearing uniforms which could also be of help to stop the spread of
                              the virus); and
                          5.  Suspension of extra- or co-curricular activities that will gather up to 10 people.

                   XII.   Flexible Learning Arrangement for the Graduate School

                              For graduate students, all flexible arrangements for undergraduate students
                       shall be adopted by the Graduate School except for the following:
                       1.  Academic Calendar

                              Saturdays following the established dates for registration, start of class, final
                              examination  and  submission  of  grades  shall  be  set  as  schedule  for  the
                              aforementioned academic activities for the Graduate School.
                       2.  Class Size

                              A maximum class size of twenty (20) for the Master’s level and fifteen (15) for
                              the Doctorate level shall be observed for graduate classes.  Classes with more
                              than the maximum number of students shall be split into two sections.
                       3.  Schedule of Classes

                              Saturdays as days of holding classes for the Graduate School shall remain.

                       4.  Academic Load

                              The academic load as set forth by the Graduate School academic policy shall
                              be followed.
                       5.  Comprehensive Examination

                              Pursuant to the CvSU Academic Policies and Guidelines in Light of Covid-19
                              Pandemic, the Graduate School and Open Learning College (GS-OLC) will
                              administer the comprehensive examination online or through any other mode
                              available  for  eligible  Master  and  PhD  students.  Below  outlines  the  general
                              guidelines in taking the comprehensive examination:
                                                       Page 6 of 9]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph




                               5.1   Modes of Delivery

                                            The  comprehensive  examination  will  have  two  modes  of
                                     delivery: (1) online – to be administered this June and (2) sit-down – to
                                     be administered starting September. Based on the urgency of taking
                                     the  examination,  graduate  students  will  be  categorized  into:  (1)
                                     Category 1 students  - Graduating Non-thesis MBA students who will
                                     be advised to take the online examination this June and (2) Category
                                     2 students – All other Master and PhD students who will be advised to
                                     take the sit-down examination on September.

                                      5.1.1  Sit-down comprehensive examination

                                                   The usual sit-down examination will be administered in
                                            compliance  with  the  set minimum health  protocols  like  social
                                            distancing and wearing of masks.

                                    5.1.2   Online comprehensive examination

                                                   The  online  comprehensive  examination  is  a  four-day
                                            long  examination  that  will  be  administered  on  June,  2020.  A
                                            student will be given sets of questions covering 3 to 4 subjects
                                            per day depending on their respective programs.

                                                   The  questions  will  be  sent  to  the  examinee  email  at
                                            around 8:00 am of the examination date. Submission of answers
                                            will  be  on  or  before  12:00  midnight  of  the  next  day.  Late
                                            submissions will not be considered for checking.

                                                   Answer sheets will be collected by GS-OLC thru email
                                            and forwarded to faculty members email for checking.

                              5.2      Development of Examination

                                           Concerned faculty members will be requested to make suitable
                                     questions for online mode of examination delivery.  The following are
                                     suggested in crafting the examination questions:

                                     5.2.1  Faculty  members  may  consider  giving  questions  to  assess
                                            higher  levels  of  learning  domains.  Questions  should  elicit
                                            analysis and critical thinking among the examinees.

                                     5.2.2  Faculty members may consider setting a minimum number of
                                            words for the examinees’ answers. By doing so, examinees will
                                                       Page 7 of 9]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                            be  obliged  to  integrate  what  they  know  and  express  them
                                            concisely in their own words.

                                     5.2.3  Faculty  members  may  require  the  examinees  to  cite  their
                                            references  used  in  their  answers  to  prompt  examinees  to  do
                                            further research.

                                            Deadline  for  the  submission  of  the  examination  questions  by
                                     concerned  faculty  members  is  on  May  30,  2020.  Submission  is  thru
                                     gs.olc@cvsu.edu.ph.


                              5.3    Checking of Comprehensive Examination

                                     5.2.1  Faculty  members  will  be  given  a month  to  check  the  answer
                                            sheets.  Faculty  members  may  use  a  plagiarism  checker  app
                                            (e.g.  Turnitin)  to  evaluate  the originality  of  the  answers at  an
                                            acceptable rate of 25 % as set by the University’s Knowledge
                                            Management Center (KMC). [For inquiries how to have a Turnitin
                                            account,  please  email  KMC  at  mfccruzada@cvsu.edu.ph.]
                                            Deadline  of  submission  of  results  is  on  July  21,  2020.
                                            Submission  is  thru  gs.olc@cvsu.edu.ph  using  an  electronic
                                            Comprehensive Examination Result form. Electronic forms will
                                            be provided by GS-OLC.


                               5.4   Student Guide for the Online Examination:


                                            The  comprehensive  examination  for  Master  of  Business
                                     Administration (professional track) is a four-day long examination that
                                     will be administered on June 6, 13, 20, and 27, 2020. Students will be
                                     given sets of questions covering 3 to 4 subjects per day depending on
                                     their respective programs.

                                     1.  Using Google account, register using the online information form.
                                         Access Link : http://tiny.cc/gsolc-onlinecompre.

                                         An  email  from  the  Graduate  School  and  Open Learning  College
                                         (GS-OLC)  with  a  subject  “GSOLC  Online  Comprehensive
                                         Examination (First/Second/Third/Fourth Day)” will be sent at around
                                         8:00 am of the examination date. The email will include instructions,
                                         sets of questions and official answer sheets.

                                     2.  Answer  the  questions  using  the  official  answer  sheets.  Type
                                         answers on a separate sheet for each subject. Save answers in
                                                       Page 8 of 9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                         Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                         PDF  format  with  a  file  name:  SUBJECT  CODE,  underline,  and
                                         student number (eg. BA201_201512345.pdf).

                                     3.  Attach answer sheets to a reply email.  Reply to the email sent by
                                         the GS-OLC. Submit answers on or before 12:00 midnight of the
                                         next  day  of  the  examination  date.  Late  submissions  will  not  be
                                         considered for checking.

                                     4.  Wait for the result of the online comprehensive examination after
                                         28-30 days of the last date of examination. Result will be sent to
                                         through email. In case of failed remarks, contact GS-OLC via email
                                         or contact number 0909-3007-560 for further instructions.

                                     5.  Answers will be subjected to a plagiarism checker app to evaluate
                                         the originality of answers. All inquiries shall be sent through email
                                         at gs.olc@cvsu.edu.ph.

                           Note  :  For  the  separate  guidelines  on  the  Regular  Semester  (First  Semester  to
                           commence in September 07, 2020, the University may fully go on a regular flexible
                           learning  arrangement  taking  into  consideration  the  most  immediate  support
                           mechanisms for the students, faculty and personnel such as but not limited to the
                           following:
                           1.  Learning management system (connectivity in the University and Campuses,
                              contextual learning and flexible learning; and related modes of learning)
                           2.  Capacity building for faculty on digital and non-digital teaching modes
                           3.  Support mechanisms and safer facilities to students and employees stipulated in CSC
                              MC10, s 2020


               References:

               De Vera, J,P. 2020. Re-shaping higher education in the Philippines delivered in a e-skewala
               webinar on May 08, 2020

               ABS-CBN News Article, 03 May 2020: “Colleges, universities should consult students on next
               academic year: CHED”

               The Manila Times, 05 May 2020, CHED pushes rolling of school opening














                                                       Page 9 of 9]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[The campus holds Capability Enhancement

                           Training for Teachers at the start of

                                               each semester.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Click to See

                                                                                   Documentation]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-06-20


               To             :      ALL T3 FACULTY AND STAFF




               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF MEETING (ZOOM)

               Date           :      26 May 2020


                       Please join and participate in the T3 Scheduled Zoom Meeting on Wednesday, 27

               May 2020 at 1 o’clock in the afternoon.


                       The following agenda are to be discussed:

                         1.  Health Protocols

                         2.  Syllabus and Module Preparation

                         3.  Final Workload Assignment

                         4.  Submission of requirements (Grades, teaching portfolio, etc.)


               Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                     ' 414-3979 ǀ ' (0977)8033809 ǀ ' 509-4148
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                 OFFICE OF THE CAMPUS ADMINISTRATOR



               Office Memorandum
               No. OCA-07-20


               To             :      ALL CONCERNED FACULTY




               From           :      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
                                     Campus Administrator

               `
               Subject        :      NOTICE OF ZOOM MEETING

               Date           :      04 July 2020


                       Please join and participate in the following Scheduled Zoom Meeting by department

               and program/subjects:


                   DEPARTMENT            PROGRAM/SUBJECTS              DATE            DAY           TIME
                Information Technology             BSIT             July 6, 2020     Monday        1:00 p.m.
                     Management                   BSBM              July 7, 2020     Tuesday       1:00 p.m.
                     Management                   BSOA              July 8, 2020   Wednesday       1:00 p.m.
                     Management                   BSHM              July 9, 2020     Thursday      1:00 p.m.
                     Management                   BSTM             July 10, 2020      Friday       1:00 p.m
                  Teacher Education                BSE             July 13, 2020     Monday        1:00 p.m.
                  Arts and Sciences          Gen. Education        July 14, 2020     Tuesday       7:30 p.m.
                  Arts and Sciences                BSP             July 15, 2020  Wednesday        1:00 p.m.


                       Please be guided accordingly. Thank you very much.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Teachers’ Capability Enhancement Seminar
                                                  February 13, 2020
                                                     Workshop


        7:00 – 8:00 AM     Registration
        8:01 – 8:30 AM     Opening Program
                           Prayer                                 Mr. Mark Joel Sibulo
                                                                  Chair, Department of Arts and Sciences
                           National Anthem
                           Welcome Remarks                        Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                                  Administrator, T3 Campuses
                           Inspirational Message                  Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro
                                                                  Vice President, Academic Affairs
                           Levelling of Expectations and Objectives   Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas
                                                                  Coordinator, Tanza Campus
                           Introduction of Participants           Ms. Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                                  Local HR, Tanza Campus
        8:31 – 9:15 AM     Discussion of CvSU Vision and Mission    Mr. Mark Joel Sibulo
                              and T3 Campuses Goals               Chair, Department of Arts and Sciences

        9:16 – 9:45 AM     Discussion on Program Educational      Mr. Ritch M. Banate
                              Objectives and Program Outcomes     Chair, Department of Management
                              BS Business Management
                              BS Information Technology
                              BS Tourism Management                       Click to See
                              BS Hospitality Management                Documentation
                              BS Psychology
                              Bachelor of Secondary Education
                              Bachelor of Elementary Education

        9:46 – 10:15 AM    Teaching Strategies and Classroom      Prof. Noel B. Manarpiis
                              Management                          Teacher Education Department Chair, General Trias
                                                                    City Campus
        10:16 – 11:00 AM   Integration of Gender-Fair Language in   Prof. Arlene L. Estrada
                              Course Syllabi Preparation          GAD Coordinator, T3 Campuses

        11:01 – 12:00 PM   Discussion on the Code of Conduct and   Ms. Shaine C. Hayag
                              Ethical Standards for Public Officials   HR Coordinator, General Trias City Campus
                              and Employees (RA 6713)

        12:00 – 1:00 PM    Lunch Break

        1:00 – 1:30 PM     Technology –Aided Education            Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio
                                                                  Department of Information Technology Chair,
                                                                   Trece Martires City Campus
        1:31 – 2:00 PM     Course Syllabus                        Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                                  Chair, Teacher Education Department
        2:01 – 2:30 PM     Test Construction and Table of         Ms. Gerry Mae Silvero
                              Specifications (TOS)                Instructor, Teacher Education Department

        2:31 – 3:00 PM     Rubrics Preparation                    Ms. Ivory Mojica
                                                                  Instructor, Teacher Education Department
        3:01 – 5:30 PM     Workshop

        5:31 – 5:45 PM     Distribution of Certificates           Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                                  Mr. Cris Albert P. Cajigas
        5:46 – 5:55 PM     Closing Remarks                        Ms. Joyce Erika S. Senaris
                                                                  Chair, Department of Information Technology
        5:56 – 6:00 PM     CvSU Hymn                              Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                                                  Coordinator, OSAS

                                          Angelika Cumayas and Audreyson Borilla
                                                  Masters of Ceremonies]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Service

























                                       individuals
                                                       competitive and morally upright
                                                     in the development of globally

                                                        Cavite recognized for excellence
                                                       The premier university in historic

                                     Vision




























                                                    July 30, 2019    Quality Policy  Excellence  Truth  Mission  development activities.  We Commit to the highest standards of education, value our   stakeholders, Strive for continual improvement of our products and   instruction and responsive research and   services, and Uphold the University’s tenets of Truth, Excellence, and   Service to produce globally competitive and morally upright individuals.  upright individuals
                                                7:00 AM – 5:00 PM

                                              International House II
                                   Cavite State University, Indang, Cavite



                                               Dr. Camilo A. Polinga
                                             Vice President for Academic Affairs
                                           This serves as an invitation]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[T3 TEACHERS’ CAPABILITY ENHANCEMENT SEMINAR WORKSHOP
                          JULY 30, 2019  | INTERNATIONAL HOUSE 2, CvSU, INDANG, CAVITE

                                                      P R O G R A M
                  7:00 – 7:30     Registration                              Click to See

                  7:31 – 8:00     Prayer
                                  National Anthem                        Documentation
                                  Introduction
                  8:01 – 8:15     Welcome Remarks                    Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                                     Campus Administrator
                  8:16 – 8:40     Inspirational Message              Dr. Camilo A. Polinga
                                                                     Vice President  for Academic Affairs
                  8:41 – 9:05     Deep Breathing Exercise            Ms. Amida Chiara Rosario N. Wolski
                                                                     Chief Executive Officer
                                                                      Radha Kunda Wellness

                  9:46 – 10:35    Topic No. 1: Understanding Mental   Ms. Yolanda T. Padilla
                                  Health in the Workplace            Assistant Manager for HR
                                                                     BBT Online Global, Inc.

                  9:46 – 10:35    Topic No. 2: Mindfulness for Mental   Ms. Amida Chiara Rosario N. Wolski
                                  Wellness                           Chief Executive Officer
                                                                     Radha Kunda Wellness
                  10: 36 – 11:16  Topic No. 3: Meditation for        Mr. Thomas F. Wolski
                                  Happiness and Fulfillment in Life  Co-Founder and CEO
                                                                     Nature’s Power Nutraceuticals
                                                                     Corporation
                  11:17 – 12:00   Giving of Certificate to Participants  Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                                     Campus Administrator
                                                                     Campus Coordinators

                  12:01- 1:00     Lunch Break
                  1:01-1:30       Topic  No. 4: Discussion on RA6713   Ms. Shaine C. Hayag
                                  Code of Conduct and Ethical        Human Resource Development
                                  Standards for Public Officials and   Office Coordinator
                                  Employees                          Gen. Trias City Campus

                  1:31 – 4:30     Topic No. 5: Workshop on Course    Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian
                                  Syllabus Preparation               T3 Quality Assurance Coordinator

                                  Topic No. 6: Discussion of CvSU    Prof. Vienna Mi A. Feranil
                                  Mission and Vision                 Coordinator
                                                                     Trece Martires City Campus
                  4:31 – 5: 00    Closing Remarks                    Ms. Alelie B. Diato
                                                                     Coordinator
                                                                     General Trias City Campus


                                                  MR. GIDEON LUKE P. TY
                                                 In-charge of Ceremonies]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Click to See
                                                                                  Documentation]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Sample lectures used during the Capability

                           Enhancement Training for Teachers








                                                      Rubric

                                                 Preparation










                                                 Test and TOS

                                                 Construction








                                                     Syllabus


                                                 Construction











                                                Code of Ethics]]></page></pages></Search>