<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="14"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.17.           The institution encourages student


                        economic ventures such as but not


                        limited to:


                           I.17.4.  Others (please specify)]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY

                                                     Tanza Campus

                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979



                                          CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT
               November 1, 2021



               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS

               Campus Administrator
               Tanza



               Dear Prof. Ramos,

               A blessed day ahead sir! We would like to ask for your permission to allow us to have a new
               campus shirt for our school. These Campus shirts will be one of the Project of the CSG for
               this school year to contribute in the renovation of the student’s area in CvSU- Tanza Campus.
               Campus shirts have many benefits for schools that help build unity and foster school spirit and
               it is affordable way for students and faculty to show their school pride whether in the classroom
               or  throughout  the  community.  Throughout  the  decade’s  campus  shirts  have  become  an
               enduring  unity  builder  for  teams,  clubs,  and  academic  organizations.  The  new  design  of
               campus shirt is not compulsory and it costs 250.00 pesos.



               Since we are on the virtual setting and a lot of students inquiring on having their own campus
               shirt. This project new campus shirt will symbolize as welcome motivation for the new students
               and for the old students in our campus.



               Attached  here  are  the  sample  design  of  the  new  campus  shirt.  We  are  hoping  for  your
               response regarding this matter.

               Thank you and God bless!




               Respectfully yours,


               CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS

               President, Central Student Government]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Noted by:


               MARK JOEL C. SIBULO
               Senior Adviser, Central Student Government





               AUDREYSON H. BORILLA
               Junior Adviser, Central Student Government




               Recommending Approval:




               MELONA I. SAQUIN

               Head, Office of the Student Affairs and Services




                                                       Approved:




                                               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines


                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus

                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite

                                                      (046)414-3979




                                         CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT


                                                ACTIVITY PROPOSAL




               I.  Title of Activity: Cavite State University –Tanza Campus Shirt Project 2021
               II.  Proponents: Cavite State University –Tanza Campus Students
               III.  Rationale:

                       The Central Student Government of Tanza Campus and the Advisers aims to help
                   build unity and foster school spirit through Campus Shirts. Together with this the Campus
                   Shirts will become a fundraising project in helping to renovate the student’s area in the

                   school to have a new school facility for the students. To Strengthen the Community –  the
                   easiest way to express our support is with custom t-shirts. Custom shirts worn by all in the

                   community  show  how  important  education  is  to  the  community,  and  also  shows  the
                   students their civic, athletic or academic endeavors are fully supported by the community
                   at large.


               IV. Objective/s of Project:

                       This project aims to foster school spirits, unity and giving hope in this New Normal by
                   having a Campus shirts and also help the school to have a new school facility for the
                   students. The Central Student Government of Tanza Campus and the Advisers aims to
                   help a lot to have a better educational environment for the students.


               V.  Mechanics and Implementations

                       A.  List of]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[All bonafide students of Cavite State University –Tanza Campus can avail the
                          Campus Shirts.

                       B.  Date and Venue
                          The schedule of online registration via google form for those students that is willing
                          to avail the Campus Shirts will be on November 15, 2021- June 12, 2022. The

                          venue of distribution of Campus Shirts will be at Cavite State University –Tanza
                          Campus.


                       C.  Strategies/Mechanics
                          1.  The students who wants to avail the campus shirts are from CVSU  –Tanza

                              Campus and official enrolled students of First Semester A.Y. 2021-2022 only.


                          2. The students must have registered first using their CvSU Gmail account. The
                          CSG officers will be notify each students who register for their schedule to get their
                          campus shirts.


                          3. The new design of campus shirt is not compulsory and it costs 250.00 pesos.
                          The purpose of the Campus Shirt will be clearly explained to the students and the

                          process of ordering of this item.

                          4. The CSG Treasurer will be the one to receive the payments for the campus shirts

                          from the students who avail this item. The mode of payment will be thru gcash,
                          paymaya, and smart padala. The CSG Treasurer will give an update to the advisers

                          and also she will be the one who will issue a receipt to the students that is signed
                          by the advisers and the csg president.


                          5.  The  distribution  of  Campus  Shirts  will  be  via  toktok  delivery  services.  The
                          delivery services are free for the students of CVSU Tanza Campus.


                          D. Safety and Security Measures
                          1.  The CSG officers will send and post an announcement for the schedule of
                              delivery date of their Campus Shirts. Campus shirts will be sanitized and wrap

                              in a clean eco paper.
                          E.  Budgetary Estimate

                               Campus Shirts                  230.00]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[CSG Income Generated Project for         20.00
                        (Student’s Area Renovation)

                                   Total:                     250.00]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[VI. Contact Person
                   CSG President: Ms. Christine Jewel Gallos – christinejewel.gallos@cvsu.edu.ph/

                   09569921033
                   CSG Treasurer: Ms. Kayla Rose Magpantay- kaylarose.magpantay@cvsu.edu.ph
                   CSG Senior Adviser: Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo- markjoel.sibulo@cvsu.edu.ph

                   CSG Junior Adviser: Mx. Audreyson Borilla – audreyson.borilla@cvsu.edu.ph





               Sample design of the new campus shirts:]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Prepared by:



               MARY ROSE S. MORAÑA

               Secretary, Central Student Government



               Noted by:




               MARK JOEL C. SIBULO
               Senior Adviser, Central Student Government





               AUDREYSON H. BORILLA
               Junior Adviser, Central Student Government






               Recommending Approval:


               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, Office of the Student Affairs and Services





                                                       Approved:


                                               GIL D. RAMOS, MaHisto
                                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979


                                           CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT
               November 12, 2021



               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Campus Administrator
               This Campus

               Dear Prof. Ramos,

               Greeting with Peace Sir! We would like to ask for your permission to allow us to have our Second Project
               Proposal entitled “: “SHOP YA’ LIKE” Virtual Shop Project 2021”. This project aims to build partnership
               and develop entrepreneur skills in this time. This pandemic brought so much struggles to everyone and
               one way to send help to our students is to help them in different ways. The students who needs our
               help this time are the students who are starting their small business at home and they are not quite
               familiar in marketing their products. To help them, we offer our help by creating a Virtual Shop Project
               for them. The benefits that the CSG will get in this project is that every product that we will resell, we
               can get 5.00-10.00 pesos for our fund in our future activities for our students.
               Attached here are the posters and waiver for the students who will register to this partnership project.
               We are hoping for your response regarding this matter.


               Thank you and God bless!

               Respectfully yours,


               CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS
               President, Central Student Government


               Noted by:

               MARK JOEL C. SIBULO                                                                         AUDREYSON H. BORILLA
               Senior Adviser, CSG                                                                                Adviser, CSG



               Recommending Approval:

               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, Office of Student Affairs and Services

                                                        Approved:




                                                 GIL D. RAMOS, MaHisto
                                                     Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979



                                         CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT


                                                ACTIVITY PROPOSAL




               I.  Title of Activity: “SHOP YA’ LIKE” Virtual Shop Project 2021

               II. Proponents: This fundraising activity involves the school community including student

               online sellers, potential customers (students of CvSU Tanza and instructors); committees
               are from the organization officers of the school.


               II.  Rationale:
                       Income- generating activities provide additional benefits that reduce poverty; improve
                   the well-being of communities; and promote empowerment, self-reliance and community

                   development (Mehra, 1997). It should be noted that income-generating activities can take
                   many forms. This is the second IGP of the CSG, this activity is conceived to be an annual
                   project or continuous if possible, this is a virtual shop and is entitled "Shop Y'a Like".  The

                   main purpose of "Shop Y'a like", is to lend a hand to the student who wants to market
                   their handmade products at home. To help the students in this time, proposing to have a
                   virtual shop to help them will be a good opportunity. It is about building partnership and

                   giving hope in different ways in this time.


               III.  Objective/s of Project:
                       This project aims to build different partnership with the students who are sellers in
                   CvSU Tanza community and the CSG Officers will help them to market their handmade

                   products to have more customers. They are the students who are not quite familiar in
                   Facebook business sites and the CSG Officers want to help them by creating a virtual

                   shop  using  Facebook  page  to  market  their  products  more.  The  Central  Student
                   Government Officers will be the one to assist the customers for explaining the details about
                   the products, and the delivery charges for it. The CSG will benefit from this project by

                   getting a 5-10 pesos in every product that the officers will be selling. This will proceed to
                   the IGP fund of the CSG to use for their future activities for the students.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[IV. Mechanics and Implementations
                       A.  List of Participants

                          All bonafide students of Cavite State University –Tanza Campus who are
                          students that selling different handmade products.

                       B.  Date and Venue
                          The schedule of online registration for the students who will partnership in this
                          project will be on November 20, 2021 onwards. The venue will be virtual and on

                          Facebook page. The items will be deliver by toktok services and that is free for the
                          students of CvSU Tanza Campus.


                       C.  Strategies/Mechanics
                          1.  The students who wants to partnership with the CSG Virtual Shop Project are

                              from CVSU –Tanza Campus and official enrolled students of First Semester
                              A.Y. 2021-2022 only.


                          2. The student sellers must have registered first in using their CvSU Gmail account.
                          The students who are willing to build partnership to the CSG Virtual Project will
                          have a contract and waiver for their approval on this project.


                          3. The student sellers will have an Officer that will guide them in the Virtual Shop

                          in purpose of start in marketing his/her products.

                          4. The CSG Treasurer will be the one to receive the payments from the customers

                          and she will provide receipt and documents every day. The CSG Officers and the
                          advisers will also have meetings about the progress of Virtual Shop.


                          5. The customer’s order will be deliver via toktok delivery services. The delivery
                          services are free for the students of CVSU Tanza Campus.


                          D. Safety and Security Measures
                          1.  The CSG officers will send and post an announcement for the schedule of

                              delivery date of Customer’s Order. Handmade Products will be sanitized and
                              wrap in a clean eco paper.
                          E.  Budgetary Estimate

                 The different handmade products will be coming from the students who register for this Virtual

                                                   Partnership Project.

                   ( Income Generate Project for future        The CSG Officers will get 5.00-10.00 pesos

                                 activities)                  in every handmade products they will resell.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[The Sellers Products               The sellers will get their full price in

                                                              every products.





                   VI. Contact Person
                   CSG President: Ms. Christine Jewel Gallos – christinejewel.gallos@cvsu.edu.ph/

                   09569921033
                   CSG Treasurer: Ms. Kayla Rose Magpantay- kaylarose.magpantay@cvsu.edu.ph

                   CSG Business Manager Geanne L. Gacu          -   0920-374-6684
                   CSG Senator Archie A. Carlos                            -    0975-693-0056
                   CSG Senior Adviser: Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo- markjoel.sibulo@cvsu.edu.ph

                     CSG Junior Adviser: Mx. Audreyson Borilla – audreyson.borilla@cvsu.edu.ph]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Prepared by:




               MARY ROSE S. MORAÑA
               Secretary, Central Student Government




               CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS
               President, Central Student Government

               Noted by:


               MARK JOEL C. SIBULO
               Senior Adviser, Central Student Government


               AUDREYSON H. BORILLA
               Junior Adviser, Central Student Government




               Recommending Approval:




               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, Office of Student Affairs and Services




                                                       Approved:



                                               GIL D. RAMOS, MaHisto
                                                  Campus Administratorr]]></page></pages></Search>