<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="13"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.            The institution has an approved printed


                        Student Handbook/Manual containing


                        policies and guidelines on the following

                        aspects of student life:


                        S.1.3.   school fees;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Individual colleges and campuses may purpose and implement other academic policies
               consistent with the general guidelines on academic rules and regulations and approved by the Board of
               Regents.

               7.General Enrollment Guidelines and Procedures. Three months prior to each registration period, the
               university Registrar’s Office shall outline the general enrollment guidelines and procedure or any
               revision thereof and present these to the University Academic Council for approval. No modification of
               the approved guidelines and procedures shall be implemented unless approved by the Office of the Vice
               President for Academic Affairs.

               8. Schedule of Payment. All fees may be paid in cash or installment. The schedule of payment for
               installment is as follows:

                       8.1 50% upon registration


                       8.2 25% two weeks before the midterm examination

                       8.3 25% two weeks before the final examination

               9. Refund of Fees. Student who withdraws their registration from the University after a period of not
               more than three weeks or fifteen days of regular classes shall be refunded in full except the medical and
               dental fees. No refund shall be given to those who withdraw after this period.

               Implementing Guidelines*

               9.1 Nature of Refundable and Non-refundable Fees

                       9.1.1 Student fees that are considered refundable are those that accrue and/or deposited to the
                       trust accounts of the University 164 shall be limited to the following:

                              9.1.1.1 Tuition


                              9.1.1.2 Laboratory Fee

                                     9.1.1.3 Student Resource fund

                                     9.1.1.4 Student Facilities Development Fund

                                     9.1.1.5 Library

                                     9.1.1.6 College Publication


                                     9.1.1.7 Guidance Fee

                                     9.1.1.8 SCUAA/Athletic Fee]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[9.1.2 In addition, miscellaneous fees that are payable and maintained in the deposit accounts of
               the Office of Student Affairs shall also be considered refundable such as student handbook, cultural fee
               and student publication.

               9.1.3 Other fees not specifically provided above shall be deemed non-refundable. These include
               payments made for the following: These include payments made for the following:

                       9.1.3.1 Identification Card


                       9.1.3.2 Medical and Dental

                       9.1.3.3 Registration

                       9.1.3.4 Insurance

                       9.1.3.5 Mutual Aid

               9.1.4 The deposit paid by the student during his initial enrolment in the University is likewise refundable.
               However, a student/group of students may opt to donate the same to the university through the Office
               of Alumni Affairs.

               9.2 Amount Refundable.


                       The amount of refundable fees that can be availed by the students shall correspond to the total
               amount actually paid in cash during enrollment, limited to specific fees stated in Nos. 9.1.1, 9.1.2, and
               9.1.3, respectively.


               9.3 Reason for Refund

                       9.3.1 The reason for which refund of school fees other than deposit are allowed shall include
               and of the following:

                              9.3.1.1 Withdrawal of registration

                              9.3.1.2 Dropping of enrolled subject

                              9.3.1.3 Scholarship

                              9.3.1.4 Overpayment


                       9.3.2 For reason of “overpayment”, refund of the excess amount shall be considered only if the
               total fees for the semester is paid in “cash” or “in full” during registration. If “in installment”, the excess
               amount shall be credited to the students for the next payment period.

                       9.3.3 Withdrawal/refund of deposit shall be allowed only for reasons of graduation from the
               University or transfer to another school as the case maybe.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[9.4 Period of Refund

                       9.4.1 The period of refund within which refund of school fees as those enumerated under 9.1.1,
                       except “deposit”, shall be on a semestral basis and to be made within three (3) weeks or 15
                       school days from the start of regular classes as indicated in the approved school calendar.


                       9.4.2 In the event that the opening or first day of regular classes is postponed to a later date
                       than what is explicitly provided in the school calendar as agreed/approved by the University
                       Administrative Council, the inclusive period mentioned in No. 9.4.1 shall likewise be observed.

                       9.4.3 If the student opts to claim for refund his paid “deposit”, the same shall be allowed within
                       15 working days from the date of graduation of from the date the honorable dismissal is issued
                       by the University Registrar.


               9.5 Procedure for Refund

                       9.5.1 Students who intend to claim or request for refund of school fees paid during enrollment
                       shall accomplish the prescribed application form.

                       9.5.2 The accomplished application form must be filed/received at the Accounting Section
                       within the period stated under No. 9.4.1 above. In no case shall application for refund be
                       entertained after said period.

                       9.5.3 Application for refund must be supported with authenticated photocopy of “Certificate of
                       Registration” and other documants depending upon the reason stated in the application as the
                       following:

               Reason for Refund                                         Supporting Documents

               Withdrawal of Registration                         Certificate of Withdrawal of Registration to be
                                                                  issued by the Registrar Office

               Dropping of Enrolled Subjects                      Dropping From duly signed by the Instructor/s
                                                                  concerned and approved by the Dean of the
                                                                  College that offers the subject

               Scholarship                                        Certification of Scholarship to be issued by the
                                                                  Dean of Students Affairs

               Overpayment                                        Free Assessment From issued by the Registrar’s
                                                                  Office


                                                                  Photocopy (ies) of Official Receipts issued by
                                                                  the Cash & Disbursement Section, duly
                                                                  authenticated by the Records Officer]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Claim for refund of paid deposit must be supported with authenticated copy of graduation
                clearance, if the reason is graduating in the university and/or authenticated copy of” Honorable
                Dismissal”, if the reason is transfer to another school.

                       9.5.4 The Accounting Section shall evaluate the application filed by the students. If found in
                       order, approval shall be made by the Accountant. Otherwise, the application should be returned
                       to the student, through the Office of Student Affairs, with notation as to the reason foe
                       disapproval.

                       9.5.5 Upon approval, the Accounting Section shall prepare the corresponding disbursement
                       voucher for processing. As much as possible, refund of student fees should be in payroll form
                       and to be paid in cash.

                       9.5.6 A student / group of students intending to donate their paid deposit to the university shall
                       execute a “waiver” or “Deed of Donation” specifying the purpose for which the donated amount
                       shall be utilized.

                       9.5.7 Completed/updated records of refund made every semester shall be maintained in the
                       accounting Section for reference and other purposes.

                       9.5.8 Refund of fees paid directly to the Office of Student Affairs shall be governed by a set of
                       separate rules to be prepared by the same office.


               10. Issuing of Grades to Students without Examination Permit*.

                       10.1 Faculty members shall sign the examination permits of the students during the final
                       examination. Students who have no permit shall be allowed to take the examination but the
                       faculty member should see to it that he/she has properly recorded the names of these students.

                       10.2 The names of students without examination permits shall be printed / written below the
                       grading sheets and shall be labeled “GRADES WITHHELD” written in red ink with no credits
                       equivalent under the column “Credit” until such time that students are able to present their
                       examination permits shall the word “no exam permit be replaced stating class cards shall be
                       kept by the concerned faulty member while the students are not yet cleared.

                       10.3 The University Registrar’s Office shall them issue a Certification of Grades upon clearing.
                       The students should present the Certification to the faculty member(s) concerned before issuing
                       their class cards and to their Registration Adviser(s) for posting of grades. The University
                       Registrar’s Office shall also provide the list of students who were cleared from their obligations
                       for consistency in recording.


                       If the Faculty member concerned is no longer connected with the University, he/she shall
                       entrust the distributed class card to the College Registrar.]]></page></pages></Search>