<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="2"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.9.  A tuition fee privilege and other forms of


                    assistance are available for faculty

                    members pursuing advanced (master’s


                    and doctoral) degrees.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         105


                          Attendance to seminars, workshop, and/or conferences of less than a
                   month  that  would  entail  much  expense  on  travel,  board  and  lodging  is
                   normally  discouraged.  Faculty  or  staff  members  desiring  to  attend
                   seminars/workshops or meetings sponsored by private entities or societies
                   should  finance  their  attendance  or  secure  financial  assistance  from  the
                   sponsors.

                   Section 15. Funding

                              a.  During  the  preparation  of  the  budget  proposal,  the  University
                                 Financial  Management  Officer  allocates  funds  for  the  FSDP
                                 taking  into  consideration  the  number  of  faculty  and  staff
                                 required in a given field of specialization for a particular period
                                 of  time  as  recommended  by  the  Dean/Director  (instead  of  the
                                 HRMO).

                              b.  There  are  several  government  and  private  agencies  providing
                                 scholarship grants leading to MS and Ph.D. degrees.

                   Section 16. Privileges

                           A scholar is entitled to the following benefits:

                              a.  actual matriculation/tuition and other fees;

                              b.  maximum        book     allowance       of   Php500.00/subject/term
                                 excluding thesis/special problem;

                              c.  graduation fee;

                              d.  monthly  stipend  of  Php  6,000.00  for  Ph.D.  and  MS,  and
                                 Php1,000.00  for  temporary/permanent  faculty  members  and
                                 staff who are authorized to enroll at the CvSU Graduate School
                                 subject to availability of funds; and

                              e.  thesis  support  of  Php  30,000.00  for  MS  thesis  and  Php
                                 40,000.00  for  Ph.D.  dissertation  in  line  with  the  University
                                 thrust  as  recommended  by  the  RECETS  Council  subject  to
                                 availability of funds.

                          Former  scholars  who  were  unable  to  finish  their  degrees  but  were
                   authorized by higher authorities to pursue graduate studies at the
                   University  Graduate  School  or  at  other  schools  are  not  entitled  to  the
                   benefits stated in items a to d.

                                                                                                           105





                  Lifted from 2009 CvSU Manual of Operations. Volume I]]></page></pages></Search>