<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="9"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.7.            There is a SAS Unit that manages


                        student affairs development and


                        welfare programs.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Manual of Operations]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[2



                              3.8.   develop skills and potentials of student writers
                              3.9.   promote  student  involvement  in  community  development
                                     programs
                              3.10.  provide  an  environment  conducive  to  free  expression  of  one’s
                                     religious orientation in accordance with institutional principles


               Article 3. Organizational Structure of OSAS

                       The OSAS shall be headed by a dean who shall be under the direct supervision
               of the Vice-President for Academic Affairs. The OSAS shall have four service units, the
               Student  Welfare  Services  (SWS)  Unit,  the  Student  Development  Services  (SDS)  Unit,
               the  Institutional  Student  Programs  and  Services  (ISPS)  Unit  and  the  Research,
               Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Student  Services  (RMESS)  Unit.  Each  unit  shall  be
               headed by an over-all coordinator who shall report directly to the OSAS dean.

               Article 4. Student Services and Programs.

                       The  OSAS  shall  deliver  three  basic  academic  support  services  to  students:
               student  welfare  services,  student  development  services  and  those  that  relate  to
               institutional  programs  and  services.  In  addition,  there  shall  be  a  separate  support
               service  for  research,  monitoring  and  evaluation  of  student  services.  These  services
               shall be delivered by the following units:

                       Section 1. The Student Welfare Services Unit

                              The  Student  Welfare  Services  Unit  shall  deliver  student  services  and
                       programs needed to ensure and promote the well-being of students. This shall
                       include information and orientation services, guidance and counselling services,
                       career  and  job  placement  services,  and  student  economic  enterprise
                       development services.
                       Section 2. The Student Development Services Unit


                              The  Student  Development  Services  Unit  shall  provide  services  and
                       programs  designed  for  the  exploration,  enhancement  and  development  of  the
                       students’  full  potential  for  personal  development,  leadership  and  social
                       responsibility  through  various  institutional  student  activities.  The  student
                       development  services  include  student  organization  and  activities,  student
                       government, student discipline, and student publication.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[OSAS Organizational Structure]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Terms of References of





                                           OSAS Unit]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[3









































































                                       Figure 1.  Organizational Structure of OSAS]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                             Tanza Campus

                                                                 Organizational Structure, AY 2022-2023



















































                   Prepared by:                                                                                  Certified Correct:



                   JEFFREY M. DELGADO                                                                            GIL D. RAMOS
                   MIS Officer                                                                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza Campus

 Organizational Structure, AY 2022-2023



















































 Prepared by:                                   Certified Correct:



 JEFFREY M. DELGADO                              GIL D. RAMOS
 MIS Officer                                    Campus Administrator]]></page></pages></Search>