<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="35"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.  The institution has a system of granting of


                    compensation and rewards to its faculty

                    and staff.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Lifted from 2009 CvSU Manual of Operations


                                     Volume II.  pp. 110 - 120











                        Approved per BOR Res. No. 85, s. 2009]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         110

                                                         RULE XIII
                                                     MERIT SYSTEM*

                          Pursuant  to  the  provisions  of  Section  32,  Book  V  of  Administrative
                   Code of 1987 (Executive Order NO. 292), CSC Memorandum Circular No. 3,
                   s.  1979  as  emended  by  CSC  Memorandum  Circular  No.  18,  s.  1988  and
                   CSC  Memorandum  No.  15,  s.  1999,  CSC  Memorandum  Circular  No.  8,  s
                   1999,  Selection  Plan  (MSP)  is  hereby  established  for  the  guidance  of  all
                   concerned.

                   Section 1.  Basic Policies

                       a)  Selection of employees for the appointment in the government service
                          shall  be  open  to  all  qualified  men  and  women  according  to  the
                          principle of merit and fitness.

                              There shall be equal employment opportunity for men and women
                       at all levels of position in Cavite State University, provided they meet the
                       minimum requirements of the position to be filled.

                       b)  The Revised Merit Promotion Plan shall cover positions in the first and
                          second levels and shall also include original appointments and other
                          related personnel actions.

                              There shall be no discrimination in the selection of employees on
                       account of gender, civil status, disability, religion, ethnicity, or political
                       affiliation.

                       c)  When  a  position  in  the  first  and  second  levels  becomes  vacant,
                          applicants for employment who are competent, qualified and possess
                          appropriate civil service eligibility shall be considered for  permanent
                          appointment.

                              In addition to the required qualifications, applicants for the third
                       level position must possess executive and managerial competence.


                   *Revised  June  2003.  Reproduced  from  Cavite  State  University  University
                   Code, 2005. There is no change in the format








                                                                                                           110]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         111

                       d)  Vacant positions marked for filling shall be published in accordance
                          with  Republic  Act  7041  (Publication  Law).  The  published  vacant
                          positions shall also be posted in at least three (3) conspicuous places
                          in the University for at least ten (10) calendar days. Other appropriate
                          modes of publication shall be considered.

                              Filling  the  vacant  positions  in  the  University  shall  be  made  after
                       ten (10) calendar days from their publication.

                              The publication of a particular vacant position shall be valid until
                       filled up but not to extend beyond six (6) months reckoned from the date
                       the vacant position was published.

                       e)  The following positions are exempt from the publication requirement:

                              o  Primarily confidential positions;

                              o  Positions which are policy determining;

                              o  Highly technical positions;

                              o  Other non-career positions;

                              o  Positions  to  be  filled  by  existing  regular  employees  in  the
                                 University in case of reorganization.

                       f)  Personnel  Selection  Board  (PSB)  for  the  first  and  second  level
                          positions  shall  be  established  in  every  campus  of  the  University,
                          preferably with the following composition:

                                As Chairman – Vice President of the unit;

                                Dean/Director;

                                Human Resource Management Officer; and


                                Two representatives of the rank-and-file career employees, one
                                 from  the  first  level  and  one  from  the  second  level,  who  shall
                                 both be chosen by the duly accredited employee association in
                                 Cavite State University.

                                 In  case  there  is  no  accredited  employee  association  in  the
                          University,  the  representatives  shall  be  chosen  at  large  by  the
                          employees through a general assembly. The candidate who garnered

                                                                                                           111]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         112

                          the  second  highest  votes  shall  automatically  be  the  alternate
                          representative. Any other mode of selection may be conducted for the
                          purpose.

                                 The  first  level  representative  shall  participate  during  the
                          screening of candidates for vacancies in the second level. Both rank-
                          and-file representatives shall serve for a period of two (2) years.  For
                          continuity  of  operation,  the  University  accredited  employee
                          association may designate an alternate.

                       g)  The  PSB  members  including  alternate  representatives  for  first  and
                          second level positions shall undergo orientation and workshop on the
                          selection/promotion process and CSC policies on appointments.

                       h)  All  candidates  for  the  appointment  to  the  first  and  second  level
                          positions  shall  be  screened  by  the  PSB  for  third  level  position
                          composed of at least three (3) career executive service officials as may
                          be constituted in the University.


                                 Appointment  to  the  following  positions  shall  no  longer  be
                          screened by the PSB:

                                Substitute  appointment  due  to  their  short  duration  and
                                 emergency nature. However, should the position be filled by the
                                 regular  appointment,  candidates  for  the  position  should  be
                                 screened and passed upon by the PSB;

                                Appointment  of  faculty  members  and  academic  staff  of  state
                                 universities  and  colleges  who  belong  to  the  closed  career
                                 service;

                                Appointment to the entry laborer positions;


                                Appointment  to  personal  and  primarily  confidential  position;
                                 and

                                Renewal  of  temporary  appointment  issued  to  the  incumbent
                                 personnel.

                       i)  The  University  head  shall,  as  far  as  practicable,  ensure  equal
                          opportunity for men and women to be represented in the PSB for all
                          levels.



                                                                                                           112]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         113

                       j)  For vacancies in the first and second levels, all qualified next-in-rank
                          employees shall be automatically considered candidates for promotion
                          to the next higher position.
                       k)  The PSB shall maintain fairness and impartiality in the assessment of
                          candidates for appointment. Towards this end, the PSB may employ
                          the assistance of external or independent resource persons and may
                          initiate innovative schemes in determining the best and most qualified
                          candidate.

                       l)  The  appointing  authority  shall  assess  the  merits  of  the  PSB’s
                          recommendation  for  appointment  and  in  the  exercise  of  sound
                          discretion,  select,  in  so  far  as  practicable,  from  among  the  top  five
                          ranking  applicants  deemed  most  qualified  for  appointment  to  the
                          vacant position.

                       m) The appointing authority may appoint an applicant who is not next-
                          in-rank but possesses superior qualification and competence, and has
                          undergone selection process.

                       n)  The  comparative  competence  and  qualification  of  candidates  for
                          appointment shall be determined on the basis of:

                       1.  Performance

                          o  For  appointment  by  transfer,  the  performance  rating  of  the
                              appointee for the last rating period prior to the effectivity  date of
                              the appointment should be at least very satisfactory.

                          o  For  the  appointment  by  transfer,  the  performance  rating  for  the
                              last  rating  period  immediately  preceding  the  transfer  from  the
                              former office should be at least very satisfactory.

                       2.  Education and Training

                       3.  Experience and Outstanding Accomplishment

                       4.  Psycho-social Attributes and Personality traits

                       5.  Potential

                       o)  An employee  may  be promoted or transferred to a position which is
                          not  more  than  three  (3)  salary,  pay  or  job  grades  higher  than  the
                          employee’s  present  position  except  in  every  meritorious  cases,  such
                          as: if the vacant position is next-in-rank as identified in the System of

                                                                                                           113]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         114

                          ranking Positions (SRP) approved by the head of the University, or the
                          lone or entrance position indicated in the University staffing pattern.

                       p)  An  employee  should  have  rendered  at  least  very  satisfactory  service
                          for  the  last  rating  period  in  the  present  position  before  being
                          considered for promotion.

                       q)  An employee who is on local or foreign scholarship or training grant or
                          maternity leave may be considered for promotion.

                              For this purpose, performance rating to be considered shall be the
                       rating  immediately  prior  to  the  scholarship,  or  training  grant,  or
                       maternity leave.

                              If  promoted,  the  effectivity  date  of  the  promotional  appointment
                       shall be on the assumption to duty.

                       r)  Promotion within six (6) months prior to compulsory retirement shall
                          not be allowed except as otherwise provided by law.

                       s)  A notice announcing the appointment of an employee shall be posted
                          in three conspicuous places in Cavite State University a day after the
                          issuance of the appointment for at least fifteen (15) calendar days.

                       t)  The approved University Merit Promotion Plan shall be used as one of
                          the bases for the expeditious approval of appointment, for attestation
                          and accreditation to take final action on appointments.

                   Section 2.  Objectives. It is the policy of the university to strictly adhere to
                          the  principles  of  merit,  fitness  and  equality.  The  selection  of
                          employees  shall  be  based  on  their  relative  qualifications  and
                          competence to perform the duties and responsibilities of the  position.
                          There  shall  be  no  discrimination  in  the  selection  of  employees  on
                          account of gender, civil status, disability,   religion,         ethnicity,      or
                          political  affiliation.  In  this  pursuit,  the  Cavite  State  University
                          Merit  Selection Plan aims to:

                       a)  Establish  a  system  that  is  characterized  by  strict  observance  of  the
                          merit, fitness and equality principles in the selection of employees for
                          appointment to positions in the career and non-career service in all
                          levels.

                       b)  Create  equal  opportunities  for  employment  to  all  qualified  men  and
                          women to enter the government service and for career advancement in
                          Cavite State University.

                                                                                                           114]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         115

                   Section 3.  Scope.  This  revised  Merit  Selection  Plan  shall  cover  career
                          positions in the first and second level in the University including   its
                   campuses. It may also include non-career positions.

                   Section 4.  Definition of Terms

                       a)  University  –  refers  to  Cavite  State  University  established  under  RA
                          8468.

                       b)  Career  Service  –  position  in  the  civil  service  characterized  by  (1)
                          entrance  based  on  merit  and  fitness  to  be  determined  as  far  as
                          practicable by competitive examination, or based on highly technical
                          qualifications;  (2)  opportunity  for  advancement  to  higher  career
                          positions; and (3) security of tenure.

                       c)  Comparative  at  Par  –  predetermined  reasonable  difference  or  gap
                          between point scores of candidates for appointment established by the
                          PSB.

                       d)  Deep Selection – the process of selecting a candidate for appointment
                          who  is  not  next-in-rank  but  possesses  superior  qualification  and
                          competence.

                       e)  Discrimination  –  is a  situation wherein  a  qualified  applicant  is not
                          included  in  the  selection  line-up  on  account  of  gender,  civil  status,
                          pregnancy, disability, religion, ethnicity, or political affiliation.

                       f)  First Level Positions – shall include clerical, trades and crafts, and
                          custodian  service  which  involve  sub-professional  work  in  a  non-
                          supervisory or supervisory capacity.

                       g)  Hiring  Quota  –  is  the  predetermined  ratio  of  applicants  for
                          appointment  to  ensure  that  one  gender  does  not  fall  short  of  the
                          desired  percentage  of  the  selection  rate  for  the  other  gender  in
                          equivalent positions at every level, provided they meet the minimum
                          requirements of the position.

                       h)  Job  Requirements  –  requisites  not  limited  to  the  qualification
                          standards  of  the  position,  but  may  include  skills,  competencies,
                          potential,  physical  and  psycho-social  attributes  necessary  for  the
                          successful performance of the duties required of the position.






                                                                                                           115]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         116

                       i)  Next-in-Rank Position – refers to a position which by reason of the
                          hierarchical arrangement of positions in the Cavite State University’s
                          System of Ranking Positions (SRP).

                       j)  Merit  and  Fitness  –  refers  to  appropriate  qualifications  and
                          competence/ability  of  the  applicant  to  assume  the  duties  and
                          responsibilities of the position.

                       k)  Non-Career Service – positions expressly declared by law to be in the
                          non-career  service;  or  those  whose  entrance  in  the  service  is
                          characterized by (1) entrance on bases other than those of the usual
                          tests  of  merit  and  fitness  utilized  for  the  career  service;  (2)  tenure
                          which  is  limited  to  the  duration  of  a  particular  project  for  which
                          purpose employment was made.

                       l)  Personnel Action – any action denoting the movement or progress of
                          personnel  in  the  civil  service  such  as  original  appointment,
                          promotion, transfer, reinstatement, reemployment, detail, assignment,
                          secondment and demotion.

                       m) Promotion – is the advancement of an employee from one position to
                          another with an increase in duties and responsibilities as authorized
                          by law and usually accompanied by an increase in salary.


                       n)  Psycho-Social Attributes – refers to the characteristics or trails of a
                          person  which  involve  both  psychological  and  social  aspects.
                          Psychological includes the way he/she perceives things, ideas, belief
                          and understanding and how he/she acts and relates these things to
                          others and in social situations.

                       o)  Qualification  Standards  –  is  a  statement  of  the  minimum
                          qualifications for a position which shall include education, experience,
                          training,  civil  service  eligibility,  and  physical  characteristics  and
                          personality traits required in the performance of the job.

                       p)  Qualified  Next-in-Rank  –  refers  to  an  employee  appointed  on  a
                          permanent  status  to  a  position  next-in-rank  to  the  vacancy  as
                          reflected in the SRP approved by the head of Cavite State University
                          and who meets the requirements for appointment to the next higher
                          position.

                       q)  Second  Level  Positions  –  involve  professional,  technical  and
                          scientific  work  in  a  non-supervisory  or  supervisory  capacity  up  to
                          Division chief level or its equivalent.


                                                                                                           116]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         117

                       r)  Selection  –  is  the  systematic  method  of  determining  the  merit  and
                          fitness of a person on the basis of qualifications and ability to perform
                          the duties and responsibilities of the position.

                       s)  Selection Line-Up – is a listing of qualified and competent applicants
                          for consideration to a vacancy which includes, but not limited to the
                          comparative information of their education, experience, training, civil
                          service  eligibility,  performance  rating  (if  applicable),  relevant  work
                          accomplishments,  physical  characteristics,  psycho-social  attributes,
                          personality traits and potential.

                       t)  Superior  Qualifications  –  shall  mean  outstanding  relevant  work
                          accomplishments,  educational  attainment  and  training  appropriate
                          for  the  position  to  be  filled.  It  shall  include  demonstration  of
                          exceptional job mastery and potential in major areas of responsibility.

                       u)  System  of  Ranking  Positions  –  is  the  hierarchical  arrangement  of
                          positions  from  highest  to  lowest,  which  shall  be  a  guide  in
                          determining which position is next-in-rank, taking into consideration
                          the following:

                          o  Organizational structure;

                          o  Salary grade allocation;

                          o  Classification and functional relationship of positions; and

                          o  Geographical allocation

                   Section 5.  Procedures  in  the  Recruitment/  Selection/  Promotion  of
                          Faculty Members and Staff.

                       a)  Recruitment and Selection of Faculty/Staff

                       1.) Unit  Head/HRMO  makes  a  request  for  authority  from  the  President
                          (thru channels) to hire contractual faculty/staff.

                          Head/HRMO/ODA makes a request for authority from the President
                          to fill up vacant position(s).

                       2.) HRMO announces/publishes the existing vacant position(s) per advice
                          of the Director/Dean.

                          Vacant positions which are not filled within six (6) months should be
                                 re-published.
                                                                                                           117]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         118

                          The following positions are exempt from the publication requirement:

                          2.1 Primary confidential positions;

                          2.2 Positions which are policy-determining;

                          2.3 Highly technical positions;

                          2.4 Other non-career positions; and

                          2.5 Positions to be filled by existing regular employees in the agency
                          in case of reorganization.

                       3.) HRMO  accepts  applicant’s  credentials  and  other  necessary
                          documents.

                       4.) HRMO and Head of Unit Concerned prepare a short list of qualifiers
                          among the applicants.

                       o  An employee  may  be promoted or transferred to a position which is
                           not  more  than  three  (3)  salary  grades  higher  than  the  employee’s
                           present  position  except,  in  very  meritorious  cases,  such  as:  if  the
                           vacant position is next-in-rank as identified in the SRP approved by
                           the head of agency, or the lone or entrance position indicated in the
                           agency staffing pattern.

                       o  An employee who is on local or foreign scholarship or training grant or
                           pregnancy  or  on  maternity  leave  may  be  considered  for  promotion.
                           For this purpose, the performance ratings to be considered shall be
                           the  rating  immediately  prior  to  or  after  the  scholarship  or  training
                           grant  or  maternity  leave.  If  promoted,  the  effectivity  date  of  the
                           promotional  appointment  shall  be  after  the  scholarship  or  training
                           grant or maternity leave.

                       o  Promotion within six (6) months prior to compulsory retirement shall
                           not be allowed except as otherwise provided by law.

                       5.) HRMO evaluates documents submitted by the applicants.

                       6.) HRMO prepares list of qualifiers based on the preliminary evaluation
                          results.

                       7.) HRMO coordinates with the psychological testing company regarding
                          the  time,  date  and  place  of  testing.  The  HRMO  shall  also  notify  the
                          qualifiers in writing as to time, date and place of testing.
                                                                                                           118]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         119

                       8.) HRMO informs the applicants of the test results and advise them to
                          report  to  the  University  Selection  and  Promotion  Board  (USPB)  fro
                          interview.

                          8.1 The criteria for final screening shall be as follows:

                          8.1.1 Psychological Tests

                              Each category is assigned weight. For technical and non-technical
                              positions, the following ratings shall be considered qualified:

                              Moderately Recommended  -  1
                          .
                              Recommended                     -  3

                              Highly Recommended              -  5



                          8.1.2  Interview

                                 The Guide for Interview Assessment which is part of this Merit
                          and Promotion Plan approved by the CSC in 1991 shall be used. The
                          scale below shall be used:

                                 8.31 – 10             -  5

                                 6.62 – 8.30           -  4
                                 4.93 – 6.61           -  3

                                 3.24 – 4.92           -  2

                                 1.55 – 3.23           -  1

                       9.) PSB conducts interview of applicants.

                       10.)      HRMO  prepares  evaluation  results  based  on  test  results  and
                                 interviews.

                       11.)      PSB  recommends  qualified  applicant(s)  to  the  President  for
                                 approval.


                                 The list of recommended candidates should specify the top five
                          ranking  candidates  whose over-all  point  scores  are  comparatively  at
                                                                                                           119]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         120

                          par  based  on  the  comparative  assessment  under  Procedure  8.1
                          hereof.

                       12.)      HRMO, upon the President’s approval, posts the results of the
                                 evaluation  conducted  in  strategic  places  of  the  University
                                 including  satellite  campuses  a  day  after  the  issuance  of  the
                                 appointment for at least 10 days. The date of posting should be
                                 indicated in the notice.

                       13.)      HRMO  advises  applicant(s)  concerned  to  submit  the  required
                                 documents to HRMO.

                       14.)      HRMO prepares appointment papers and facilitates the signing
                                 of the same by higher authorities.

                       15.)      HRMO  submits  appointment  papers  to  CSC  for  appropriate
                                 action  and  conducts  follow-up  to  facilitate  the  approval  of
                                 appointment.

                       16.)      HRMO, upon CSC approval, furnish the concerned person with
                                 the original copy of approved appointment.

                       b)  Promotion of University Personnel for Non-Academic Position

                       1.) HRMO  and  Unit  head  concerned  make  a  request  for  authority  from
                          the President (thru channels) to fill up a natural vacant position.

                                 HRMO announces/publishes the existing vacant position(s).

                                 Vacant  positions  which  are  not  filled  within  six  (6)  months
                          should be re-published.

                          The following positions are exempt from the publication requirement:

                          1.1 Primary confidential positions;

                          1.2 Positions which are policy determining;

                          1.3 Highly technical positions;

                          1.4 Other non-career positions;

                          1.5 Positions to be filled by existing regular employees in the agency in
                              case of reorganization.

                                                                                                           120]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[CvSU Program of Rewards and Incentives for

                       Service Excellence (PRAISE) Guidelines]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[CvSU Approved Workload System]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>