<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="13"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.            The institution has an approved printed


                        Student Handbook/Manual containing


                        policies and guidelines on the following

                        aspects of student life:


                        S.1.7.   examination and grading


                                       system;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Claim for refund of paid deposit must be supported with authenticated copy of graduation
                clearance, if the reason is graduating in the university and/or authenticated copy of” Honorable
                Dismissal”, if the reason is transfer to another school.

                       9.5.4 The Accounting Section shall evaluate the application filed by the students. If found in
                       order, approval shall be made by the Accountant. Otherwise, the application should be returned
                       to the student, through the Office of Student Affairs, with notation as to the reason foe
                       disapproval.

                       9.5.5 Upon approval, the Accounting Section shall prepare the corresponding disbursement
                       voucher for processing. As much as possible, refund of student fees should be in payroll form
                       and to be paid in cash.

                       9.5.6 A student / group of students intending to donate their paid deposit to the university shall
                       execute a “waiver” or “Deed of Donation” specifying the purpose for which the donated amount
                       shall be utilized.

                       9.5.7 Completed/updated records of refund made every semester shall be maintained in the
                       accounting Section for reference and other purposes.

                       9.5.8 Refund of fees paid directly to the Office of Student Affairs shall be governed by a set of
                       separate rules to be prepared by the same office.


               10. Issuing of Grades to Students without Examination Permit*.

                       10.1 Faculty members shall sign the examination permits of the students during the final
                       examination. Students who have no permit shall be allowed to take the examination but the
                       faculty member should see to it that he/she has properly recorded the names of these students.

                       10.2 The names of students without examination permits shall be printed / written below the
                       grading sheets and shall be labeled “GRADES WITHHELD” written in red ink with no credits
                       equivalent under the column “Credit” until such time that students are able to present their
                       examination permits shall the word “no exam permit be replaced stating class cards shall be
                       kept by the concerned faulty member while the students are not yet cleared.

                       10.3 The University Registrar’s Office shall them issue a Certification of Grades upon clearing.
                       The students should present the Certification to the faculty member(s) concerned before issuing
                       their class cards and to their Registration Adviser(s) for posting of grades. The University
                       Registrar’s Office shall also provide the list of students who were cleared from their obligations
                       for consistency in recording.


                       If the Faculty member concerned is no longer connected with the University, he/she shall
                       entrust the distributed class card to the College Registrar.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Concurrent registration of the prerequisites and an advanced subject is not allowed.
                              However, registration of two (2) major courses determined to be co-requisites by the
                              college department concerned may be allowed.

               g) Leave of Absence.  A student who is granted leave of absence (LOA) within 75% of the time devoted
               to a semester/term shall be given a corresponding grade by the instructor concerned for record purpose
               only but this will not be reflected in his Permanent Record. A student granted leave of absence due to
               illness or other justifiable reasons after 75% of the time has elapse shall be given numerical grade
               depending on his/her class performance.

               h) Honorable Dismissal. Honorable dismissal shall be issued by the University Registrar to a student who
               stopped schooling in the University Registrar to a student who stopped schooling n the University
               provided that he was not found guilty or misdemeanor defined under the University Students’ Norm of
               Conduct. If a student left the University for Reasons of misdemeanor and/or academic delinquency, no
               certification of honorable dismissal shall be issued.

               i) Grades and Grading System.  The University shall adopt the numerical grading system of “1.00” to
               “5.00” where “1.00” is the highest and “5.00” is a failing grade. The system of grading is as follows:

                       1.00 ------------------- Excellent (Highest Grade)

                       1.25


                       1.50 ----------------- Very Good

                       1.75

                       2.00 ---------------- Good

                       2.25

                       2.50 ---------------- Satisfactory


                       2.75

                       3.00 --------------- Passing Grade

                       4.00 --------------- Conditional Grade has to be removed by taking a removal examination either to
                       obtain a grade of “3.00” or slide to “5.00”

                       “Inc.” --------------- Grade of Incomplete. The student is passing but has not completed other
                       requirements of the course.

                       5.00 ---------------- The student failed the course. The numerical grade of “5.00” must be written
                       in red ink by the teacher.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Each College shall endeavor to formulate and adopt a uniform method or system of
                       assigning grades to scores and the assignment of weights to different types of test,
                       requirements, laboratory exercises and the like. This should be forwarded to the Vice President
                       for Academic Affairs for his review and corrections before final adoption of the College
                       concerned.

                              College Deans shall include the grading system in their orientation of new teachers and
                       each teacher should explain the grading system to his students at the start of the classes each
                       semester/term.

                              No teacher shall be allowed to adopt a grading system different from the one being
                       implemented by his College where he belongs.

               j) Honor Students. Students who obtain a GPA of “1.75” to “1.51” in a semester shall be listed in the
               Vice President for Academic Affairs’ Honor Students List while those who obtain GPA of “1.50” to “1.00”
               shall be included in the Presidents’ List of Honor Students.

               k) Removal/Completion of Grades of “4.00” and “Inc.” The grades of “4.00” and “Inc.” may be removed
               through any of the following:

                       1. without Paying the Special Examination Fee. A grade of “4.00” may be removed within one
               (1) year by taking the examination during the regular schedule for removal examinations .


                              An “Inc.” grade may be removed by completing the requirements for the subject any
                              time within one (1) year provided that he/she is currently enrolled.

                       3.  Paying the Special Examination Fee. A grade of “4.00” may be removed by a special
                          removal examination administered any time upon payment of special examination fee of
                          P10.00 per unit (may be changed without prior notice) and upon presentation of duly
                          approved permit to the instructor concerned.


               l) Obtaining Permit for special Removal Examination.  A student fills a request form available from the
               University Registrar Office to take special examination addressed to the College Dean concerned stating
               among others, the reason(s) why he was not able to take the examination during the schedule
               examination period; the request should be duly endorsed by his registration adviser and approved by
               the College Dean concerned. The Dean approves the request and the student presents this for payment
               to the University Cashier.

                       Upon payment of fees, the student reports to the Instructor/Professor concerned and presents
               is permit with the receipt of payment to rearrange for the date of the removal examination.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[After a student has taken the removal examination or has completed all the
                       requirements, his final grade shall be recorded by the teacher concerned in the prescribed
                       completion report form accomplished in quadruplicate. The report from shall be forwarded to
                       the Department Chairperson for recommendation, then to the Dean for approval, and finally to
                       the registrar. The report for removal examination should forward to the Registrar within ten (10)
                       days after the examination.

                              The removal examination for Grades of “4.00” obtained in the current semester shall
                       not be scheduled during the regular final examination period of that semester. The final Grade
                       of “4.00” shall be reflected first in the student’s record before this can be removed.

               m) Automatic Grade of “5.00” from Grades of “4.00” and “Inc.” If the a student is unable to remove his
               grade of “4.00” through a removal examination or has not completed the requirements to remove his
               grade of “Inc.” within one year from the last semester/term when these were obtained, these grades
               shall be automatically converted to grades of”5.00” by the University Registrar.

               n) Rules on Scholarship Delinquency. The CvSU shall promulgate suitable and effective guidelines on
               academic deficiencies. Any students whose scholastic performance in subjects enrolled for the semester
               in “Incomplete (Inc.)” or below the passing mark of “3.00’ and/or who dropped the subjects for
               unjustifiable reasons shall be subjected to the rules on academic deficiencies below:

               1. Types of academic deficiency

                       1.1 Warning. Any student who, at the end of the semester is found to have dropped the course
               or obtained an incomplete, conditional or failing grades or a combination thereof in 30% - 50% of the
               enrolled subjects shall fall under this category. The students shall be warned by the Office of the
               College/ University Registrar to improve his/her academic performance.

                              Warning status for two consecutive semesters place the student on the probationary
               status in the succeeding semester.

                       1.2 Probation. Any student who at the end of the semester is found to have dropped the course
               or obtained an incomplete, or grades below “3.00’ or a combination thereof in 51% or more of the
               enrolled subjects shall be placed under probationary status. Academic load of students under this
               category for the succeeding semester shall be limited to 15 units only.

                       If he/she incurs probationary status for two consecutive semesters, he/she shall be classified
               under the disqualification status to 15 units only.

                       Probationary status maybe removed by obtaining a grade of “3.00”in 75% of the enrolled
               subjects.


                       1.3 Disqualification. Any student who, at the end of the semester failed in 75% or more of the
               enrolled subjects shall be rendered ineligible to enroll for one semester. He/she shall be allowed to carry
               an academic load of not more than 15 units when he/she enrolls in the succeeding semester.]]></page></pages></Search>