<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="34"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.5.            The institution supports the


                        researchers in all of the following


                        activities:

                        I.5.5.  patenting of research outputs.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[NATIONAL LIBRARY OF THE PHILIPPINES
                                           T.M. Kalaw Street, Ermita, Manila, 1000 Philippines

              __(Published)                                                                   ___________________
                 __(Unpublished)                                                               FILING DATE
                                                                                         PAPER NO. ___________


              The Director, The National Library of the Philippines                                     Date
              _______________

                     SIR: I have the honor to apply for the copyright registration of the (a) unpublished (b) Published work
              named herein of which Two (2) complete copies  are herewith deposited compliance with the provisions of
              REPUBLIC ACT 8293. The amount of P200.00 for the registration fee and thirty pesos worth of documentary
              stamp to be affixed to the certificate and application form are also enclosed. The data required by the rules and
              regulations of that office are the following:

              1. Name and address of copyright owner: __CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY___
                                                                                                             (Claimants full legal name)
                    Tanza Campus, Cavite
              ______________________________________________________________________________________________________________________
              _
                                                                                                              (Street number, municipality and province)
              2. Name of author:
              3. Country of which the author is a citizen:
                        Philippines
              ______________________________________________
                                                                                                                                                                              (Country)
              4.  If  alien  author,  state  Alien  Certificate  No.  and  where  domiciled  in  the  Philippines:


              ______________________________________________________________________________
              5. Title of the Work:
                                 (Title as it appears on the front part of the title page of the work followed by the edition number, if any)

              ______________________________________________________________________________________________________________________
              6. Class to which the work belongs:
              7. If copyright is claimed upon a new matter in a reissued work, state new matter specifically:
              _____________________________________________________________________________
                            (Additional chapters by numbers followed by inclusive pages in parenthesis; other more or less short but materials alterations)

              8. (d) Completed (e) Printed or Reproduced in copies on the ____day of June, 2020
                                                                            th
                                                                         30
                                          Indang, Cavite
                                                                     Cavite State University
                                                    at __________________by ______________________________________
                                                               (Municipality, Province)                       (Person or Establishment making the printing or reproduction in copies)


              9. First published or sold to the public in the Philippines on the _____day of ______________,


              (Day the work was placed on sale, sold or publicly distributed)
                ________________________________________________________   by  _______________________________________________________
                                             (Municipality, Province)                                                                                              (Person or Establishment)

              10.  Send  certificate  of  registration  to:  Innovations  and  Technology  Support  Office,  CvSU  Bancod

              Indang Cavite , 4122                                                                                         (Name and address)
              11. Unit price if reproduced in copies for sale: P_____________
                                                                                                                         Very Respectfully,

                                                                                                                                 TEDDY F. TEPORA

                                                                                                                               (Signature of Applicant)
              =====================================================================
              Deposit    received   on________________________                     Certificate   issued   on
              ______________________
              Application received on_____________________     Signed by __________________________
              Affidavit received on_______________________     Certificate mailed by___________________
              Fee received P_______O.R. _________________     Certificate received by _________________
                                                                                                                                                                     (Signature of receiver)


              _________________________________________________________________________________________________________
                  ___NLP-034                             Application for Copyright Registration      1 of 3
                                                           Rev. 1]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[NATIONAL LIBRARY OF THE PHILIPPINES
                                           T.M. Kalaw Street, Ermita, Manila, 1000 Philippines

              Date of Registration _______________________
              XXc___________________________________
              =====================================================================
              ===
                             (Please Read Instructions Carefully Before Filling Blanks)
                 Of the lines marked (a) to (e) use the ones which apply and cross out the lines not used
              **  The word author includes a translator, a composer, painter, sculptor or other artists, or a photographer or a producer of a cinematographic film
              or publisher of a periodical, or an editor of work without known authors.
              + In case of periodicals, the title should include the volume and number as well as the date of each issue separately registered e.g. Philippine
              Magazine Vol. XXX No. 2, July 1933.
              ++ See  class designations at the bottom  of the reverse  or back side hereof. A representative may sign the application under the name  of the
              claimant Accomplish this form in duplicate.
                                    FORM SHOULD BE FILLED UP LEGIBLY
                               (THIS FORM IS NOT FOR SALE AND MAYBE REPRODUCED)

                                                     AFFIDAVIT
                     (IMPORTANT- This affidavit must be executed by individual (an official of a corporation or firm may act) and must be under
              the seal of an officer authorized to administer oaths within the Philippines. In case of published works, the execution must be subsequent
              to the date of publication. The affiant must fill in the required statements to accord with the fact concerning the work named, and draw pen
              through statements not intended to be made.)

              REPUBLIC OF THE PHILIPPINES
              Municipality of  INDANG_______________
              Province or City of CAVITE____    S.S.                                   CAVITE


                              TEDDY F. TEPORA
                     I _________________________________ being duly sworn, depose do solemnly affirm and say:
              That I am the (a) person claiming copyright   (b) printer who printed   (c) duly authorized agent or representative
              residing in the Philippines of the claimant of copyright in the Work named herein;
                                                                                                CAVITE
              That (d) I am a resident of the municipality of ____________________________Province of __________________
                                                             INDANG
                                                                                   Tanza, Cavite
              and       (e) __________________________________________ of _______________________ claim/s

                                          (name of claimant if other than affiant)                                                       (municipality, province)
              ownership of copyright in the said work (f) as (g) by assignment (h) by inheritance from the author hereof, that




              said work is ( i) original, not copied from any work whether published or unpublished (j) a work falling  under Sec.
              172 of R.A. 8293 of which consent of the copyright owner has been  secured of  which 2 complete copies have
              been deposited, is entitled _______________________________________________________________
                                                                                      (Title  as it appears on the front part or title page (if book)



              _____________________________________________________________________________________________________________________
                                                                           (of the work, edition number if any; author`s name if he is different from claimant)

              and have been (k) completed (l) printed or reproduced in copies at _____Indang, Cavite_____________
                                                                                                                                                         (Municipality, Province)

              by ______________________________________, the work or its printing or reproduction having been

              completed on the 30th day of ___June, 2020, and the said work was first published or sold to the public in

              the    Philippines   on     the    _____      day   of                                ________,
                                                                        _____N/A____________,
                                                                        (same date given in the application)
              at_________________N/A____________ by _____________N/A_________________________
                                (Municipality; Province)                                                                                          (Name of person in the application)

                                                                                TEDDY F. TEPORA
                                                                                                                                                    ____________________________________________
                                                                                                                 (Signature of person making affidavit)

                     Subscribed and sworn to before me this _________ day of ________________, _________. The deponent in

              the  foregoing  affidavit  exhibited  to  me  his  Identification  Passport          EC78  4167  Issued  at  the  Municipality  of


              ___________DFA,  Pasay  ,  Province  of  ___________________  Philippines  ,  on  ________________,
                                                                               June 1
                                                    Pasay City
              _____2016____.

                    NOTARIAL
                       P15.00
                    Documentary

                        Stamp
              _________________________________________________________________________________________________________
                        SEAL
                  ___NLP-034                             Application for Copyright Registration      2 of 3

                                                           Rev. 1]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[NATIONAL LIBRARY OF THE PHILIPPINES
                                           T.M. Kalaw Street, Ermita, Manila, 1000 Philippines


                                                                         ___________________________________
                                                                                                                                   Notary Public
                                                                                                           My commission expires on ___________

              Doc. No. __________
              Page No. __________
              Book No. _________
              Series of __________

                            1.   Of the lines number (a) to (1) use the ones which apply and cross out lines not used.
                            2.   See footnote** on the reverse back side hereof.
                            3.   In case of periodicals the title includes the volume and number as well as the date of which issue separately registered.
                                For example: Philippine Magazine, Vol. XXX, No. 2 July 1933.
                            4.   In case of manuscripts or unpublished works, data regarding publication are not required and the corresponding blank
                                spaces should be crossed out.
                             CLASS DESIGNATIONS OF COPYRIGHTABLE WORKS UNDER R. A. 8293
                     (a) Books, Pamphlets, articles and other writings; (b) Periodicals and newspaper; (c) Lectures, sermons, addresses, dissertations for oral
              delivery, whether or not reduced in writing or other material form; (d) Letters; (e) Dramatic or dramatico-musical compositions; choreographic
              works or entertainment in dumb shows; (f) Musical compositions with or without words; (g) Works of drawing, painting, architecture, sculpture,
              engraving,  lithography  or  other  works  of  arts,  model  or  design  for  works  of  arts;  (h)  Original  ornamental  designs,  or  models  for  articles  of
              manufacture, whether or not registrable as an industrial designs and other works of applied art; (I) Illustrations maps, plans, sketches, charts and
              three-dimensional  works  relative  to  geography,  topography,  architecture  or  science;  (j)  drawings  or  plastic  works  of  a  scientific  or  technical
              character, (k) Photographic works including works produced  by a process analogous to photography, lantern slide; (l) Audiovisual works and
              cinematographic works produced by a process analogous to  cinematography  or any process  for making audio-visual recordings; (m) Pictorial
              illustrations and advertisements; (n) Computer  Programs; (o) Other literary; scholarly, scientific and artistic works; (P) Sound recordings,  and  (q)
              Broadcast recordings



















































              _________________________________________________________________________________________________________
                  ___NLP-034                             Application for Copyright Registration      3 of 3
                                                           Rev. 1]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                    CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                             DON SEVERINO DELAS ALAS CAMPUS
                                                                        Indang, Cavite
                                                                       (046) 4150-010
                                                                       www.cvsu.edu.phi





                                   AFFIDAVIT ON COPYRIGHT OWNERSHIP

                   REPUBLIC OF THE PHILIPPINES
                   Municipality of Indang
                   Province of Cavite

                          The undersigned, being duly sworn, do solemnly affirm and say:

                       1.  That he/she the creators/authors of the work
                                                                        _ _ _ __ __ _ __ __ _ __ _
                          ________________                            ,   the subject of the application for
                          copyright;

                       2.  That they presented and submitted the said work to the Cavite State University
                          as their output;

                       3.  That  upon  submission  of  the  work  to  the  Cavite  State  University,  they
                          acknowledge  the  University  as  COPYRIGHT  OWNER  of  the  above-mentioned
                          work; and

                       4.  That as copyright owner, CvSU has the right to reproduce, publish and publicly
                          distribute copies of the said work, in whatever form, electronic or otherwise for
                          instruction  purposes,  and  for  any  other  purposes  that  promote  access  to  and
                          utilization of intellectual property of the University; provided that the names of the
                          authors  shall  be  acknowledged/cited  in  all  dissemination  and  utilization  of  the
                          work.

                   In witness whereof, the authors/creators hereunto set their signature on this ___
                                                                              s.

                                                         i
                                                         n
                                                 _
                                                  _
                                                _
                                             a
                                              r
                                                        ,

                                                      _
                                                    _
                                                     _
                                                           M

                                                                  ,
                                                                       i
                                                                    Ph
                                                                i
                                                               n
                                                                 a
                                                                 l
                                                                            n
                                                                           i
                                                             a
                                                                             e
                                                                        i
                                                                       l
                                                                          p
                                                                        p
                                 _
                                _
                                    _
                                  _
                              _
                          _
                   day of ___________, year ______, in Manila, Philippines.
                             _
                            _

                                         ,
                                           e
                                          y
                                      _
                                        _
                                     _

                   Authors’/Creators’ Name                Signature:                Identification No.


                   ________________                     ________________             _________________



                   ________________                    ________________             _________________


                   Subscribed  and  sworn  to  or  affirmed  before  me  this  _____  day  of
                   _____________. 2020.
                                                                             NOTARY PUBLIC
                   Doc. No.____________
                   Page No.____________
                   Book No.___________
                   Series of ___________]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>