<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="133"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.5.            The institution supports the


                        researchers in all of the following


                        activities:

                        I.5.2.  paper presentations, journal


                                       publication, classroom lectures,


                                       and other similar activities;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           266
                          Research  Center  to  keep  track  of  ongoing  projects  for  monitoring
                          and evaluation as well as workload compensation purposes.

                              The technical reports are submitted by the project proponent to
                          the Monitoring and Evaluation Unit of the Research Center.   The
                          numbers of copies are stated below:

                                Copies  of  Progress  Report  to  be  forwarded  to  the  funding
                                 agency
                                Copies of the Annual Report to be used in annual agency in-
                                 house review
                                Copies  of  the  Terminal  Report  to  be  submitted  two  months
                                 after the termination or completion of the project.


                          Annual Local Agency In-House Review

                                 One major activity to facilitate the monitoring and evaluation
                          purposes  is  the  holding  of  the  Annual  Local  Agency  In-house
                          Review.  It involves the evaluation of all researches that are either
                          completed  or  ongoing  during  the  particular  year  under  review.
                          During these reviews, researchers present the progress/highlights
                          of  their  researches.    The  panel  of  reviewers  consists  of  members
                          from  STARRDEC,  SUC’s  and  PCARRD.    The  guidelines  for  the
                          conduct of Annual Local Agency In-House Review of the Research
                          Center are based from the implementing guidelines set by PCARRD
                          for all SUC’s conducting the review.

                          The  major  criteria  that  shall  be  used  in  evaluation  the  ongoing
                                 projects are:


                                   Attainment of the objectives.
                                   Adherence to the approved methodology.
                                   Adherence to the approved budget.
                                   Accomplishments,          including      status    of    technology
                                     generated/verified.
                                   Actions taken in response to previous year’s comments.


                                 1.      Scope  and  Scheme  of  Agency  In-House  Reviews
                          (AIHR’s)

                                       a.   Completed, ongoing and new (those initiated within
                                            the  year)  R&D  projects  (i.e.  TG,  TA,  and  extension
                                            projects)  regardless  of  sources  of  funds  will  be
                                            presented.    All  completed  researches  of  faculty
                                            scholars  and  theses/dissertations  funded  by  the
                                            University shall likewise be reported during the in-
                                            house reviews.




                                                                                                      266]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           267
                                       b.   Sessions  shall  be  conducted  by  sector  (i.e.,  crops,
                                            environment,  livestock,  farm  resources,  forestry,
                                            and socio-economics) or integrated, if feasible.


                                       c.   Reports  shall  be  by  program/project/study  basis,
                                            but  related  projects  shall  be  reported  in  the  same
                                            session.

                                       d.   Agriculture       and     natural      resources       (ANR)
                                            programs/projects/studies  should  be  presented
                                            separately.

                                 2.      Objectives


                                       a.        To  evaluate  completed  and  ongoing  R&D  projects
                                            particularly  with  regards  to  the  attainment  of
                                            objectives  and  adherence  to  the approved  program
                                            of activities.

                                       b.    To  review  initial  activities  of  new  projects  giving
                                            emphasis  on  the  research  methods/procedures  to
                                            check/verify if the objectives were attained.

                                       c.   To     identify    problems       met     during      project
                                            implementation and recommend specific courses of
                                            action, i.e. continuation, extension, modification of
                                            planned  activities  and  methodology,  suspension,
                                            termination,      etc.,    in    accordance      with     the
                                            recommendation of the evaluation panel.


                                       d.  To  identify  technologies  generated  requiring  field
                                            testing, verification and piloting.

                                       e.   To  identify      research  results/technologies  for
                                            presentation  during  the  Regional  Symposium  on
                                            R&D       Highlights       (RSRDH),       and      potential
                                            technologies for technology assessment.


                                       f.   To identify significant results/information for policy
                                            formulation  and  development  planning  of  the
                                            University, Consortium and PCARRD.


                                       g.    To classify status of technologies.

                                       h.    To identify new researchable areas.








                                                                                                      267]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           268
                                 3.      Schedule

                                         a.     The reviews shall be conducted between July to
                                                September  to  select  papers  in  time  for  the
                                                regional reviews.


                                 4.      Evaluation Panel

                                         The  University  shall  notify  the  STARRDEC  and
                                 PCARRD regarding the upcoming agency in-house review to
                                 identify  external  evaluators  of  the  projects.  The  following
                                 shall comprise the panel of evaluators:


                                         a.     Experts  within  and  nearby  regions  shall  be
                                                tapped as evaluators.

                                         b.     Members  of  the  National/regional  Commodity
                                                R&D Teams/Experts’ Pool.

                                         c.     Farmer cooperators (Magsasaka Siyentista).


                                         d.     PCARRD,  DA-BAR  and  DENR-ERDB  senior
                                                technical staff

                                         e.     Participants:  Researchers, extensions


                                         f.     Duties  and  Responsibilities  Agency  Conducting
                                                the In-House Review


                                                a)    Facilitate  the  smooth  conduct  of  the  review
                              by:

                                                   o  Creating  committees  to  work  on  the
                                                       different aspects of the review;
                                                   o  Making       arrangements        for    necessary
                                                       logistics;
                                                   o  Providing  the  researchers  about  the
                                                       mechanics of the paper presentation;
                                                   o  Providing the list of programs/projects for
                                                       review  to  the  consortium  at  least  one
                                                       month before the review schedule. All R&D
                                                       programs/projects implemented regardless
                                                       of  funding  source  shall  be  included  for
                                                       evaluation;
                                                   o  Inviting      evaluators      to     assist     the
                                                       consortium evaluators not later one month
                                                       before the review schedule;




                                                                                                      268]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           269
                                                   o  Notifying  the  concerned  researchers  at
                                                       least  two  months  before  the  review
                                                       schedule;
                                                   o  Inviting Budget/Finance Officer and COA;
                                                   o  Notifying  the  concerned  researchers  at
                                                       least  two  months  before  the  review
                                                       schedule;
                                                   o  Reproducing         the      necessary       forms
                                                       (NARRDS  Form  No.  1/No.2)  for  use  of
                                                       researchers  and  for  preparing  outputs  of
                                                       the  review  (NARRDS  Form  Nos.  5  and  6).
                                                       (Appendix 4, 5, 6 and 7 respectively);
                                                   o  Accomplishing NARRDS Form No. 4 (Items
                                                       A-I)    for   distribution      to    evaluators;
                                                       (Appendix 8)
                                                   o  Convening  the  evaluation  panel  and
                                                       secretariat before the review to discuss the
                                                       evaluation  policies/guidelines,  and  after
                                                       the     review     to    discuss      the    final
                                                       action/recommendation  (e.g.  to  continue,
                                                       terminate,  etc.)/  synthesize  the  output;
                                                       and
                                                   o  Preparing/consolidating  the  output  for
                                                       submission to the consortium (AIHR Form
                                                       Nos.  1  and  2)  (Appendix  9  and  10,
                                                       respectively);

                                               b.   Ensures the utility of the review by:


                                                   o  Informing the concerned researchers of the
                                                       comments  and  recommendations  to  be
                                                       complied  within  their  respective  projects;
                                                       and
                                                   o  Monitoring  compliance  of  the  researchers
                                                       to the evaluators’ recommendations.

                              7. Expected Outputs


                                   Specific  courses  of  action  for  each  project,  i.e.  for
                                     continuation,  extension,  expansion,  modification  of  plan
                                     of  activities  and  methodology,  suspension,  termination,
                                     etc.;
                                   Technologies  requiring  field  testing,  verification  and
                                     piloting;
                                   Best paper and posters;
                                   Papers for possible presentation during the RSRDH;
                                   Potential technologies and information for dissemination;
                                   Significant research  results/information for the PCARRD
                                     publication “R&D Highlights”;
                                                                                                      269]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           270
                                   New researchable areas;
                                   Suggested solutions/recommendation to problems met.

                                8.   Research Reports


                          Research reports are to be submitted on a quarterly basis.

                           Awards and Recognition


                                 Awards,  in  line  with  the  University  Merit  System,  are
                          available  for  Faculty  Researchers  and  other  Research  personnel.
                          These are:


                                 a. Monetary Award

                                         Cash award in accordance with scales decided by the
                                 University  may  be  granted  for  accomplishments  that  result
                                 in  monetary  savings  and  tangible  benefits.  The  amount  of
                                 cash award shall be determined on the basis of its estimated
                                 or total value or benefits and in accordance with the scales
                                 established by the University.


                   Undergraduate and Graduate Thesis Support

                          Objective:


                                 To  strengthen  students’  research  capabilities  by  providing
                          Graduate and undergraduate theses financial assistance


                          Criteria for Application


                                 Graduate and undergraduate students of the university with
                          approved thesis/dissertation outline can apply for thesis support.


                          Guidelines for Availment

                                 The  thesis  should  be  in  line  with  the  existing  research
                          thrusts/ priorities of R and E.


                                 In  case  the  thesis  is  not  in  line  with  the  existing  research
                          thrusts of R and E, the following criteria will be considered:


                                Importance  to  national  development  considering  its  social,
                                 economic and environmental impact
                                Originality (done by the students themselves)
                                Urgency in terms of the college’ needs.






                                                                                                      270]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           271
                          Faculty  and  Students  Research  Capability  Enhancement
                          Program (FSRCEP)

                                 A  program  designed  to  support  the  conduct  of  research
                          undergone  by  faculty  members  of  the  University  and  senior
                          students presently enrolled in the University.

                                 Students  can  be  junior  researchers  and  can  be  involved  as
                          part  of  an  approved  R  and  E  programs/  projects.  A  copy  of  the
                          approved proposal must be on file with the in Charge of the Faculty
                          and  Students  Research  Capability  Enhancement  Program
                          (FSRCEP)  Financial  or  material  support  is  granted  if  funds  are
                          available.


                                 a.1 Requirements:

                                       Proposed  research  should  be  in  conformity  with  the
                                         research thrusts/agenda of the University;
                                       Properly endorsed by the College Deans;
                                       Should  be  included  in  the  list  of  research  titles
                                         approved by their respective College;
                                       In  accordance  with  the  prescribed  format  of  the
                                         University  and  the  DA-BAR  for  students  and  faculty,
                                         respectively;
                                       Defined budgetary requirement of the proposed study;


                                     Maximum  allowable  fund  to  be  allocated  to  approved
                                 programs/      projects/studies  would  be  P25,000.00  for
                                 studies  having  budgetary  requirements  of  P50,000.00.  On
                                 the  other  hand,  50%  of  the  total  cost  shall  be  allocated  to
                                 studies with budgetary requirements lower than P50,000.00

                              a.2. Publication


                                       Research  results  shall  be  submitted  to  the  CvSU
                                         Research  Journal’s  Editorial  Committee  as  technical
                                         paper for publication.
                                       Students’  thesis  shall  have  the  student  as  the  main
                                         author


                             a.3. Intellectual Property Rights

                                   Patented product shall be treated as a joint ownership of
                                     the author and the University.
                                   If  commercialized,  student  and  the  faculty  adviser  are
                                     eligible  to  acquire  an  equal  share  from  70%  of  the
                                     royalties and the remaining 30% to the University.




                                                                                                      271]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           272
                             a.4.  Workload Credit


                                   A  faculty  researcher  who  exceeds  the  minimum
                                     requirement  for  teaching  shall  be  entitled  to  a  research
                                     overload pay with the corresponding credit points earned
                                     for the semester.

                          The  College  Research,  Development  and  Extension  (RDE)
                   Coordinator in consultation with the department chairpersons selects the
                   entries for their corresponding colleges.

                              The thesis proposals are then submitted to the Research Center
                          on or before the following schedules:


                            September  to  November  –  Theses  to  be  conducted  during  the
                              second semester
                            June  to  August  -  Theses  to  be  conducted  during  the      first
                              semester
                            Submitted  proposals  are  then  referred  to  minimum  of  3
                              members of the RDE Council.
                            The members of the RDE Council finally review and recommend
                              to the University President, approval of the theses to be funded.
                            With  an  initial  budget  of  Php  1M  in  one  year,  at  least  20  per
                              cent shall be allocated for graduate theses and 80 per cent shall
                              be allocated for undergraduate theses.
                            A total of 5 graduate students and 34 undergraduate students
                              which are on the stage of conducting their theses could avail of
                              the financial support. In case where not all the budget allotted
                              to graduate students was awarded, the remaining balance shall
                              be allocated to undergraduate theses.
                            Each undergraduate student is entitled to a theses support in
                              the form of supplies and materials with a minimum amount of
                              Php  25,000.00.  Graduate  students  will  be  granted  a  thesis
                              support with a minimum amount of Php 30,000.00.
                            Upon  approval,  a  notarized  memorandum  of  agreement  duly
                              signed  by  the  student,  thesis  adviser,  Dean  of  the  college
                              concerned,  Director  for  research,  VP  for  Academic  Affairs  and
                              VP for RDE.
                            After  the  completion  of  the  research,  students  are  required  to
                              submit  two  copies  of  the  manuscript  to  the  Research  Center,
                              and together with the Adviser/ Senior Researcher, present the
                              results of the study during the Annual Agency In House Review,
                              and  publish  them  in  refutable  and  /or  refereed  journal.
                              Likewise, the student must submit to the RDE, one copy of the
                              financial  report  including  the  Official  Receipts  of  materials
                              purchased.






                                                                                                      272]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           273




































































                     Figure 3: Flowchart for the implementation of Faculty and   Students
                               Research Capability Enhancement Program (FSRCEP)














                                                                                                      273]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           274
                                         MEMORANDUM OF AGREEMENT

                          KNOW ALL MEN BY THESE PRESENTS:


                                 This  MEMORANDUM  OF  AGREEMENT  made  and  executed
                          by  and  between  CAVITE  STATE  UNIVERSITY,  a  government
                          educational  institution  created  and  existing  pursuant  to  the
                          provisions  of  R.  A.  8468,  with  principal  office  at  its  represented
                          herein by its president, DR. DIVINIA C. CHAVEZ, herein referred to
                          as  the  UNIVERSITY  and  ____________________________________,  of
                          legal      age,       single      ,      and       residing                  at
                          __________________________________,hereafter  referred  to  as  the
                          FACULTY          AND       STUDENTS           RESEARCH           CAPABILITY
                          ENHANCEMENT PROGRAM GRANTEE ,

                                                       W I T N E S S E T H


                                 WHEREAS,  the  GRANTEE    is  a  graduate/undergraduate
                          student  of  the  CAVITE  STATE  UNIVERSITY  with  an  approved
                          thesis/dissertation  outline,  has  applied  for  and  found  to  be
                          qualified  as  grantee  of  the  Faculty  and  Students  Research
                          Capability  Enhancement  Program  (FSRCEP)  this  First/Second
                          Semester, 200__-20___.

                                 WHEREAS,  the  thesis  outline  of  the  GRANTEE  has  been
                          selected by the College RDE  Coordinator in consultation with the
                          department  chairpersons,  and  referred  to  the  members  of  the
                          RECETS Council who then recommend to the university president
                          for its approval.


                                 NOW, THEREFORE, for and in consideration of the foregoing
                          premises, the Parties hereby agree as follows:

                          1.  In  consideration  for  the  thesis/dissertation  support  in  the
                          amount of Php________________ granted to _________________ by the
                          UNIVERSITY,    the  GRANTEE  hereby  binds  herself  to  comply
                          strictly with the terms and conditions thereof.


                          2. After the completion of the research, that is within 5 months to a
                          maximum of one year, two copies of the final manuscript must be
                          submitted  to  the  Research  Center;  results  of  the  study  must  be
                          presented  during  the  Annual  Agency  In-House  Review,  and
                          research  results  must  be  presented  during  the  Agency  In-House
                          Review  and  published  in  refutable  and  or  refereed  journal.    The
                          GRANTEE  must  submit  two  copies  of  the  manuscript  to  the
                          Research Center and one copy of the financial report including the
                          Official Receipt of materials purchased.




                                                                                                      274]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           275
                          3. The PARTIES agree that the obligations of the GRANTEE, under
                          this contract are binding, and that in any event of any violation by
                          the  GRANTEE,  the  UNIVERSITY  may  require  the  GRANTEE’S
                          performance at the UNIVERSITY’s discretion.


                          4. The PARTIES, likewise agree that any and all actions to enforce
                          the provisions of this MOA will be filed with the court of competent
                          jurisdiction within the province of Cavite.


                                 IN  WITNESS  WHEREOF,  the  PARTIES  have  signed  this
                          Contract  at  the  Municipality  of  Indang,  Province  of  Cavite,  this
                          ______ day of _______________, 20___.


                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY                    ______________________________

                                                                                    Grantee


                          By:

                          DIVINIA C. CHAVEZ


                                President

                          _______________________                    ________________________


                                    Adviser                              RDE Coordinator

                                                  ___________________________


                                                     Dean


                   Signed in the presence of:



                   ____________________________               ___________________________


                           VP-RECETS                          VP-Academic Affairs
















                                                                                                      275]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           276
                          Search for Best Graduate and Undergraduate Theses

                          Objectives:


                                 The main objective of the search is to encourage students to
                          develop outstanding thesis/dissertation by giving incentive to their
                          work.

                          Specifically, it aims to:


                                 Select  one  outstanding  thesis  each  for  science  and  non-
                          science  courses  in  the  undergraduate  level  and  one  each  for  MS
                          and PhD; and


                                 Provide  certificate  of  recognition  and  cash  awards  to
                          students with outstanding thesis/dissertation.


                          Mechanics of Implementation

                          Who May Join?


                                 Theses  of  all  graduating  undergraduate  /graduate  students
                          can  be  considered  for  the  best  thesis  award.    These  include  all
                          science  and  non-science  undergraduate  theses/dissertations
                          theses  and  all  MS  theses  and  PhD  dissertations.  However,  those
                          which are part of any ongoing government funded researches are
                          not eligible in the search.

                          Selection is done sequentially in three levels, namely:


                          Department Level

                                 Every  department  screens  students’  theses  /dissertations
                          during the final defense. For the undergraduate level, the selection
                          committee,  composed  of  the  chairman  and  the  members  of  the
                          faculty, selects an outstanding thesis for the department.


                                 For  the  graduate  level,  members  of  the  advisory  committee
                          recommend  potential  candidates  to  the  department  where  the
                          student  belongs.  The  selection  committee  composed  of  the
                          chairman  and  the  faculty  members  then  selects  one  outstanding
                          thesis/dissertation for the department.


                                 Theses selected for each department in both undergraduate
                          and  graduate  levels  are  submitted  to  the  head  of  the  college
                          screening  committee  and  Office  of  the  Graduate  School,
                          respectively.



                                                                                                      276]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           277
                          College/Graduate Level

                                 From  all  nominees  in  each  department,  the  selection
                          committee  composed  of  the  dean,  department  chairpersons  and
                          college     research       coordinator       selects     one      outstanding
                          undergraduate thesis for the college.

                                 For the graduate level, the selection committee, composed of
                          the  dean,  secretary  and  chairpersons,  selects  the  best  MS  thesis
                          and PhD dissertation for each graduate degree program.

                          Final Selection Level


                                 The best thesis for each college and graduate programs are
                          then submitted to the director for research for final screening.

                                 All nominees from each college are evaluated by a screening
                          committee composed of the RDE Council and the college research
                          coordinators.

                          Requirements for Participation


                                 The  following  are  submitted  to  the  chairman  of  the  final
                          screening committee not later than three working days before the
                          meeting  of  the  University  Academic  Council  to  approve  the
                          candidates for graduation:

                                 One  copy  of  the  final  manuscript,  and  five  copies  of  the
                          abstract and the summary, conclusions and recommendation


                          Criteria for Selection

                                 The  student  theses  shall  be  divided  into  six  divisions,
                          namely:  Agricultural  Bio  Resources,  Humanities  and  Social
                          Sciences,  Biomedical  and  Life  Sciences,  Engineering  and
                          Nanotechnology, and secondary school Divisions























                                                                                                      277]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           278
                   The following are the criteria for the selection of the best thesis award.

                                                                                                      Weight (%)


                          Originality                                                      30
                          (Student’s original proposal)
                          Organization                                                     30
                          (Validity of approach and reliability of results)
                          Relevance/Significance (potential contribution to
                          countryside development considering its social,
                          economic and ecological impacts)                                     40

                                 A  cut-off  point  of  85  percentile  for  secondary  and
                          undergraduate  levels  and  90  percentile  for  graduate  level  for  the
                          above  criteria  will  be  maintained  during  the  final  selection.  The
                          candidates receiving the highest point which is equal or above the
                          cut-off points are considered winners.


                          Incentives

                                 All  nominees  for  the  best  thesis  are  given  a  certificate  of
                          recognition.

                                 During the university recognition program, the best thesis is
                          awarded the following:


                                   Certificate of Recognition
                                   Cash Award:  Php 5,000 for doctoral

                                                       Php 4,000 for masteral


                                                       Php 3,000 for undergraduate

                                                       Php  2,000 for secondary


                                 The cash awards can be sourced out by tapping sponsors or
                          through the income generating unit of the university.


                                 The  abstracts  of  selected  best  theses  are  immediately
                          published in the R and D Highlights. The full papers are published
                          in the CvSU Research Journal.

                          Trainings/Seminars for Students

                                 Departmental  or  college-based  research/extension  paper
                          presentation can be done for information dissemination.






                                                                                                      278]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           311
                   APPENDIX  13

                   PROPOSED TITLE:                 FACULTY        AND     STUDENTS          RESEARCH
                                                   CAPABILITY ENHANCEMENT PROGRAM
                                                                                                   1

                   PROPONENT:                      RESEARCH AND EXTENSION SERVICES

                   IMPLEMENTING                    CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                   AGENCY:

                   INITIAL BUDGET:                 1 Million Pesos (initial year of implementation)

                   INITIAL       YEAR        OF
                   IMPLEMENTATION:
                                                   FIRST  SEMESTER,  ACADEMIC  YEAR  2004-
                                                   2005


                   RATIONALE:

                   Research  is  one  of  the  functions  of  the  university  and  all  colleges,
                   including  those  of  the  campuses  are  expected  to  be  involved  in  its
                   conduct.


                   The AACCUP guidelines in accrediting academic programs of colleges and
                   universities  also  look  at  the  kind  of  research  outputs  the  colleges  are
                   producing during the time of evaluation.

                   Faculty  members  who  serve  as  thesis  advisers  have  no  continuing
                   research project(s) in spite their potential in proposing and implementing
                   researches along their fields of specialization and experiences.


                   Thesis  in  the  graduate  and  undergraduate  levels  as  well  as  in  the
                   laboratory school are expensive and need some forms of financial support
                   in pursuing student’s researches with improved quality of output.

                   Faculty  research  project  may  also  accommodate  and  fund  thesis  of
                   students.


                   Students and faculty members need to expose and be more confident and
                   in coming up with quality of outputs.

                   There  is  need  for  the  colleges  to  identify  workable  and  doable  research
                   thrust, agenda and program that will serve as guide in implementing the
                   research activities of the university.

                   For  these  activities,  the  university  has  a  starting  capital  of  one  million
                   pesos for the research project of the colleges.



                                                                                                      311]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           312
                   ___________________________


                   1   Prepared  and  submitted  by  SIMEON  S.  CRUCIDO,  Vice  President  for
                   Research and Extension and Professor V, Cavite State University, Indang,
                   Cavite for discussion by the Administrative Council and approval of the
                   University Board of Regents.  April 2004.

                   Approved by the BOR per Resolution No. 75, S. 2004.  December 9, 2004
                   (signed by Gloria L. Martonito, Board Secretary V)







































































                                                                                                      312]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           313
                   OBLECTIVES

                   General Objective:


                          To  provide  direction  and  guide  for  the  conduct  of  faculty  and
                   student’s research in the university.

                   Specific Objectives:


                   To  increase  the  level  of  participation  of  faculty  members  in  conducting
                   research in their respective colleges;

                   To provide some forms of assistance for the graduate, undergraduate and
                   the laboratory school’s research projects;

                   To increase the number of technical papers/articles for publication in the
                   university research journal;


                   To satisfy the requirement of each college in AACCUP accreditation;

                   To  produce  quality  research  output  that  could  be  transformed  into  a
                   material that is useful to the university’s various clienteles; and

                   To satisfy SUC leveling requirements.


                   Organization and Management

                   Each College/campus shall organize a research team to be headed by the
                   College/Campus  Research  Coordinator  that  will  formulate  and  update
                   Research  and  Development  (R&D)  agenda  and  program  for  their
                   respective disciplines.  All faculty members serving as advisers of thesis
                   students have to qualify as members of the research team.

                   All researchers shall be directly supervised by the Dean of the College but
                   will be regularly monitored by the Research Center, through the Director
                   or his/her representative(s).


                   The  college  shall  designate  appropriate  faculty  members  who  will
                   implement the research projects through a special job order that will be
                   recommended by the Dean and the Research Director and approved by
                   the University President.


                   Only  studies  to  be  jointly  conducted  by  faculty  members  and  students
                   shall qualify for assistance under this program.


                   Coordinative  research  shall  be  considered  among  colleges/campuses
                   provided the project falls within their thrust/agenda and program.




                                                                                                      313]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           314
                   A  Monitoring  and  Evaluation  Committee  shall  be  created  to  monitor,
                   review and evaluate on-going and completed projects.

                   All  R&D  activities  require  the  support  from  all  units  of  the  university,
                   including the Administrative and Support Services.


                   A  University  Intellectual  Property  Rights  Officer  shall  be  designated  by
                   the  President  to  work  on  issues  pertaining  to  the  Intellectual  Property
                   Rights (IPR) of products/process developed through research.







































































                                                                                                      314]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           315
                   Mechanics of Implementation:

                   Agenda/Program/Project/Study Setting and Prioritization


                   The  college/campus  shall  prepare  a  research  agenda/program  that
                   corresponds  to  their  academic  offerings.    The  R&D  Agenda/Program
                   should be prepared by assessing the current problems and issues of the
                   industry.    The  R&D  Agenda/Program  of  each  of  the  colleges/campuses
                   shall be reviewed and evaluated by the Research Council for approval of
                   the Administrative Council and the Board of Regents.

                   All approved R&D Agenda/Program will be consolidated by the Research
                   Center and shall become the University’s R&D Agenda and Program.


                   In  the  absence  of  a  more  comprehensive  research  agenda/program  for
                   each  of  the  different  colleges/campuses,  the  university  recommends
                   those that are presented in Annex “A”.


                   Short  term  applied  or  practical  researches  shall  be  conducted  as  a
                   component of a long-term project.


                   Only student thesis conducted in conformity with the approved research
                   thrust/agenda  of  the  university  shall  qualify  for  assistance  under  this
                   program.


                   The  faculty  researchers  who  will  be  designated  as  project  leaders  shall
                   prepare a research project proposal by following the format prescribed by
                   the  university  (Annex  “B”).  For  student  thesis,  an  outline  shall  be
                   prepared by the student by following the prescribed style and format for
                   the College and/or the University.


                   Screening and Evaluation of the Research Proposal

                   The proposal prepared by the faculty members shall be initially reviewed
                   and  evaluated  by  the  College/Campus  Research  Team  (activity  flow  in
                   Annex “C”).


                   For student thesis, an outline shall be reviewed and evaluated during the
                   thesis defense by the Guidance Committee and one representative of the
                   Research,  Extension,  Continuing  Educational  and  Training  Services
                   (RECETS) Council to be designated by its Chairman.


                   All proposals that have passed the review and evaluation of the Research
                   Team shall be endorsed by the College Dean to the RECETS Council for
                   final  evaluation,  through  the  Vice  President  for  Research,  Extension,
                   Continuing Education and Training Services.  The review and evaluation
                   shall be conducted to determine 1) relevance, 2) usefulness, 3) quality, 4)
                   viability and technical feasibility, 5) impact and social acceptability and
                   6) global competitiveness of the proposed project(s).

                                                                                                      315]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           316
                   Each  College  Campus  shall  submit  to  the  RECETS  Council  list  of
                   students  with  the  title  of  their  approved  thesis  (by  project)  for
                   endorsement  to  the  Administrative  Council  and  for  approval  of  the
                   University Board of Regents.


                   Budget Allocation

                   Every  year,  the  university  shall  allocate  funds  (1  to  3  million  pesos)  to
                   fund research priorities of the colleges in the main campus.  The branch
                   campuses,  through  their  Deans  shall  also  allocate  funds  for  their
                   identified priority R & D agenda/program.

                   Funding  shall  be  allocated  in  accordance  with  the number  of  approved
                   programs/projects/studies  for  each  of  the  disciplines,  e.g.  Agriculture;
                   Engineering;  Education;  Economics,  Management  and  Development
                   Studies;  Physical  and  Health  Services,  etc.    The  college  through  the
                   research team shall schedule the allocation of funds to the projects based
                   on priorities.

                   All colleges are required to avail  of the funding under this proposal for
                   student theses that will be jointly conducted by the faculty advisers and
                   their advisees.


                   When approved, the research shall be funded by the university.  A project
                   can  accommodate  student’s  research  with  a  minimum  amount  of  Php
                   25,000.00,  from  the  research  fund  of  the  university  and  the  remaining
                   balance shall be shouldered by the student.

                   If  the  total  budgetary  requirement  of  a  student  thesis  is  lower  than
                   Php50,000.00,  only  50%  of  the  total  project  shall  be  provided  by  the
                   university.

                   The  funds  will  be  allocated  for  the  maintenance  and  other  operating
                   expenses (MODE) of the project.

                   All requests for the purchase and/or use of the university funds for this
                   purpose  shall  conform  to  the  existing  government  and  accounting  and
                   auditing rules and regulations.


                   Implementation

                   The  proponent(s)  shall  start  implementing  the  project/study  soon  after
                   receiving a notice to commence and an approved special order from the
                   Office of the President (OUP).

                   The  proponent  shall  notify  the  Research  Director  with  the  Office  of  the
                   Vice  President  for  Research,  Extension,  Continuing  Education  and
                   Training  Services,  Vice  President  for  Administrative  and  Support
                   Services,  Financial  Management  Director,  Vice  President  for  Academic

                                                                                                      316]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           317
                   Affairs  and  the  OUP  copy  furnished  of  the  date  the  project  officially
                   started.

                   Monitoring and Evaluation


                   All on-going and completed researches shall be monitored, reviewed and
                   evaluated quarterly while the completed projects shall be finally reviewed
                   and evaluated by the research monitoring and evaluation committee;


                   The College/Campus Research Coordinator with the permission from the
                   Dean  shall  schedule  for  and  conduct  an  Annual  Research  In-House
                   Review of all on-going and completed research.


                   During  the  review,  the  project/study  leaders  of  all  on-going
                   projects/studies shall prepare a progress report using format prescribed
                   for  the  purpose  (Annex  “D”).    A  terminal  report  and  a  technical  paper
                   shall  be  prepared  and  submitted  by  the  project/study  leaders  on
                   completed project (Annex “E”).

                   The project/study leaders shall be required to present the progress of the
                   on-going  projects/studies  and  the  final  results  of  the  completed
                   projects/studies.

                   The  evaluators  shall  make  a  written  report  about  the  results  of  the
                   evaluation, including a recommendation for the on-going research project
                   or  study.    For  completed  projects/studies  the  evaluators  shall  make
                   recommendation that will help improve the manuscript.

                   Publication


                   Technical  papers  shall  be  written  from  the  results  of  the  project/study
                   and  will  be  submitted  to  the  CvSU  Research  Journal’s  Editorial
                   Committee for publication.


                   Articles  written  from  the  results  of  the  student’s  thesis  shall  have  the
                   student(s)  as  the  major  author  and  the  faculty  adviser  as  a  co-author.
                   This  holds  true  even  if  the  final  form  of  the  article  was  written  by  the
                   faculty adviser.


                   Intellectual Property Rights (IPR)

                   Patented fabricated equipment or any form of patented product that was
                   developed from student thesis with 50% funding from the university shall
                   be  a  joint  ownership  of  the  author(s)  and  the  university.    When
                   commercialized, the author(s) and the faculty adviser shall have an equal
                   share from the 70% of the royalty while the remaining 30% shall go to the
                   university.




                                                                                                      317]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           318
                   Registration  for  copyright  and  patenting  of  products  or  equipment
                   developed  from  research  shall  be  the  joint  responsibility  of  the  author
                   and the university through the IPR Officer.


                   Commercialized patented equipment/product that was produced from a
                   faculty  research  project  shall  be  jointly  owned  by  the  author  and  the
                   university.

                   The  author  shall  be  entitled  to  60%  of  the  royalty  while  the  remaining
                   40% shall go the university.

                   The  amount  earned  by  the  university  in  the  form  of  royalties  shall  be
                   placed  in  a  thrust  fund  and  shall  be  used  to  fund  future  faculty  and
                   student research projects.

                   Workload Credit


                   The  involvement  of  faculty  members  to  actual  operation  of  the
                   colleges/campuses  or  the  university  shall  be  credited  to  a  research
                   workload  with  the  corresponding  credit  points  earned  for  the  semester
                   (Annex “D”).


                   A faculty researcher who exceeds the minimum workload requirement in
                   teaching shall be entitled to a research overload pay that is equivalent to
                   the amount approved for the academics.


                   Effectivity

                   This shall take effect upon the approval of the University Administrative
                   Council and the Board of Regents.






























                                                                                                      318]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           319
                   APPENDIX 14

                              PROTECTING THE INTELLECTUAL PROPERTIES OF
                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY


                   I. Rationale

                          Republic  Act  No.  8293,  otherwise  known  as  the  Intellectual
                   Property Code of the Philippines, states that:


                          “The  State  recognizes  that  an  effective  intellectual  and  industrial
                   property  system  is  vital  to  the  development  of  domestic  and  creative
                   activity,  facilitates  transfers  of  technology,  attracts  foreign  investments,
                   and ensures market access for our products.  It shall protect and secure
                   the  exclusive  rights  of  scientist,  inventors,  artists  and  other  gifted
                   citizens  to  their  intellectual  property  and  creations,  particularly  when
                   beneficial to the people.”


                          With  the  various  intellectual  properties  (IP’s)  developed  in  the
                   university  such  as  the  Aguinaldo  Blend  Coffee,  processed  products,
                   design  for  biogas  digester  and  innumerable  research  outputs  being
                   presented  for  public  consumption,  a  few  of  them  were  able  to  acquire
                   protection. The biogas digester was just recently granted a patent, while
                   research  outputs/publications  have  been  presented  without  copyright
                   protection,  except  for  some  that  were  able  to  acquire  ISBN  registration
                   from  the  National  Library.  Therefore,  the  University  must  develop  a
                   system  for  protecting  economically  viable  intellectual  properties  to
                   maximize gains that could finance more researches in the future.


                   II. Definition of Terms


                          “Copyright” is  the  protection  extended  to  expressions  and  not  to
                   ideas, procedures, and methods of operations or mathematical concepts
                   as  such.  Such  expressions  may  be  in  the  forms  of  literary,  scholarly,
                   scientific and artistic works.

                          “Intellectual Property or IP” is an asset that possesses commercial
                   value  which  can  be  exploited  to  generate  revenue.  IP  value  lies  in  its
                   utilization, not existence.

                          “Intellectual Property Rights” or “IPR” refers to the entitlement and
                   enjoyment of the attributes of ownership over intellectual properties. IPR
                   consists  of:  a)  Copyright  and  related  rights;  b)  Trademarks  and  Service
                   Marks;  c)  Geographic  Indications;  d)  Industrial  Designs;  e)  Patents;  f)
                   Layout-Designs (Topographies) of Integrated Circuits; and g) Protection of








                                                                                                      319]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           320
                   Undisclosed Information.  IPR shall likewise include plant varieties  and
                                                 1
                   animal breeds.

                          “Patent’       is a grant issued by the Philippine government giving
                   an  inventor  the  right  to  exclude others  from  making,  using,  setting,  or
                   importing the product of his invention within the Philippines in exchange
                   of his patentable information or disclosure.

                          “Patentable inventions”  means any technical solution of a problem
                   in  any  field  of  human  activity  which  is  new,  involves  an  inventive  step
                   and is industrially applicable, which may be, or may related to a product,
                   or process, or an improvement of any of the foregoing.
                                                                                  2

                          “Plant variety”       means a plant grouping within a single botanical
                   taxon of the lowest known rank which can be defined by the expression
                   of the characteristics resulting from a given genotype, or combination of
                   genotypes,  distinguished  from  any  other  plant  groupings  by  the
                   expression  of  at  least  one  characteristic  and  considered  as  a  unit  with
                   regard to the suitability for being propagated unchanged. A variety may
                   be  represented  by  seed,  transplants,  plants,  tubers,  and  tissue  culture
                   plantlets.


                          “Prior art”   Everything made available to the public by means of a
                   written or oral disclosure, by use, or in any other way, before the filing
                   date  or  the  priority  date  of  the  application  claiming  the  invention.
                   Prior use which is not present in the Philippines, even if widespread in a
                   foreign country, cannot form part of the prior art if such prior use is not
                   disclosed in printed documents or in any tangible form.


                   III. Objective


                          To establish a system protecting the intellectual properties (IP’s) or
                   results/products  generated  through  researches  conducted  in  the
                   university.

                   IV. Strategy


                          The  University  shall  establish  an  IPR  Office  that  covers  all
                   intellectual property protection activities and provide trainings/seminars
                   to  researchers  to  increase  awareness  on  IPR.  The  IPR  Office  will  be
                   divided in to two sections, each having IPR Assistants, one for patentable
                   IP’s and the other for publishable IP’s.


                          The IPR Officer will work under the Office of the Vice-President for
                   Research,  Extension,  Continuing  Education  and  Training  Services
                   (RECETS), and is tasked to identify, protect and exploit commercially on


                   1  Section 4, R.A. 8293 (1998); TRIPS.
                   2  Section 21, R.A. 8293 (1998).
                                                                                                      320]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           321
                   the  University’s  behalf  the  intellectual  property  rights  generated  by  the
                   University’s researchers.

                          The  IPR  Officer  will  be  involved  in  identifying  and  protecting  the
                   University’s  intellectual  property  rights,  and  in  conforming  to  existing
                   systems in managing, recording and tracking the progress of intellectual
                   property  applications  and  commercialization  of  the  property.  The  IPR
                   Officer will be required to work in close coordination with both research
                   and  academic  units  of  the  university  to  identify  research  results  and
                   intellectual property rights with commercial potential. In this capacity the
                   IPR  Assistants  will  be  responsible  for  applying  for  and  liquidating  cash
                   advances  accrued  during  the  applications  and  payment  of  other  fees
                   pertinent  to  the  application.  Where  necessary  the  IPR  Officer  will  work
                   with the University’s legal advisers.

                          The  IPR  Officer  and  IPR  Assistants  will  be  provided  with
                   appropriate external training to ensure that they can become competent
                   in all aspects of the role.

                   Other responsibilities include the following:


                          Formulate,  propose  and  implement  governing  guidelines  in
                   patenting/copyrighting research results in the University

                          Deal  with  agencies  requesting  for  commercialization  rights  for
                   patented/ copyrighted materials from the university, enter into licensing
                   agreements and manage the payment of royalties.

                          Monitor  violations  and  persecute  violators  for  patents/copyrights
                   issued to the university.


                   V. Implementation

                          The  CvSU-Intellectual  Property  Office  (CvSU-IPO)  shall  head  two
                   units,  Patentable  IP  Unit  and  Publishable  IP  Unit,  each  having  IPR
                   Assistants and will work in consultation with the legal authority of the
                   University;






















                                                                                                      321]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           322









































                          Figure 1:       Proposed Organizational set-up of the IPR Office











































                                                                                                      322]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           323
                   Intellectual properties generated through the university researches shall
                   be  jointly  owned  by  the  researcher  and  the  university.  Sharing  of  the
                   royalties will be at 70% for the researcher and 30% for the University


                          A 5% cut from the royalty share of the researcher shall be placed in
                   a  trust  fund  for  future  research  projects,  travels,  attendance  to
                   conferences of the respective researcher

                          Registration/processing  fees  for  patents/copyrights  shall  be
                   shouldered by the University.

                          All  research  outputs,  patentable/copyrightable  or  not,  shall  be
                   reported  to  the  CvSU-IPO  and  shall  only  be  presented/published  for
                   public consumption if, and only if, a written permit from the CvSU-IPO
                   has been granted to the researcher

                          Licensing agreements, before being entered into shall be reviewed
                   and approved by the University President and Board of Regents.

                   VI. IPR Application Process Flow (University Level)


                   A.  Patents  (filing  fee,  PhP  3,636.00,  until  4  years  after  publication  of
                   patent, annual fees on each subsequent anniversary) *validity: 20 years
                   from filing date


                          The  researcher  submits  the  terminal  report  to  the  University
                   Research Center.

                          The  IPR  Officer  and  the  Research  Center  Director  periodically
                   submit technologies for patentability evaluation to the Vice President for
                   RECETS.

                          If  approved,  the  researcher  is  asked  to  fill  up  Patent  Application
                   Form and submit necessary documents to the IPR Officer.

                          The  IPR  Officer  applies  for  Cash  Advance  that  would  cover
                   expenses  for  the  application  including,  but  not  limited  to,  filing  fee,
                   photocopying fee, transportation and travel allowances, etc.


                   As the cash advance is released, the application will be filed at the:

                                      INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY PHILIPPINES
                                                       IPO Building
                                         351 Sen. Gil Puyat Ave., Makati City

                   Other documents and fees, as the need arises, related to the application
                   will be accomplished, submitted and paid promptly by the IPR Officer.



                                                                                                      323]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           324
                   B. Copyrights (registration fee: PhP 150.00) * validity: lifetime + 50 years

                          Register and deposit two (2) copies each to:


                                 i. National Library Copyright Division


                                 ii. Supreme Court Library










































































                                                                                                      324]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           325
                   VII. Potential IP’s developed in the University


                                                   Classificat                                  Unit/College/
                   IP                                            Year       Author
                                                   ion                                          Campus
                   1.  Aguinaldo Blend             Patent        2002       Dr.  Alejandro  Coffee Center
                                                                            C. Mojica, Sr.
                   2.  Aguinaldo  Blend  in  Utility             2002       Dr.  Alejandro  Coffee Center
                   Filter Bags                     Model                    C. Mojica, Sr.
                   3.Chevon               Mara,   Patent         2000       Prof.    Fe    N.  CAFENR
                   Nuggets                                                  Dimero
                   4.  Native Chicken Mara,  Patent              2001       Prof.    Fe    N.  CAFENR
                   reformed  ham,  sausage,                                 Dimero
                   nuggets, franks
                   5.  Laya at Diwa                Copyright  2006
                   6.    Softwares,  computer  Copyright  ---               Students  and  CEIT
                   programs, etc.                                           faculty
                   7.    Research  results,  Copyright  ---                 Students  and  All
                   articles,          journals,                             faculty
                   theses,       presentation,
                   photographs, leaflets
                   8.       T-shirt     designs  Copyright  2007            Dr.  Tepora  /  Research
                   (dragonfruit             and                             Dr. Mojica          Center
                   Aguinaldo blend)
                   9.Processed  dragonfruit  Patent              2007       Dr.  Teddy  F.  Research
                   products                                                 Tepora              Center






































                                                                                                      325]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           326
                   APPENDIX 17

                   Research Thrusts/Agenda Program by Discipline:


                   I.  Agriculture


                            High value vegetables
                            Fruit crops – mango, banana, pineapple, papaya, dragon fruit
                            Beverages – coffee
                            Plantation crops – coconut, yellow corn
                            Ornamental plants


                   2.     Swine and Poultry
                   3.     Forestry
                   4.     Environmental Services
                   5.     Wood fuel and Bio-fuels
                   6.     Environment and Natural Resources
                   7.     Socio Economics
                   8.     Education
                   9.     Health, Food and Nutrition
                   10.    Information and Communications Technology
                   11.    Industrial Technology


                           The  R  and  D  programs  include,  but  are  not  limited  to,  the
                   following problem areas:

                   1.  Crops


                         Improving production system
                         Reducing post harvest losses
                         Improving processing and marketing efficiencies
                         Accelerating technology adoption
                         Improving processing technologies


                   2.  Animals

                         Enhancing  competitiveness  and  sustainability  of  commercial
                          animal production
                         Building  assets  from  sustained  small  livestock  and  poultry-based
                          enterprise

                   Forestry


                         Development  of  processing  machine  for  oil  extraction  and  its
                          utilization for bio-ethanol
                         Enhancing sustainable watershed management
                         Production and marketing efficiencies



                                                                                                      326]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           327
                         Managing  waste  and  pollutant  for  environment  protection  and
                          resource recovery
                         Minimizing effects of agriculture and forestry activities on climate
                          changes
                         Improving      biodiversity     conservation      and     management        for
                          sustainable  ecotourism  preservation  and  effective  use  of
                          indigenous structures and system for community development and
                          sustainable  tourism  for  community  development  and  sustainable
                          tourism


                   3. Socio-Economics

                         Models of development programs
                         Credit and Financing schemes
                         Market economics
                         Consumer economics
                         Production economics
                         Technology Delivery System
                         Monitoring and Impact Assessment
                         Entrepreneurship
                         Aspirations and value orientation
                         Employment opportunities
                         Leadership patterns and styles
                         Policy analysis, formulation and implementation
                         Gender and development
                         Cultural traditions, customs and beliefs

                   4. Education


                         Curriculum assessment, development and enhancement
                         Teaching competencies and effectiveness
                         Instructional materials development
                         Performance evaluation
                         Evaluation of student services
                         Graduate tracer studies

                   5. Health and Nutrition


                         Governance
                         Health regulation
                         Health Service Delivery
                         Health Education
                         Health Technology Development

                   6. Information and communication Technology


                         web interfaces
                         Bioinformatics
                                                                                                      327]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           328
                         Multimedia application
                         Convergence technologies
                         Data warehousing
















































































                                                                                                      328]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Reseach Presentations, Publications


                         In-House Reviews, Workshops, Trainings,

                                       Seminars, and Conferences]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                     CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                   Tanza Campus
                                    Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                  (046) 414 – 3979
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                         LIST OF FACULTY RESEARCHES

                   Research                                                      Institution/
                    Thrust/         Title of Research        Proponents                          Duration
                    Agenda                                                       Department
                                                              Mildred A.
                                                           Sebastian, Glenn
                                                          Bryan A. Creencia,
                                                           Ritch M. Banate,
                                                             Audreyson H.
                                                            Borilla, Ivory P,
                                 Learning Assessment         Mojica, Gil D.      CvSU-Tanza       Septemb
                    Societal
                 Development     in Flexible Learning     Ramos, Robert H.       Campus and       er 2021-
                                                                                 CvSU-Main
                                 Environment in the
                                                                                                  August
                                                           Nova, Gerry Mae
                  and Equity
                                 New Normal                   T. Silvero,          Faculty         2023
                                                               Mary Joy
                                                             Angelique R.
                                                          Mojica, Joyce Erika
                                                           S. Senaris, Maria
                                                           Cristina C. Tagle,
                                                            Estelita A. Villa
                                 Study 1: Learning
                                 Assessment used in                             Department of
                                                                                 Management
                                 Flexible Learning         Ritch M. Banate
                                                                                   Teacher
                                 Environment in the         Ivory P. Mojica       Education
                                 Business Education                              Department
                                 Programs
                                 Study 2: Learning          Prof. Mildred A.
                                 Assessment used in
                                 Flexible Learning            Sebastian            Teacher
                                                               Mary Joy           Education
                                 Environment in the          Angelique R.        Department
                                 Teacher Education
                                 Programs                       Mojica
                                 Study 3: Learning
                                 Assessment used in         Joyce Erika S.      Department of
                                 Flexible Learning                               Information
                                 Environment in the            Senaris           Technology
                                                           Maria Cristina C.
                                 Engineering and                Tagle              Teacher
                                 Information and                                  Education
                                 Communication                                   Department
                                 Technology
                                                                                 CvSU-Main
                                 Study 4: Learning        Mr. Glenn Bryan A.
                                 Assessment used in            Creencia            (Biology)
                                                                                   Teacher
                                 Flexible Learning         Ms. Gerry Mae T.
                                 Environment in                 Silvero           Education
                                                                                 Department]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Mathematics and
                                 Natural Sciences
                                 Study 5: Learning
                                 Assessment used in       Prof. Gil D. Ramos    Department of
                                 Flexible Learning        Ms. Mary Dean P.         Arts and
                                 Environment in Liberal         Ampon              Sciences
                                 Arts
                                 Study 6: Utilization     Ms. Estelita A. Villa    Teacher
                                 and Acceptability of
                                                           Mr. Audreyson H.       Education
                                 an Assessment Guide
                                 in the New Normal              Borilla          Department
                     Smart
                 Engineering,    Workplace
                    ICT and
                                                                                                    May
                   Industrial    Performance of                                                    2021-
                                 CvSU-Tanza
                 Competitiven    Graduates: Inputs to              n                                May
                      ess
                    Societal     Curriculum                                                        2023
                                 Development
                 Development
                  and Equity
                                                             Ms. Melona I.
                                 Study 1: Level of              Saquin
                                 Workplace
                                 Preparedness and            Mr. Ritch M.
                                                                Banate
                                 Attitudes of CvSU-        Ms. Debbie Rose
                                 Tanza Graduates
                                                               T. Banag
                                                          Ms. Joyce Erika S.
                                 Study 2: Employers’
                                                               Senaris
                                 Satisfaction on the      Prof. Gil D. Ramos
                                 Workplace
                                                          Ms. Mary Rose E.
                                 Performance and              Elamparo
                                 Attitudes of CvSU -       Mr. Mark Joel C.
                                 Tanza Graduates
                                                                Sibulo
                                 Study 3: Employers’
                                 Perceived Quality of       Prof. Mildred A.
                                 Workplace
                                                              Sebastian
                                 Performance of CvSU       Ms. Mary Joy R.
                                 – Tanza Graduates         Angelique Mojica
                                 and Relevance and
                                 Responsiveness of         Ms. Gerry Mae T.
                                                                Silvero
                                 Curricular Programs
                                 to Industry Needs
                                 Study 4:  Acceptability   Ms. Charmaine T.
                                 and Usability of               Banag
                                 CvSU-TC Graduate            Mr. Jeffrey F.
                                 Tracing Mobile                Delgado
                                 Application               Ms. Erika Precia
                                                            Dr. Rachelle M.
                                                                Santos
                                 E-Commerce and             Dr. Reynold A.      Department of
                    Societal                                                     Management
                 Development     Traditional Business           Campo           Department of
                  and Equity     During Pandemic: A         Prof. Randy D.       Information
                                 Comparative Analysis          Enderina
                                                           Prof. Christopher     Technology
                                                               Mabalay]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Prof. Ana Marie
                                                                Obon
                                                           Dr. Nelson Nico
                                                            Dr. Rachelle M.
                                                                Santos
                                                            Dr. Reynold A.
                                 School-Based-                  Campo           Department of
                    Societal     Entrepreneurial            Prof. Randy D.       Management
                 Development  Center: Cost-Benefit             Enderina         Department of
                  and Equity     and Environmental         Prof. Christopher     Information
                                 Analyses                      Mabalay           Technology
                                                           Prof. Ana Marie
                                                                Obon
                                                           Dr. Nelson Nico
                                                            Prof. Mildred A.                        June
                                 Gender-Based                 Sebastian            Teacher         2018 –
                                                                                  Education
                  Gender and     Differentiation among       Mr. Ritch M.        Department       August
                 Development  Public Elementary                 Banate          Department of      2022
                                 Teachers of Cavite         Ms. Melona O.                         (complet
                                                               Igmasine          Management         ed)
                                 Study 1:
                                 Characterization of        Prof. Mildred A.       Teacher

                                 the Public Elementary        Sebastian           Education
                                 Schools in Cavite
                                 Study 2: Gender
                                 Roles in
                                 Reproductive,
                                 Productive,                 Mr. Ritch M.       Department of

                                 Community and                  Banate           Management
                                 Leisure Activities of
                                 Public Elementary
                                 Teachers of Cavite
                                 Study  3:  Access  and
                                 Control         among      Ms. Melona O.       Department of

                                 Elementary  Teachers          Igmasine          Management
                                 of Cavite




               Prepared by:


               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
               Research Coordinator


               Certified Correct:



               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                        Tanza Campus
                                          Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414 – 3979
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                            DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT

                                                  List of Student Researches

                                                                                   Place of
                                                                                   Conduct        Date
                             Title of Research               Researchers
                                                                                    of the     Completed
                                                                                    Study
                        Online and Offline Shopping      Gerollo, Jerfaulyn A.
                         Experience and Preference
                        During Pandemic of Selected     Joaquin, Rj Romulo A.       Cavite      June 2022
                                                          Sagadal, Jessica C.
                        Working-Class Millennials in       Tesorero, Gina T.
                                   Cavite
                        Online Shopper’s Perception
                                                           Calindatas, Ivy O.
                          and Satisfaction with the     Encarnacion, Jheann L.      Tanza,
                          Service Quality of Online                                             June 2022
                         Courier Services in Tanza,      Madrio, Mary Anna B.       Cavite
                                   Cavite               Sereño, Leme Jane B.
                         Cashless Payment System:         Genesis, Alyssa R.
                          Acceptability and Usage          Pajulas, Jenny S.        Tanza,      June 2022
                           Among Working–Class           Igtos, Reymer Joy A.       Cavite
                         Millennials in Tanza, Cavite      Nuñez, Josan V.
                                                          Alcana, Jocelyn C.
                         Business Continuity During
                                                           Gotera, Susan B.
                         Pandemic: Challenges and          Sandoy, Claire P.        Cavite      June 2022
                        Crisis Management of Micro-     Serrano, John Aldrin B.
                            Enterprises in Cavite
                                                          Villaflor, Charity D.
                            Effects of Community       De Claro, Ellen Grace P.
                        Quarantine on The Business         Mequiabas, Carl          Tanza,
                          Performance of Selected             Christian T.                      June 2022
                          Micro, Small and Medium           Nava, Jeizel D.         Cavite
                        Enterprises in Tanza, Cavite    Quintana, Dave Jhon P.
                            Work Motivation and          Antonio, Sphenler G.
                          Performance of Business
                         Process Outsourcing (BPO)       Asido, Annsherina G.       Cavite      June 2022
                                                         Daligcon, Geldain L.
                         Employees During Flexible       Turla, Maria Niña M.
                             Work Arrangement
                         Socio-Demographic Profile
                           and Level of Financial          Morada, Jofhel D.
                            Literacy of Business        Presto, Florida Mae C.      Tanza,      June 2022
                          Management Students of           Reyes, Lorivic P.        Cavite
                           CvSU -Tanza: Basic for          Tabua, Angel L.
                         Financial Literacy Program
                         Strategies and Practices on   Catabay, Jannah Nina C.
                        Green Marketing of Selected       Macabenta, Roniela        Cavite      June 2019
                             Local Food Product               Marimar F.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Producers of One Town, One
                              Product in Cavite
                          Customer Perception and
                           Preferences on Green                                     Tanza,
                         Packaging of Fast-Moving         Cortez, Abegail P.                    June 2019
                         Consumer Goods in Tanza,                                   Cavite
                                   Cavite
                            Customer Perceived
                            Importance of Green        Francisco, Lovely Joy D.
                        Practices Towards Consumer       Lumantad, Gerby G.         Tanza,      June 2019
                        Dining Decisions in Selected                                Cavite
                          Fastfood Restaurants in
                               Tanza, Cavite
                          Level of Engagement and
                         Perceived Benefits of Green
                            Business Practices of      Mendoza, Abigail Joy S.      Tanza,      June 2019
                                                        Pacamparra, Jolina P.
                           Fisherfolks in Selected                                  Cavite
                        Coastal Barangays in Tanza,
                                   Cavite



                       Prepared by:


                       MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                       Research Coordinator


                       Certified Correct:



                       GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                       Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                          List of Faculty Research Presentations

                       Title of Research
                      Presented/ Activity       Name of Faculty        Date/Venue         Participation
                            Attended
                                                                     June 29-30, 2022
                         th
                        5  Division Basic        Ms. Jonane J.       SDO Marinduque           Paper
                      Education Research             Saguid          Conference Hall,       Presenter
                             Summit                                   Malusak, Boac,
                                                                        Marinduque
                      Mathematical Model
                      Equation: Predictor of
                         Success in the
                     Licensure Examination
                        for Teachers for                              January 21-22,
                    Mathematics Program of     Engr. Ma. Cristina          2022               Paper
                     Cavite State University     C. Tagle, LPT         via Microsoft        Presenter
                                                                          Teams
                                        th
                       Tanza Campus (4
                      DLSAU International
                        Multidisciplinary
                     Research Conference)
                        BSE Mathematics
                    Program Performance of
                    Cavite State University –
                      Tanza Campus in the      Engr. Ma. Cristina    December 8 – 10,         Paper
                     Licensure Examination       C. Tagle, LPT             2021             Presenter
                     for Teachers Basis for
                       LET Math Equation
                             Model
                    Narrative Experiences of
                            Student
                     Leaders among Public
                          High Schools         Ms. Jhollie Anne D.  March 13-14, 2021         Paper
                      in Trece Martires City,      Lopez, LPT        Philippine Normal      Presenter
                      Cavite (International                              University
                       Graduate Teacher
                    Education Summit 2021)
                         Gender-based
                      Differentiation among        Mildred A.
                       Public Elementary           Sebastian*
                       Teachers in Cavite       Ritch M. Banate,       December 17,           *Paper
                         (5  Gender and            Melona O.               2020             Presenter
                           th
                     Development Research           Igmasine
                          Conference)
                    Achievement Motivation,
                      Locus of Control and      Engr. Estelita A.      November 18,           Paper
                        Study Habits ‘as              Villa                2019             Presenter
                          Predictors of]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Mathematics
                         Achievement of
                       Freshman College
                      Students (T3 Inhouse
                            Review)


                   Prepared by:


                   MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                   Research Coordinator



                   Certified Correct:


                   GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 – 3979
                                                      www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                               List of Published Researches


                                                                        Journal/Volume/Issue        Year of
                    Title of Research               Researcher
                                                                             No./Page No.        Publication
                   Leadership Styles of                                  International Journal of
                Managers in Correlation To                               Research in Education
                    Employees' Work               Ritch M. Banate           Humanities and           2022
                 Performance in Selected                                   Commerce, Vol. 3,
                  Fast-food Restaurants                                     Issue 5, 244-245
                Stakeholders’ Acceptance
               and Perceived Attainability of                            International Journal of
                 Cavite State University –                               Research in Education
                  Tanza Campus Vision,          Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                                            Humanities and
                   Mission, Goals, and            Estelita A. Villa        Commerce, Vol. 3,         2022
                    Objectives towards
                Educational Activities and                                  Issue 5, 145-163
                         Practices
                Application of Time Series        Glenn Bryan A.           Turkish Journal of
                 Analysis and Geographic
               Information System (GIS) in    Creencia, John Daniel V.       Computer and
                                                 Cap-atan, Charles
                                                                              Mathematics
                  Forecasting the At-Risk     Vincent Boral, Mildred A.    Education, Vol. 13,       2022
                Areas of Dengue in Cavite,           Sebastian              Issue 1, 364-371
                        Philippines
                 Achievement Motivation,
                Locus of Control and Study      Mildred A. Sebastian     International Electronic
                  habits as Predictors of                               Journal of Mathematics       2021
               Mathematics Achievement of         Estelita A. Villa         Education, 16(3)
                  New College Students
                    Transition towards                                   International Journal of
                   Alternative Learning         Gerry Mae T. Silvero      Studies in Education       2020
                                                Mildred A. Sebastian
                  Activities: The Case of                                and Science (IJSES),
               Tertiary Education Students      Mary Joy R. Mojica           1(2), 140-156
                Classification of Test Items                             International Electronic
               Written by Mathematics Pre-      Mildred A. Sebastian    Journal of Mathematics       2020
                     Service Teachers                                      Education, 15 (2)
                  Existing Land Use and
                   Extend of Lead (Pb)
                   Contamination in the           Noel A. Sedigo        Heliyon Journal, Vol. 5,     2019
                Grazing Food Chain of the     Richard Dein D. Altarez       Issue 5, E01680
                 Closed Carmona Sanitary
                 Landfill in the Philippines


               Prepared by:                               Certified Correct:


               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                       GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto

               Research Coordinator                       Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                       CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                  Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                        Indang, Cavite
                                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph

                         OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH AND EXTENSION

                                               RESEARCH CENTER

               April 22, 2021


               PROF. MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
               Faculty Researcher
               Tanza Campus
               This University


               Dear Prof. Sebastian:

               The Research Center will conduct a Research Proposal Presentation on April 27, 2021 via
               Cisco Webex.

               In  this  regard, may  we  invite  you  to  present  your  research  proposal  entitled  “Assessment
               Strategies in the New Normal: Inputs to Curriculum Design”.

               During the presentation, only a maximum of 10 slides  will be allowed to  include Rationale,
               Objectives, Summary of Methodology, Expected Outputs (6Ps), Workplan and LIB. Ten (10)
               minutes will be allotted for presentation and ten (10) minutes for question and answer.

               Kindly  submit  your  PowerPoint  Presentation  to  cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph  on  or  before
               April 26, 2021. Mechanics of presentation, program of activities and Cisco Webex link shall be
               sent to all not later than April 23, 2021.

               Should you have any queries, please contact us thru mobile number 09069453267.

               Thank you


               Sincerely,



               KHAY B. ARANDIA
               Head, Monitoring and Evaluation Division



               Noted:



               MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
               Director]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                       CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                  Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                        Indang, Cavite
                                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph

                         OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH AND EXTENSION

                                               RESEARCH CENTER

               April 22, 2021


               PROF. MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Faculty Researcher
               Tanza Campus
               This University


               Dear Prof. Saquin:

               The Research Center will conduct a Research Proposal Presentation on April 27, 2021 via
               Cisco Webex.

               In  this  regard,  may  we  invite  you  to  present  your  research  proposal  entitled  “Workplace
               Performance of CvSU-Tanza Graduates: Inputs to Curriculum Development”.

               During the presentation, only a maximum of 10 slides  will be allowed to  include Rationale,
               Objectives, Summary of Methodology, Expected Outputs (6Ps), Workplan and LIB. Ten (10)
               minutes will be allotted for presentation and ten (10) minutes for question and answer.

               Kindly  submit  your  PowerPoint  Presentation  to  cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph  on  or  before
               April 26, 2021. Mechanics of presentation, program of activities and Cisco Webex link shall be
               sent to all not later than April 23, 2021.

               Should you have any queries, please contact us thru mobile number 09069453267.

               Thank you


               Sincerely,



               KHAY B. ARANDIA
               Head, Monitoring and Evaluation Division



               Noted:



               MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
               Director]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                             Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                       Indang, Cavite
                                                  (046) 8620-850/8621-654


                                 Office of the Vice President for Research and Extension
                                                   RESEARCH CENTER




               March 08, 2021


               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Administrator, Tanza Campus
               This University


               Dear Prof. Ramos:


               Good day!

               This is to inform you that the Research Center will conduct a Research Proposal Presentation
               on April 27, 2021.

               In this regard, we would  like to invite your faculty members to submit research proposals for
               possible  funding  under  the  CvSU  Research  Grant  and  Faculty  and  Students  Research
               Capability Enhancement Program. Please refer to the attached guidelines on the submission of
               research proposals.

               Should  you  have  any  queries,  please  contact  Ms.  Khay  B.  Arandia  of  the  Monitoring  and
               Evaluation    Division   thru   these   contact   details:   862-1654,   09069453267,     and
               cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph.

               Thank you very much.


               Sincerely,



               MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
               Director]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[Activity: Research Proposal Presentation
               Date: April 27, 2021
               Venue: To be Announced

                   1.  Please submit e-copies of the following to cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph.
                         Research proposal (please use UREC-QF-01 or UREC-QF-02)
                              o  Complete signatures of proponents, endorsement of Research Coordinators,
                                 College Dean/Campus Administrators/RDE Unit Director.
                              o  Please provide a detailed Line Item Budget. If the program or project
                                 duration is more than 1 year, please break down your LIB into Year 1 and
                                 Year 2.
                         Accomplished GAD-HGDG (Please use Box 7a Generic Checklist)
                         Accomplished ERB Forms and Questionnaire  (Short Description of Research
                          Proposal, and Informed Consent Approval Sheet)
                   2.  The deadline for the submission of research proposals is on April 5, 2021.
                   3.  After pre-screening, deadline of submission of revised proposals is on April 16.


               Note:  All the forms to be accomplished and submitted are attached in this email.]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                            Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                               Indang, Cavite
                                                                            www.cvsu.edu.ph

                            OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH AND EXTENSION

                                               RESEARCH CENTER

              June 21, 2021



              PROF. MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
              Faculty Researcher
              Tanza Campus
              This University



              Dear Prof. Sebastian:
              The Research Center will conduct the Annual In-House Review of On-going Researches on
              July 28-29, 2021 via Cisco Webex.

              In  this  regard,  we  are  inviting  you  to  present  the  status  of  your  on-going  research  entitled
              “Gender-Based Differentiation among Public Elementary Teachers of Cavite”.

              Please  send  an  e-copy  of  your  paper  and  PowerPoint  presentation  on  or  before
              July 16, 2021 to cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph. For the format of the paper, please refer to the
              attached Information and Guidelines.

               Program of activities and Cisco Webex link shall be sent to all not later than July 23, 2021.

               Should you have any queries, please contact us thru mobile number 09069453267.

              Thank you



                Sincerely,



                KHAY B. ARANDIA
                Head, Monitoring and Evaluation Division




                Noted:

                MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
                Director]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                           Don Severino delas Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite



                    CvSU RESEARCH REVIEW (ANNUAL IN-HOUSE REVIEW) MECHANICS



                                    Information and Guidelines for On-going Research

            I.  RESEARCH
                   All research duly recognized by the University are requested to be presented during the
            CvSU Research Review (Annual In-House Review) . Recognized research are those that have
            funding  through  the  Faculty-Students  Research  Capability  Enhancement  Program  (FSRCEP),
            CvSU Research Grant (CRG), Thesis Grant  and other external funding agencies such as DOST,
            BAR, CHED and others.

            II.  SUBMISSION OF ENTRIES
                   On-going research paper should:
                1.   not be more than  30 pages including tables and figures, printed on A4 bond paper,
                    double-spaced, in 11 font size, preferably in Arial font.
                2.  follow the format below:
                   a.  Title Page
                           •  Title
                           •  Researcher’s  name  including  designation  (Program/Project/Study  leader
                               and  etc.)  and  contact  information  (i.e.  office  telephone  and  fax  numbers,
                               mobile number, and email address). For student-researchers, also include
                               the  degree  program.  Indicate  the  nature  of  involvement  in  the  study  (i.e.
                               experimental  design,  conduct  of  experiments,  analysis  of  data,  writing  of
                               manuscript, etc.)
                           •  Duration (Month and year the project started and expected completion)
                           •  Budget
                           •  Source(s) of Funds
                           •  Collaborating Agency(ies)

                   b.  Technical Report

                           ●  Introduction (rationale, state of the art, analysis of the problem)
                           ●  Objectives (Indicate % accomplishment)
                           ●  Expected Output
                           ●  Procedure/Methodology
                                       Framework of the study
                                       Original procedure/methodology
                                       Change in procedure/methodology (cite reasons)
                           ●  Research Highlights/Accomplishments
                                       Previous year
                                       Year under review
                           ●  Problems met/recommendations
                           ●  Justification for continued implementation]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[c.  Financial Report (Please use UREC-QF-12)
                   d.  Plan of Activities (Gantt Chart)

            II.    ORAL PRESENTATION
                1.  Presentation must be made only by researchers directly involved in the implementation of
                    the project.
                2.  All presentations must be in PowerPoint following the prescribed template.
                3.  Text slides should be easily read.
                4.  The maximum duration for presentation is 10 minutes. An additional 10 minutes will be
                     allotted for questions of evaluators. If time permits, questions from the audience may also
                     be entertained.
                5.  An  electronic  copy  of  the  Paper  and  PowerPoint  file  must  be  sent  thru  email
                     (cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph) on or before July 27, 2021.

            III.  EVALUATION
                On-going researches will be evaluated by the R and E Council and invited technical evaluators.
            The criteria that will be used for evaluation are the following:
                    1.  Attainment of the objectives
                    2.  Adherence  to  the  approved  methodology/Recommendation  of  more  appropriate
                       methodology
                    3.  Attainment of expected output
                    4.  Accomplishments, including status of technology generated/verified
                    5.  Adherence to the approved budget
                    6.  Actions taken in response to previous year’s comments (if applicable)
                    7.  Recommendations on problems met
                    8.  Plan of activities

                   Upon evaluation, the evaluators will make necessary recommendations (i.e. for information
               dissemination, completion, termination, suspension or extension of the project/study).]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[CvSU – T3 Research and Extension                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY

        President                                                                                      GENERAL TRIAS CITY / TANZA / TRECE MARTIRES CITY
               Dr. Hernando D. Robles, CEO IV
                                                                                                 T3 Research Development & Extension
        Vice President for Academic Affairs
               Dr. Camilo A. Polinga, ASEAN Engineer

        Vice President for Research and Extension
               Dr. Ruel M. Mojica                                                                 T3 In-house Review 2019

        Director for Research
               Dr. Yolanda A. Ilagan

        Director for Extension
               Dr. Lilybeth P. Novicio

        CvSU T3 Campus Administrator
               Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, MSc.

        CvSU – Gen. Trias City Coordinator for Research
               Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis

        CvSU – Tanza Coordinator for Research
               Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, MAT

        CvSU – Trece Martires City Coordinator for Research
               Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo

        CvSU – General Trias Coordinator for Extension                                              Theme: “Empowering Communities through
               Ms. Estelita A. Villa                                                                           Research and Extension”

        CvSU – Tanza Coordinator for Extension
               Mr. Ritch M. Banate                                                                     November 18, 2019 / 7:00 AM - 5:00 PM
                                                                                                Gen. Trias Manpower Building, South Square Village,
        CvSU – Trece Martires City Coordinator for Extension                                        Barangay Pasong Kawayan I, Gen. Trias City
               Ms. Pamela Daphne R. Busog


                                                                                                                 (This serves as an Invitation)]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[OPENING PROGRAM

                                                                                                     Thank you so much for your support:
             7:00 AM - 8:00 AM                Registration
                                                                                            Dr. Camilo A. Polinga, Vice President for Academic Affairs

             8:00 AM                          Opening Program                               Dr. Ruel M. Mojica, Vice President for Research and Extension

             Doxology                         Anglicists Guild                              Dr. Yolanda A. Ilagan, Research Director

             National Anthem                  Anglicist Guild                               Dr. Lilybeth P. Novicio, Extension Director

             Welcome Remarks                  Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                              T3 Campus Administrator                       Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, Campus Administrator

             Inspirational Message            Dr. Ruel M. Mojica                            Dr. Agnes C. Francisco, Faculty Researcher, CAS
                                              Vice President for Research
                                              And Extension                                 Ms. Lady Aileen Orsal, Faculty Researcher, Main Campus

                                                                                            Prof. Glenn Bryan A. Creencia, Faculty Researcher, CAFENR
             Intermission Number              Cariñosa, Anglicist Guild
                                              Janggay (Badjao Dance)                        Committees of the In-House Review 2019

             Introduction of the              Prof. Noel A. Sedigo                          Faculty and Staff of CvSU – Tanza Campus
             Keynote Speaker

             Keynote Address                  Dr. Yolanda A. Ilagan                         Faculty and Staff of CvSU – Gen. Trias City Campus
                                              Director for Research, CvSU
                                                                                            Faculty and Staff of CvSU – Trece Martires City Campus
             Awarding of Certificate          T3 Officials with the
             of Appreciation                  Dean                                          The Anglicists Guild

                                                                                            Ms.  Gerry  Mae  Silvero  /  Mr.  Audreyson  Borilla,  In-charge  of
             Roll Call of Attendees                                                         Ceremonies and Moderators

             Introduction of the Panelists    Dr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo
               9:30 AM                        Snacks
                                                                                                 See you next year for the

                         Ms. Gerry Mae Silvero / Mr. Audreyson Borilla                            IN-HOUSE REVIEW 2020
                                 In-Charge of the Ceremonies]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PART II
             Awarding

                Awarding Certificate of Appreciation to the Panelists
                  Awarding Certificate of Participation to the Paper Presenters             10:00 AM  Reading of the Mechanics / Rules

                                                                                                        Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian; Dr. Jessie T. Demetillo


                Awarding Certificate of Participation to Poster Presenters                         PRESENTATION OF COLLABORATIVE RESEARCH
                                                                                                  INSTRUCTOR/STUDENTS COLLABORATIVE WORKS:
                Awarding of the Best Paper Presenter
                   st                                                                           Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Mr. Ariel Lomuntad, Ms. Jenelyn Bajo, Ms.
                1  Place – Php 700.00                                                      Kasselle Branzuela, Ms. Grace Ann Brones, Ms. Janica Bruno Impact of
                 nd
                                                                                                  Language Ego to the Residents of Julugan V, Tanza Cavite
                2  Place – Php 500.00                                                       Presentor: Mr. Ariel D. Lomuntad (BSE – English 2  Year)
                 rd
                                                                                                                                            nd
                3  Place – Php 300.00

                Awarding of the Best Research Paper                                         Prof. Luke P. Ty, Elaissa Monique M. Tenorio, Ian Shane B. Duais An
                                                                                         Interpretative Phenomenological Analysis of Social Media Use as a Catalyst of
                 st
                1  Place – Php 700.00                                                     Depressive Symptoms among Filipino Youth
                 nd
                2  Place – Php 500.00                                                            Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis. Mr. Joriel O. Perucho, Mr. Mark John O.
                 rd
                3  Place – Php 300.00                                                     Gadores, Ms. Princess Gia V. Perez, Ms. Honey Rose R. Quisto, Ms. Imee

                Awarding of the Best Paper Poster                                         M. Rosario, Ms. Rose Ann G. Volante Language Used by Market Vendors in
                                                                                                                    Bagtas Local Market
                                                                                                                                                  nd
                1  Place – Php 700.00                                                              Presentor: Mr. Joriel O. Perucho (BSE – English 2  Year)
                 st
                 nd
                2  Place – Php 500.00                                                        Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Mr. Jan Eric C. Rin, Ms. Khaila Diaz, Ms. Joanne
                 rd
                3  Place – Php 300.00                                                        Marie Magao, Ms. Jhoy Manalo, Ms. Mary Rose Morana Teenagers’
                                                                                           Sociolinguistic Competence in Using Politically Correct Terms: Sociocultural
                Distribution of Certificates of Attendance to Attendees                   Perspectives of the Gen Z Group in Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
                                                                                                                                                 nd
                                                                                                    Presentor: Mr. Jan Eric C. Rin (BSE – English 2  Year)
             CvSU Hymn                        Ms. Melona O. Igmasine                           Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Ms. Noren B. Alivia, Ms. Edilyn L. Alvarez, Ms.
                                              OSAS Coordinator, Tanza Campus                 Christine Jewel R. Gallos, Ms. Joanna Lei P. Lapig, Mr. Ramesis F.
                                                                                            Macabenta Acculturation Story of Sama Dilaut (Badjaos) in Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                               Presentor: Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis

                                                                                            Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Mr. John Mark D. Mirambel, Ms. Laurence Nunez,
                       Ms. Gerry Mae Silvero / Mr. Audreyson Borilla                      Ms. Kayla Buena, Ms. Elsa Coros, Ms. Temotea Omosura Millennial Terms
                               Program In-Charge / Moderators                             and Other Popular Terms Used in Social Media by Gen Z Youth:  21  Century
                                                                                                                                                       st
                                                                                                                  Filipino Language Terms
                                                                                                                                                     nd
                                                                                                Presentor: Mr. John Mark D. Mirambel (BSE – English 2  Year)
                                   THANK YOU.]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PART III                                                                PROGRAM PART IV


             12:00 NN - 1:00 PM               Lunch / Judging Of                               Ms. Charmaine T. Banag Development of Mobile Application in Sign
                                              Paper Posters                                                    Language Tutorial for Filipinos
                                                                                               Ms. Estellita A. Villa Achievement Motivation, Locus of Control and Study
             ENTRIES FOR POSTER PRESENTATION
             1. Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio Development and Validation of Arduino-based        Habits as Predictors of Mathematics Achievement of Freshman College
          General Physics II Laboratory Experiments for Computing Programs                                              Students

             2.  Dr.  Noel  B.  Manarpiis,  Mr.  Ariel  Lomuntad,  Ms.  Jenelyn  Bajo,  Ms.    Mr. John Daniel V. Cap-atan Forecasting At Risk Areas of Dengue in
          Kasselle  Branzuela,  Ms.  Grace  Ann  Brones,  Ms.  Janica  Bruno  Impact of   Cavite using Geographic Information System (GIS) and Time Series Analysis
          Language Ego to the Residents of Julugan V, Tanza Cavite
                                                                                             Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio Development and Validation of Arduino-based
             3.  Dr.  Noel  B.  Manarpiis.  Mr.  Joriel  O.  Perucho,  Mr.  Mark  John  O.    General Physics II Laboratory Experiments for Computing Programs
          Gadores, Ms. Princess Gia V. Perez, Ms. Honey Rose R. Quisto, Ms. Imee
          M. Rosario, Ms. Rose Ann G. Volante Language Used by Market Vendors in                        PRESENTATION OF EXTENSION WORKS
          Bagtas Local Market                                                                  REPORT OF EXTENSION PROGRAM IN THREE CAMPUSES

             4.  Dr.  Noel  B.  Manarpiis,  Mr.  Jan  Eric  C.  Rin,  Ms.  Khaila  Diaz,  Ms.   Ms. Roncesvalle J. Caipang Extension Experiences in General Trias City,
          Joanne Marie Magao, Ms. Jhoy Manalo, Ms. Mary Rose Morana Teenagers’           Cavite
          Sociolinguistic Competence in Using Politically Correct Terms: A Case Study
          on  Sociocultural  Perspectives  of  the  Gen  Z  Group  in  Pasong  Kawayan  II,   Mr. Ritch M. Banate Extension Experiences in Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          General Trias, Cavite
                                                                                         Ms. Pamela Daphne R. Busog Extension Experiences in Trece Martires City.
             5. Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Ms. Noren B. Alivia, Ms. Edilyn L. Alvarez, Ms.   Cavite
          Christine  Jewel  R.  Gallos,  Ms.  Joanna  Lei  P.  Lapig,  Mr.  Ramesis  F.
          Macabenta Acculturation Story of Sama Dilaut (Badjaos) in Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                            4:00 PM - 5:00 PM  ANNOUNCEMENT OF WINNERS / SNACKS
             6.  Dr.  Noel  B.  Manarpiis,  Ms.  John  Mark  D.  Mirambel,  Ms.  Laurence
          Nunez, Ms. Kayla Buena, Ms. Elsa Coros, Ms. Temotea Omosura Millennial                  Panellists’ Post Presentation Comments / Suggestions /
          Terms and Other Popular Terms Used in Social Media by Gen Z Youth: A Case                                Recommendations
                    st
          Study of 21  Century Filipino Language Terms
                                                                                            Closing Remarks: Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis
             1:00 PM            Presentation Of Faculty Research

             Prof. Noel A. Sedigo Surface Water Measurements and Carrying Capacity
          Assessment in Maragondon River Watershed, Cavite, Philippines                               Ms. Gerry Mae Silvero / Mr. Audreyson Borilla
                                                                                                              In-charge of the Ceremonies
               Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian Gender-based Differentiation among Public
             elementary Teachers of Cavite (to present progress report of her CvSU-
                                     budgeted research)]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                      Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                               T3 In-House Review 2019
                        Theme: “Empowering Communities through Research and Extension”


               Faculty Research Presentation

                       Name of Presenter                             Title                     Affiliation
                                                    Surface Water Measurements and Carrying
                                                                                                  T3
                       Prof. Noel A. Sedigo         Capacity Assessment in Maragondon River    Campuses
                                                         Watershed, Cavite, Philippines
                                                    Gender-based Differentiation among Public    Tanza
                    Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                         elementary Teachers of Cavite          Campus
                                                    Development of Mobile Application in Sign    Tanza
                     Ms. Charmaine T. Banag
                                                         Language Tutorial for Filipinos        Campus
                                                   Achievement Motivation, Locus of Control and
                                                                                                 Tanza
                       Ms. Estellita A. Villa       Study Habits as Predictors of Mathematics   Campus
                                                   Achievement of Freshman College Students
                                                     Forecasting At Risk Areas of Dengue in
                                                                                                 Tanza
                   Mr. John Daniel V. Cap-atan     Cavite using Geographic Information System   Campus
                                                         (GIS) and Time Series Analysis
                                                   Development and Validation of Arduino-based   Trece
                     Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio    General Physics II Laboratory Experiments for   Martires City
                                                             Computing Programs                 Campus


               Prepared by:


               MILDRED SEBASTIAN
               Research Coordinator


               Certified Correct:


               NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
               Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                      Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                               T3 In-House Review 2019
                        Theme: “Empowering Communities through Research and Extension”


               Collaborative Research Presentation

                       Name of Presenter                             Title                     Affiliation
                                                   Impact of Language Ego to the Residents of
                                                            Julugan V, Tanza Cavite

                      Mr. Ariel D. Lomuntad       Researchers: Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Mr. Ariel   Tanza
                    (BSE – English 2nd Year)                                                    Campus
                                                  Lomuntad, Ms. Jenelyn Bajo, Ms. Kasselle
                                                  Branzuela, Ms. Grace Ann Brones, Ms.
                                                  Janica Bruno
                                                   An Interpretative Phenomenological Analysis   Trece
                 Prof. Luke P. Ty, Elaissa Monique     of Social Media Use as a Catalyst of   Martires City
                  M. Tenorio, Ian Shane B. Duais
                                                   Depressive Symptoms among Filipino Youth     Campus
                                                   Language Used by Market Vendors in Bagtas
                                                                 Local Market
                                                   Researchers: Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis. Mr. Joriel
                      Mr. Joriel O. Perucho        O. Perucho, Mr. Mark John O. Gadores, Ms.     Tanza
                    (BSE – English 2nd Year)                                                    Campus
                                                    Princess Gia V. Perez, Ms. Honey Rose R.
                                                   Quisto, Ms. Imee M. Rosario, Ms. Rose Ann
                                                                  G. Volante
                                                    Teenagers’ Sociolinguistic Competence in
                                                   Using Politically Correct Terms: Sociocultural
                                                    Perspectives of the Gen Z Group in Pasong
                       Mr. Jan Eric C. Rin              Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite     General Trias
                    (BSE – English 2nd Year)
                                                   Researchers: Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Mr. Jan   City Campus
                                                     Eric C. Rin, Ms. Khaila Diaz, Ms. Joanne
                                                    Marie Magao, Ms. Jhoy Manalo, Ms. Mary
                                                                 Rose Morana
                                                   Acculturation Story of Sama Dilaut (Badjaos)
                                                                in Tanza, Cavite
                                                     Researchers: Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Ms.     Tanza
                      Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis
                                                    Noren B. Alivia, Ms. Edilyn L. Alvarez, Ms.   Campus
                                                   Christine Jewel R. Gallos, Ms. Joanna Lei P.
                                                        Lapig, Mr. Ramesis F. Macabenta
                                                    Millennial Terms and Other Popular Terms
                                                   Used in Social Media by Gen Z Youth:  21st
                                                        Century Filipino Language Terms
                Mr. John Mark D. Mirambel (BSE –   Researchers: Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Mr. John   Tanza
                        English 2nd Year)                                                       Campus
                                                   Mark D. Mirambel, Ms. Laurence Nunez, Ms.
                                                    Kayla Buena, Ms. Elsa Coros, Ms. Temotea
                                                                   Omosura


               Prepared by:                        Certified Correct:



               MILDRED SEBASTIAN                   NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
               Research Coordinator                Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                      Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                               T3 In-House Review 2019
                        Theme: “Empowering Communities through Research and Extension”

               Poster Presentation

                       Name of Presenter                        Title                     Affiliation
                                                     Development and Validation of
                                                   Arduino-based General Physics II    Trece Martires City
                     Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio
                                                      Laboratory Experiments for           Campus
                                                         Computing Programs
                  Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Mr. Ariel   Impact of Language Ego to the
                 Lomuntad, Ms. Jenelyn Bajo, Ms.
                Kasselle Branzuela, Ms. Grace Ann    Residents of Julugan V, Tanza      Tanza Campus
                                                               Cavite
                    Brones, Ms. Janica Bruno
                Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis. Mr. Joriel O.
               Perucho, Mr. Mark John O. Gadores,   Language Used by Market Vendors
                  Ms. Princess Gia V. Perez, Ms.                                        Tanza Campus
                Honey Rose R. Quisto, Ms. Imee M.       in Bagtas Local Market
                 Rosario, Ms. Rose Ann G. Volante
                                                       Teenagers’ Sociolinguistic
                Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Mr. Jan Eric   Competence in Using Politically
                C. Rin, Ms. Khaila Diaz, Ms. Joanne   Correct Terms: A Case Study on   General Trias City
                Marie Magao, Ms. Jhoy Manalo, Ms.   Sociocultural Perspectives of the      Campus
                       Mary Rose Morana            Gen Z Group in Pasong Kawayan
                                                        II, General Trias, Cavite
                Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Ms. Noren B.
                 Alivia, Ms. Edilyn L. Alvarez, Ms.   Acculturation Story of Sama Dilaut
                   Christine Jewel R. Gallos, Ms.      (Badjaos) in Tanza, Cavite       Tanza Campus
                Joanna Lei P. Lapig, Mr. Ramesis F.
                           Macabenta
                  Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, Ms. John   Millennial Terms and Other Popular
                 Mark D. Mirambel, Ms. Laurence     Terms Used in Social Media by
                Nunez, Ms. Kayla Buena, Ms. Elsa   Gen Z Youth: A Case Study of 21st    Tanza Campus
                  Coros, Ms. Temotea Omosura        Century Filipino Language Terms


               Prepared by:


               MILDRED SEBASTIAN
               Research Coordinator


               Certified Correct:


               NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
               Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[T3 In-house Review 2019
                        Theme: “Empowering Communities through Research and Extension”
                                        November 18, 2019, 7:00 AM – 5:00 PM
                                 Gen. Trias Manpower Building, South Square Village,
                                     Barangay Pasong Kawayan I, Gen. Trias City
































                              Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English students as
                                              they perform for the doxology.
































                       T3 Campus Administrator Prof. Noel A. Sedigo gives his welcome message.]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[Dr. Yolanda A. Ilagan, University Director for Research,
                                           as she delivers her keynote address.






































                       The Anglicists Guild as they entertain the participants by performing Cariñosa.]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[Dr. Yolanda A. Ilagan with the T3 Campus Officials as she
                                          receives her certificate of appreciation.

































                  Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian as she reads the rules and mechanics for the presentation of
                                        instructors/students collaborative research.]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[Mr. Ariel D. Lomuntad, second year BSEE student, as he presents their collaborative
                   research on the Impact of Language Ego to the Residents of Julugan V, Tanza Cavite.]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[Prof. Luke P. Ty, instructor from CvSU – Trece Martires City Campus, as he presents their
                collaborative research entitled An Interpretative Phenomenological Analysis of Social Media
                            Use as a Catalyst of Depressive Symptoms among Filipino Youth.]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[Mr. Joriel O. Perucho, second year BSEE student, as he presents their collaborative
                         research on Language Used by Market Vendors in Bagtas Local Market.]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[Mr. Jan Eric C. Rin, second year BSEE student, as he presents their collaborative research
                on Teenagers’ Sociolinguistic Competence in Using Politically Correct Terms: Sociocultural
                      Perspectives of the Gen Z Group in Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite.]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, instructor from CvSU – Tanza Campus, as he answers the query of
                   the panel about their collaborative research on the Acculturation Story of Sama Dilaut
                                               (Badjaos) in Tanza, Cavite.]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[Mr. John Mark D. Mirambel, second year BSEE student, as he presents their collaborative
                  research on Millennial Terms and Other Popular Terms Used in Social Media by Gen Z
                                                st
                                      Youth:  21  Century Filipino Language Terms.]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3 Campuses Administrator, as he presents his research on Surface
                Water Measurements and Carrying Capacity Assessment in Maragondon River Watershed,
                                                   Cavite, Philippines]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[Ms. Charmaine T. Banag, instructor from CvSU – Tanza Campus, as she presents her
                 research on the Development of Mobile Application in Sign Language Tutorial for Filipinos.]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[Ms. Estellita A. Villa, instructor from CvSU – Gen. Trias City Campus, as she presents her
                research on the Achievement Motivation, Locus of Control and Study Habits as Predictors of
                                Mathematics Achievement of Freshman College Students.]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[Mr. John Daniel V. Cap-atan, instructor from CvSU – Tanza Campus, as he presents his
                 research on Forecasting At Risk Areas of Dengue in Cavite using Geographic Information
                                         System (GIS) and Time Series Analysis.]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio, instructor from CvSU – Trece Martires City Campus, as he
               presents his research on the Development and Validation of Arduino-based General Physics
               II Laboratory Experiments for Computing Programs.]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[Ms. Roncesvalle J. Caipang, extension coordinator of CvSU – General Trias City Campus,
                  Mr. Ritch M. Banate, extension coordinator of CvSU – Tanza Campus, and Ms. Pamela
                 Daphne R. Busog, extension coordinator of CvSU – Trece Martieres City Campus, as they
                                   present the extension works of the three campuses.]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[Awarding of certificate of appreciation to the paper presenters.]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[Awarding of the best research paper.]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[Awarding of certificate of appreciation to the panelists.]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[The participants as they listen to each presenters.]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[SEMINARS ATTENDED]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                             Tanza Campus
                                                                          Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                            (046) 414 – 3979
                                                                            www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                         LIST OF CAPACITY BUILDING/TRAININGS ATTENDED BY ALL FACULTY MEMBERS
                                                                         January-December 2021

               College/Campus:  TANZA Campus

                     Type                                                                              Name of Faculty                         Online or
                   (Local or                   Title                   Sponsoring Agency                                          Date         Face-to-
                 International)                                                                     Member(s) Attended                          Face?
                                 Philippine Table Tennis                                                                       January 16,
                 National                                           1PhysEd.Ph                   Caballero, Jackielyn S.                     online
                                 Federation: Now and Beyond                                                                    2021
                                 Researchable Areas and Funding
                 Local           Opportunities for CvSU             Cavite State University -    Sebastian, Mildred A.         February      online
                                                                    CCAT Campus
                                                                                                                               26, 2021
                                 Researchers
                                                                    Philippine Press Institute,
                                                                    Pimentel Institute for
                 National        Media and Information Literacy     Leadership and               Ortigosa, Rein R.             February      online
                                                                    Governance, Hanns Seidel                                   27, 2021
                                                                    Foundation
                                 Level 2 Museum Mgt. Training for                                                              Feb 25, 26,
                                 HEIs : Transforming  University
                 National        Museums as Sites of Cultural                                    Ramos, Gil D.                 Mar. 4 5,     online
                                                                                                                               11,12,
                                 Education and Creativity Tourism                                                              26,26,31
                                 Destinations
                                                                    Cavite State University -                                  Feb. 17 &
                 Local           Training of the Trainers on GAD    Gender and Development       Tagle, Maria Cristina C.      18, March 3  online
                                                                    Resource Center                                            & 4, 2021]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[February 4
                                 Year-End Review and Strategic
                 Local                                               Cavite State University     Ramos, Gil D.                 and 22,       online
                                 Planning Workshop
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 Paradigm Shift: The Context of
                 Local           Technology Transfer in University   Cavite State University -   Sebastian, Mildred A.         March 5,      online
                                                                    CCAT Campus
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 Extension
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 Webinar on Sex and                                                                            March 8,
                 Local                                              Gender and Development       Tagle, Maria Cristina C.                    online
                                 Relationships                                                                                 2021
                                                                    Resource Center
                                                                                                 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.
                                 Delivery of Flexible Learning in                                Mojica, Ivory P.              March 12, 2021
                 Local           Higher Education in the New        Cavite State University      Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique  online
                                 Normal
                                                                                                     R.
                                 Humanizing Teaching and                                         Ortigosa, Rein R.             March 12,
                 Local                                              Cavite State University                                                  online
                                 Learning                                                        Sebastian, Mildred A.         2021
                                 Spread Korfball Around the                                                                    March 13,
                 National                                           1PhysEd.Ph                   Caballero, Jackielyn S.                     online
                                 Globe                                                                                         2021
                                 Building Community for Student                                                                March 19,
                 Local                                              Cavite State University      Sebastian, Mildred A.                       online
                                 Success                                                                                       2021
                                 Webinar on MOVs of Enhanced        Cavite State University -
                 Local           Gender Mainstreaming               Gender and Development       Tagle, Maria Cristina C.      March 23-     online
                                                                                                                               24, 2021
                                 Evaluation Framework               Resource Center
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 Local and International Laws and                                                              March 24,
                 National                                           Gender and Development       Tagle, Maria Cristina C.                    online
                                 Policies in line with COVID-19                                                                2021
                                                                    Resource Center
                                                                                                                               March 26,
                 Local           Student Assessment                 Cavite State University      Sebastian, Mildred A.                       online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 Library Online Resources and       De La Salle University -     Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique  March 27,
                 Local                                                                                                                       online
                                 Services Training                  Dasmariñas                       R.                        2021

                                 Fundamentals of Mixed Martial                                   Caballero, Jackielyn S.       April 10,
                 National                                           1PhysEd.Ph                                                               online
                                 Arts                                                            Denzo, John Derick R.         2021]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[International Association of
                                 Global Workshop on Functional                                                                 April
                 International                                      Physical Education and       Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 Fitness                                                                                       10,2021
                                                                    Sports Inc.
                                 Ju-Jitsu International Federation's
                                 Celebration of International Day   Ju-Jitsu International                                     April
                 International                                                                   Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 of Sport for Development and       Federation                                                 10,2021
                                 Peace
                                                                    International Association of
                                 International Webinar on Sports                                                               April
                 International                                      Physical Education and       Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 Medicine                                                                                      12,2021
                                                                    Sports Inc.
                                 Research Integrity and             University of the Philippines                              April 12,
                 National                                                                        Senaris, Joyce Erika S.                     online
                                 Plagiarism                         - Manila                                                   2021
                                 Introduction to Qualitative        MAXQDA: The Art of Data                                    April 14,
                 International                                                                   Sebastian, Mildred A.                       online
                                 Research with MAXQDA               Analysis                                                   2021
                                                                    Cavite Provincial Tourism                                  April 14,
                 Local           Kalutong Caviteño:e-Kwentuhan                                   Quezada, Jessica Avon C.                    online
                                                                    Office                                                     2021
                                 Kagitingan: The PVAO Historical    Department of National
                 National        Webinar Series Bridging the Past  Defense and Philippine        Ramos, Gil D                  April 15,     online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                                                                                 Denzo, John Derick R.
                                 and the Present                    Veterans Affairs Office
                                 Webinar on Gender Issues in        Cavite State University -    Saquin, Melona I.
                 Local           Safety and Health at the           Gender and Development       Senaris, Joyce Erika S.       April 15,     online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 Workplace                          Resource Center              Tagle, Maria Cristina C.
                                                                    EINS Consultancy/
                                                                    Philippine Association of                                  April 16,
                 National        Conjoint Analysis using SPSS       Researchers and Statistical   Sebastian, Mildred A.        2021          online
                                                                    Software Users in the
                                                                    Philippines
                                                                                                 Caballero, Jackielyn S.       April 17,
                 National        Coaching: Beyond Medals            1PhysEd.Ph                                                               online
                                                                                                 Denzo, John Derick R.         2021
                                                                    International Federation of
                                 Physical Culture and Social Well-  Physical Educaiton, Fitness                                April
                 International                                                                   Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 Being                              and Sports Science                                         17,2021
                                                                    Association
                                                                    D2L, Lemann, Lenovo,                                       April 17,
                 International   Teacher Tech Summit                                             Precia, Erika D.                            online
                                                                    Pango                                                      2021]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[International Association of
                                 International Webinar on                                                                      April
                 International                                      Physical Education and       Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 Pickleball                                                                                    18,2021
                                                                    Sports Inc.
                                 A systematic approach to           MAXQDA: The Art of Data                                    April 20,
                 International                                                                   Sebastian, Mildred A.                       online
                                 analyzing coded data               Analysis                                                   2021
                                 Homeroom Guidance, Career          Rex Academy in
                                 Guidance and Mental Health                                                                    April 21,
                 National                                           Cooperation with Far         Gaunia, Jonerizza L.                        online
                                 Programs in Schools: Overview,                                                                2021
                                 Rationale and Discussion           Eastern University
                                 Kagitingan: The PVAO Historical    Department of National
                 National        Webinar Series Bridging the Past  Defense and Philippine        Ramos, Gil D                  April 22,     online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 and the Present                    Veterans Affairs Office
                                                                                                 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.
                                 Strategies to Sustainable          Cavite State University -    Senaris, Joyce Erika S.       April 22,
                 Local                                                                                                                       online
                                 University Extension Program       CCAT Campus                  Banate, Ritch M.              2021
                                                                                                 Sebastian, Mildred A.
                                                                    EINS Consultancy/
                                                                    Philippine Association of
                                 Discriminant Analysis using                                                                   April 23,
                 National                                           Researchers and Statistical   Sebastian, Mildred A.                      online
                                 SPSS                                                                                          2021
                                                                    Software Users in the
                                                                    Philippines
                                 Love for Chabacano Dialect:        Cavite State University -                                  April 23,
                 Local                                                                           Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 Gems for People                    Cavite City Campus                                         2021
                                 Modern Tools for Scientists and    Cavite State University -                                  April 23,
                 Local                                                                           Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 Engineers                          CCAT Campus                                                2021
                                 Magpapabakuna ka ba? A
                                 Webinar Awareness and              Kalinga Day Care Center
                                 Understanding of Covid 19                                                                     April 24,
                 National                                           and UP Center for Women's  Tagle, Maria Cristina C.                      online
                                 Vaccines: Implication and          and Gender Studies                                         2021
                                 Considerations for Child
                                 Development Program
                                 School Sports Program in the                                    Caballero, Jackielyn S.       April
                 National                                           1PhysEd.Ph                                                               online
                                 New Normal                                                      Denzo, John Derick R.         24,2021]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[LHCN WEBINAR SERIES  2020-                                                                    April 26,
                 National        2021, SERIES 10: Remembering                                    Ramos, Gil D.                 2021          online
                                 World War II in Cavite
                                 Role of Yoga in Physical           International Association of
                 International   Education for School Children      Physical Education and       Denzo, John Derick R.         April         online
                                                                                                                               26,2021
                                 and Societal Growth                Sports Inc.
                                 Charting Progress: The Philippine
                 National        Economic History During the Post                                Ramos, Gil D.                 April 27,     online
                                 War Period                                                                                    2021
                                 Commemorative Talk on the
                 International   410th Founding Anniversary of                                   Ramos, Gil D.                 April 28,     online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 the University of Santo Tomas
                                                                    University of Santo Tomas
                                 Revolutionizing Sports with                                     Caballero, Jackielyn S.       April
                 National                                           Institute of Physical                                                    online
                                 Innovative Games                                                Denzo, John Derick R.         28,2021
                                                                    Education and Athletics
                                                                                                 Mojica, Ivory P.
                                                                                                 Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique
                                                                                                     R.
                                                                                                 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.
                                                                                                 Delgado, Jeffrey M.
                                 Bookkeeping and Financial          Cavite State University -    Senaris, Joyce Erika S.       April 29-30,
                 Local           Management for Small and           Tanza Campus                 Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.     2021          online
                                 Medium Enterprises (SMEs)
                                                                                                 Banate, Ritch M.
                                                                                                 Quezada, Jessica Avon C.
                                                                                                 Saquin, Melona I.
                                                                                                 Sebastian, Mildred A.
                                                                                                 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 Introduction to Data Analysis      College of Arts and                                        April 29,
                 Local                                                                           Precia, Erika D.                            online
                                 using MS Excel                     Sciences - Physical                                        2021
                                                                    Sciences Department
                                                                    Cavite State University -                                  April 29,
                 Local           New Normal in the Office Industry                               Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.                   online
                                                                    Gen. Trias City Campus                                     2021
                                 Sustainable and Collective Efforts  Cavite State University -                                 April 29,
                 Local                                                                           Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 to Address Climate Change          CCAT Campus                                                2021]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[EINS Consultancy/
                                                                    Philippine Association of
                 National        Cluster Analysis using SPSS        Researchers and Statistical   Sebastian, Mildred A.        April 30,     online
                                                                    Software Users in the                                      2021
                                                                    Philippines
                                 Conducting Research Towards        Cavite State University -                                  April 30,
                 Local                                                                           Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 Science Education                  CCAT Campus                                                2021
                                                                    Philippine Paralympic
                 National        Introduction to Para Cycling                                    Denzo, John Derick R.         May 1,2021  online
                                                                    Committee
                                 Think Outside the Box, "Utilizing
                 National        Outdoor Adventure Education in     1PhysEd.Ph                   Caballero, Jackielyn S.       May 1,        online
                                                                                                 Denzo, John Derick R.
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 the New  Normal"
                                 Kagitingan: The PVAO Historical    Department of National
                 National        Webinar Series Bridging the Past  Defense and Philippine        Ramos, Gil D                  May 6,        online
                                 and the Present                    Veterans Affairs Office                                    2021
                                 Incorporating Fitness Into Sports
                 National                                           1PhysEd.Ph                   Denzo, John Derick R.         May 8,2021  online
                                 Practices in the New Normal
                                                                    Philippine Paralympic
                 National        Introduction to Para Triathlon                                  Denzo, John Derick R.         May 8,2021  online
                                                                    Committee
                                                                    EINS Consultancy/
                                 Multivariate Statistical           Philippine Association of
                 National        Techniques for Correlational       Researchers and Statistical   Sebastian, Mildred A.        May 9,        online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 Research (PART III)                Software Users in the
                                                                    Philippines
                                 Webinar on “Seeing through
                 Local           Misinformation: Combating the                                   Saquin, Melona I.             May 11,       online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 Fake News Online
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 Webinar Series on Responsible                                                                 May 13,
                 Local                                              Gender and Development       Navida, Allan L.                            online
                                 Parenthood                                                                                    2021
                                                                    Resource Center
                                 Methods in Teaching Dance  in                                                                 May 15,
                 National                                           1PhysEd.Ph                   Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 New Normal                                                                                    2021
                                                                    Polytechnic University of
                                 Yes to Mindfulness: Discovering                                                               May 15,
                 National                                           the Philippines Graduate     Gaunia, Jonerizza L.                        online
                                 your own Power                                                                                2021
                                                                    School]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[Empowering Youth Resiliency        Cavite State University -    Costa, Haizel Anne M.         May 17-20,
                 Local           amidst Pandemic through Culture    Tanza Campus                 Pitagan, Charles Vincent C.  2021           online
                                 and Arts.
                                                                    Philippine Health Research
                                                                    Ethics Board and Philippine                                May 20-21,
                 Local           Basic Research Ethics Training                                  Senaris, Joyce Erika S.                     online
                                                                    Council for Health Research                                2021
                                                                    and Development
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 Training of Traners on Anti-                                                                  May 24, 25
                 National                                           Gender and Development       Tagle, Maria Cristina C.                    online
                                 Human Trafficking Advocacy                                                                    & 26, 2021
                                                                    Resource Center
                                                                    EINS Consultancy/
                                 Validation of Test and Likert-Type  Philippine Association of
                 National        Questionnaires using Rasch         Researchers and Statistical   Sebastian, Mildred A.        May 29-30,    online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 Approach                           Software Users in the
                                                                    Philippines
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 Error Pattern Analysis and         College of Arts and                                        May 19,
                 Local           Designing  Remedial                Sciences - Physical          Precia, Erika D.              2021          online
                                 Interventions in Mathematics
                                                                    Sciences Department
                                 5S: A Waste Management                                                                        May 20,
                 Local                                                                           Saquin, Melona I.                           online
                                 Process                                                                                       2021
                                                                                                 Delgado, Jeffrey M.
                                                                                                 Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.
                                                                                                 Banate, Ritch M.
                                                                                                 Saquin, Melona I.
                                                                                                 Ortigosa, Rein R.
                                 Behind the Webcam: Reaching,
                                 Supporting and Empowering          Cavite State University -    Sebastian, Mildred A.         May 21,
                 Local                                                                           Silvero, Gerry Mae T.                       online
                                 Students and Faculty During        Tanza Campus                 Tagle, Maria Cristina C.      2021
                                 Pandemic
                                                                                                 Precia, Erika D.
                                                                                                 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.
                                                                                                 Sanchez, Micah M.
                                                                                                 Denzo, John Derick R.
                                                                                                 Mojica, Ivory P.]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique
                                                                                                     R.
                                                                                                 Quezada, Jessica Avon C.
                                                                                                 Senaris, Joyce Erika S.
                                 Resources Management for           Cavite State University -                                  May 21,
                 Local                                                                           Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 Efficient R and D Implementation   CCAT Campus                                                2021
                                                                    Philippine Guidance and
                                 The Filipino Counselor Amidst                                                                 May 21,
                 National                                           Counselling Association,     Peralta, Mary Gilianne R.                   online
                                 the Challenges of the Times                                                                   2021
                                                                    Inc.
                                                                    Association of
                                 Amplifying Tourism and             Administrators in
                                 Hospitality Students vigor amidst                                                             May 22,
                 Local                                              Hospitality, Hotel and       Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      online
                                 the Challenges of the Global       Restaurant Management                                      2021
                                 Pandemic
                                                                    Educational Institutions
                                                                                                 Caballero, Jackielyn S.       May 22,
                 National        Eazzy Hiphop during Pandemic       1PhysEd.Ph                                                               online
                                                                                                 Denzo, John Derick R.         2021
                                                                    Philippine Paralympic                                      May
                 National        Introduction to Para Obstacles                                  Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                                                    Committee                                                  22,2021
                                 LHCN WEBINAR SERIES  2020-
                                 2021, SERIES 11: Sustaining the                                                               May 24,
                 National                                                                        Ramos, Gil D.                               online
                                 Discussion on Philippine History                                                              2021
                                 and Culture During the Pandemic
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 An Awareness Session on            College of Arts and                                        May 26,
                 Local                                                                           Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      online
                                 Intellectual Property              Sciences - Physical                                        2021
                                                                    Sciences Department
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 IP IGNITE: An awareness            College of Arts and          Precia, Erika D.              May 26,
                 Local                                                                           Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 Session on Intellectual Property   Sciences - Physical          Saquin, Melona I.             2021
                                                                    Sciences Department
                                 Maintaining Honesty and Integrity                                                             May 27,
                 Local                                              Cavite State University      Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 in Public Service                                                                             2021
                                 Sports Performance Session 1:      International Federation of                                May
                 International                                                                   Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 Sports Science: New                Physical Educaiton, Fitness                                29,2021]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[Approaches, Strategies, and        and Sports Science
                                 Pedagogy                           Association
                                 Educators' Wellbeing Amidst the                                                               May 30,
                 National                                           Youth on the Rock            Ortigosa, Rein R.                           online
                                 New Normal                                                                                    2021
                                                                    Cavite State University -
                                 Webinar Series on Responsible                                                                 May 12, 19,
                 Local                                              Gender and Development       Tagle, Maria Cristina C.                    online
                                 Parenthood                                                                                    & 20, 2021
                                                                    Resource Center
                                 Literary Arts during Virtual       Cavite State University -                                  May 17 -
                 Local                                                                           Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      online
                                 Culture and Arts Festival 2021     Tanza Campus                                               20, 2021
                                                                                                                               June 1,
                 Local           On Becoming A Teacher                                           Navida, Allan L.                            online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 Professional Development of
                                 Aspiring Hospitality and Tourism   Cavite State University -                                  June 1,
                 Local                                                                           Elamparo, Mary Rose E.                      online
                                 Professionals in a Multi-cultural   Gen. Trias City Campus                                    2021
                                 Industry amidst Pandemic
                                 Innovative Approaches to           Philippine Normal University
                                 Education: Crafting                - College of Graduate                                      June 5,
                 National                                                                        Silvero, Gerry Mae T.                       online
                                 Technologically-Based              Studies and Teacher                                        2021
                                 Instructional Materials            Education Research
                                 Overview of Psychological First                                                               June 5,
                 Local                                                                           Sanchez, Micah M.                           online
                                 Aid                                                                                           2021
                                                                    International Federation of
                                 Teaching Sports Strategies: A      Physical Educaiton, Fitness                                June
                 International                                                                   Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 Road to Sports Performance         and Sports Science                                         5,2021
                                                                    Association
                                                                                                                               June
                 National        The How of Creating a Dance        1PhysEd.Ph                   Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                                                                                                               5,2021
                                                                    Philippine Press Institute,
                                                                    Pimentel Institute for
                                 Pedagogical Competencies For                                                                  June 6,
                 National                                           Leadership and               Ortigosa, Rein R.                           online
                                 Online/Remote Learning Setup                                                                  2021
                                                                    Governance, Hanns Seidel
                                                                    Foundation
                                 Cavite State University Tanza      Cavite State University -                                  June 7,
                 Local                                                                           Galicha, Maria Kristina P.                  online
                                 Flairtending Competition 2021      Tanza Campus                                               2021]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[Polytechnic University of
                                 Cyberbullying and Roles of                                                                    June 7,
                 National                                           the Philippines Graduate     Gaunia, Jonerizza L.                        online
                                 Mental Health Professionals                                                                   2021
                                                                    School
                                 Teaching Philippine Folkdance                                                                 June
                 National                                           1PhysEd.Ph                   Denzo, John Derick R.                       online
                                 During Pandemic                                                                               12,2021
                                 Distance Learning Assessment:
                                 Monitoring and Evaluation of                                                                  June 13,
                 National                                           Youth on the Rock            Ortigosa, Rein R.                           online
                                 Learners’ Progress and                                                                        2021
                                 Achievement
                                                                    Philippine Normal University
                                 Turning Facebook Group into an     - College of Graduate                                      June 13,
                 National                                                                        Silvero, Gerry Mae T.                       online
                                 Online Classroom                   Studies and Teacher                                        2021
                                                                    Education Research
                                 Let’s Move Forward: Unboxing
                 International   the Opportunities of Hospitality                                Galicha, Maria Kristina P.    June 14,      online
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 and Tourism.
                                                                                                 Galicha, Maria Kristina P.
                                                                                                 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.
                                                                                                 Delgado, Jeffrey M.
                                 Product Distribution in the New    Cavite State University -                                  June 14,
                 Local                                                                           Apellanes, Johnny Rick S.                   online
                                 Normal                             Tanza Campus                                               2021
                                                                                                 Banate, Ritch M.
                                                                                                 Quezada, Jessica Avon C.
                                                                                                 Saquin, Melona I.
                                 Developing Problem Solving         Cavite State University -                                  June 2,
                 Local                                                                           Guban, Sarah Jane                           online
                                 Skills                             Tanza Campus                                               2021
                                 Discovering Modern Techniques
                 Local           in Teaching Literature in the 21st   Cavite State University -   Guban, Sarah Jane            June 4,       online
                                 Century Approach                   Tanza Campus                                               2021
                                 Teaching Values through            Cavite State University -                                  June 4,
                 Local                                                                           Guban, Sarah Jane                           online
                                 Literature in this time of Adversity  Tanza Campus                                            2021
                                 Differently Abled Students in an   Cavite State University -                                  June 8,
                 Local                                                                           Guban, Sarah Jane                           online
                                 Inclusive Classroom                Tanza Campus                                               2021
                                 Managing Student's and
                 Local           Teacher's Mental Health in the     Cavite State University -    Guban, Sarah Jane             June 8,       online
                                 New Normal                         Tanza Campus                                               2021]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[Level 2 Museum Mgt. Training for
                                 HEIs : Transforming  University                                                               June 16,
                 National        Museums as Sites of Cultural                                    Ramos, Gil D                  23, 30,       online
                                 Education and Creativity Tourism                                                              2021
                                 Destinations
                                                                                                 Tagle, Maria Cristina C.
                                                                                                 Delgado, Jeffrey M.
                                                                                                 Senaris, Joyce Erika S.
                                                                                                 Banate, Ritch M.
                                                                                                 Quezada, Jessica Avon C.
                                 Managing Teaching and Learning
                 Local           in the New Normal and Special      Cavite State University -    Saquin, Melona I.             June 2, 3     online
                                 Education                          Tanza Campus                 Mojica, Ivory P.              &4, 2021
                                                                                                 Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique
                                                                                                     R.
                                                                                                 Ortigosa, Rein R.
                                                                                                 Sebastian, Mildred A.
                                                                                                 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.
                 Local                                                                           Senaris, Joyce Erika S.
                                                                                                 Banate, Ritch M.
                                 Managing Government Policies                                    Sebastian, Mildred A.         July 22,      online
                                                                                                 Saquin, Melona I.             2021
                                                                                                 Banag, Debbie Rose T.
                 Local                                                                           Senaris, Joyce Erika S.
                                                                                                 Banate, Ritch M.
                                 Ubuntu Remote Connections and      Department of Information    Sebastian, Mildred A.         July 23,      online
                                 Essential Applications                                                                        2021
                                                                    and Communication            Saquin, Melona I.
                                                                    Technology and Cavite        Banag, Debbie Rose T.
                 Local                                              State University             Senaris, Joyce Erika S.
                                                                                                 Banate, Ritch M.
                                 LibreOffice: Free and Open                                                                    July 27,
                                 Source Productivity Suite                                       Sebastian, Mildred A.         2021          online
                                                                                                 Saquin, Melona I.
                                                                                                 Banag, Debbie Rose T.
                 Local                                                                           Senaris, Joyce Erika S.
                                 Exploring Basic Components of                                   Banate, Ritch M.              July 29,      online
                                 Google Suite                                                                                  2021
                                                                                                 Sebastian, Mildred A.]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[Saquin, Melona I.
                                                                                                 Banag, Debbie Rose T.
                 Local           Leveraging Data with Impactful     Cavite State University      Banate, Ritch M.              August 19,    online
                                 Infographics                                                                                  2021
                 International   Concepts and Components of         Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 20,    online
                                 Quantitative Research              Professionals                Son, Kristina D.              2021
                 International   Achieving Success Through          Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 21,    online
                                 Innovation                         Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 International   Communications and Leadership      Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 22,    online
                                 in the Workplace                   Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 International                                      Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 23,    online
                                 Leadership in Education
                                                                    Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 International   Intervention Strategies for        Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 24,    online
                                 Distance Learning                  Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 Local           Assessing Technology Maturity      Cavite State University      Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 via the Technology Readiness                                                                  August 24,
                                                                                                                               2021
                                 and Investment Readiness Level
                 International   Social Emotional Teaching and      Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 25,    online
                                 Learning Management                Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 International   Self-Empowerment for Young         Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 26,    online
                                 Professionals                      Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 Local           Networking for Collaborative       Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 27,    online
                                 Research and Development           Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 International   Significant and Dynamic change     Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 28,    online
                                 in Education                       Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 International                                      Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 29,    online
                                 Principles of Leading Change
                                                                    Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 International   Meeting the Challenges of the      Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 30,    online
                                 New Normal in School Education     Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                 International   Young Leaders Changing the         Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              August 31,    online
                                 World                              Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2021
                                                                    Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              September     online
                 International   Redefining Education
                                                                    Professionals                Son, Kristina                 1, 2021]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[2021 Employees Orientation         Cavite State University –    All Faculty Members           September     online
                 Local
                                 Cum Enhancement for Teachers       Tanza Campus                                               1, 2021
                 International   The Importance of Developing       Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              September     online
                                 the Skills of Young People         Professionals                Son, Kristina                 2, 2021
                 International   Importance of Co-curricular        Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.                            online
                                 Activities in Teaching and         Professionals                Son, Kristina                 September
                                                                                                                               3, 2021
                                 Learning Process
                 International   The Importance of Education in     Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              September     online
                                 the Society                        Professionals                Son, Kristina                 4, 2021
                 International   Educators Time and                 Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              September     online
                                 Management                         Professionals                Son, Kristina                 5, 2021
                 International   Social Empowerment Through         Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              September     online
                                 Education and Entrepreneurship     Professionals                Son, Kristina                 6, 2021
                 International                                      Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              September     online
                                 ICT Uses in Everwhere
                                                                    Professionals                Son, Kristina                 7, 2021
                 International   Productivity and Time              Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              September     online
                                 Management                         Professionals                Son, Kristina                 8, 2021
                 International   Authentic Assessment in            Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              October 1,    online
                                 Teaching and Learning Part 1       Professionals                                              2021
                 International   Acing the New Normal in            Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              October 3,    online
                                 Education                          Professionals                                              2021
                 International   Authentic Assessment in            Institute of Global          Banate, Ritch M.              October 4,    online
                                 Teaching and Learning Part 2       Professionals                                              2021
                 Local           Deceptive, Unfair,                 Department of Trade and      Banate, Ritch M.              October 5,    online
                                 Unconscionable Sales Acts or       Industry                                                   2021
                                 Practices and Entrepreneurial
                                 Mindset
                 Local           Extension Methods in the New       Cavite State University      Banate, Ritch M.              November      online
                                 Normal                                                          Villa, Estelita A.            10, 2021
                 Local           The Role of Teachers in            Cavite State University –    Tagle, Maria Cristina C.      December      online
                                 Promoting Multilingual Education:  Tanza Campus                 Delgado, Jeffrey M.           2, 2021
                                 Preparing the Pre-Service                                       Banate, Ritch M.
                                 Teachers in Multilingual                                        Mojica, Ivory P.
                                 Classroom Setting                                               Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique
                                                                                                     R.]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[Ortigosa, Rein R.
                                                                                                 Sebastian, Mildred A.
                                                                                                 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.
                                                                                                 Villa, Estelita A.
                 Local           Adapting, Evolving and Thriving    Cavite State University –    Tagle, Maria Cristina C.      December      online
                                 in Remote Learning and Coping      Tanza Campus                 Delgado, Jeffrey M.           3, 2021
                                 with the New Normal: Addressing                                 Banate, Ritch M.
                                 the Emotional and Mental Needs                                  Mojica, Ivory P.
                                 of the Students                                                 Mojica, Mary Joy Angelique
                                                                                                     R.
                                                                                                 Ortigosa, Rein R.
                                                                                                 Sebastian, Mildred A.
                                                                                                 Silvero, Gerry Mae T.
                                                                                                 Villa, Estelita A.
                 Local           The New Normal of Online           Cavite State University –    Banate, Ritch M.              December      online
                                 Business: Setting, Starting and    Tanza Campus                 Son, Kristina D.              16, 2021
                                 Selling                                                         Saquin, Melona I.
                                                                                                 Fabian, Debbie Rose B.
                                                                                                 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.
                 Local           Successful Digital Business        Cavite State University –    Banate, Ritch M.              December      online
                                 Strategies: Creating Online        Tanza Campus                 Son, Kristina D.              17, 2021
                                 Marketplace and Digital Supply                                  Saquin, Melona I.
                                 Management                                                      Fabian, Debbie Rose B.
                                                                                                 Elamparo, Mary Rose E.



               Prepared by:                                       Certified Correct:


               CHARMAINE T. BANAG                                 GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Campus Secretary                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                                                  414-3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                                            www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                                          TANZA CAMPUS

                                                        LIST OF SEMINARS ATTENDED BY FACULTY MEMBERS
                                                                      JANUARY TO OCTOBER 2020

              TITLE OF TRAINING/                NATURE OF                    PARTICIPANTS                      VENUE                    INCLUSIVE DATES
                   SEMINAR                    PARTICIPATION
          Teacher’s Capability Enhance                                     Mildred A. Sebastian        Hostel Tropicana, Cavite
           Seminar Workshop for CvSU         Resource Speakers              Gerry Mae Silvero               State University             February 12, 2020
             Gen. Trias City Campus                                           Ivory M. Mojica
          Teacher’s Capability Enhance                                     Mildred A. Sebastian        Hostel Tropicana, Cavite
           Seminar Workshop for CvSU         Resource Speakers              Gerry Mae Silvero               State University             February 13, 2020
                 Tanza Campus                                                 Ivory M. Mojica
                  Women 2020                                                                          World Trade Center, Pasay
            Entrepreneurship Summit               Participant              Debbie Rose Banag                  City, Manila                 March 3, 2020
           Rapid Transitioning to Hybrid
          Education in the Age of Covid           Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 16, 2020
           Understanding and Enabling
               the Millennials in the             Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 18, 2020
              Educational Workplace
             Effective Online Learning
            Guidelines for Emergency              Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 20, 2020
                    Situations
             The Future of Instruction            Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 21, 2020
                     Design
           From Physical to Virtual: The          Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 22, 2020
             Shift to Online Teaching
            Flexible Classes: How Do              Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 23, 2020
                   They Work?
            Distance Learning: Online
            Teaching Techniques and               Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 25, 2020
                   Approaches]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[TITLE OF TRAINING/                NATURE OF                    PARTICIPANTS                      VENUE                    INCLUSIVE DATES
                   SEMINAR                    PARTICIPATION
              How To Plan A Virtual               Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 27, 2020
                   Classroom
               Educational Policy:
               Understanding and                  Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 29, 2020
           Addressing Compliance Gap
              Developing Self-paced
             Learning Through Digital             Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     April 30, 2020
                     Content
           Understanding and Using the
           Genre-process Approach in              Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     May 12, 2020
                  Writing Tasks
             Webinar on Redesigning
          Classroom based Lessons for             Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Zoom                       May 13, 2020
                 Online Learning
             Privacy, Plagiarism and
           Proper Information in Online           Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     May 14, 2020
                    Teaching
                                                                               Jonna Matel
            Integrating Assessment in
            Developing Online Lesson             Participants              Mildred A. Sebastian                Webinar                     May 19, 2020
                                                                            Gerry Mae Silvero
            Integrating Assessment in                                          Ivory Mojica
           Developing an Online Lesson           Participants           Mary Joy Angelique Mojica               Online                     May 20, 2020
             Managing Life’s Crisis: A            Participant              Mary Rose Elamparo                  Webinar                     May 21, 2020
              Leadership Challenge
             Online Basic Bartending              Participant              Mary Rose Elamparo                  Webinar                     May 22, 2020
                    Seminar
            Equip oneself to meet the
            Trends for the New Normal
           The Hospitality and Tourism            Participant              Mary Rose Elamparo                  Webinar                     May 22, 2020
               Industry Perspective
            Webinar on How Can We
            Revolutionize the Future of           Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Zoom                       May 23, 2020
                    Education
           Receiving and Responding to           Participants                  Jonna Matel                     Webinar                     May 25, 2020
            Workplace Communication                                         Gerry Mae Silvero]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[TITLE OF TRAINING/                NATURE OF                    PARTICIPANTS                      VENUE                    INCLUSIVE DATES
                   SEMINAR                    PARTICIPATION
              Alignment of Different
             Learning Tasks To Most               Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     May 25, 2020
                Essential Learning
                  Competencies
             Contextualized Learning              Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     May 27, 2020
               Delivery Modalities
           Addressing the Challenges in
           Leading the School to Online           Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     May 28, 2020
              Teaching and Learning
            Addressing Challenges in
           Delivering Remote Learning             Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     May 28, 2020
               for Offline Learners
                                                                               Jonna Matel
           Designing Student-Centered                                          Ivory Mojica
              Assessment in Flexible             Participants           Mary Joy Angelique Mojica              Webinar                     May 29, 2020
                    Learning                                               Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                                            Gerry Mae Silvero
                Merging Learning
           Competencies and Practices             Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     May 29, 2020
           to Facilitate the Shift to New
                     Normal
             Leadership Challenge &
           Virtual Management Teams               Participant              Mary Rose Elamparo                  Webinar                     May 29, 2020
             Infection Prevention and
             Control in Housekeeping              Participant              Mary Rose Elamparo                  Webinar                     May 29, 2020
               Key Consideration in
              Designing Modules for               Participant               Haizel Anne Costa                   WebEx                      June 2, 2020

                Distance Learning
          Modular Distance Learning: A                                                                                                     June 3, 2020
           Key in Developing Learner's            Participant               Haizel Anne Costa                   WebEx
                    Autonomy
           Bite Size Distance Learning                                                                                                     June 4, 2020
            through Practical Modulae             Participant               Haizel Anne Costa                   WebEx
                    Approach
             EduTECHAsia Webinar:
           Effective Online Learning at           Participant               Ma. Cristina Tagle                Singapore                    June 4, 2020
                      Scale]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[TITLE OF TRAINING/                NATURE OF                    PARTICIPANTS                      VENUE                    INCLUSIVE DATES
                   SEMINAR                    PARTICIPATION
            Conducting Assessment on              Participant               Haizel Anne Costa                   WebEx                      June 5, 2020
            Online Distance Learning
           Webinar: Technology-Based
          Instruction in Online Teaching          Participant               Ma. Cristina Tagle            New York, NY, US                 June 6, 2020
                                                                               Jonna Matel
             Planning, Designing and
           Delivering Course Materials           Participants           Mary Joy Angelique Mojica              Webinar                     June 8, 2020
                                                                           Mildred A. Sebastian
               for Flexible Learning
                                                                            Gerry Mae Silvero
              Designing Instructional
          Modules for Remote Learning             Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     June 11, 2020
            Choosing Developmentally
           Appropriate Materials Across           Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     June 15, 2020
                   Age Groups
              Home-Based Learning
            Unwired: No Gadgets, No               Participant                Ritch M. Banate                   Webinar                     June 17, 2020
                     Internet
             Establishing Educational
           Discipline in Homeschooling            Participant              Mary Rose Elamparo                  Webinar                     June 17, 2020
           Online Pedagogy: Embracing
           the Virtual Classroom Amidst          Participants           All Tanza Faculty Members               WebEx                      June 22, 2020
                 a Global Crisis
          Course Development Process             Participants           All Tanza Faculty Members               WebEx                      June 23, 2020
           Conceptualization, Use and
           Creation of Self made Videos           Participant              Mary Rose Elamparo                  Webinar                     June 23, 2020
               for Online Teaching
              Creating Engaging and
             Interactive Power Point             Participants           All Tanza Faculty Members               WebEx                      June 24, 2020
                  Presentation
            Teaching and Learning in
           Distance e-Learning Mode of           Participants           All Tanza Faculty Members               WebEx                    June 25-26, 2020
                   Instruction
              Designing Instructional
           materials using TV and Radio           Participant              Mary Rose Elamparo                  Webinar                     June 26, 2020
             as Platforms in Teaching
            WE, ELF, EII., GE: Some
           Pedagogical Implications for           Participant                Audreyson Borilla                 Webinar                     June 27, 2020
              ELT in the Philippines]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[TITLE OF TRAINING/                NATURE OF                    PARTICIPANTS                      VENUE                    INCLUSIVE DATES
                   SEMINAR                    PARTICIPATION
             E-module Development                Participants           All Tanza Faculty Members               WebEx                      June 29, 2020
             Strategic Way of Making
            Continuous Learning Plan              Participant              Mildred A. Sebastian                 Online                     June 29, 2020
            Webinar on Supplementary
             Learning Materials in the            Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Online                      July 1, 2020
           Fourth Industrial Revolution
             Webinar on Embedding
             Pedagogy and Blending
             EdTech Solutions in the              Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Online                      July 2, 2020
           Learning Design of a Virtual
             Classroom: A Retrospect
           Redesigning Course Syllabi
               for Flexible Learning              Participant                Ritch M. Banate                    Online                      July 2, 2020
                  Arrangement
           Creating Videos for Teaching
             and Learning in the New              Participant                Ritch M. Banate                    Online                      July 3, 2020
                     Normal
              Webinar on Designing
             Supplementary Reading                Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Online                      July 3, 2020
               Materials based on
             Constructivist Approach
            Curriculum Planning in the
           New Normal: Reconciling the            Participant              Mildred A. Sebastian                 Online                      July 5, 2020
                MELCs with Kto12
                   Standards"
           Migrating to Online Learning          Participants                Ritch M. Banate                    Online                      July 6, 2020
                                                                          Mary Rose E. Elamparo
              Webinar on Changing
           Perspective: Homeschooling             Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Online                     July 10, 2020
               in the Digital World
          Offline Resources for Remote            Participant             Debbie Rose T. Banag                  Online                     July 14, 2020
              Teaching and Learning
              "Importance of Socio-
           Emotional Well-Being During            Participant              Mildred A. Sebastian                 Online                     July 15, 2020
                  Early Years"
             The "Doing" of Learning"             Participant              Mildred A. Sebastian                 Online                     July 15, 2020]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[TITLE OF TRAINING/                NATURE OF                    PARTICIPANTS                      VENUE                    INCLUSIVE DATES
                   SEMINAR                    PARTICIPATION
              "Importance of Socio-
           Emotional Well-Being During            Participant              Mildred A. Sebastian                 Online                     July 15, 2020
                  Early Years"
                                   st
             National Webinar on 21
               Century Educators:
             LEARNING TO TEACH                    Participant             Debbie Rose T. Banag                  Online                     July 17, 2020
                    ONLINE
             Webinar entitled Beyond
                Borders: Research
              Challenges for Filipino             Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Online                     July 18, 2020
                    Scientists
             Webinar on Independent
            English Learning at Home              Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Online                     July 22, 2020
             Webinar on Developing
           Social Awareness and Civic-
           Mindedness among Learners              Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Online                     July 23, 2020
              through Social Inquiry
                    Approach
           Webinar entitled Getting your         Participants             Joyce Erika S. Senaris                Online                     July 28, 2020
                Papers Published                                           Mildred A. Sebastian
               Active Listening and
             Responding to Children               Participant              Mildred A. Sebastian                 Online                     July 28, 2020
           A Convenient Truth: Rewiring
            Education During the New              Participant             Debbie Rose T. Banag                  Online                     July 31, 2020
               Normal and Beyond
          Hacks, Facts, and Challenges
              of a YouTube Content                Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris               FB Live                    August 4, 2020
                     Creator
             Handling Student Online              Participant              Mildred A. Sebastian            Virtual (FB LIve)              August 6, 2020
                   Misbehavior
            Practical Ways to Promote
             and Enhance Learning at
              Home: From Limited to               Participant             Joyce Erika S. Senaris               FB Live                    August 7, 2020
            Prolific Technology Use at
                     Home”]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[TITLE OF TRAINING/                NATURE OF                   PARTICIPANTS                      VENUE                    INCLUSIVE DATES
                    SEMINAR                    PARTICIPATION
               The Art of Questioning:
                                                                           Mildred A. Sebastian
           Developing Critical Thinking at        Participants            Joyce Erika S. Senaris           Virtual (FB LIve)              August 10, 2020
                       Home
                 Synchronous and
           Asynchronous Assessment for
           Beginning and Critical Reading          Participant            Joyce Erika S. Senaris               FB Live                    August 11, 2020
                       Skills
           Emotive and Inspiring Methods
            for Orientation of Parents and         Participant            Joyce Erika S. Senaris               FB Live                    August 17, 2020
                     Students
           Practical Checklist to Find Out
           Our Readiness for the Opening           Participant            Joyce Erika S. Senaris               FB Live                    August 18, 2020
             of School Year 2020-2021
              Preparing the Mindset of
            Teachers Towards Distance              Participant            Joyce Erika S. Senaris               FB Live                    August 19, 2020
                     Education
              Government Guidelines:
           Ensuring Safety of Everyone for         Participant            Joyce Erika S. Senaris               FB Live                    August 21, 2020
            the Opening of School Year
                    2020-2021
            Getting to Know Each Other:
            How Teachers can Creatively
              Facilitate Knowing their             Participant             Mildred A. Sebastian            Virtual (FB LIve)              August 22, 2020
                     Learners
             E-Mentoring on the Use of            Participants                  All Faculty                 Virtual (Webex)               August 24, 2020
             CvSU e-Learning System
               G-Suite for Online for
           Education: Migrating to Online         Participants                  All Faculty                 Virtual (Zoom)                August 27, 2020
               Learning Using Google
                    Classroom
           Guide Preparation and Course           Participants                  All Faculty                 Virtual (Zoom)                August 28, 2020
               Material Development
           Capacity Building on the Use of        Participants                  All Faculty                 Virtual (Webex)               August 31, 2020
               G-Suite for Education
               GNED 02 Orientation                 Partcipant              Jonerizza L. Gaunia               CiscoWebex                 September 1, 2020
            2020 Orientation Program for           Participant                  All Faculty                  CiscoWebex                 September 2, 2010
                 Faculty Members]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[TITLE OF TRAINING/                NATURE OF                   PARTICIPANTS                      VENUE                    INCLUSIVE DATES
                    SEMINAR                    PARTICIPATION
                 Faculty Orientation              Participants                  All Faculty                   Via Zoom                  September 3, 2020
            Revitalizing Education for the
           Emerging Normal and Beyond"             Participant            Joyce Erika S. Senaris          Via Facebook Live             September 4, 2020
            Parents and Students Virtual
            Orientation on the CvSU T3
            Campuses Implementation of            Participants                  All Faculty               Via Facebook Live             September 5, 2020
          Flexible Learning Delivery Mode
           Capacity Building on the Use of        Participants                  All Faculty                   Via Zoom                 September 9-11, 2020
                Gsuite for Education
           Gourmazing na Negosyo, Kita                                         Ritch Banate
             ay Sigurado: A Webinar on                                    Jan Edizon J. De Silva
           Gourmet Tinapa and Alamang              Participant            Mary Rose E. Elamparo               14-Sep-20                  Via Facebook live
                    Processing                                           Maria Kristina P. Galicha
               Orientation on AACUP               Participants                  All Faculty                   Via Zoom                  September 16, 2020
                 Accreditation Visit
                Creating Diagnostic
           Assessment Tools for Listening          Participant             Mildred A. Sebastian           Via Facebook Live             September 16, 2020
                     Capacity
            School-Based Entry and Exit
             Assessment Tools for Each             Participant             Mildred A. Sebastian           Via Facebook Live             September 17, 2020
                Learning Key Stage
            Parents and Students Virtual
            Orientation and Reorientation         Participants                  All faculty               Via Facebook Live             September 21, 2020
                      (Part II)
            Using Blogs, Vlog, and other
            Online Platforms for Student           Participant            Joyce Erika S. Senaris          Via Facebook Live             September 21, 2020
                   Interest Clubs
              Homeroom for Distance                Participant            Joyce Erika S. Senaris          Via Facebook Live             September 22, 2020
                    Education"

         Prepared by:                                              Certified Correct


         CHARMAINE T. BANAG                                        MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
         MIS Officer                                               OIC-Campus Coordinator]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                 TANZA ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                               LIST OF SEMINARS ATTENDED BY FACULTY MEMBERS
                                             APRIL TO SEPTEMBER 2019


                     TITLE OF THE
                SEMINAR/WORKSHOP/               PARTICIPANT           DATE AND VENUE            LEVEL
               TRAINING/CONFERENCE
               Pre-employment Seminar       Faculty Member with     April 1, 2019 at SM       Local
               2018: Understanding          Graduating Classes      Rolle Hall, CvSU-Don
               Career Opportunities: A                              Severino de las alas
               Big Step to Start Your                               Campus
               Future

               CvSU Form and Style for      T3 Faculty Members      April 5, 2019 at          Local
               Manuscript Writing                                   Quadrangle, CvSU-
                                                                    Main Campus

               CvSU Form and Style          Lucky Cedrick           April 5, 2019 at BioSci   Local
               Refresher Seminar            Guyamin                 Conference Hall, CvSU
               Workshop for Accredited      Czerina Mae Antonio     –Main Campus
               English Critics              Arlene L. Estrada
                                            Jessie Anne T.
                                            Demetillo
                                            Kristel Shane
                                            Paminter
                                            Arvin Flores
                                            Mildred Sebastian
                                            Ricth Banate
                                            Erika Joyce Senaris
                                            Melona Igmasine
                                            Alellie Diato
                                            Roncesvalles J.
                                            Caipang
                                            Shane Hayag
               Blockchain Workshop for      Keno A. Villavicencio   April 10-11, 2019 at      Local
               Teachers                     Pamela Daphne R.        Activity Area,
                                            Busog                   LEENTech Network
                                            Joyce Erika S.          Solution, General Trias
                                            Senaris                 City
                                            Charmaine Banag

               International Seminar-       Jessie Anne T.          April 13-14, 2019 at      International
               workshop on Innovative       Demetillo               YMCA, Ermita, Manila
               and Effective Classroom
               Technology]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[TITLE OF THE
                SEMINAR/WORKSHOP/               PARTICIPANT           DATE AND VENUE            LEVEL
               TRAINING/CONFERENCE
               Teaching and Research: A  Jessie Anne T.             April 14, 2019 at         International
               Take-off in the Field of     Demetillo               Microtel, General Trias
               Instruction                  Jelyn Digma             City
                                            Arlene L. Estrada
                                            Vienna Mi A. Feranil
                                            Cristza d.O. Manlapig
                                            Lillian Sidamon
                                            Kristel Shane C.
                                            Paminter

               1st Cavite Arduino           IT Instructors          April 22, 2019 at SM      Local
               Technology Research                                  Rolle Hall, CvSU-Main
               Forum and Exhibit                                    Campus

               Two-day Training on          Jessie Ann T.           April 27-28, 2019 at      National
               Rasch Modeling:              Demetillo               Manila Grand Opera
               Development and                                      Hotel, Manila
               Validation of Multiple
               Choice Test and Likert-
               Type Questionnaire

               Disaster Risk Reduction      Sheryl Dungo            July 3-4, 2019 at Rolle   Local
               Management Seminar           Rommel Sarreal          Hall, CvSU Main
                                                                    Campus

               Innovation Management        Keno A. Villavicencio   July 11, 2019 at          National
               Seminar                                              PTTC GMEA, Pasay
                                                                    City

               Creative Nation Certified    Keno A. Villavicencio   July 19, 2019 at          National
               Specialist: Xontent                                  Creative Nation
               Creation using Spark                                 Academy, Pasig City

               Baybayin Buhayin             Gideon Luke P. Ty       July 28, 2019 at          National
               Seminar-Workshop                                     Museo ni Manuel
                                                                    Quezon, Quezon City

               Livelihood Training on       Cristina Ballano        September 7, 2019 at
               Embutido and Candle          Mary Ann Palomar        MSF Bldg. CvSU-
               Making                       Estelita Villa          General Trias City
                                            Marlon Sacopanio Jr.    Campus
                                            Jessica Enriquez
                                            Genisa Antonio
                                            Cleafere Nocon
                                            John Riel Labiang
                                            Queency Colocado
                                            Mey Gesulga
                                            Alelie Diato]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[TITLE OF THE
                SEMINAR/WORKSHOP/               PARTICIPANT           DATE AND VENUE            LEVEL
               TRAINING/CONFERENCE
               T3 Entrepreneurial Day       Cristza D.O. Manlapig  September 7. 2019 at       Local
               2019                         Jessie Anne T.          S.M. Role Hall, CvSU –
                                            Demetillo               main campus
                                            Lilian O. Sidamon
                                            Debbie Rose Banag
                                            Melona O. Igmasine
                                            Ritch M. Banate
                                            April Gile
                                            Cheyne Banongon
                                            Kayceline Marjorie
                                            Gambon Sheryl
                                            Dungo Antonio
                                            Frederick Pellano

               56  Annual Convention of     Gideon Luke P. Ty       September 18-20, 2019  National
                  th
               the Psychological                                    at Ateneo de Davao
               Association of the                                   University
               Philippines

               International Design         Pamela Daphne R.        September 20, 2019 at     International
               Conference: Design           Busog                   The Eye, Green Sun,
               Futures                      Keno A. Villavicencio   Makati

               Seminar-Workshop in          Jessie Anne T.          September 20, 2019 at     Local
               Strengthening Instructional  Demetillo               International House I,
               Materials Development at     Charise Mae D. Galve  CvSU- Main Campus
               CVSU- T3Campus               Kristel Shane C.
                                            Paaminter
                                            Emerson G.
                                            Manlapaz
                                            Cristza C. D.O.
                                            Manlapig
                                            Lilian O. Sidamon
                                            Viena Mi A. Feranil
                                            Alexix D.
                                            Tumbagahan
                                            Khenilyn P. Lewis
                                            Ronel Asas
                                            Noel B. Manarpiis
                                            Gerry mae T. Silvero
                                            Mildred A. Sebastian
                                            Erwin M. Regio
                                            Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                            Ivory Mojica
                                            Ritch M. Banate
                                            Joyce Erika S.
                                            Senaris
                                            Charmaine T.Banag
                                            Cris Albert P. Cajigas
                                            Debbie Rose T.
                                            Banag April Gile]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[May Ann Palomar
                                            Katherine Magracia
                                            Roncesvalle Caipang
                                            Antonio Frederick
                                            Pellano
                                            Daniel Abuton
                                            Mary Joy Ignacio
                                            Sheryl Dungo
                                            Alelie Diato
               Cavite Entrepreneurship      Cristza D.O. Manlapig  24 Sept 2019 at            Local
               Students’ Conference         Jessie Anne T.          Provincial Gymnasium,
                                            Demetillo               Trece Martires City
                                            Lilian O. Sidamon
                                            Debbie Rose Banag
                                            Melona O. Igmasine
                                            Ritch M. Banate

               Seminar-Workshop on           Prof. Noel A. Sedigo   September 26-28, 2019  National
               Research Publication in
               Scopus/Web of
               Science/Journal Incentive
               Program/ASEAN Citation
               Indexed Journals

               PAFTE Pre-Service            Gerry Mae Silvero       September 27, 2019 at     Regional
               Teachers’ Congress 2019      Mildred Sebastian       Ynares Center Rizal
                                            Jessa Dinlasan
                                            Charise Mae Galve




               Prepared by:


               CHARMAINE T. BANAG
               MIS Officer



               Certified Correct:


               CRIS ALBERT P. CAJIGAS
               Campus Coordinator]]></page><page Index="132"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                                                  414-3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                                            www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                                          TANZA CAMPUS

                                                        LIST OF SEMINARS ATTENDED BY FACULTY MEMBERS
                                                                    NOVEMBER TO DECEMBER 2019

                                                 NATURE OF
           TITLE OF TRAINING/ SEMINAR                                       PARTICIPANTS                          VENUE                   INCLUSIVE DATES
                                               PARTICIPATION
                                                                          Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                                          Gery Mae T. Silvero
                                                  Facilitators
                                                                          Audreyson h. Borilla
                 T3 In-house Review                                      Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis            General Trias City, Cavite      November 18, 2019
                                                                         Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis
                                              Research Presenters         Charmaine T. Banag
                                                                        John Daniel V. Cap-atan
            th
           4  National Research Conference    Research Presenter         Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis         Villa Caceres Hotel, Naga City     November 29, 2019
             on Arts, Science, and Health
                                                                                                         SM Rolle Hall, Cavite State
                 T3 Year-end Review               Participants            All Faculty Members                                             December 17, 2019
                                                                                                             University- Tanza



         Prepared by:


         CHARMAINE T. BANAG
         MIS Officer

         Certified Correct:


         CRIS ALBERT P. CAJIGAS
         Campus Coordinator]]></page><page Index="133"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>