<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="66"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.            The institution has an organizational


                        structure approved by the BOT/ BOR.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Extracted from CvSU website]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[2021 Organizational Structure]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[In this approved 2017 organizational structure Vice President for Research, Extension, Continuing
               Education and Trainings Services (VPRECETS) was renamed for Vice President for Research and
               Extension (VPRE); Knowledge Management Center was created and Executive Vice President position
               was abolished and Vice President for Planning and Development was created.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[FUNCTIONS, DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES of ADMINISTRATIVE AND
               ACADEMIC COUNCILS LIFTED FROM THE CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                           VOLUME I ARTICLE 7 – 13 ISBN NO.978-971-9032-65-6



               Article 7. Organization of the University


                       Section 1.  Organization.  The  Officers  of  the  Administration  of  the
                       University  shall  consist  of  the  University  President,  designated  Vice
                       presidents,  Administrative  Officer,  The  University  Secretary,  the
                       Deans,     the    Registrar,     and     other    current      members       of   the
                       Administrative Council, including other officers who may be  designated
               by the Board of Regents.



               Article 8. Officers of the University



                       Section  1.  The  University  President.  The  overall  administration  and
                          supervision  of  the  University  is  vested  on  the  President  who  must
                          render full-time service.



                       a)     Search  Committee.  The  University  President  shall  be  selected
                              and     appointed      by    the     Board     of    Regents      upon     the
                              recommendation of the Search Committee for the Presidency duly
                       constituted by the Commission on Higher Education   (CHED).


                              The composition, functions and the procedures in the selection to
                       be conducted by the Search Committee unless otherwise specified by the
                       Board of Regents shall conform to the provision of CHED MC. No.04, s.
                       1997 or any other latest legal documents on this matter.



                       b)     Qualification  of  the  University  President.  The  minimum
                              qualification of the University President shall be as follows:

                          1.  Must be at least forty (40) years old on the date of his   application
                       for the position;]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[2.  Must be a natural-born citizen of the Philippines;

                          3.  Must  be  academically  qualified,  preferably  holder  of  an  earned
                              doctorate degree;

                          4.  Must have relevant administrative experience of at least five  years;
                       and

                          5.  Must  possess  leadership  and  managerial  skills  within  the
                              purview  of  the  needs,  thrusts,  goals  and  objectives  of  the
                              University.


                              The  Board  of  Regents  may  prescribe  additional  qualifications  as
                       it deems fit.



                       c)     Term  of  Office.  The  University  President  shall  have  a  term  of
                              four  (4)  years,  the  beginning  and  end  of  which  must  be  clearly
                              specified  in  the  appointment  issued  by  the  Board  of  Regents.
                              The  University  President  shall  be  eligible  for  reappointment  for
                              another term only.


                              No search needs to be conducted if the incumbent is eligible and
                       qualified for reappointment as deemed by the Board of Regents.



                       d)     Vacancy.  In  case  of  vacancy  by  reason  of  death,  resignation,
                              removal  for  cause  or  incapacity  of  the  incumbent  President  to
                              perform  the  functions  of  his  office,  the  Board  of  Regents,
                              through the Board Chairman shall, within fifteen (15) days from
                              the occurrence of such vacancy, designate an Officer-in-Charge
                              (OIC) in the Office of the President.


                              In case a new President is appointed by the Board after a permanent
                       vacancy occurs in the Office of the President but during the term of office
                       of the original appointee, the new President as his

                       successor  shall  hold  office  for  the  unexpired  portion  of  the  term.  This
                       service for the unexpired term shall not, however, count one (1) full-term
                       for purpose of appointment / reappointment.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[e)     Powers  of  the  University  President.  The  President  shall  carry
                              out  the  general  policies  laid  down  by  the  Board  of  Regents  and
                              shall  have  the  power  to  act  within  the  limits  of  said  general
                              policies  and  in  accordance  with  his  specific  duties  and
                              responsibilities.


                       f)     Specific  Duties  and  Responsibilities.  The  specific  duties  and
                              responsibilities of the University President shall be as follows:

                          •  Direct or assign the details of executive action;

                          •  Act as ex-officio head of the University faculty;

                          •  Exercise general supervision of all business and financial operations
                              of the University;

                          •  Determine the agenda of all meetings of the Board of Regents, of the
                              Executive  Council,  and  of  the  Administrative  and  Academic
                              Councils; provided, however, that any member of among hereinafter
                              Councils shall be entitled to have any matter included in the agenda;

                          •  Preside  all  commencement  and  other  public  exercises  of  the
                              University and confer such degrees and honors as are granted by
                              the Board of Regents. All diplomas and certificates issued by the
                              University  shall  be  signed  by  the  President  and  attested  by  the
                              Registrar;

                          •  Act as the official medium of communication between the faculty,
                              staff, and students of the University on one hand, and the Board of
                              Regents on the other;

                          •  Appoint qualified and competent persons to fill all  vacancies and
                              new  positions  as  per  approved  criteria  of  recruitment  upon
                              recommendation of the appropriate recruitment / selection
                              board, to make such appointments necessary to meet  emergencies
                       occurring between meetings of the Board so that                 the work of the
                       University will not suffer, and to make special   appointments as are
                       permitted by the Board of Regents;

                          •  Grant or deny leaves of absence with pay or without pay  and/or
                              extension of such leaves or delegate the same to duly authorized
                              officer of the University;]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[•  Grant or deny extension of fellowships for a period not beyond one
                              academic year if the budget permits and for reasons he may deem
                              appropriate;

                          •  Approve/defer retirement of members of the faculty and employees
                              confirmed by the Board of Regents;

                          •  Authorize renewal of appointments for not more than one year if the
                              budget permits and the services are deemed necessary to make ad
                              interim appointments when the need of the service so requires;

                          •  Authorize  the  transfer/detail  of  faculty  members  and  employees
                              from  one  department  or  unit  of  the  University  to  another  or  to
                              another  educational  institution  in  accordance  with  their
                              specializations with the consent of the transferee and with proper
                              compensation;

                          •  Appoint qualified members of the faculty as fellows of the University
                              (full or partial) in order to enable them to pursue graduate studies
                              locally or overseas and to fix the financial assistance to any such
                              fellow  in  accordance  with  the  rules  promulgated  by  the  Board  of
                              Regents and within the lump sum appropriated for fellowships;

                          •  Grant  or  deny  permission  for  members  of  the  faculty  to  accept
                              training  grants,  fellowships,  scholarships,  assistantships,  or
                              invitations  to  conferences  sponsored  by  outside  agencies  or
                              organizations  without  any  financial  obligation  on  the  part  of  the
                              University outside of the regular salary of the person concerned;

                          •  Supervise  and  control  through  the  Dean  of  the  Student  Affairs,
                              extracurricular  activities  of  the  students;  and  to  issue  adequate
                              rules for their organizations and qualifications of officers;

                          •  In consultation with the head of the units concerned, initiate the
                              necessary disciplinary action against the erring personnel before an
                              appropriate investigating body;


                          •  Prepare and endorse annual report to the Board of Regents on the
                              work of the past year and the needs for the current year. He shall
                              also present to the Board the annual budget of the University with
                              estimates of income and expenditure;

                          •  Execute and sign, in behalf of the University, contracts, deeds and
                              other instruments necessary for the proper conduct of business of]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[the  University.  However,  in  regularly  recurring  undertakings  and
                              transactions  where  his  actions  is  virtually  ministerial,  conditions
                              and  terms  thereof  having  been  fixed  in  the  existing  University
                              regulations,  and  general  laws,  direct  through  appropriate  written
                              instruction that approval in specified cases be made in his behalf by
                              officers of administration or head of offices or units, subject to such
                              safeguards  he  may  impose.  All  existing  regulations  inconsistent
                              herewith are abrogated.

                          •  Enforce  discipline  in  the  University  for  the  maintenance  of
                              satisfactory academic standards in all units; and

                          •  Designate a ranking officer of the administration to act as Officer–
                              in–Charge  of  the  Office  of  the  President,  who  shall  carry  out  the
                              management  of  the  affairs  of  the  University  in  the  name  of  the
                              President, subject to his instruction and the policies of the board. In
                              this regard, the President shall initiate a policy on designation of
                              command-succession  for  the  University  and  for  each  of  the
                              individual major units.


                       Section 2.  The Vice President for Academic Affairs



                          a)  General  Functions.  There  shall  be  a  Vice  President  for
                              Academic  Affairs  to  be    designated  by  the  University  President
                              whose general functions shall be as follows:

                          •  Provide  leadership  and  direction  in  all  academic  and  related
                              programs of the University in curriculum and instruction as well as
                              student affairs;


                          •  Coordinate the academic programs, sports and recreation activities;
                              and

                          •  Represent  the  University  on  matters  of  academic  nature  with
                              appropriate agency, body or office whether in country or overseas
                              when so designated by the University President.

                          b)  Specific  Duties  and  Responsibilities.  The  specific  duties  and
                              responsibilities  of  the  Vice  President  for  Academic  Affairs  shall
                              be as follows:]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[•  Serve as Chairman of the Academic Council as well as any other
                              council  or  academic  advisory  body  when  so  designated  by  the
                              President;


                          •  Coordinate  the  sports  and  recreation  program  of  the  University
                              through the College of Sports, Physical Education and Recreation
                              (CSPEAR) with Academic Council;

                          •  Resolve organizational conflicts on Academic Affairs;


                          •  Recommend policies and/or revisions thereof on matters affecting
                              curriculum and instruction and related academic matters;

                          •  Coordinate  curriculum  development  in  all  levels  through  the
                              University Academic Council of Colleges;

                          •  Review  all  proposed  programs/projects  for  internal  development
                              particularly those affecting instruction and student welfare;

                          •  Review/analyze reports on status of faculty workload;


                          •  Act  as  the  Chairman  of  the  University  Promotion  and  Selection
                              Board pertinent to the selection and promotion of members of the
                              University faculty regardless of the employment status;

                          •  Provide  leadership  in  planning  and  in  budgetary  estimates  and
                              allocations for all academic units;

                          •  Assess all evaluations made by the deans of Graduate School and
                              Student Affairs as well as those of the different College Deans;

                          •  Sign vouchers and RIVs, purchase orders from within subordinate
                              offices within levels of amounts approved by the BOR;


                          •  Approve travel papers and leaves of academic staff of not more than
                              30 days; and

                          •  Perform other duties related to his position and/or delegated by the
                              President from time to time.


                     Section 3. The Vice President for Administrative and Support Services
                     (VPASS).]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[a)     Function.  The  Administrative  and  Support  Services  Unit  is
                              directly  under  the  office  of  the  University  President  and  is
                              primarily  tasked  of  providing  assistance  to  the  President  in  the
                              general     supervision     and     administration       of   administrative
                              operations,  financial  matters,  general  maintenance  and  support
                              services, medical care and security services.


                       b)     Offices.  The  following  offices  shall  comprise  the  administrative
                              and support services unit of the University:

                       •  Office of the Vice President for Administrative and Support Services.


                       •  Administrative Services

                       •  Financial Services


                       •  Medical and Dental Services

                       •  Physical Plant Services


                       •  Civil Security

                       c)     Responsibility and Functions of the Different Offices


                       Office  of  the  Vice  President  for  Administrative  and  Support  Services
                       (OVPASS) –  The office shall be headed by a Vice President who is appointed or
                       designated by the University President and confirmed by the Board shall have
                       the following functions:



                       General Functions: Assist the University President in general supervision and
                       administration  of  administrative,  support,  fiscal,  health  care  and  security
                       services.


                       Specific Duties and Responsibilities: The specific duties and responsibilities of
                       the Vice President for Administrative and Support Services shall be as follows:]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[•  Develop, formulate and implement programs, projects and activities
                              that are of administrative and auxiliary in nature including fiscal,
                              health care and security matters;


                          •  Manage  and  /  or  supervise  preparation,  allocation  and
                              disbursement  of  budgetary  resources  in  accordance  with  existing
                              laws, rules and regulations;

                          •  Sign Obligation Request (OR) for transactions involving payroll and
                              personal services, remittances for GSIS insurance premiums, PAG-
                              IBIG,  PHILHEALTH  and  other  financial  transactions  and  request
                              under the OVPASS;

                          •  Approve  Disbursement  Vouchers  (DVs)  including  Work  Orders
                              (WOs)/Purchased Orders (POs) in the amount not exceeding One
                              Hundred  Thousand  Pesos  (P100,000.00)  for  and  in  behalf  of  the
                              President;

                          •  Approve payroll for and in behalf of the President regardless of the
                              amount;

                          •  Approve for and in behalf of the President, Disbursement Vouchers
                              for  remittance  to  GSIS,  PHILHEALTH,  PAG-IBI,  BIR,  other
                              government       offices    and    personnel      remittances      to    other
                              offices/claimants regardless of amount.

                          •  Approve/countersign checks for payment of other expenditures that
                              may be authorized for specific purpose in an amount of not more
                              than P100,000.00 per transaction;

                          •  In the absence of HRMO, sign certification issued by the office.

                          •  Issue  policy  memorandum  on  Administrative  matters  as  decided
                              upon on Administrative Council level and/or those inherent to his
                              general functions;


                          •  Issue memorandum related to matters and concerns of the OVPASS.

                          •  Supervise  the  affairs  of  the  administrative,  human  resources,
                              physical plant, financial, health as well as security services  such
                              that  their  inherent  goals  and  objectives  of  the  University  are
                              satisfactorily attained;]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[•  Act  as  Chairman  of  the  Promotion  and  Selection  Board  for  non-
                              academic  positions  within  the  umbrella  of  the  administrative,
                              support, financial, health and security services;

                          •  Recommend  appointments  of  non-academic  personnel  within
                              administrative  and  support  services  to  the  University  President
                              regardless of employment status;

                          •  Establish  a  continuing  program  for  career  and  personnel
                              development for non-academic personnel;

                          •  Initiate job rotation program for non-academic personnel within the
                              OVPASS as a means of developing and enhancing their potential by
                              exposing them to their work climate within the University and more
                              importantly to increase/enlarge their repertoire of knowledge and
                              skills;

                          •  Act on the daily time records of the heads of major offices under the
                              VPASS;

                          •  Act on application for leave of absence of personnel under VPASS for
                              the period covering 30 days or less;

                          •  Sign PHILHEALTH hospitalization form, application agreement for
                              GSIS policy and salary loan and PAG-IBIG multi-purpose loan;

                          •  Perform the functions of the Director for Administration in case the
                              latter is absent or on official travel;

                          •  Sign all requests for official travel of personnel under the OVPASS;


                          •  Prepare  proposals  for  Board  approval  on  matters  related  to  the
                              operation of the unit; and

                          •  Perform  other  duties  that  may  be  assigned  by  the  University
                              President from time to time.]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Section 3.1. Director for Administrative Services



                   The Director for Administrative Services shall perform the following:



                   a)  Supervise and direct the daily activities of the following offices:

                          ▪  Supply and Procurement

                          ▪  Internal Audit

                          ▪  Records

                          ▪  Clerical and support services assigned at the OVPASS

                   b)  Supervise  the  planning  of  activities  of  the  above-mentioned  offices  and
                       implement improvement in their operations;

                   c)  Recommend, implement and evaluate policies, plans and programs that
                       are related to administrative service functions;

                   d)  Sign the following for and on behalf of the President:

                          •  Purchase Request(PR) – P100,000.00 and below


                          •  Purchase Order (PO) and Work Order (WO) – P50,000.00 and below

                          •  Disbursement  Vouchers  (DV)  except  for  personnel  services  –
                              P50,000.00 below;

                          •  Payroll and DV for personal services – without limit


                          •  PO, WO, DV and other documents that are within the discretion of
                              the VPASS in case the latter is on official leave or official travel

                          •  Itinerary of travel, DTR and application for vacation/sick leave of not
                              more than 5 days of personnel under his/her direct supervision

                   e)  Countersign  check  in  the  amount  not  more  than  P25,000.00  per
                       transaction during the time VPASS is on official leave of absence or on
                       official travel;]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[f)  Sign  documents  related  to  GSIS  and  PAGIBIG  loan  and  claims  for
                       PHILHEALTH services;

                   g)  Act as member of Personnel Selection Board and Scholarship Committee
                       of the University;

                   h)  Act as chair of the University Grievance Committee;

                   i)  Supervise and coordinate the preparation of periodic, annual and other
                       required reports on administrative service function;

                   j)  Conduct  in-service  training  for  personnel  under  the  OVPASS  in
                       coordination with the Director of CETS and FSDO; and

                   k)  Perform other functions as may be assigned by higher authorities.



               Section 3.2. Director for Human Resource Development.



               The HRD Director shall head Human Resource Development Office.


                   The Director shall:



                   a)  Supervise and direct the operation of the HRD Office;


                   b)  Assist  the  VPASS  and  the  University  President  in  the  development,
                       formulation and execution of policies, rules and regulation in the areas of
                       human  resource  management  in  accordance  with  CSC  rules  and
                       regulation;

                   c)  Implement human resource development program of the University;

                   d)  Establish a sound recruitment and selection program in the University;

                   e)  Administer  the  position  classification  and  compensation  system
                       prescribed by the DBM and other employees welfare programs such as
                       medical  and  hospitalization  benefits,  health  and  safety  standards,
                       disability, retirement and other benefits;]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[f)  Implement  performance  standard  evaluation  system  and  employees
                       recognition programs;

                   g)  Establish  and  administer  a  continuing  employee  suggestions  and
                       incentives  and  awards  system  for  the  improvement  of  employees
                       performance and productivity;

                   h)  Facilitate the needed human resource training and development programs;

                   i)  Maintain a complete and up to date personnel information system;

                   j)  Act as the BILIS AKSYON PERSON in the University following CSC Memo
                       No.3, s 1994;

                   k)  Act  as  member  of  the  Council  of  Personnel  Manager  (CPO),  actively
                       participate in all programs and activities of the Council;

                   l)  Sign documents for submission to CSG;

                   m) Liaise  with  CSC  and  other  government  agencies  on  matters  related  to
                       human resources;

                   n)  Issue memorandum and guidelines within the scope of his duty;

                   o)  Sit as member of Personnel Selection Board in the University;

                   p)  Perform other functions as assigned by higher authorities.


               Section 3.3. Director for Financial Management Services. The Director shall
                              perform the following:



                   a.) Exercise direct supervision on the following offices:
                              ▪  Cashier


                              ▪  Budget

                              ▪  Accounting

                       a)  Prepare,  consolidate  and  review  annual  budget,  supplemental  and
                          special budgets;]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[b)  Take action on request for funding on various requisitions of different
                          units;

                       c)  Coordinate with concerned offices in connection with budget operations
                          and guidelines;

                       d)  Assist the VPASS and the University President during budget hearings
                          and review and during BOR meeting whenever necessary;

                       e)  Monitor disbursement of approved agency budget;

                       f)  Prepare financial plan for Fund 164 for BOR approval;

                       g)  Prepare  and  submit  financial  report  to  DBM  and  other  concerned
                          offices;

                       h)  Follow-up request for budget like NOSCA, NCA, SARO, etc.;

                       i)  Initiate  and  follow-up  request  for  funding  from  other  government
                          agencies;

                       j)  Prepare  periodic,  annual  and  other  required  report  related  to  the
                          financial management function; and

                       k)  Perform other functions that may be assigned by higher authorities.


               Section  3.4.  Director  for  Medical  Services  –  The  University  Director  for
                   Medical Services shall be designated by the University President and whose
                   designation is approved by the Board of Regents.



                       The director for Medical Services shall:



                       a)  Supervise and direct the operation of the University infirmary, medical
                          clinic and other related facilities;


                       b)  Plan and implement health care program of the University personnel;

                       c)  Attend to the health needs of the students and other members of the
                          academic community;]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[d)  Prepare periodic, annual and other required report related to the health
                          care function;

                       e)  Perform other functions that may assigned by higher authorities.






               Section 3.5. Director for Civil Security.



                   The Director for Civil Security shall:


                   a)  Spearhead the planning, maintenance and up-keep of peace and order in
                       the University;


                   b)  Coordinate strict enforcement of University policies, rules and regulations
                       with all the members of the academic community;

                   c)  Prepare periodic, annual and other required report related to civil security
                       function;

                   d)  Represent VPASS in the evaluation of bids for security services;

                   e)  Coordinate strict enforcement of University policies, rules and regulations
                       with all the members of the academic community; and

                   f)  Perform other functions that may be assigned by higher authorities.



               Section 3.6.  Director for General Services/Physical Plant Services.



                       The Director shall:


                   a)  Exercise  direct  supervision  on  all  personnel  assigned  to  the  general
                       maintenance and services in the University;]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[b)  Assist  the  VPASS  and  the  University  President  in  the  development,
                       formulation and execution of policies related to the general maintenance
                       and services in the University;

                   c)  Implement  program  for  the  development  and  improvement  of  physical
                       facilities of the University;

                   d)  Prepare periodic, annual and other required report related to the general
                       services function;

                   e)  Evaluate request for repair and maintenance projects; and

                   f)  Perform other functions that may be assigned by higher authorities.



               Section 3.7. Accountant



                   The Accountant shall:



                   a)  Prepare financial statements and other financial records;

                   b)  Record  all  official  financial  transactions,  journal  entries  and  accounts
                       classification;

                   c)  Keep and maintain complete, accurate and update subsidiary ledgers for
                       all accounts;

                   d)  Prepare  payroll  of  regular  personnel  and  coordinate  the  preparation  of
                       payroll of non-regular personnel; and

                   e)  Perform other functions that may be assigned from time to time.


               Section 3.8. Cash and Disbursement Officer



               The Cash and Disbursement Officer shall:


                   a)  Handle collection of fees and other funds due to the University;]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[b)  Deposit all collections due to the University within the reglamentary period
                       allowed by law;


                   c)  Prepare and submit regularly reports of collections;

                   d)  Prepare and supervise remittance of taxes due the government through
                       the  Bureau  of  Internal  Revenue  (BIR);  insurance  premiums,  Medicare,
                       loans and other mandatory contributions of personnel;

                   e)  Handle immediate salaries, disbursement of wages and other obligations
                       of the University;

                   f)  Render periodic report of checks issued and cancelled;

                   g)  Record of cash advances; and

                   h)  Perform other functions that may be assigned from time to time.








               Section 3.9. Property and Supply Officer



                   The Property and Supply Officer shall:


                   a)  Supervise acquisition, storage and disposal of supplies and materials and
                       other properties of the University;


                   b)  Spearhead the conduct of physical inventories of the University properties;

                   c)  Keep complete, accurate and updated records of all University properties;

                   d)  Perform other functions that may be assigned from time to time.


               Section 3.10. Records Officer]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[The Records Office shall:



                   a)  Keep and maintain official record and documents of the University;


                   b)  Authenticate documents on file;

                   c)  Maintain  a  continuing  program  for  the  preservation  and  disposition  of
                       permanent records; and

                   d)  Perform other functions that may be assigned from time to time.


                 Section 4. The Vice President for Research, Extension, Continuing
                              Education and Training Services (RECETS).



                       There  shall  be  a  Vice  President  for  Research,  Extension,  Continuing
                   Education and Training Services to be designated by the University President.



                       a)     General  Functions.  The  General  functions  of  the  Vice  President
                              for  Research,  Extension,  Continuing  Education  and  Training
                              Services (VPRECETS) shall be as follows:


                       ▪  Provide leadership and direction in planning of research, extension and
                          training programs of the University;


                       ▪  Coordinate  with  other  units  of  the  University  and  with  other
                          governmental and non-governmental research, extension and training
                          institutions/organizations for effective program implementation; and

                       ▪  Represent the University on matters relevant to its research, extension
                          and training functions when so designated by the University President.

                       b)     Specific Duties and Responsibilities.


                       ▪  Act as Chairman of the RECETS Council;


                       ▪  Recommend  to  the  University  President  policies  and  programs
                          concurred in by the RECETS Council;]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[▪  Review  and  recommend  to  the  President  programs,  proposal  and
                          projects  on  research  and  extension  submitted  by  the  directors  for
                          research, extension, continuing education and training services;

                       ▪  Provide leadership in formulating budgetary  allocations for research,
                          extension,  continuing  education  and  training  and  recommend
                          realignment, if necessary;

                       ▪  Countersign PR and purchase orders from RECETS units;

                       ▪  Approve travel papers and leaves of absence of  RECETS personnel not
                          more than 30 days;

                       ▪  Act as Chairman of the Selection and Promotion Board for RECETS
                          personnel; and

                       ▪  Perform other duties that may be assigned by the President from time
                          to time.





















                   Section 5.   The Vice President for External and Business Affairs
                              (VPEBA).


                       There shall be a Vice President for External and Business Affairs to be
                   designated by the University President.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[a)  Functions. The  Vice  President  for  External  and  Business  Affairs  to  be
                       designated by the University President, shall be as follows:

                       •  Recommend policies and/or revision of existing policies pertaining to
                          business  operations,  income  generation,  alumni  affairs,  public
                          information and external linkages;


                       •  Coordinate  and  promote  the  activities  of  the  University  Alumni
                          Association;

                       •  Provide  adequate  and  relevant  data  and/or  information  to  the
                          University populace and the general public;

                       •  Establish  and  maintain  linkages  with  non-governmental  and  other
                          government organizations along various concerns that are
                            beneficial to the University.

                       •  Head the Selection and Promotion Board for personnel of external and
                          business affairs personnel; and

                       •  Recommend to the University President, personnel to fill up  various
                          contractual or permanent positions to compose the main office and its
                          three  major  subordinate  offices  upon  the  recommendation of  a  duly
                          constituted search committee.


                   Section 6. College Deans. There  shall  be  Deans  of  the  main  campus
                       colleges,  branch  campuses  and  other  major  academic  offices  to  be
                       designated by the University President. The designation of Heads of

                       Integrated  non-chartered  institutions  shall  be  Campus  Administrator.
                       Only  the  heads  of  integrated  non-chartered  institutions  who  enjoyed
                       plantilla position before the integration shall be accorded this designation.
                       Provided,  further  that  the  Integrated  non-chartered  campus  is  on  fully
                       autonomous  operation  particularly  on  financial  management  and  fund
                       sourcing.  Designated  College  and  Campus  Deans  and  Campus
                       Administrators,  should  be  holders  of  earned  Ph.D.  degrees  or  with  the
                       academic rank of at least Associate Professor I.



                       a)     Functions. The  Deans  and  Campus  Administrators  shall
                              perform the following duties and responsibilities:]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[•      Take  charge  of  the  planning,  development  and  supervision  of
                              the college;


                       •      Prepare  budgetary  estimates  for  the  college  in  coordination  with
                              unit heads;

                       •      Propose  a  new  and/or  revision  of  policies,  rules,  and  regulations
                              affecting the college;

                       •      Coordinate  all  the  instruction,  research  and  extension  programs
                              of the college;


                       •      Establish     linkage     with     government       and     non-government
                              agencies  in  the  effective  implementation  of  the  programs  of  the
                              college;

                       •      Sign vouchers and RIVs up to P10,000.00; and

                       •      Perform  such  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  be
                              assigned by the higher authorities.


                       Campus Administrators may perform such other functions that have been
                   particularly  and  traditionally  authorized  for  their  positions  prior  to  the
                   integration.



                   Section  7.  Dean  of  Student  Affairs.  There  shall  be  a  Dean  of  Students
                       Affairs designated by the University President and confirmed by the Board
                       of Regents, who shall coordinate the operations of the following units of
                       the  Office  of  the  Student  Affairs  (OSA):  financial  assistance,  student
                       housing,  student  organization,  guidance  and  testing,  career  and
                       placement, social and cultural affairs, student publication, and student
                       discipline.  In  addition,  the  OSA  Dean  shall  also  exercise  overall
                       management of the student admission.



                              Appropriate  rules,  regulations  and  guidelines  on  the  operation
                       of the different units of the OSA shall be prepared and  implemented
                       by the Dean of Student Affairs as approved by the Board of Regents.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Section 8. Directors of Centers and Non-academic Units and Divisions.
                              There shall be directors of centers and other major non-academic
                       units designated by the University President. In addition to those specified
                       in  their  terms  of  reference  and  as  demanded  by  the  nature  of  their
                       respective units, the major duties and responsibilities of directors are the
                       same as those of the Deans of Colleges or major academic offices.



                   Section  9.  Director  for  Planning.  There  shall  be  a  Director  for  Planning
                       designated  by  the  University  President  and  confirmed  by  the  Board  of
                       Regents who shall be charged with the following functions:



                       a)  Prepare  a  development  plan  for  the  University  at  macro-level  in
                          accordance  with  the  mission  of  the  University  within  the  general
                          provision of its charter and in accordance with national and regional
                          priorities;


                       b)  Develop,  review,  and  synthesize  micro  strategies  of  the  different
                          Colleges/units toward the overall University master plan;

                       c)  Coordinate  with  all  the  colleges/units  in  connection  with  the
                          preparation and implementation of the development plan;

                       d)  Establish and manage a Management Information System (MIS) that
                          shall continuously monitor the needed data and information to top-
                          level  management  and  other  appropriate  offices,  from  within  and
                          without, when needed, as the case may be;

                       e)  Conduct  periodic  monitoring  and  evaluation  of  the  institutional and
                          development plans; and

                       f)  Perform  such  other  duties  and  responsibilities  as  may  assigned  by
                          higher authorities.


                   Section 10. Department Chairpersons and Heads of Units. It shall be the
                       responsibility of Department Chairpersons and Heads of Units to:



                   a)  Take charge of planning, development an supervision of their respective
                       units;]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[b)  Prepare budgetary estimates of their respective units in coordination with
                       the College deans/Division Directors; and

                   c)  Propose  new  and  appropriate  rules  and  regulations  affecting  their
                       respective units.



                   Section 11. Secretary of the University Board of Regents. The Secretary
                       of the University Board shall be appointed by the President. He shall take
                       charge  of  the  communications  in  the  University/Board  including  those
                       that  relate  to  endorsements  to  the  Board,  requests  for  meetings  and
                       schedules, referenda, and other University endorsements to the Board. In
                       addition, he shall also serve as Secretary of the University Administrative
                       Council.



                   Section 12. University Registrar. The University Registrar is charged with
                       the responsibility of keeping up-to-date and accurate records of student
                       enrollment, grades, delinquency lists, drop-outs and causes, graduation,
                       and  the  like.  More  specially,  the  following  are  the  functions  of  the
                       University Registrar:



                   a)  Prepare yearly academic calendar and scholastic activities in line with the
                       academic calendar issued by the Commission on Higher Education;


                   b)  Plan out effective registration routing procedures and guidelines;

                   c)  Record advance credits of transfer students;

                   d)  Establish  procedures  for  dropping  of  courses,  leaves  of  absence  and
                       change of classes. Keeping and issuing forms for these purposes;

                   e)  Record approved leaves of absence, change of courses, change of classes,
                       and the like;

                   f)  Notify students to drop a course;

                   g)  Automatically  convert  all  grades  of  “Inc.”  and  “4”  if  not  completed  or
                       removed  after  one  year  preceding  registration  of  subject(s)  with  these
                       grades per academic rules and regulations.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[h)  Officially inform registration advisers of students who repeated subjects
                       for the second time and failed;

                   i)  Prepare student delinquency list after each semester;

                   j)  Prepare list of graduating students; and

                   k)  Publish the general catalogues as often as changing academic and other
                       programs of the University, which requires a more permanent publicity.
                   l)  Inform parents/guardians of students of the academic performance of the
                       latter two weeks after the end of the semester/term.


                          To assist the University Registrar in the above functions, each College
                   Dean shall designate a College registrar who shall serve office at the discretion
                   of the College Dean.



                   Section 13. Director for Special Projects.  The University President shall
                       designate a Director for Special Projects. The Special Projects Office shall
                       be directly under the Office of the President. This office shall be concerned
                       with all the external linkages of the University particularly those covered
                       by the Memorandum of Agreement (MOA).



                       The duties and responsibilities of the Director for Special Projects shall be
                              as follows:



                       Review existing special projects of the University;



                   a)  If necessary, recommend revisions to MOA covering these projects;


                   b)  Keep updated records of the activities;

                   c)  Take charge of the review and revision of proposed special projects;

                   d)  Prepare and submit regular and required reports to the President;

                   e)  Establish linkages with other agencies; and]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[f)  Perform other related functions as may be assigned by higher authorities


                   Section 14. Director, Presidential Management Coordinating Office



                   a)  Assist the President in the General Supervision and  Administration of
                       Academic,  Research  and  Development,  Administrative  and  Business
                       Affairs;


                   b)  Serve  as  Presidential  Assistant  on  the  day  to  day  operation  of  the
                       University;

                   c)  Facilitate the flow of information among the various units of the University
                       in aid of Presidential decision;

                   d)  Liaise between the University and external linkage institutions;

                   e)  Monitor, evaluate and submit the performance reports of all units in the
                       University in coordination with the Planning Office;

                   f)  Provide technical advice to the President on matters related to institutional
                       and policy development; and

                   g)  Perform other duties the President may assign from time to time.


                   Section 15. Director, Quality Assurance and Accreditation Center



                   a)  Plan,  monitor  and  evaluate  the  internal  assessment  system  of  the
                       University

                   b)  Plan    accreditation     visits    in   coordination      with    the    respective
                       Deans/Administrators of Colleges, and also with the Internal Assessment
                       Body (IAB);

                   c)  Initiate the conduct of self-surveys of the different academic programs of
                       the  University  in  coordination  with  the  IAB  of  the  University,    using
                       prescribed accreditation instruments;]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[d)  liaise  with  the  various  campuses/colleges  within  the  University  on  all
                       accreditation  matters  ranging  from  finalizing  arrangements  of  external
                       visits  to  monitoring  of  compliance  of  the  campus/college  to  the
                       recommendations of AACCUP; and

                   e)  Monitor the compliance of the colleges concerned to the recommendations
                       of the AACCUP; and

                   f)  Monitor the implementation and operation of the University-wide quality
                       management system.


                   Section 16. The University Librarian



                       The librarian shall:



                   a)  Provide efficient and effective library services to the University personnel,
                       students and other authorized clientele;


                   b)  Initiate continuous enrichment of library resources; and

                   c)  Perform other functions that may be assigned from time to time.





               Article 9. Other Officers. Advisers of the University may               be       designated
                       or appointed by the President and approved by the Board of  Regents
                       as    deemed       necessary      in    the    effective    administration       and
                       management         of    University      functions.      Provided      that     their
                       designations are covered by specific terms of reference or              regulated by
                   the nature of their designations.



               Article 10. Induction Training for Designated Officers – No officer of   the
                   University,  with  the  exception  of  the  President  and/or  Campus
                       Administrator, shall be designated to any middle level  management
                       position without having successfully undergone  induction                    training
                       specific to the terms of reference required by the office concerned.   The]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[University President, in his discretion, may forego this            requirement        as
                   he/she deems fit.



               Article  11.  Tenure  of  Designated  Officers.  Except  for  the  University
                       President and the Administrator of the integrated campus,   designated
                       officers shall hold office for a period of two years  renewable  for  another
                   two years.



                              In case of vacancy, the next designated officers shall hold             office
                       only   for the remaining term. The President may                recommend to the
               Board of Regents the termination of services of any              designated  officer  any
               time he deems necessary.



               Article 12. Councils of the University.



               Section 1.  Executive Council. There shall be a University  Executive
                       Council composed of the President as Chairman and Vice                  Presidents
               as members. It shall be the duty and responsibility of the              Executive  Council
               to review policy recommendations emanating from                  the  middle  level  units
               before endorsement to the Board of Regents.               The  Council  shall  ensure  the
               proper and effective implementation of             programs  and  projects  approved  by
               the Board of Regents.



                 Section      2.    The     Administrative         Council.      There     shall    be    an
                       Administrative  Council  composed  of  the  University  President  as
                       Chairman, Vice Presidents, Deans of Colleges, and Directors. The   heads
               of various technical and academic units and departments may                     be
               requested to join the meeting of the administrative Council to be   held at least
               once a month.



                              The Administrative Council shall propose, review and   recommend
               appropriate policies governing curriculum and   instruction,                administration,
               management, and development                 planning      of the University.

                              The  tenure  of  office  of  the  members  of  the  Administrative
                       Council shall be two years renewal for another two years only.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Section 3. The Academic Council. There shall be a University  Academic
               Council with the University President as Chairman and all   the  members  of
               the instructional staff with the rank not lower than             Assistant  Professors  as
               members. The University Librarian, the             Registrar  and  the  other  officials  of
               equal rank whose duties and   responsibilities relate to the Academic Affairs of
               the University        shall be non-voting members of the Academic Council.



                              The  duties  and  responsibilities  of  the  Academic  Council  shall  be
                       as follows:



                   a)  Determine, review and recommend for approval of the Board of Regents,
                       the academic programs including academic rules and regulations of the
                       University;


                   b)  Devise/draft,  review  and  recommend  for  the  approval  of  the  Board  of
                       Regents the rules of discipline for students and faculty and employees;
                       and

                   c)  Fix  the  requirements  for  the  admission  of  students  as  well  as  their
                       graduation and the conferment of degrees and submit the same for the
                       approval of the Board of Regents.

                       The University Academic Council shall be presided by the University
                   President and shall meet at least twice a semester on the date and venue to
                   be agreed by the members of the Council.

               Section 4. College Academic Councils. The colleges and/or branch campuses
                   of the University may continue their own              respective  academic  council
                   with the College Deans as Chairman and faculty members with the rank of at
                   least  Assistant  Professor  as  members.  The  College  Registrar  and  the
                   Chairperson of the department whose academic rank is lower than Assistant
                   Professor shall be non-voting members of the College Academic Council.



                       The  duties  and  responsibilities  of  the  College  Academic  Council  shall
                   conform to the duties and responsibilities of the University Academic Council.
                   All  academic  policies,  programs,  and  projects  including  curriculum,
                   instruction,  change,  revision,  and  other  policies  on  academic  affairs  for]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[consideration of the University Academic Council shall have the endorsement
                   of the College Academic Council concerned.



                 Section 5. Graduate Academic Council. There shall be a Graduate Council
                   to  be  constituted  by  the  faculty  with  the  rank  not  lower  than  Assistant
                   Professor  with  the  Dean  of  Graduate  School  as  Chairman.  The  Graduate
                   School Registrar and the Chairperson of the department offering graduate
                   programs whose academic  rank is lower than Assistant Professor shall be
                   non-voting members of the Graduate Academic Council.



                       The  Graduate  Academic  Council  shall  formulate  and  review  policies
                   governing  graduate  programs.  All  new  policies/departmental  requests  for
                   permission to offer advanced degrees are referred to the GS Council, OVPAA,
                   and the Board of Regents. The Council shall also screen/recommend to the
                   University  President  appointments  of  new  graduate  faculty;  conduct
                   regular/special meetings on approval of candidates for graduation; curricular
                   innovations, introduction of new policies and the like; and create standing
                   and ad hoc committee/work groups as the need arises.



               Section 6. The Vice President for Academic Affairs may create core group faculty
                     members with the rank of at least Associate Professor who are members of
                     the  University  Administrative  Council  to  formulate,  review  and  revise
                     academic  policies,  rules  and  procedures  for  approval  of  the  Board  of
                     Regents.


                Section  7.  Research,  Extension,  Continuing  Education  and  Training
                     Services Council.  There shall be a Research, Extension and Continuing
                     Education  and  Training  Services  Council  to  be  constituted  by  the  Vice
                     President for Research, Extension and Continuing Education and Training
                     Services  as  Chairman.  The  members  of  the  Council  shall  consist  of
                     specialists representing the different research commodity emphases of the
                     University, extension and continuing education and training specialists. The
                     members of the Council shall serve for two years renewable up to the second
                     term. In case of vacancy in membership, a substitute may be designated by
                     the University President and shall serve only for the remaining period of
                     service.]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[The  duties  and  responsibilities  of  the  Research,  Extension  and
                     Continuing  Education  and  Training  Services  Council  shall  be  as
                     follows:



                       a)     Determine,  review  and  recommend  to  the  executive  Council,
                              policies,  rules,  and  regulations,  and  the  directions  for  the
                              University  research,  extension,  continuing  education  and
                              training programs;

                       b)     Review and recommend research and extension proposals; and

                       c)     Review  the  findings  and  recommendations  of  faculty  and
                              Institutional Research.


                              The  Research,  Extension  and  Continuing  Education  and
                       Training  Services  Council  shall  hold  at  least  one  meeting  every
                       quarter  at  the  date  and  venue  to  be  determined  by  the  Council
                       members.



                   Section  8.  University  Textbook  and  Publication  Board.  The  University
                       shall create a Textbook Board composed of six (6) senior faculty members
                       representing major disciplines with the academic rank of at least Associate
                       Professor  to  be  designated  by  the  University  Presidents.  The  Editor-in-
                       Chief of the University Gazettes shall represent the student body in this
                       Board.


                              The members of the Board shall select a Chairman of the Textbook
                       Board  who  shall  preside  over  meetings  of  the  Board  and  an  Executive
                       Secretary who shall serve office for two years subject to reappointment for
                       a  second  term.  No  member  of  the  Board  shall  serve  office  for  three
                       consecutive terms.



                              The  functions  of  the  University  Textbook  and  Publications  Board
                       shall be as follows:



                   a)  Prepare  and  implement  policies,  regulations  and  guidelines  on  book
                       writing, book writing process flow and remunerations to writers subject to]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[the approval of the Board of Regents. It shall also formulate guidelines on
                       the  preparation,  testing,  publication,  adaptation  and  sale  of  textbooks,
                       laboratory manuals, modules, and other instructional materials prepared
                       by the members of the University academic community;


                   b)  Screen  and  review  reference  materials  required  by  the  teachers
                       particularly  those  that  are  to  be  purchased  by  the  students  such  as
                       manuals, textbooks, and recommend final adoption or rejection of such
                       instructional materials;

                   c)  Establish  linkage  with  the  University  Printing  Office  and  outside
                       publishers and printers for possible publication of instructional materials;
                       and

                   d)  Perform other related functions as may be assigned by higher authorities.


                 Section 9. Sports Council. There shall be a Sports Council with Dean of the
                     13College of Sports, Physical Education and Recreation as Chairman. The
                     members  of  the  Council  shall  consist  of  the  Chairpersons  of  Sports  and
                     Recreation Department, all Deans and selected Directors, Professors of the
                     University.



                              The  duties  and  responsibilities  of  the  Sports  Council  shall  be  as
                       follows:



                     a)  Formulate, recommend and implement policies and regulation of athletic
                        sports;


                     b)  Determine the privileges and benefits of varsity athletes, coaches  and
                     trainers following the approved guidelines set by the Council;
                     c)  Investigate and recommend penalties for varsity athletes, coaches and
                        officials which can adversely affect the name of the University.


                       The Sports Council shall hold at least one meeting every quarter at the
                     date and venue to be determined by the council members.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Section 10. Other Councils. The Board of Regents upon recommendation of
                       the University President may create other councils, as it deems necessary,
                       for the effective and efficient management of the affairs of the University.



                Article  13.  Command  Succession.  The  University  shall  adopt  command
                   succession to be agreed upon by the members of the Administrative Council.
                   This shall be implemented immediately upon the designation of the middle
                   level Managers and shall be co-terminus with the end of their designations.



                        Command succession is the designation of next in line in the command
                   succession of taking over the responsibilities of an office once the head is
                   absent. Once the head is absent, the next in command shall automatically
                   and immediately take charge of all responsibilities and make all decisions
                   except on financial matters.



                   In case of next in command to the University President, the taking over of
                   responsibilities  is  valid  for  a  period  of  ten  days  only  beyond  which,  an
                   authorization to act, as University Officer-in-Charge (OIC) shall be issued by
                   the President.



                   The Vice President for Planning and Development (VPPD)

                   Vice President for Planning and Development (VPPD)


               There shall be a Vice President for Planning and Development designated by the

               University President and confirmed by the Board of Regents who shall be charged

               with the following functions:

                   a.  General Functions: Assist the University President in the planning and

                       development programs of the University.
                   b.  Specific  Duties  and  Responsibilities:  The  specific  duties  and

                       responsibilities of the VPPD shall be as follows:

                         i.   Supervise the preparation of a development plan for the University
                              at  macro-level  in  accordance  with  the  mission  of  the  University]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[within the general provision of its charter and in accordance with

                              national and regional priorities;
                        ii.   Supervise the conduct of periodic monitoring and evaluation of the

                              institutional and development plans and projects;

                       iii.   Supervise  the  establishment  and  management  of  a  Management
                              Information  System  (MIS)  that  shall  continuously  monitor  the

                              needed  data  and  information  to  top-level  management  and  other

                              appropriate offices;
                       iv.    Spearhead  the  implementation  of  the  University’s  quality

                              management system and other quality assurance programs; and

                        v.    Perform such other duties and responsibilities as may be assigned
                              by the President of the University.

                   c.  Offices under Vice-President for Planning and Development
                         i.   Planning Office

                        ii.   Institutional Development Office

               Director for Planning

               The Director for Planning shall perform the following:


                   a.  Supervise and direct the daily activities of the following offices:

                         i.   Institutional Planning Unit
                        ii.   Physical Planning Unit

                       iii.   Project Management Unit
                   b.  Spearhead  the  preparation  of  the  various  plans  of  the  University

                       (development, strategic, operational, physical, and investment plans);

                   c.  Supervise  the  planning  of  activities  of  the  above-mentioned  units  and
                       implement improvement in their operations;

                   d.  Monitor and evaluate the development plans and projects of the University;

                   e.  Conduct the initial performance assessment of the various offices of the
                       University based on the submitted Office Performance Commitment and

                       Review Form;]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[f.  Conduct university performance planning and review conference annually;

                       and
                   g.  Perform other functions as may be assigned by higher authorities.




               Director for Institutional Development

               The Director for Institutional Development shall perform the following:


                   a.  Supervise and direct the daily activities of the following units:

                         i.   Quality Assurance Unit
                        ii.   Policy Development Unit

                   b.  Recommend, implement and evaluate policies, plans and programs that
                       are related to institutional development;

                   c.  Plan,  monitor  and  evaluate  the  internal  assessment  system  of  the

                       University;
                   d.  Monitor  the  implementation  of  the  University’s  quality  management

                       system and conduct of quality assurance programs; and

                   e.  Perform other functions as may be assigned by higher authorities.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Extracted from CvSU Annual Report 2020]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Organizational Structure of the Office of

               the Vice President for Academic Affairs]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Organizational structure of the Office of


               the Vice President for Administrative


               and Support Services]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Organizational Structure of the Office of

               the Vice President for Planning and


               Development]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[ORGANIZATIONAL STRUCTURE OF OVPPD





                                               UNIVERSITY PRESIDENT






                                                      Vice President
                                            PLANNING AND DEVELOPMENT





                                                  MIS                 Staff





                                    Director                                   Director
                                Planning Office                  Institutional Development Office





                                Institutional Planning                       Quality Assurance





                                  Physical Planning                         Policy Development






                                Project Management]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Organizational Structure of the Office of


               the Vice President for Research and


               Extension]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[UNIVERSITY ACADEMIC COUNCIL


                                                  MEMBERS]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                            Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                      Indang, Cavite
                                          415-0010 loc 270/200    862-0806
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                              OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR ACADEMIC AFFAIRS


                                      UNIVERSITY ACADEMIC COUNCIL MEMBERS


                                    CAFENR

                                1  Autriz, Mariedel L.             Assistant Professor IV
                                2  Barcelon, Eufemio G.            Associate Professor III
                                3  Magsino, Analita dM.            Professor V
                                4  Manuel, Adolfo, Jr. C.          Professor V
                                5  Matel, Irvin D.                 Assistant Professor I
                                6  Novicio, Lilibeth P.            Professor III
                                7  Olo, Cristina F.                Professor VI
                                8  Pareja, Gary A.                 Assistant Professor II
                                9  Sangalang, Adelaida E.          Professor VI
                                10  Saz, Venus O.                  Assistant Professor II
                                11  Sedigo, Noel A.                Associate Professor IV
                                12  Sierra, Sheryl N.              Assistant Professor I
                                13  Singson, Evelyn O.             Professor VI
                                14  Tepora, Teddy F.               Associate Professor V


                                    CAS

                                1  Agdalpen, Renato T.             Assistant Professor II
                                2  Agustin, Raquel G.              Assistant Professor I
                                3  Alimboyoguen, Agnes B.          Associate Professor II
                                4  Baltazar, Miriam D.             Assistant Professor IV
                                5  Betonio, Rene B.                Assistant Professor III
                                6  Bono, Michelle T.               Assistant Professor III
                                7  Cinto, Antonio V.               Associate Professor V
                                8  Cruzada, Ma. Fatima I.          Assistant Professor II
                                9  Delos Reyes, Orlando B.         Assistant Professor IV
                                10  Dico, Analyn T.                Assistant Professor I
                                11  Dimero, Dickson N.             Associate Professor II
                                12  Feranil, Bernard S.            Assistant Professor I
                                13  Ferrer, Ammie P.               Assistant Professor IV
                                14  Francisco, Agnes C.            Associate Professor II
                                15  Herrera, Ma. Corazon V.        Associate Professor II
                                16  Hilario, Paulito V.            Assistant Professor I
                                17  Ilagan, Bettina Joyce P.       Associate Professor I]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[18  Ilagan, Yolanda A.             Professor VI
                                19  Legaspi, Gemma S.              Associate Professor III
                                20  Matel, Hosea D.                Associate Professor II
                                21  Matilla, Marilou S.            Assistant Professor I
                                22  Mojica, Analyn A.              Associate Professor II
                                23  Mora, Evangelina B.            Assistant Professor III
                                24  Pelorina, Renato N.            Associate Professor IV
                                25  Penales, Lynn G.               Assistant Professor IV
                                26  Ramos, Gil D.                  Assistant Professor II
                                27  Reyes, Jocelyn L.              Associate Professor V
                                28  Rodis, Lani S.                 Assistant Professor IV
                                29  Romeroso, Manny A.             Assistant Professor II
                                30  Signo, Cristina M.             Associate Professor III
                                31  Solis, Allan Robert C.         Associate Professor I


                                    CCJ

                                1  Lontoc, Marissa C.                Assistant Professor II
                                2  Matic, Famela Iza C.              Associate Professor II
                                3  Tan, Susan G.                     Assistant Professor I


                                    CEd

                                1  Abanes, Florencio R.            Assistant Professor I
                                2  Alaras, Nancy C.                Associate Professor I
                                3  Batiles, Carmen A.              Assistant Professor IV
                                4  Costa, Liza C.                  Associate Professor III
                                5  Crizaldo, Rhodora S.            Associate Professor V
                                6  Guevara, Julie S.               Associate Professor II
                                7  Ilano, Patrick Glenn C.         Assistant Professor I
                                8  Legaspi, Myleen P.              Associate Professor V
                                9  Lucero, Pia Rhoda P.            Associate Professor I
                                10  Maniacop, Jason R.             Assistant Professor IV
                                11  Nuestro, Ma. Agnes P.          Associate Professor V
                                12  Tayag, Joana Marie M.          Assistant Professor I
                                13  Venzon, Alfredo A.             Assistant Professor III



                                    CEIT

                                1  Arboleda, Edwin R.              Assistant Professor III
                                2  Bago, Cene M.                   Assistant Professor III
                                3  Banasihan, Florence M.          Associate Professor II
                                4  Buclatin, Willie C.             Assistant Professor IV
                                5  Carandang, Charlotte B.         Assistant Professor IV
                                6  Cero, David L.                  Professor I
                                7  Cero, Leyma L.                  Professor IV
                                8  Coronado, Vanessa G.            Assistant Professor II]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[9  Costa, Michael T.               Assistant Professor III
                                10  Cubilla, Renato B.             Associate Professor V
                                11  Daez, Simeon E.                Assistant Professor III
                                12  Dizon, Marivic G.              Associate Professor II
                                13  Escaño, Danielito R.           Assistant Professor III
                                14  Escobar, Marilyn M.            Professor VI
                                15  Fenol, Sheryl D.               Assistant Professor II
                                16  Guevarra, Emeline C.           Assistant Professor IV
                                17  Mojica, Ruel M.                Professor III
                                18  Nuestro, Jo-Anne C.            Assistant Professor IV
                                19  Peña, Ronald P.                Associate Professor II
                                20  Peña, Roslyn P.                Assistant Professor IV
                                21  Pereña, Marlon R.              Assistant Professor IV
                                22  Polinga, Camilo A.             Professor III
                                23  Rocillo, Efren R.              Associate Professor III
                                24  Sarmiento, Bienvenido Jr. C.  Associate Professor II
                                25  Torres, Lilia O.               Assistant Professor I
                                26  Vida, Poinsettia A.            Associate Professor I


                                    CEMDS

                                1  Abogadie, Lina C.               Associate Professor IV
                                2  Aguilar, Alberto M.             Assistant Professor I
                                3  Aguilar, Dolores L.             Assistant Professor III
                                4  Buena, Ma. Corazon A.           Assistant Professor II
                                5  Cubillo, Gilchor P.             Professor I
                                6  Ebo, Jenny Beb F.               Assistant Professor II
                                7  Ilagan, Florindo C.             Associate Professor V
                                8  Lising, Maria Soledad M.        Assistant Professor III
                                9  Magcawas, Almira G.             Assistant Professor I
                                10  Mojica, Marlon A.              Assistant Professor IV
                                11  Noceda, Rowena R.              Assistant Professor IV
                                12  Plete, Adora Joy T.            Assistant Professor II
                                13  Polinga, Elizabeth E.          Associate Professor V
                                14  Rupido, Roderick M.            Associate Professor V
                                15  Sustrina, Ma. Isolde R.        Assistant Professor III


                                     CoN

                                 1  Del Mundo, Evelyn M.            Associate Professor II
                                 2  Destura, Ederlyn P.             Associate Professor I
                                 3  Panaligan, Nenita B.            Associate Professor III
                                 4  Rona, Jane A.                   Assistant Professor I
                                 5  Sapinoso, Bernadette A.         Assistant Professor I


                                     CSPEAR

                                 1  Cubillo, Jazmin P.             Assistant Professor II]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[2  Eustaquio, Erlinda C.          Assistant Professor III
                                 3  Mojica, Ana Liza R.            Assistant Professor III
                                 4  Oquendo, Almon R.              Associate Professor IV
                                 5  Piores, Victor F.              Associate Professor I


                                     CVMBS

                                 1  Alvarez, Alvin-William A.       Assistant Professor III
                                 2  Alvarez, Cherry R.              Assistant Professor I
                                 3  Bahia, Rezin C.                 Associate Professor III
                                 4  Del Mundo, Desiree C.           Assistant Professor I
                                 5  Dela Cruz, Ma.  Cynthia R.      Associate Professor III
                                 6  Macalanda, Miki Adrian C.       Assistant Professor IV
                                 7  Mago, Emmanuel D.               Assistant Professor I
                                 8  Montialto, Nelzon J.            Assistant Professor III
                                 9  Sison, Mariano Jr. P.           Assistant Professor I
                                 10  Talactac, Melbourne R.         Associate Professor I



                                     Bacoor Campus

                                 1  Cajigal, Ronan M.              Assistant Professor III
                                 2  Gamuyao, Zannie I.             Assistant Professor I



                                     Carmona Campus

                                 1  Consignado, Michael G.         Assistant Professor I
                                 2  Domingo, Lea Marissa S.        Assistant Professor III
                                 3  Satiada, Yolanda L.            Assistant Professor I



                                     Cavite City Campus

                                 1  Baesa, Maria Cristina J.       Assistant Professor IV


                                     Imus Campus

                                 1  Apostol, Mildred A.            Assistant Professor II
                                 2  Marzan, Luisita A.             Assistant Professor II
                                 3  Ras, Sixto Jr. N.              Assistant Professor I
                                 4  Solina, Alfe M.                Associate Professor I
                                 5  Valdez, Luningning A.          Assistant Professor II


                                     Naic Campus]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[1  Bernal, Marte L.                 Assistant Professor I
                                 2  Clores, Lomalinda J.             Assistant Professor I
                                 3  Correo, Ma. Pilar N.             Assistant Professor IV
                                 4  De Guzman, Manuel A.             Assistant Professor I
                                 5  Diones, Catherine S.             Assistant Professor II
                                 6  Galang, Diosalyn T.              Assistant Professor III
                                 7  Guerrero, Ma. Leonora D.         Assistant Professor I
                                 8  Guerrero, Ma. Lourdes D.         Assistant Professor I
                                 9  Gutierrez, Ernesto Jr. A.        Assistant Professor III
                                 10  Lacson, Leah C.                 Assistant Professor III
                                 11  Mojica, Daniel G.               Assistant Professor I
                                 12  Navarro, Leah C.                Assistant Professor IV
                                 13  Nazareno, Adiliza G.            Master Teacher I
                                 14  Nepomuceno, John Xavier B.      Assistant Professor III
                                 15  Nuestro, Mat M.                 Assistant Professor I
                                 16  Nueva, Elsa D.                  Assistant Professor I
                                 17  Pabalate, Ferry M.              Assistant Professor I
                                 18  Papa, Jeffrey F.                Assistant Professor III
                                 19  Perea, Rossian V.               Assistant Professor I
                                 20  Pugay, Armina B.                Assistant Professor I
                                 21  Rasdas, Sherrlyn M.             Assistant Professor I
                                 22  Ridao, Jelita F.                Assistant Professor I
                                 23  Robles, Jocelyn H.              Assistant Professor I
                                 24  Tesorero, Marilyn L.            Assistant Professor I


                                     Rosario Campus

                                 1  Alvarez, Nestor M.                Associate Professor IV
                                 2  Ambas, Arman M.                   Assistant Professor I
                                 3  Bartolome, Gee Jay C.             Assistant Professor I
                                 4  Bernal, Melissa M.                Assistant Professor II
                                 5  Delos Reyes, Regie C.             Assistant Professor I
                                 6  Dumlao, Elizabeth R.              Assistant Professor III
                                 7  Emelo, Marian Concepcion A.       Assistant Professor IV
                                 8  Hernandez, Melita D.              Associate Professor I
                                 9  Legaspi, Elizabeth H.             Assistant Professor II
                                 10  Legaspi, Noelle D.               Assistant Professor III
                                 11  Lim, Bernadette F.               Assistant Professor III
                                 12  Lisama, Jose P.                  Associate Professor V
                                 13  Lorenzana, Cecilia F.            Assistant Professor II
                                 14  Lubong, Rodel B.                 Associate Professor I
                                 15  Luseco, Marilou P.               Assistant Professor IV
                                 16  Luseco, William P.               Assistant Professor I
                                 17  Parcon, Deanna C.                Assistant Professor I
                                 18  Pascua, Lauro B.                 Associate Professor III
                                 19  Pegos, Efren E.                  Assistant Professor II
                                 20  Policar, Reynaldo G.             Assistant Professor I
                                 21  Quilapio, Ladylyn L.             Assistant Professor I
                                 22  Rodriguez, Janet L.              Associate Professor II]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[23  Santos, Ariel G.                 Associate Professor IV
                                 24  Santos, Ma. Daisy A.             Assistant Professor IV
                                 25  Talactac, Ligaya B.              Assistant Professor I


                                     Silang Campus

                                 1  Alvarez, Haziel T.              Assistant Professor I
                                 2  Malabag, Beverly A.             Assistant Professor I
                                 3  Mendoza, Hermilina A.           Assistant Professor I
                                 4  Patambang, Emy Grace B.         Assistant Professor I
                                 5  Pragacha, Rosemarie N.          Assistant Professor II
                                 6  Ymana, Roselyn A.               Assistant Professor IV


                                     Tanza Campus

                                 1  Manarpiis, Noel B.              Assistant Professor II
                                 2  Sebastian, Mildred A.           Assistant Professor I



                                     Trece Martires Campus


                                 1  Estrada, Arlene L.              Assistant Professor I
                                 2  Feranil,Vienna Mi A.            Assistant Professor III
                                 3  Manlapig, Cristza O.            Assistant Professor II]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[O-265
                                             ED
                                             02-09-2022]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>