<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="58"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.8.            Instruction is enriched through, at least


                        10 of the following strategies:


                        I.8.10.  informal creative groups;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[VPAA-QF-10


                       CvSU Vision                                      Republic of the Philippines                       CvSU Mission
                    The  premier  university  in                  CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY                           Cavite  State  University  shall  provide
                 historic  Cavite  recognized  for                                                              excellent,  equitable  and  relevant  educational
                 excellence  in  the  development                              Tanza Campus                     opportunities  in  the  arts,  science  and
                 of  globally  competitive  and                            Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite                technology  through  quality  instruction  and
                 morally upright individuals.                                   (046) 414-3979                 relevant research and development activities.
                                                                                                                    It  shall  produce  professional, skilled  and
                                                                              www.cvsu.edu.ph                   morally   upright   individuals   for   global
                                                                                                                competitiveness.


                                                                     DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT


                                                                           COURSE SYLLABUS
                                                                     Second Semester, AY 2020-2021
                                                              E-Commerce/
                                ELEC 4/                                                           Lecture      ✓
               Course Code                   Course Title     Internet          Type                                     Credit Units             3
                                MKTG 111                                                          Laboratory
                                                              Marketing
                                This course focuses on principles of e-commerce from a business perspective, providing an overview of business and technology
               Course           topics,  business  models,  virtual  value  chains  and  social  innovation  and  marketing  strategies.  In  addition,  some  of  the  major
               Description      issues  associated  with  e-commerce  -  security,  privacy,  intellectual  property  rights,  authentication,  encryption,  acceptable  use
                                policies, and legal liabilities - will be explored. Students will build their own web presence and market it using an online platform.
                                                                                                 Lecture:       _______________________________
               Pre-requisites  None                           Course Schedule
                                                                                                 Laboratory: _______________________________
                                Students are expected to live by and stand for the following University tenets:

                                TRUTH is demonstrated by the student’s objectivity and honesty during examinations, class activities and in the development of
                                projects.

               Core Values      EXCELLENCE is exhibited by the students’ self-confidence, punctuality, diligence and commitment in the assigned tasks, class
                                performance and other course requirements.

                                SERVICE is manifested by the students’ respect, rapport, fairness and cooperation in dealing with their peers and members of
                                the community.
                                In addition, they should exhibit love and respect for nature and support for the cause of humanity.

                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-06-01]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[VPAA-QF-10


 CvSU Vision   Republic of the Philippines   CvSU Mission
 The  premier  university  in   CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY   Cavite  State  University  shall  provide
 historic  Cavite  recognized  for   excellent,  equitable  and  relevant  educational
 excellence  in  the  development   Tanza Campus   opportunities  in  the  arts,  science  and
 of  globally  competitive  and   Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite   technology  through  quality  instruction  and
 morally upright individuals.     (046) 414-3979   relevant research and development activities.
                               It  shall  produce  professional, skilled  and
    www.cvsu.edu.ph         morally   upright   individuals   for   global
                            competitiveness.


 DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT


 COURSE SYLLABUS
 Second Semester, AY 2020-2021
 E-Commerce/
 ELEC 4/      Lecture      ✓
 Course Code   Course Title   Internet   Type   Credit Units   3
 MKTG 111     Laboratory
 Marketing
 This course focuses on principles of e-commerce from a business perspective, providing an overview of business and technology
 Course   topics,  business  models,  virtual  value  chains  and  social  innovation  and  marketing  strategies.  In  addition,  some  of  the  major
 Description   issues  associated  with  e-commerce  -  security,  privacy,  intellectual  property  rights,  authentication,  encryption,  acceptable  use
 policies, and legal liabilities - will be explored. Students will build their own web presence and market it using an online platform.
             Lecture:       _______________________________
 Pre-requisites  None   Course Schedule
             Laboratory: _______________________________
 Students are expected to live by and stand for the following University tenets:

 TRUTH is demonstrated by the student’s objectivity and honesty during examinations, class activities and in the development of
 projects.

 Core Values   EXCELLENCE is exhibited by the students’ self-confidence, punctuality, diligence and commitment in the assigned tasks, class
 performance and other course requirements.

 SERVICE is manifested by the students’ respect, rapport, fairness and cooperation in dealing with their peers and members of
 the community.
 In addition, they should exhibit love and respect for nature and support for the cause of humanity.

                                                          V02-2020-06-01]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[The campus shall endeavor to:

               Goals of the         1.  provide high quality of instructions that will lead to globally competitive students;
               College/             2.  develop researches and extension activities through arts, sciences and technology that will help in promoting the
               Campus
                                       university’s goals; and
                                    3.  develop graduates that are skilled and morally upright.


                                The department shall endeavor to:

                                    1.  provide  high  quality  instruction  and  professional  expertise  to  students,  to  prepare  them  in  the  different  organizational
                                       settings as upright and competitive individuals;
               Objectives of
               the                  2.  equip students with the knowledge and principles of marketing management, tourism and hospitality management and its
                                       application in their future career;
               Department
                                    3.  develop global awareness among students to meet the dynamic requirements of marketing management, tourism and
                                       hospitality industry thru research works, and community development programs by creating strong linkages with related
                                       organizations; and
                                    4.  deliver a gender-fair and gender sensitive instructions to students aligned with the university goals and objectives.

                                                      Program Educational Objectives (based on the program CMO)

               The Bachelor of Science in Business Management graduates should be able to:

                   1.  apply theories and principles of business management;
                   2.  develop comprehensive business plans;
                   3.  conduct an in-depth analysis and provide creative solutions on various business situations both in the local and international setting;
                   4.  exemplify ethically responsible and gender sensitive behavior in all business undertakings;
                   5.  design knowledge–sharing arrangements /linkages and effectively deliver desired value contributions to the various sectors of the
                      society; and
                   6.  conduct relevant trainings and developmental extension activities among various stakeholders.
                                                 Student Outcomes and Relationship to Program Educational Objectives
                                                                                                           Program Educational Objectives Code (based on
                              Program/Student Outcomes (based on the program CMO)
                                                                                                                           the program CMO)


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[The campus shall endeavor to:

 Goals of the   1.  provide high quality of instructions that will lead to globally competitive students;
 College/   2.  develop researches and extension activities through arts, sciences and technology that will help in promoting the
 Campus
 university’s goals; and
 3.  develop graduates that are skilled and morally upright.


 The department shall endeavor to:

 1.  provide  high  quality  instruction  and  professional  expertise  to  students,  to  prepare  them  in  the  different  organizational
 settings as upright and competitive individuals;
 Objectives of
 the   2.  equip students with the knowledge and principles of marketing management, tourism and hospitality management and its
 application in their future career;
 Department
 3.  develop global awareness among students to meet the dynamic requirements of marketing management, tourism and
 hospitality industry thru research works, and community development programs by creating strong linkages with related
 organizations; and
 4.  deliver a gender-fair and gender sensitive instructions to students aligned with the university goals and objectives.

 Program Educational Objectives (based on the program CMO)

 The Bachelor of Science in Business Management graduates should be able to:

 1.  apply theories and principles of business management;
 2.  develop comprehensive business plans;
 3.  conduct an in-depth analysis and provide creative solutions on various business situations both in the local and international setting;
 4.  exemplify ethically responsible and gender sensitive behavior in all business undertakings;
 5.  design knowledge–sharing arrangements /linkages and effectively deliver desired value contributions to the various sectors of the
 society; and
 6.  conduct relevant trainings and developmental extension activities among various stakeholders.
 Student Outcomes and Relationship to Program Educational Objectives
                       Program Educational Objectives Code (based on
 Program/Student Outcomes (based on the program CMO)
                                      the program CMO)


                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[1        2        3         4        5        6
                     The students should:
                   a.   Analyze the business environment for strategic decision.                             ✓        ✓        ✓        ✓         ✓       ✓
                   b.   Prepare operational plans.                                                           ✓        ✓        ✓        ✓         ✓       ✓
                   c.   Innovate business ideas based on emerging industry.                                  ✓        ✓        ✓        ✓         ✓       ✓
                   d.   Manage a strategic business unit for economic sustainability.                        ✓        ✓        ✓        ✓         ✓       ✓
                   e.   Conduct business research.                                                           ✓        ✓        ✓        ✓         ✓       ✓
                                                        Course Outcomes and Relationship to Student Outcomes
                          Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course                                           Program Outcomes Code
                      After completing this course, the students will be able to:           a              b             c              d              e
                   1.  introduce the frameworks and models for e-commerce used in
                      business;                                                             I              I             E              E              I
                   2.  update  oneself  regarding  the  latest  trends  and  technologies   E              I             E              E              I
                      used in e-commerce;
                   3.  create simple e-commerce website;                                    D             E              D              D              E
                   4.  define  the  strategic  planning,  project  management,  enterprise   D            E              D              D              E
                      risk management and electronic marketing strategies; and
                   5.  integrate in business process the implementing standards used        D             D              D              D              E
                      in e-business.
                      *Level :          I-Introductory         E- Enabling           D-Demonstrative
                                                                           COURSE COVERAGE
                                                                                                                                                   Due Date
               Week                                                            Teaching and                                       Outcomes-            of
                No.         Intended Learning                Topic               Learning         Mode of       Resources            based         Submissio
                             Outcomes (ILO)                                                       Delivery        Needed         Assessment
                                                                              Activities (TLA)                                                        n of
                                                                                                                                     (OBA)
                                                                                                                                                     Output
                        After  the  completion  of  the  I.  Introduction    Synchronous           Online:        Online:         Reflection       On or
                        unit, students will be able to:   A.  University VMGO  and/or            Synchrono        Video of          Paper:         before the
                           1.  explain the vision,        and Quality        asynchronous         us online    CvSU Official   1-page reflection  end of
                               mission and quality                           discussion          discussion        AVP)           paper on the     week 1
                  1                                       Policy
                               policy of the          B.  Gender and                              via group     Powerpoint      relevance of e-
                               University;                                   Interactive Online    meeting      presentation     commerce in
                           2.  discuss the                Development        class discussion    app (Zoom,                      your goal as a
                               importance of          C.  Disaster                                  Cisco         Offline:          student.



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[1        2        3         4        5        6
 The students should:
 a.   Analyze the business environment for strategic decision.   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓
 b.   Prepare operational plans.   ✓   ✓   ✓        ✓         ✓       ✓
 c.   Innovate business ideas based on emerging industry.   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓
 d.   Manage a strategic business unit for economic sustainability.   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓
 e.   Conduct business research.   ✓   ✓   ✓        ✓         ✓       ✓
 Course Outcomes and Relationship to Student Outcomes
 Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course   Program Outcomes Code
 After completing this course, the students will be able to:   a   b   c   d   e
 1.  introduce the frameworks and models for e-commerce used in
 business;   I         I             E              E              I
 2.  update  oneself  regarding  the  latest  trends  and  technologies   E   I   E   E   I
 used in e-commerce;
 3.  create simple e-commerce website;   D   E   D   D            E
 4.  define  the  strategic  planning,  project  management,  enterprise   D   E   D   D   E
 risk management and electronic marketing strategies; and
 5.  integrate in business process the implementing standards used   D   D   D   D   E
 in e-business.
 *Level :          I-Introductory         E- Enabling           D-Demonstrative
 COURSE COVERAGE
                                                               Due Date
 Week   Teaching and                          Outcomes-            of
 No.   Intended Learning   Topic   Learning   Mode of   Resources   based   Submissio
 Outcomes (ILO)   Delivery    Needed         Assessment
 Activities (TLA)                                                 n of
                                                (OBA)
                                                                Output
 After  the  completion  of  the  I.  Introduction   Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Reflection   On or
 unit, students will be able to:   A.  University VMGO  and/or   Synchrono  Video of   Paper:   before the
 1.  explain the vision,   and Quality   asynchronous   us online   CvSU Official   1-page reflection  end of
 mission and quality   discussion    discussion   AVP)   paper on the   week 1
 1   Policy
 policy of the   B.  Gender and      via group   Powerpoint   relevance of e-
 University;   Interactive Online   meeting   presentation   commerce in
 2.  discuss the   Development   class discussion   app (Zoom,      your goal as a
 importance of   C.  Disaster      Cisco   Offline:   student.



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[gender and                 Management         Informal/ Creative   Webex or        Syllabus
                               development                Plan               Learning              Google        Handouts
                               awareness;             D.  Waste                                     Meet)
                           3.  identify the disaster      Management         Reflection
                               management plan;                                                    Offline:
                           4.  explain blended            Plan               Video watching of    Viewing of
                               learning approach;     E.  The Course         CvSU at the            video
                           5.  determine the                a.  Description   Glance retrieved   Reading of
                               course description,          b.  Content      from                    the
                               content and                  c.  Guidelines   https://www.youtu    provided
                               guidelines; and                  and          be.com/watch?v=       syllabus
                           6.  reflect personal goal            policies     _4bQ1Z9gUuA&t
                               as a student to        F.  Overview about     =49s
                               CvSU VMGO.                 Blended Learning

                        After the completion of the   II. Introduction on e-  Synchronous          Online:        Online:          Individual        On or
                        chapter, students will       Commerce                and/or              Synchrono      Video of the      Activity 1:      before the
                        be able to:                    A.  e-Commerce        asynchronous         us online      recorded        E-commerce          end of
                         1.  define e-Commerce;        B.  Business          discussion          discussion    synchronous      Elements of an       week 3
                         2.  explain how the               Models related                         via group      class via       Organization
                             Internet has enable           to E-Commerce     Interactive Online    meeting      zoom/Cisco
                             this type of business;    C.  Technical and     class discussion    app (Zoom,       Webex/        Group Activity
                         3.  identify the typical          Economic                                 Cisco      Google meet             1:
                             categories of making          Challenges        Informal/ Creative   Webex or                           Group
                 2-3         business digitally;                             Learning              Google         Offline:      presentation  of
                         4.  identify the                                                           Meet)       Module (can     the Title, design,
                             advantages and                                  Small Group                            be            and scope/
                             disadvantages of                                Discussion/         Consultatio    downloaded      features of their
                             digital business;                               Brainstorming       n via email    from CvSU        e-Commerce
                         5.  determine the                                                         or social       LMS)         Page (FB page)
                             technical and                                   Collaborative          media
                             economic challenges                             work                  platform     Multimedia
                             when doing business                                                                 resources
                             electronically; and                             Online                Offline:     (PowerPoint
                         6.  present the title,                              Quiz/Laboratory      Lectures     Presentation,



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[gender and   Management   Informal/ Creative   Webex or   Syllabus
 development   Plan   Learning   Google   Handouts
 awareness;   D.  Waste      Meet)
 3.  identify the disaster   Management   Reflection
 management plan;      Offline:
 4.  explain blended   Plan   Video watching of   Viewing of
 learning approach;   E.  The Course   CvSU at the   video
 5.  determine the   a.  Description   Glance retrieved   Reading of
 course description,   b.  Content   from   the
 content and   c.  Guidelines   https://www.youtu  provided
 guidelines; and   and   be.com/watch?v=  syllabus
 6.  reflect personal goal   policies   _4bQ1Z9gUuA&t
 as a student to   F.  Overview about   =49s
 CvSU VMGO.   Blended Learning

 After the completion of the   II. Introduction on e-  Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Individual   On or
 chapter, students will   Commerce   and/or   Synchrono  Video of the   Activity 1:   before the
 be able to:   A.  e-Commerce   asynchronous   us online   recorded   E-commerce   end of
 1.  define e-Commerce;    B.  Business   discussion    discussion   synchronous   Elements of an   week 3
 2.  explain how the   Models related      via group   class via   Organization
 Internet has enable   to E-Commerce   Interactive Online   meeting   zoom/Cisco
 this type of business;   C.  Technical and   class discussion   app (Zoom,   Webex/   Group Activity
 3.  identify the typical   Economic      Cisco   Google meet    1:
 categories of making   Challenges   Informal/ Creative   Webex or      Group
 2-3   business digitally;      Learning    Google   Offline:   presentation  of
    4.  identify the      Meet)   Module (can   the Title, design,
 advantages and   Small Group      be         and scope/
 disadvantages of   Discussion/   Consultatio  downloaded   features of their
 digital business;   Brainstorming   n via email   from CvSU   e-Commerce
 5.  determine the      or social   LMS)    Page (FB page)
 technical and   Collaborative   media
 economic challenges   work   platform   Multimedia
 when doing business         resources
 electronically; and   Online   Offline:   (PowerPoint
 6.  present the title,   Quiz/Laboratory   Lectures   Presentation,



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[design, and scope/                              Exercise             Readings      video clips,
                             features of an e-                                                                      etc.)
                             Commerce page (FB
                             page).                                                                             References
                                                                                                                (textbooks/
                                                                                                                  eBooks)

                                                                                                                 Computer
                                                                                                                unit/ laptop/
                                                                                                               tablet mobile
                                                                                                                   phone

                                                                                                                   Guide
                                                                                                                 Questions

                                                                                                                Rubrics for e-
                                                                                                                Commerce
                                                                                                                  Website
                                                                                                                Plan/Project
                                                                                                               (Website Title
                                                                                                                and Scope)
                        After the completion of the   III.  Frameworks and  Synchronous            Online:        Online:          Individual        On or
                        chapter, students will       Architecture            and/or              Synchrono      Video of the      Activity 2:      before the
                        be able to:                    A.  Actors and        asynchronous         us online      recorded          Part of e-        end of
                         1.  differentiate the main        Stakeholders      discussion          discussion    synchronous      commerce that        week 5
                             actors and                B.  Fundamental                            via group      class via       cannot still be
                             stakeholders in the           Sales Process     Interactive Online    meeting      zoom/Cisco         digitalized
                             area of e-Commerce;       C.  Technological     class discussion    app (Zoom,       Webex/        Traditional sales
                 4-5
                         2.  execute the                   Elements                                 Cisco      Google meet      process vs sales
                             fundamental sales                               Informal/ Creative   Webex or                      process in daily
                             process;                                        Learning              Google         Offline:            life
                         3.  identify the                                                           Meet)       Module (can
                             technological                                   Small Group                            be          Group Activity
                             elements, which                                 Discussion/         Consultatio    downloaded             2:
                             enabled the big                                 Brainstorming       n via email    from CvSU       Progress Report



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[design, and scope/   Exercise   Readings   video clips,
 features of an e-             etc.)
 Commerce page (FB
 page).                     References
                            (textbooks/
                             eBooks)

                             Computer
                            unit/ laptop/
                           tablet mobile
                              phone

                               Guide
                             Questions

                            Rubrics for e-
                            Commerce
                             Website
                            Plan/Project
                           (Website Title
                            and Scope)
 After the completion of the   III.  Frameworks and  Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Individual   On or
 chapter, students will   Architecture   and/or   Synchrono  Video of the   Activity 2:   before the
 be able to:   A.  Actors and   asynchronous   us online   recorded   Part of e-  end of
 1.  differentiate the main   Stakeholders   discussion    discussion   synchronous   commerce that   week 5
 actors and   B.  Fundamental      via group   class via   cannot still be
 stakeholders in the   Sales Process   Interactive Online   meeting   zoom/Cisco   digitalized
 area of e-Commerce;   C.  Technological   class discussion   app (Zoom,   Webex/   Traditional sales
 4-5
 2.  execute the   Elements      Cisco   Google meet    process vs sales
 fundamental sales   Informal/ Creative   Webex or      process in daily
 process;    Learning    Google   Offline:        life
 3.  identify the      Meet)   Module (can
 technological   Small Group      be        Group Activity
 elements, which   Discussion/   Consultatio  downloaded   2:
 enabled the big   Brainstorming   n via email   from CvSU   Progress Report



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[success of e-                                                         or social       LMS)        and Monitoring of
                             Commerce; and                                   Collaborative          media                        e-Commerce
                         4.  design a simple e-                              work                  platform     Multimedia           Page
                             Commerce Website                                                                    resources
                             Plan of the approved                            Online                Offline:     (PowerPoint
                             e-Commerce                                      Quiz/Laboratory      Lectures     Presentation,
                             business.                                       Exercise             Readings      video clips,
                                                                                                                    etc.)

                                                                                                                References
                                                                                                                (textbooks/
                                                                                                                  eBooks)

                                                                                                                 Computer
                                                                                                                unit/ laptop/
                                                                                                               tablet mobile
                                                                                                                   phone

                                                                                                                   Guide
                                                                                                                 Questions


                        After the completion of the   IV. B2C Business       Synchronous           Online:        Online:          Individual        On or
                        chapter, students will         A.  The Process       and/or              Synchrono      Video of the      Activity 3:      before the
                        be able to:                        model and its     asynchronous         us online      recorded       Payment before       end of
                         1.  define B2C Business;          variance          discussion          discussion    synchronous      or after delivery    week 7
                         2.  discuss the               B.  The Pricing                            via group      class via     in an online shop
                             fundamental sales             Challenge         Interactive Online    meeting      zoom/Cisco
                 6-7         process ;                 C.  The Fulfilment    class discussion    app (Zoom,       Webex/        Group Activity
                         3.  explain the three             Challenge                                Cisco      Google meet             3:
                             challenges in             D.  The Payment       Informal/ Creative   Webex or                      Progress Report
                             establishing B2C              Challenge         Learning              Google         Offline:     and Monitoring of
                             business; and             E.  B2C-Business                             Meet)       Module (can      e-Commerce
                         4.  add features/                 and CRM           Small Group                            be               Page
                             improvements on e-        F.  B2C Software      Discussion/         Consultatio    downloaded



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[success of e-     or social   LMS)        and Monitoring of
 Commerce; and   Collaborative   media       e-Commerce
 4.  design a simple e-  work   platform   Multimedia   Page
 Commerce Website            resources
 Plan of the approved   Online   Offline:   (PowerPoint
 e-Commerce   Quiz/Laboratory   Lectures   Presentation,
 business.     Exercise   Readings   video clips,
                               etc.)

                            References
                            (textbooks/
                             eBooks)

                             Computer
                            unit/ laptop/
                           tablet mobile
                              phone

                               Guide
                             Questions


 After the completion of the   IV. B2C Business   Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Individual   On or
 chapter, students will   A.  The Process   and/or   Synchrono  Video of the   Activity 3:   before the
 be able to:   model and its   asynchronous   us online   recorded   Payment before   end of
 1.  define B2C Business;   variance    discussion    discussion   synchronous   or after delivery   week 7
 2.  discuss the   B.  The Pricing      via group   class via   in an online shop
 fundamental sales   Challenge   Interactive Online   meeting   zoom/Cisco
 6-7   process ;   C.  The Fulfilment   class discussion   app (Zoom,   Webex/   Group Activity
 3.  explain the three   Challenge      Cisco   Google meet    3:
 challenges in   D.  The Payment   Informal/ Creative   Webex or      Progress Report
 establishing B2C   Challenge   Learning    Google   Offline:   and Monitoring of
 business; and   E.  B2C-Business      Meet)   Module (can   e-Commerce
 4.  add features/   and CRM   Small Group      be   Page
 improvements on e-  F.  B2C Software   Discussion/   Consultatio  downloaded



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Commerce Pag                  Systems           Brainstorming       n via email    from CvSU
                             (including B2C key                                                    or social       LMS)
                             factors).                                       Collaborative          media
                                                                             work                  platform     Multimedia
                                                                                                                 resources
                                                                             Online                Offline:     (PowerPoint
                                                                             Quiz/Laboratory      Lectures     Presentation,
                                                                             Exercise             Readings      video clips,
                                                                                                                    etc.)

                                                                                                                References
                                                                                                                (textbooks/
                                                                                                                  eBooks)

                                                                                                                 Computer
                                                                                                                unit/ laptop/
                                                                                                               tablet mobile
                                                                                                                   phone
                        After the completion of the   V. B2B Business        Synchronous           Online:        Online:          Individual        On or
                        chapter, students will be      A.  The Process       and/or              Synchrono      Video of the      Activity 4:      before the
                        able to:                           model and its     asynchronous         us online      recorded       Comparison of 2      end of
                         1.  define B2B Business;          variants          discussion          discussion    synchronous      different market     week 8
                         2.  identify the              B.  B2B Software                           via group      class via       places online
                             commonalities of B2C          Systems           Interactive Online    meeting      zoom/Cisco
                             and B2B businesses;                             class discussion    app (Zoom,       Webex/        Group Activity
                          3.  differentiate B2C and                                                 Cisco      Google meet             4:
                  8           B2B businesses; and                            Informal/ Creative   Webex or                      Progress Report
                         4.  add features/                                   Learning              Google         Offline:     and Monitoring of
                             improvements on e-                                                     Meet)       Module (can      e-Commerce
                             Commerce Page                                   Small Group                            be               Page
                             .                                               Discussion/         Consultatio    downloaded
                                                                             Brainstorming       n via email    from CvSU
                                                                                                   or social       LMS)
                                                                             Collaborative          media
                                                                             work                  platform     Multimedia



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Commerce Pag   Systems   Brainstorming   n via email   from CvSU
 (including B2C key      or social   LMS)
 factors).   Collaborative   media
    work      platform      Multimedia
                             resources
 Online        Offline:    (PowerPoint
 Quiz/Laboratory   Lectures   Presentation,
 Exercise     Readings      video clips,
                               etc.)

                            References
                            (textbooks/
                             eBooks)

                             Computer
                            unit/ laptop/
                           tablet mobile
                              phone
 After the completion of the   V. B2B Business   Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Individual   On or
 chapter, students will be   A.  The Process   and/or   Synchrono  Video of the   Activity 4:   before the
 able to:   model and its   asynchronous   us online   recorded   Comparison of 2   end of
 1.  define B2B Business;    variants   discussion    discussion   synchronous   different market   week 8
 2.  identify the   B.  B2B Software      via group   class via   places online
 commonalities of B2C   Systems   Interactive Online   meeting   zoom/Cisco
 and B2B businesses;   class discussion   app (Zoom,   Webex/   Group Activity
 3.  differentiate B2C and      Cisco   Google meet    4:
 8   B2B businesses; and   Informal/ Creative   Webex or      Progress Report
 4.  add features/   Learning    Google   Offline:   and Monitoring of
 improvements on e-     Meet)   Module (can   e-Commerce
 Commerce Page   Small Group      be             Page
 .    Discussion/   Consultatio  downloaded
    Brainstorming   n via email   from CvSU
              or social        LMS)
 Collaborative   media
 work         platform      Multimedia



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[resources
                                                                             Online                Offline:     (PowerPoint
                                                                             Quiz/Laboratory      Lectures     Presentation,
                                                                             Exercise             Readings      video clips,
                                                                                                                    etc.)

                                                                                                                References
                                                                                                                (textbooks/
                                                                                                                  eBooks)

                                                                                                                 Computer
                                                                                                                unit/ laptop/
                                                                                                               tablet mobile
                                                                                                                   phone
                  9                             MIDTERM EXAMINATION (Presentation of E-Commerce Website (Design and Content)
                        After the completion of the   VI. Impact of e-        Synchronous          Online:        Online:         Individual         On or
                        chapter, students will be     Commerce                and/or             Synchrono      Video of the      Activity 5:      before the
                        able to:                         A.  Ethics, Morale  asynchronous         us online      recorded        e-commerce          end of
                         1.  explain the                     & Technology     discussion          discussion   synchronous        price levels:     week 11
                             consequences of ICT         B.  Ethical                              via group      class via       increasing or
                             in the area of ethics           Aspects of IT    Interactive Online   meeting      zoom/Cisco        decreasing?
                             and morale;                 C.  Overall          class discussion       app          Webex/
                         2.  discuss the positive            Impacts of E-                         (Zoom,      Google meet      Group Activity
                             and negative impact of          Commerce         Informal/             Cisco                              5:
               10-11         e-Commerce on               D.  Specific         Creative            Webex or        Offline:      Progress Report
                             human being; and                Impacts of E-    Learning             Google       Module (can    and Monitoring of
                         3.  identify the significant        Commerce                               Meet)           be           e-Commerce
                             changes in the                                   Small Group                       downloaded           Page
                             economic world                                   Discussion/        Consultatio    from CvSU
                             brought by e-                                    Brainstorming      n via email       LMS)
                             Commerce.                                                             or social
                                                                              Collaborative         media       Multimedia
                                                                              work                 platform      resources
                                                                                                                (PowerPoint
                                                                              Online               Offline:    Presentation,



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[resources
 Online        Offline:    (PowerPoint
 Quiz/Laboratory   Lectures   Presentation,
 Exercise     Readings      video clips,
                               etc.)

                            References
                            (textbooks/
                             eBooks)

                             Computer
                            unit/ laptop/
                           tablet mobile
                              phone
 9   MIDTERM EXAMINATION (Presentation of E-Commerce Website (Design and Content)
 After the completion of the   VI. Impact of e-  Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Individual   On or
 chapter, students will be   Commerce   and/or   Synchrono  Video of the   Activity 5:    before the
 able to:   A.  Ethics, Morale  asynchronous   us online   recorded   e-commerce   end of
 1.  explain the   & Technology   discussion    discussion   synchronous   price levels:   week 11
 consequences of ICT   B.  Ethical      via group   class via   increasing or
 in the area of ethics   Aspects of IT   Interactive Online   meeting   zoom/Cisco   decreasing?
 and morale;   C.  Overall   class discussion   app   Webex/
 2.  discuss the positive   Impacts of E-     (Zoom,   Google meet    Group Activity
 and negative impact of   Commerce   Informal/   Cisco      5:
 10-11   e-Commerce on   D.  Specific   Creative   Webex or   Offline:   Progress Report
    human being; and   Impacts of E-  Learning    Google   Module (can   and Monitoring of
 3.  identify the significant   Commerce      Meet)   be   e-Commerce
 changes in the   Small Group      downloaded    Page
 economic world   Discussion/   Consultatio  from CvSU
 brought by e-  Brainstorming   n via email   LMS)
 Commerce.       or social
    Collaborative   media   Multimedia
 work          platform      resources
                           (PowerPoint
 Online        Offline:    Presentation,



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Quiz/Laboratory     Lectures      video clips,
                                                                              Exercise            Readings          etc.)

                                                                                                                References
                                                                                                                (textbooks/
                                                                                                                  eBooks)

                                                                                                                 Computer
                                                                                                                unit/ laptop/
                                                                                                               tablet mobile
                                                                                                                   phone
                        After the completion of the   VII. Security and       Synchronous          Online:        Online:         Individual         On or
                        chapter, students will be     Compliance              and/or             Synchrono      Video of the    Activity 6: Risk   before the
                        able to:                      Management              asynchronous        us online      recorded        Management          end of
                         1.  define the basic          A.  Foundation of      discussion          discussion   synchronous      Strategies in e-    week 13
                             elements of risk              Risk                                   via group      class via        Commerce
                             management;                   Management         Interactive Online   meeting      zoom/Cisco
                         2.  explain compliance        B.  Compliance         class discussion       app          Webex/        Group Activity
                             management;                   Management                              (Zoom,      Google meet             6:
                         3.  identify the basic        C.  Information        Informal/             Cisco                       Progress Report
                             elements of                   Security           Creative            Webex or        Offline:     and Monitoring of
                             information security          Management         Learning             Google       Module (can      e-Commerce
               12-13         management;               D.  Technology                               Meet)           be               Page
                         4.  apply security            E.  Legal Aspects of  Small Group                        downloaded
                             management and                E-Commerce         Discussion/        Consultatio    from CvSU
                             compliance to the e-                             Brainstorming      n via email       LMS)
                             commerce business;                                                    or social
                             and                                              Collaborative         media       Multimedia
                         5.  describe the most                                work                 platform      resources
                             important legal                                                                    (PowerPoint
                             aspects of e-                                    Online               Offline:    Presentation,
                             Commerce.                                        Quiz/Laboratory     Lectures      video clips,
                                                                              Exercise            Readings          etc.)

                                                                                                                References



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Quiz/Laboratory   Lectures   video clips,
 Exercise     Readings         etc.)

                            References
                            (textbooks/
                             eBooks)

                             Computer
                            unit/ laptop/
                           tablet mobile
                              phone
 After the completion of the   VII. Security and   Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Individual   On or
 chapter, students will be   Compliance   and/or   Synchrono  Video of the   Activity 6: Risk   before the
 able to:   Management   asynchronous   us online   recorded   Management   end of
 1.  define the basic   A.  Foundation of   discussion    discussion   synchronous   Strategies in e-  week 13
 elements of risk   Risk      via group   class via   Commerce
 management;   Management   Interactive Online   meeting   zoom/Cisco
 2.  explain compliance   B.  Compliance   class discussion   app   Webex/   Group Activity
 management;   Management      (Zoom,   Google meet    6:
 3.  identify the basic   C.  Information   Informal/   Cisco      Progress Report
 elements of   Security   Creative   Webex or   Offline:   and Monitoring of
 information security   Management   Learning    Google   Module (can   e-Commerce
 12-13   management;   D.  Technology      Meet)   be   Page
    4.  apply security   E.  Legal Aspects of  Small Group      downloaded
 management and   E-Commerce   Discussion/   Consultatio  from CvSU
 compliance to the e-  Brainstorming   n via email   LMS)
 commerce business;      or social
 and   Collaborative   media   Multimedia
 5.  describe the most   work   platform   resources
 important legal           (PowerPoint
 aspects of e-  Online   Offline:   Presentation,
 Commerce.   Quiz/Laboratory   Lectures   video clips,
 Exercise     Readings         etc.)

                            References



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[(textbooks/
                                                                                                                  eBooks)

                                                                                                                 Computer
                                                                                                                unit/ laptop/
                                                                                                               tablet mobile
                                                                                                                   phone
                        After the completion of the   VIII. Electronic        Synchronous          Online:        Online:         Individual         On or
                        chapter, students will be     Payment                 and/or             Synchrono      Video of the      Activity 7:      before the
                        able to:                       A.  Business and       asynchronous        us online      recorded        Encouraging         end of
                         1.  explain how money             Money              discussion          discussion   synchronous     customers to pay     week 15
                             helps to make             B.  The Payment                            via group      class via          online.
                             business;                     Challenge          Interactive Online   meeting      zoom/Cisco
                         2.  identify which payment    C.  Payment            class discussion       app          Webex/        Group Activity
                             method/s is/are should        Procedures                              (Zoom,      Google meet             7:
                             be included in an e-      D.  Receivables        Informal/             Cisco                       Progress Report
                             Commerce business;            Management         Creative            Webex or        Offline:     and Monitoring of
                         3.  determine the roles       E.  Cyber Money        Learning             Google       Module (can      e-Commerce
                             played by banks and                                                    Meet)           be               page
                             payment service                                  Small Group                       downloaded
               14-15         providers; and                                   Discussion/        Consultatio    from CvSU
                         4.  explain how cyber                                Brainstorming      n via email       LMS)
                             money becomes an                                                      or social
                             appropriate means for                            Collaborative         media       Multimedia
                             running an e-                                    work                 platform      resources
                             Commerce business.                                                                 (PowerPoint
                                                                                   Online          Offline:    Presentation,
                                                                              Quiz/Laboratory     Lectures      video clips,
                                                                                  Exercise        Readings          etc.)

                                                                                                                References
                                                                                                                (textbooks/
                                                                                                                  eBooks)

                                                                                                                 Computer



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[(textbooks/
                             eBooks)

                             Computer
                            unit/ laptop/
                           tablet mobile
                              phone
 After the completion of the   VIII. Electronic   Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Individual   On or
 chapter, students will be   Payment   and/or   Synchrono  Video of the   Activity 7:   before the
 able to:   A.  Business and   asynchronous   us online   recorded   Encouraging   end of
 1.  explain how money   Money   discussion    discussion   synchronous   customers to pay   week 15
 helps to make   B.  The Payment      via group   class via   online.
 business;   Challenge   Interactive Online   meeting   zoom/Cisco
 2.  identify which payment   C.  Payment   class discussion   app   Webex/   Group Activity
 method/s is/are should   Procedures      (Zoom,   Google meet    7:
 be included in an e-  D.  Receivables   Informal/   Cisco      Progress Report
 Commerce business;   Management   Creative   Webex or   Offline:   and Monitoring of
 3.  determine the roles   E.  Cyber Money   Learning    Google   Module (can   e-Commerce
 played by banks and         Meet)   be          page
 payment service   Small Group      downloaded
 14-15   providers; and   Discussion/   Consultatio  from CvSU
    4.  explain how cyber   Brainstorming   n via email   LMS)
 money becomes an      or social
 appropriate means for   Collaborative   media   Multimedia
 running an e-  work   platform   resources
 Commerce business.         (PowerPoint
 Online        Offline:    Presentation,
 Quiz/Laboratory   Lectures   video clips,
 Exercise     Readings         etc.)

                            References
                            (textbooks/
                             eBooks)

                             Computer



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[unit/ laptop/
                                                                                                               tablet mobile
                                                                                                                   phone
                        After the completion of the   IX. Performance         Synchronous          Online:        Online:         Individual         On or
                        chapter, students will be     Management              and/or             Synchrono      Video of the      Activity 8:      before the
                        able to:                       A.  Foundations of     asynchronous        us online      recorded      Conversion Rate       end of
                         1.  identify are the basic        Performance        discussion          discussion   synchronous        in an Online      week 17
                             terms on ICT                  Analysis                               via group      class via           Shop
                             performance               B.  ICT                Interactive Online   meeting      zoom/Cisco
                             management;                   Performance        class discussion       app          Webex/          Online Shop
                         2.  implement KPIs and            Management                              (Zoom,      Google meet   Monitoring Score
                             scorecards as                                    Informal/             Cisco                            Card
                             important tools for ICT                          Creative            Webex or        Offline:
                             Performance                                      Learning             Google       Module (can     Group Activity
                             Management;                                                            Meet)           be                 8:
                         3.  determine the main                               Small Group                       downloaded      Progress Report
                             control objects in the                           Discussion/        Consultatio    from CvSU      and Monitoring of
                             ICT area;                                        Brainstorming      n via email       LMS)          e-Commerce
               16-17     4.  measure the                                                           or social                         Page

                             performance in the ICT                           Collaborative         media       Multimedia
                             area; and                                        work                 platform      resources         Project:
                         5.  present the final output                                                           (PowerPoint      e-Commerce
                             (e-Commerce Page)                                     Online          Offline:    Presentation,       Page and
                                                                              Quiz/Laboratory     Lectures      video clips,    Documentation
                                                                                  Exercise        Readings          etc.)

                                                                                                                References
                                                                                                                (textbooks/
                                                                                                                  eBooks)

                                                                                                                 Computer
                                                                                                                unit/ laptop/
                                                                                                               tablet mobile
                                                                                                                   phone
                 18                           FINAL EXAMINATION  (Presentation of Complete e-Commerce Page with Financial Report)



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[unit/ laptop/
                           tablet mobile
                              phone
 After the completion of the   IX. Performance   Synchronous   Online:   Online:   Individual   On or
 chapter, students will be   Management   and/or   Synchrono  Video of the   Activity 8:   before the
 able to:   A.  Foundations of   asynchronous   us online   recorded   Conversion Rate   end of
 1.  identify are the basic   Performance   discussion    discussion   synchronous   in an Online   week 17
 terms on ICT   Analysis      via group   class via   Shop
 performance   B.  ICT   Interactive Online   meeting   zoom/Cisco
 management;    Performance   class discussion   app   Webex/   Online Shop
 2.  implement KPIs and   Management      (Zoom,   Google meet   Monitoring Score
 scorecards as   Informal/   Cisco               Card
 important tools for ICT   Creative   Webex or   Offline:
 Performance   Learning    Google   Module (can   Group Activity
 Management;      Meet)         be                8:
 3.  determine the main   Small Group      downloaded   Progress Report
 control objects in the   Discussion/   Consultatio  from CvSU   and Monitoring of
 ICT area;   Brainstorming   n via email   LMS)   e-Commerce
 16-17   4.  measure the      or social          Page

 performance in the ICT   Collaborative   media   Multimedia
 area; and   work   platform   resources       Project:
 5.  present the final output         (PowerPoint   e-Commerce
 (e-Commerce Page)   Online   Offline:   Presentation,   Page and
 Quiz/Laboratory   Lectures   video clips,   Documentation
 Exercise     Readings         etc.)

                            References
                            (textbooks/
                             eBooks)

                             Computer
                            unit/ laptop/
                           tablet mobile
                              phone
 18   FINAL EXAMINATION  (Presentation of Complete e-Commerce Page with Financial Report)



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[COURSE REQUIREMENTS
               Requirements:

                   1.  Group Activities
                   2.  Individual Activities
                   3.  Midterm Examination
                   4.  Final Examination
                   5.  Participation/Recitation/Attendance
                   6.  Class or Group Project

               *All exams must follow a Table of Specifications (TOS) and Rubrics for evaluation of student’ performance or projects.

                                                                            GRADING SYSTEM
               Grading system (for 3 units lecture)

                     Group Activities                                                     20%
                     Individual Activities                                                15%
                     Midterm Examination                                                  20%
                     Final Examination                                                    20%
                     Participation/Recitation/Attendance                                  10%
                     Class or Group Project                                               15%
                                                                                          100%


                      Passing Grade is 70%

                    STANDARD TRANSMUTATION TABLE FOR ALL COURSES

                      96.7 – 100.0            1.00
                      93.4 – 96.6              1.25
                      90.1 - 93.30             1.50
                      86.7 – 90.0              1.75
                      83.4 – 86.6              2.00
                      80.1 – 83.3              2.25
                      76.7 – 80.0              2.50
                      73.4 – 76.6              2.75



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[COURSE REQUIREMENTS
 Requirements:

 1.  Group Activities
 2.  Individual Activities
 3.  Midterm Examination
 4.  Final Examination
 5.  Participation/Recitation/Attendance
 6.  Class or Group Project

 *All exams must follow a Table of Specifications (TOS) and Rubrics for evaluation of student’ performance or projects.

 GRADING SYSTEM
 Grading system (for 3 units lecture)

 Group Activities   20%
 Individual Activities   15%
 Midterm Examination   20%
 Final Examination   20%
 Participation/Recitation/Attendance   10%
  Class or Group Project         15%
      100%


 Passing Grade is 70%

 STANDARD TRANSMUTATION TABLE FOR ALL COURSES

 96.7 – 100.0            1.00
 93.4 – 96.6              1.25
 90.1 - 93.30             1.50
 86.7 – 90.0              1.75
 83.4 – 86.6              2.00
 80.1 – 83.3              2.25
 76.7 – 80.0              2.50
 73.4 – 76.6              2.75



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[70.00 – 73.3            3.00
                      50.0-69.9                4.00
                      Below 50                5.00
                      INC                         Passed the course but lack some requirements.
                      Dropped                If unexcused absence is at least 20% of the Total Class Hours.

                      Total Class Hours/Semester: (2 unit Lec – 36 hrs; 1 unit Lab – 54 hrs) 90 hours

                                                                             CLASS POLICIES
               A.  Attendance
                   Students are not allowed to have 20% or more unexcused absences of the total face to face class hours; otherwise, they will be graded as
                   “DROPPED”.

               B.  Classroom Decorum

                   During face to face mode
                        Students are required to:
                        1.  wear identification cards at all times;
                        2.  wear face mask at all times
                        3.  observe physical/social distancing at all times
                        4.  clean the classroom before and after classes;
                        5.  avoid unnecessary noise that might disturb other classes;
                        6.  practice good manners and right conduct at all times;
                        7.  practice gender sensitivity and awareness inside the classroom; and
                        8.  come to class on time.

                   During distance mode
                        Students are required to:
                        1.  sign an honor system pledge;
                        2.  avoid giving or receiving unauthorized aid of any kind on their examinations, papers, projects and assignments,
                        3.  observe proper netiquette during on-line activities, and
                        4.  submit take home assignments on time.

               C.  Examination/ Evaluation
                        1.  Quizzes may be announced or unannounced.



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[70.00 – 73.3            3.00
 50.0-69.9                4.00
 Below 50                5.00
 INC                         Passed the course but lack some requirements.
 Dropped                If unexcused absence is at least 20% of the Total Class Hours.

 Total Class Hours/Semester: (2 unit Lec – 36 hrs; 1 unit Lab – 54 hrs) 90 hours

 CLASS POLICIES
 A.  Attendance
 Students are not allowed to have 20% or more unexcused absences of the total face to face class hours; otherwise, they will be graded as
 “DROPPED”.

 B.  Classroom Decorum

 During face to face mode
      Students are required to:
 1.  wear identification cards at all times;
 2.  wear face mask at all times
 3.  observe physical/social distancing at all times
 4.  clean the classroom before and after classes;
 5.  avoid unnecessary noise that might disturb other classes;
 6.  practice good manners and right conduct at all times;
 7.  practice gender sensitivity and awareness inside the classroom; and
 8.  come to class on time.

 During distance mode
      Students are required to:
 1.  sign an honor system pledge;
 2.  avoid giving or receiving unauthorized aid of any kind on their examinations, papers, projects and assignments,
 3.  observe proper netiquette during on-line activities, and
 4.  submit take home assignments on time.

 C.  Examination/ Evaluation
 1.  Quizzes may be announced or unannounced.



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[2.  Mid-term and Final Examinations are scheduled.
                        3.  Cheating is strictly prohibited. A student who is caught cheating will be given a score of ”0” for the first offense. For the second
                           offense, the student will be automatically given a failing grade in the subject.
                        4.  Students who will miss a mid-term or final examination, a laboratory exercise or a class project may be excused and allowed to take
                           a special exam, conduct a laboratory exercise or pass a class project for any of the following reasons:
                                a.  participation in a University/College-approved field trip or activity;
                                b.  due to illness or death in the family; and
                                c.  due to force majeure or natural calamities.

                                                             REFERENCES & SUPPLEMENTARY READINGS
               References:

                   A.  Required Textbook/Workbook

                   B.  Laboratory Manual (if with laboratory)

                   C.  Reference Books
                       Bridge, D. & Stuckenschmidt, H. (2017). E-commerce and web technologies. Switzerland: Springer.

                                                                                                                                nd
                       Reynolds, J. The complete e-commerce book: Design, build & maintain a successful web-based business (2  Ed). USA: Focal Press

                   D.  Electronic References (E-books/Websites)
                       Bridge, D. & Stuckenschmidt, H. (2017). E-commerce and web technologies. Switzerland: Springer. Retrieved from
                                https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_ 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid=
                                IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

                                                                                                                    st
                       Kutz, M. (2016). Introduction to e-commerce: Combining business and information technology (1  Ed). Bookboon.com. Retrieved
                                from https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid= IwAR0ddM2h-
                                TwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

                                                                                                                th
                       Laudon, K.C. & Traver, C.G. (2017). E-commerce 2017:  Business. Technology. Society (13  Ed). USA: Pearson. Retrieved from
                                https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_ 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid=
                                IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

                       Stuckenschmidt, H. & Jannach, D. (2015). E-commerce and web technologies. Switzerland: Springer. Retrieved from



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[2.  Mid-term and Final Examinations are scheduled.
 3.  Cheating is strictly prohibited. A student who is caught cheating will be given a score of ”0” for the first offense. For the second
 offense, the student will be automatically given a failing grade in the subject.
 4.  Students who will miss a mid-term or final examination, a laboratory exercise or a class project may be excused and allowed to take
 a special exam, conduct a laboratory exercise or pass a class project for any of the following reasons:
 a.  participation in a University/College-approved field trip or activity;
 b.  due to illness or death in the family; and
 c.  due to force majeure or natural calamities.

 REFERENCES & SUPPLEMENTARY READINGS
 References:

 A.  Required Textbook/Workbook

 B.  Laboratory Manual (if with laboratory)

 C.  Reference Books
 Bridge, D. & Stuckenschmidt, H. (2017). E-commerce and web technologies. Switzerland: Springer.

                                            nd
 Reynolds, J. The complete e-commerce book: Design, build & maintain a successful web-based business (2  Ed). USA: Focal Press

 D.  Electronic References (E-books/Websites)
 Bridge, D. & Stuckenschmidt, H. (2017). E-commerce and web technologies. Switzerland: Springer. Retrieved from
 https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_ 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid=
 IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

                                st
 Kutz, M. (2016). Introduction to e-commerce: Combining business and information technology (1  Ed). Bookboon.com. Retrieved
 from https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid= IwAR0ddM2h-
 TwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

                            th
 Laudon, K.C. & Traver, C.G. (2017). E-commerce 2017:  Business. Technology. Society (13  Ed). USA: Pearson. Retrieved from
 https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_ 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid=
 IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

 Stuckenschmidt, H. & Jannach, D. (2015). E-commerce and web technologies. Switzerland: Springer. Retrieved from



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_ 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid=
                                IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

                       Turban, E., Outland, J., King, D., Lee, J.K., Liang, T., & Turban, D.C. (2018). Electronic commerce2018: A managerial and social
                                                       th
                                networks perspective (9  Ed). Retrieved from https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_
                                2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid= IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

                       Ullman, L. (2011). Effortless e-commerce with PHP and MySQL. USA: Pearson. Retrieved from
                                https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_ 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid=
                                IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg
                                                                           REVISION HISTORY
                  Revision              Date of Revision                    Date of Implementation                         Highlights of Revision
                  Number
                       1                January 27, 2020                 Second Semester, AY 2019-2020                     Update contents and TLA
                                                                                                                  OBE Syllabus revision with flexible learning
                       2                 June 30, 2020                    First Semester, AY 2020-2021
                                                                                                                                   approach
                       3               February 15, 2021                 Second Semester, AY 2020-2021                         Revised Activities
               Prepared by:                                       Evaluated by:                                   Approved:


               MELONA I. SAQUIN                                   RITCH M. BANATE, MBA                            GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Instructor                                         Chairperson                                     Campus Administrator
               0930-095-8194                                      Department of Management                        Tanza Campus
               E-mail Address: melona.igmasine@cvsu.edu.ph        ritchbanate@cvsu.edu.ph                         Date Approved: February 22, 2021
               Consultation Schedule: Wednesday 2pm-4pm           Date Evaluated: February 18, 2021
               Date Prepared: February 15, 2021
















                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_ 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid=
 IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

 Turban, E., Outland, J., King, D., Lee, J.K., Liang, T., & Turban, D.C. (2018). Electronic commerce2018: A managerial and social
 th
 networks perspective (9  Ed). Retrieved from https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_
 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid= IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg

 Ullman, L. (2011). Effortless e-commerce with PHP and MySQL. USA: Pearson. Retrieved from
 https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1VbP0dcBa_ 2cxkroAUyrhwVKdIINVmmfX?fbclid=
 IwAR0ddM2hTwPADWFlmiiWck2tGzJlS4lsIgjvh0w2w_JlqeKkVmKwS0ezPg
 REVISION HISTORY
 Revision   Date of Revision   Date of Implementation   Highlights of Revision
 Number
 1   January 27, 2020   Second Semester, AY 2019-2020   Update contents and TLA
                              OBE Syllabus revision with flexible learning
 2   June 30, 2020   First Semester, AY 2020-2021
                                               approach
 3   February 15, 2021   Second Semester, AY 2020-2021   Revised Activities
 Prepared by:   Evaluated by:   Approved:


 MELONA I. SAQUIN   RITCH M. BANATE, MBA   GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
 Instructor   Chairperson    Campus Administrator
 0930-095-8194   Department of Management   Tanza Campus
 E-mail Address: melona.igmasine@cvsu.edu.ph   ritchbanate@cvsu.edu.ph   Date Approved: February 22, 2021
 Consultation Schedule: Wednesday 2pm-4pm   Date Evaluated: February 18, 2021
 Date Prepared: February 15, 2021
















                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[VPAA-QF-10



                      CvSU Vision                                      Republic of the Philippines                            CvSU Mission
                                                                                                                        Cavite  State  University  shall  provide
                    The premier university in                      CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY                          excellent,  equitable  and  relevant  educational
                 historic  Cavite  recognized                                                                       opportunities  in  the  arts,  science  and
                 for   excellence   in   the                                     Tanza Campus                       technology  through  quality  instruction  and
                 development  of  globally                               Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite                      relevant research and development activities.
                 competitive  and  morally                                    (046) 414-3979                           It  shall  produce  professional,  skilled  and
                 upright individuals.                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph                         morally   upright   individuals   for   global
                                                                                                                    competitiveness.

                                                                   DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT

                                                                           COURSE SYLLABUS
                                                                      Second Semester, AY 2020-2021

                 Course                                          Product                                 Lecture ✓
                 Code          MKTG 60          Course Title     Management          Type                Laboratory _     Credit Units      3
                 Course        The course discusses product management typically deals with all of the end-to-end aspects of a product or product line including product
                 Description   profitability, the role may be split with closely related functions product marketing, program management, and project management.
                                                                                                       Monday, 9:00 am-12:00 nn (Section 1)
                 Pre-          MKTG 50 and MKTG 55               Course Schedule                       Monday, 1:00-4:00 pm (Section 2)
                 requisites                                                                            Wednesday, 9:00 am-12:00 nn (Section 3)
                                                                                                       Thursday, 9:00 am-12:00 nn (Section 4)
                               Students are expected to live by and stand for the following University tenets:

                               TRUTH is demonstrated by the student’s objectivity and honesty during examinations, class activities and in the development of projects.

                               EXCELLENCE is exhibited by the students’ self-confidence, punctuality, diligence and commitment in the assigned tasks, class performance
                 Core Values
                               and other course requirements.

                               SERVICE  is  manifested  by  the  students’  respect,  rapport,  fairness  and  cooperation  in  dealing  with  their  peers  and  members  of  the
                               community.
                               In addition, they should exhibit love and respect for nature and support for the cause of humanity.
                               The Campus shall endeavor to achieve the following goals:
                 Goals of the   1.  Provide high quality instruction in order to produce skilled, morally upright, and globally competitive graduates:
                 Campus        2.  Develop and pursue advance research activities through arts, sciences, and technology to support instruction: and
                               3.  Develop and conduct extension activities that will empower local people and communities.


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-06-01]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[VPAA-QF-10



 CvSU Vision   Republic of the Philippines   CvSU Mission
                                   Cavite  State  University  shall  provide
 The premier university in   CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY   excellent,  equitable  and  relevant  educational
 historic  Cavite  recognized   opportunities  in  the  arts,  science  and
 for   excellence   in   the         Tanza Campus   technology  through  quality  instruction  and
 development  of  globally   Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite   relevant research and development activities.
 competitive  and  morally     (046) 414-3979   It  shall  produce  professional,  skilled  and
 upright individuals.   www.cvsu.edu.ph   morally   upright   individuals   for   global
                                competitiveness.

 DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT

 COURSE SYLLABUS
 Second Semester, AY 2020-2021

 Course   Product    Lecture ✓
 Code   MKTG 60   Course Title   Management   Type   Laboratory _   Credit Units   3
 Course   The course discusses product management typically deals with all of the end-to-end aspects of a product or product line including product
 Description   profitability, the role may be split with closely related functions product marketing, program management, and project management.
                   Monday, 9:00 am-12:00 nn (Section 1)
 Pre-  MKTG 50 and MKTG 55   Course Schedule   Monday, 1:00-4:00 pm (Section 2)
 requisites        Wednesday, 9:00 am-12:00 nn (Section 3)
                   Thursday, 9:00 am-12:00 nn (Section 4)
 Students are expected to live by and stand for the following University tenets:

 TRUTH is demonstrated by the student’s objectivity and honesty during examinations, class activities and in the development of projects.

 EXCELLENCE is exhibited by the students’ self-confidence, punctuality, diligence and commitment in the assigned tasks, class performance
 Core Values
 and other course requirements.

 SERVICE  is  manifested  by  the  students’  respect,  rapport,  fairness  and  cooperation  in  dealing  with  their  peers  and  members  of  the
 community.
 In addition, they should exhibit love and respect for nature and support for the cause of humanity.
 The Campus shall endeavor to achieve the following goals:
 Goals of the   1.  Provide high quality instruction in order to produce skilled, morally upright, and globally competitive graduates:
 Campus   2.  Develop and pursue advance research activities through arts, sciences, and technology to support instruction: and
 3.  Develop and conduct extension activities that will empower local people and communities.


                                                          V02-2020-06-01]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[The department shall endeavor to:
                                  1.  provide high quality instruction and professional expertise to students, to prepare them in the different organizational settings as
                                      upright and competitive individuals;
                 Objectives       2.  equip students with the knowledge and principles of marketing management, tourism and hospitality management and its application
                 of the               in their future career;
                 Department
                                  3.  develop global awareness among students to meet the dynamic requirements of marketing management, tourism and hospitality
                                      industry thru research works, and community development programs by creating strong linkages with related organizations; and
                                  4.  deliver a gender-fair and gender sensitive instructions to students aligned with the university goals and objectives.
                                                       Program Educational Objectives (based on the program CMO)
                 The Bachelor of Science in Business Management graduates should be able to:
                    1.  Apply theories and principles of business management.
                    2.  Develop comprehensive business plans.
                    3.  Conduct an in-depth analysis and provide creative solutions on various business situations both in the local and international setting.
                    4.  Exemplify ethically responsible and gender sensitive behavior in all business undertakings.
                    5.  Design knowledge–sharing arrangements /linkages and effectively deliver desired value contributions to the various sectors of the society.
                    6.  Conduct relevant trainings and developmental extension activities among various stakeholders.
                                                   Student Outcomes and Relationship to Program Educational Objectives
                                                                                                       Program Educational Objectives Code (based on the
                               Program/Student Outcomes (based on the program CMO)                                       program CMO)
                                                                                                          1        2       3        4        5       6
                 The students should:
                    a.   Analyze the business environment for strategic decision.                         ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓
                    b.   Prepare operational plans.                                                       ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓
                    c.   Innovate business ideas based on emerging industry.                              ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓
                    d.   Manage a strategic business unit for economic sustainability.                    ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓
                    e.   Conduct business research.                                                       ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓       ✓        ✓
                                                          Course Outcomes and Relationship to Student Outcomes
                           Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course                                   Program/Student Outcomes Code
                       After completing this course, the students must be able to:       a             b             c              d             e
                    1.  explain the role of product management in business success;      I             I                            I              I
                    2.  describe the role the product manager plays;                     I             I                            I              I
                    3.  generate great product ideas;                                   D              D             D              D             D
                    4.  develop business case, market needs, product description,
                        market strategy, road map, launch plan, and comprehensive       D              D             D              D             D
                        marketing plan.
                        *Level :          I-Introductory         E- Enabling           D-Demonstrative





                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[The department shall endeavor to:
 1.  provide high quality instruction and professional expertise to students, to prepare them in the different organizational settings as
 upright and competitive individuals;
 Objectives   2.  equip students with the knowledge and principles of marketing management, tourism and hospitality management and its application
 of the   in their future career;
 Department
 3.  develop global awareness among students to meet the dynamic requirements of marketing management, tourism and hospitality
 industry thru research works, and community development programs by creating strong linkages with related organizations; and
 4.  deliver a gender-fair and gender sensitive instructions to students aligned with the university goals and objectives.
 Program Educational Objectives (based on the program CMO)
 The Bachelor of Science in Business Management graduates should be able to:
 1.  Apply theories and principles of business management.
 2.  Develop comprehensive business plans.
 3.  Conduct an in-depth analysis and provide creative solutions on various business situations both in the local and international setting.
 4.  Exemplify ethically responsible and gender sensitive behavior in all business undertakings.
 5.  Design knowledge–sharing arrangements /linkages and effectively deliver desired value contributions to the various sectors of the society.
 6.  Conduct relevant trainings and developmental extension activities among various stakeholders.
 Student Outcomes and Relationship to Program Educational Objectives
                   Program Educational Objectives Code (based on the
 Program/Student Outcomes (based on the program CMO)   program CMO)
                      1        2       3        4       5        6
 The students should:
 a.   Analyze the business environment for strategic decision.   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓
 b.   Prepare operational plans.   ✓   ✓   ✓    ✓       ✓        ✓
 c.   Innovate business ideas based on emerging industry.   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓
 d.   Manage a strategic business unit for economic sustainability.   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓   ✓
 e.   Conduct business research.   ✓   ✓   ✓    ✓       ✓        ✓
 Course Outcomes and Relationship to Student Outcomes
 Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course   Program/Student Outcomes Code
 After completing this course, the students must be able to:   a   b   c   d   e
 1.  explain the role of product management in business success;   I   I      I   I
 2.  describe the role the product manager plays;   I   I      I   I
 3.  generate great product ideas;   D   D   D   D            D
 4.  develop business case, market needs, product description,
 market strategy, road map, launch plan, and comprehensive   D   D   D   D   D
 marketing plan.
 *Level :          I-Introductory         E- Enabling           D-Demonstrative





                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[COURSE COVERAGE
                                                       Topic              Teaching and                                     Outcomes-based     Due Date of
                                                                                              Mode of
                 Week    Intended Learning                                   Learning         Delivery      Resources        Assessment       Submission
                          Outcomes (ILO)
                                                                                                             Needed
                  No.                                                     Activities (TLA)                                      (OBA)          of Output
                   1     After the orientation,   ORIENTATION           Orientation           Distance    Student           One Page Class     End of the
                         the students will   A.  Vision, Mission, Goals                        Mode       Handbook            Expectation        Week
                         be able to:             and Objectives of the   Self-Introduction
                         1.  familiarize the     University                                               Syllabus
                            VMGO and GAD  B.  GAD                       Class Expectations
                            policies of the   C.  Campus Goals and
                            university as well   Objectives             Supplementary                     CMO 17 s2017
                            as the campus    D.  BSBM Program           video:
                            goals and            Educational Objectives   https://tinyurl.com/
                            objectives;          and Outcomes           y3pu9akf
                         2.  recite the      E.  Course Overview and    (Cavite State
                            program              Requirements           University Official
                            educational                                 Audio Visual
                            objectives and                              Presentation)
                            outcomes of
                            BSBM program;
                         3.  Remember
                            course
                            requirements
                            and regulations
                            in the new
                            normal of
                            module-based
                            learning.
                   2     At the end of the   I.  Introduction to        Interactive learning   Distance       Module       Individual          Third week
                         unit, the students      Product Management                            Mode                        Activity No. 1
                         should be able to:      A.  Understanding the     Brainstorming                    e-Learning/    Rank your traits as
                         1.  explain the vital       Need for Product                                       Messaging      an aspiring
                            part the product         Management           Supplementary                      Platform      product manager.
                            manager plays in     B.  Recognizing the         readings:                                     Set the goals on
                            product success;         Critical Role of   •  Traits of a Great                Computer/      the areas you
                            and                      Product               Product                          Smartphone     want to improve
                         2.  describe the            Management            Manager                                         in.
                            typical product                                                                 Reference
                                                                                                             materials


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[COURSE COVERAGE
    Topic   Teaching and               Outcomes-based     Due Date of
          Mode of
 Week   Intended Learning      Learning   Delivery   Resources   Assessment   Submission
 Outcomes (ILO)
                         Needed
 No.      Activities (TLA)                  (OBA)          of Output
 1   After the orientation,   ORIENTATION   Orientation   Distance   Student   One Page Class   End of the
 the students will   A.  Vision, Mission, Goals      Mode   Handbook   Expectation   Week
 be able to:      and Objectives of the   Self-Introduction
 1.  familiarize the   University      Syllabus
 VMGO and GAD  B.  GAD   Class Expectations
 policies of the   C.  Campus Goals and
 university as well   Objectives   Supplementary   CMO 17 s2017
 as the campus   D.  BSBM Program   video:
 goals and   Educational Objectives   https://tinyurl.com/
 objectives;    and Outcomes   y3pu9akf
 2.  recite the   E.  Course Overview and   (Cavite State
 program   Requirements   University Official
 educational      Audio Visual
 objectives and      Presentation)
 outcomes of
 BSBM program;
 3.  Remember
 course
 requirements
 and regulations
 in the new
 normal of
 module-based
 learning.
 2   At the end of the   I.  Introduction to   Interactive learning   Distance   Module   Individual   Third week
 unit, the students   Product Management      Mode      Activity No. 1
 should be able to:   A.  Understanding the   Brainstorming      e-Learning/   Rank your traits as
 1.  explain the vital   Need for Product      Messaging   an aspiring
 part the product   Management   Supplementary   Platform   product manager.
 manager plays in   B.  Recognizing the   readings:       Set the goals on
 product success;   Critical Role of   •  Traits of a Great   Computer/   the areas you
 and   Product   Product   Smartphone   want to improve
 2.  describe the   Management   Manager       in.
 typical product         Reference
                         materials


                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[management
                            responsibilities.
                   3     At the end of the   II.  Product Life Cycle    Interactive learning   Distance       Module       Individual
                         unit, the students     A.  Defining the Product                       Mode                        Activity No. 2
                         should be able to:         Life Cycle          Brainstorming                       e-Learning/    Research on a
                         1. describe the        B.  Breaking Down the                                       Messaging      product that is    Fourth week
                           product life cycle       Product Life Cycle                                       Platform      considered a
                           and how it           C.  Optimal Product                                                        failure and is
                           integrates with          Process                                                 Computer/      already phased-
                           various                                                                          Smartphone     out in the market.
                           development                                                                                     Explain why it
                           methods                                                                          Reference      happened.
                         2. spell out the                                                                    materials
                           seven-phase and
                           four-phased
                           product life cycle
                         3. elaborate the
                           Optimal Product
                           Process and its
                           nine core
                           documents.
                   4     At the end of the   III.  Discovering Great    Interactive learning   Distance       Module       Group Activity      Fifth week
                         unit, the students      Product Ideas                                 Mode                        No. 1
                         should be able to:      A.  Handling the       Brainstorming                       e-Learning/    Generate ideas by
                         1. find sources of          Creative Process                                       Messaging      mind mapping or
                           inspiration           B.  Generating         Cooperative                          Platform      four actions
                         2. discover                 Creative Ideas     learning                                           framework. Each
                           techniques to                                                                    Computer/      student should
                           bring about                                  Critical explanation                Smartphone     present at least
                           creative new                                                                                    three product
                           ideas                                        Group work                          Reference      ideas in the
                                                                                                             materials     beginning and
                                                                        Supplementary                                      may submit one or
                                                                        videos:                                            two mind mapping
                                                                          •  The Final                                     or four actions
                                                                            Pitch                                          framework. They
                                                                          •  Shark Tank                                    will also submit a
                                                                                                                           transcript,
                                                                                                                           screenshot/video


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[management
 responsibilities.
 3   At the end of the   II.  Product Life Cycle   Interactive learning   Distance   Module   Individual
 unit, the students   A.  Defining the Product      Mode      Activity No. 2
 should be able to:   Life Cycle   Brainstorming   e-Learning/   Research on a
 1. describe the   B.  Breaking Down the   Messaging   product that is   Fourth week
 product life cycle   Product Life Cycle    Platform   considered a
 and how it   C.  Optimal Product      failure and is
 integrates with   Process   Computer/   already phased-
 various               Smartphone      out in the market.
 development                           Explain why it
 methods                Reference      happened.
 2. spell out the        materials
 seven-phase and
 four-phased
 product life cycle
 3. elaborate the
 Optimal Product
 Process and its
 nine core
 documents.
 4   At the end of the   III.  Discovering Great   Interactive learning   Distance   Module   Group Activity   Fifth week
 unit, the students   Product Ideas      Mode      No. 1
 should be able to:   A.  Handling the   Brainstorming   e-Learning/   Generate ideas by
 1. find sources of   Creative Process      Messaging   mind mapping or
 inspiration   B.  Generating   Cooperative   Platform   four actions
 2. discover   Creative Ideas   learning      framework. Each
 techniques to          Computer/      student should
 bring about   Critical explanation   Smartphone   present at least
 creative new                          three product
 ideas   Group work     Reference      ideas in the
                         materials     beginning and
 Supplementary                         may submit one or
 videos:                               two mind mapping
 •  The Final                          or four actions
 Pitch                                 framework. They
 •  Shark Tank                         will also submit a
                                       transcript,
                                       screenshot/video


                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[of their
                                                                                                                           brainstorming
                                                                                                                           session.
                   5     At the end of the   IV.  Understanding         Interactive learning   Distance       Module       Individual
                         unit, the students      Customers                                     Mode                        Activity No. 3
                         should be able to:      A.  Market to          Brainstorming                       e-Learning/    Fill in the         End of the
                         1. develop customer         Segments                                               Messaging      segmentation         5  week
                                                                                                                                                 th
                           segments              B.  Harnessing the     Cooperative                          Platform      worksheet for a
                         2. create and use           Creativity of      learning                                           product that you
                           personas                  Personas                                               Computer/      are familiar with.
                         3. explain how to       C.  Covering all       Group work                          Smartphone
                           handle on                 Persona Roles                                                         Group Activity
                           customer visits       D.  Visiting Customers                                     Reference      No. 2
                                                                                                             materials     Create one
                                                                                                                           persona for the     Sixth week
                                                                                                                           generated ideas
                                                                                                                           and describe them
                                                                                                                           by goal, role,
                                                                                                                           attitude, and
                                                                                                                           behavior. Submit a
                                                                                                                           transcript,
                                                                                                                           screenshot/video
                                                                                                                           of your
                                                                                                                           brainstorming
                                                                                                                           session.
                   6     At the end of the   V.  Evaluating and         Interactive learning   Distance       Module       Group Activity       Seventh
                         unit, the students      Selecting Ideas                               Mode                        No. 3                 week
                         should be able to:      A.  Importance of      Brainstorming                       e-Learning/    Analyze the
                         1. review market            Market Research                                        Messaging      competition of
                           research from a           and Competitive    Cooperative                          Platform      your product ideas
                           product                   Intelligence       learning                                           using SWOT
                           management            B.  Reality Checking                                       Computer/      Analysis. Write at
                           perspective               Ideas and          Group work                          Smartphone     least 5 for each
                         2. completing               Hypotheses                                                            factor. Submit a
                           competitive           C.  Financial                                              Reference      transcript,
                           intelligence              Forecasting                                             materials     screenshot/video
                         3. determine how to     D.  Prioritizing Ideas                                                    of your
                           validate ideas with   E.  Scoring Models                                                        brainstorming
                           customers                                                                                       session.


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[of their
                                       brainstorming
                                       session.
 5   At the end of the   IV.  Understanding   Interactive learning   Distance   Module   Individual
 unit, the students   Customers      Mode      Activity No. 3
 should be able to:   A.  Market to   Brainstorming   e-Learning/   Fill in the   End of the
 1. develop customer   Segments      Messaging   segmentation   5  week
                                                             th
 segments   B.  Harnessing the   Cooperative   Platform   worksheet for a
 2. create and use   Creativity of   learning      product that you
 personas   Personas      Computer/    are familiar with.
 3. explain how to   C.  Covering all   Group work   Smartphone
 handle on   Persona Roles             Group Activity
 customer visits   D.  Visiting Customers   Reference   No. 2
                         materials     Create one
                                       persona for the    Sixth week
                                       generated ideas
                                       and describe them
                                       by goal, role,
                                       attitude, and
                                       behavior. Submit a
                                       transcript,
                                       screenshot/video
                                       of your
                                       brainstorming
                                       session.
 6   At the end of the   V.  Evaluating and   Interactive learning   Distance   Module   Group Activity   Seventh
 unit, the students   Selecting Ideas      Mode      No. 3   week
 should be able to:   A.  Importance of   Brainstorming   e-Learning/   Analyze the
 1. review market   Market Research      Messaging   competition of
 research from a   and Competitive   Cooperative   Platform   your product ideas
 product   Intelligence   learning      using SWOT
 management   B.  Reality Checking      Computer/   Analysis. Write at
 perspective   Ideas and   Group work   Smartphone   least 5 for each
 2. completing   Hypotheses            factor. Submit a
 competitive   C.  Financial      Reference   transcript,
 intelligence   Forecasting      materials   screenshot/video
 3. determine how to   D.  Prioritizing Ideas      of your
 validate ideas with   E.  Scoring Models      brainstorming
 customers                             session.


                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[4. describe the first
                           steps in financial                                                                              Group Activity
                           forecasting                                                                                     No. 4
                                                                                                                           Prioritize the     Eighth week
                                                                                                                           product ideas that
                                                                                                                           you generated by
                                                                                                                           using one
                                                                                                                           prioritization
                                                                                                                           techniques.
                                                                                                                           Determine one
                                                                                                                           product idea that
                                                                                                                           you want to
                                                                                                                           proceed with.
                                                                                                                           Submit a
                                                                                                                           transcript,
                                                                                                                           screenshot/video
                                                                                                                           of your
                                                                                                                           brainstorming
                                                                                                                           session.
                   7     At the end of the   VI.  Planning to Plan      Interactive learning   Distance       Module
                         unit, the students      A.  Adopting Planning                         Mode
                         should be able to:          Best Practices     Brainstorming                       e-Learning/
                         1. define the basic     B.  Lean and Simple                                        Messaging
                           planning                  Planning           Cooperative                          Platform
                           guidelines            C.  In-depth Planning   learning
                         2. describe planning                                                               Computer/
                           under Lean, Agile,                           Group work                          Smartphone
                           and waterfall
                                                                                                            Reference
                                                                                                             materials
                   8     At the end of the   VII. Developing Business   Interactive learning   Distance       Module       Group Activity      Ninth week
                         unit, the students      Case                                          Mode                        No. 5
                         should be able to:      A.  Making a Business   Brainstorming                        e-book       Create your
                         1. explain the value        Case for New                                                          business case.
                           of the business           Product or Service   Cooperative                       e-Learning/    Submit a
                           case;                 B.  Documenting your   learning                            Messaging      transcript,
                         2. break down and           Business Case                                           Platform      screenshot/video
                           create a business                            Group work                          Computer/      of your
                           case’s sections                                                                  Smartphone


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[4. describe the first
 steps in financial                    Group Activity
 forecasting                           No. 4
                                       Prioritize the     Eighth week
                                       product ideas that
                                       you generated by
                                       using one
                                       prioritization
                                       techniques.
                                       Determine one
                                       product idea that
                                       you want to
                                       proceed with.
                                       Submit a
                                       transcript,
                                       screenshot/video
                                       of your
                                       brainstorming
                                       session.
 7   At the end of the   VI.  Planning to Plan   Interactive learning   Distance   Module
 unit, the students   A.  Adopting Planning      Mode
 should be able to:   Best Practices   Brainstorming   e-Learning/
 1. define the basic   B.  Lean and Simple      Messaging
 planning   Planning   Cooperative   Platform
 guidelines   C.  In-depth Planning   learning
 2. describe planning      Computer/
 under Lean, Agile,   Group work   Smartphone
 and waterfall
                        Reference
                         materials
 8   At the end of the   VII. Developing Business   Interactive learning   Distance   Module   Group Activity   Ninth week
 unit, the students   Case      Mode      No. 5
 should be able to:   A.  Making a Business   Brainstorming      e-book   Create your
 1. explain the value   Case for New         business case.
 of the business   Product or Service   Cooperative   e-Learning/   Submit a
 case;   B.  Documenting your   learning   Messaging   transcript,
 2. break down and   Business Case      Platform   screenshot/video
 create a business   Group work   Computer/   of your
 case’s sections       Smartphone


                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[brainstorming
                                                                                                            Reference      session.
                                                                                                             materials
                   9                                                         MIDTERM EXAMINATION
                                                                        Oral Presentation of Business Case
                  10     At the end of the   VIII.   Developing         Brainstorming         Distance        Module       Group Activity      Eighteenth
                         unit, the students      Market Strategy                               Mode                        No. 6                 week
                         should be able to:      A.  Importance of      Cooperative                         e-Learning/    Work on
                         1. explain why you          Market Strategy    learning                            Messaging      developing your
                           need market           B.  Strategy Tools                                          Platform      market strategy to
                           strategy              C.  Other Components   Group work                                         be included in
                         2. determine the            of Market Strategy                                     Computer/      writing your
                           best market           D.  Market Strategy in                                     Smartphone     marketing plan.
                           strategy tools            Writing                                                               Submit a
                         3. define the power                                                                Reference      transcript,
                           of segmentation,                                                                  materials     screenshot/video
                           targeting,                                                                                      of your
                           positioning                                                                                     brainstorming
                         4. create your                                                                                    session.
                           market strategy
                           document
                  11     At the end of the   IX.  Developing a Plan     Brainstorming         Distance        Module       Group Activity      Eighteenth
                         unit, the students      A.  Market Needs                              Mode                        No. 7                 week
                         should be able to:      B.  Product Feature    Cooperative                         e-Learning/    Work on
                         1. list down your           Descriptions       learning                            Messaging      developing your
                           market needs          C.  Product Road Map                                        Platform      market needs,
                           statement                                    Group work/                                        product feature
                         2. build product                               Informal creative                   Computer/      descriptions, and
                           descriptions with                            groups                              Smartphone     product road map.
                           the development                                                                                 Submit a
                           team                                         Supplementary                       Reference      transcript,
                         3. use road maps                               reading:                             materials     screenshot/video
                                                                        Road Maps to Help                                  of your
                                                                        You Succeed                                        brainstorming
                                                                                                                           session.

                                                                                                                           Extension
                                                                                                                           Activity on
                                                                                                                           Developing a


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[brainstorming
                        Reference      session.
                         materials
 9   MIDTERM EXAMINATION
 Oral Presentation of Business Case
 10   At the end of the   VIII.   Developing   Brainstorming   Distance   Module   Group Activity   Eighteenth
 unit, the students   Market Strategy      Mode      No. 6   week
 should be able to:   A.  Importance of   Cooperative      e-Learning/   Work on
 1. explain why you   Market Strategy   learning   Messaging   developing your
 need market   B.  Strategy Tools      Platform   market strategy to
 strategy   C.  Other Components   Group work      be included in
 2. determine the   of Market Strategy   Computer/   writing your
 best market   D.  Market Strategy in   Smartphone   marketing plan.
 strategy tools   Writing              Submit a
 3. define the power    Reference      transcript,
 of segmentation,        materials     screenshot/video
 targeting,                            of your
 positioning                           brainstorming
 4. create your                        session.
 market strategy
 document
 11   At the end of the   IX.  Developing a Plan   Brainstorming   Distance   Module   Group Activity   Eighteenth
 unit, the students   A.  Market Needs      Mode      No. 7   week
 should be able to:   B.  Product Feature   Cooperative      e-Learning/   Work on
 1. list down your   Descriptions   learning   Messaging   developing your
 market needs   C.  Product Road Map      Platform   market needs,
 statement   Group work/               product feature
 2. build product   Informal creative   Computer/   descriptions, and
 descriptions with   groups   Smartphone   product road map.
 the development                       Submit a
 team   Supplementary   Reference      transcript,
 3. use road maps   reading:   materials   screenshot/video
 Road Maps to Help                     of your
 You Succeed                           brainstorming
                                       session.

                                       Extension
                                       Activity on
                                       Developing a


                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Marketing and
                                                                                                                           Product
                                                                                                                           Development
                                                                                                                           Plan














                  12     At the end of the   X.  Development Phase      Brainstorming         Distance        Module
                         unit, the students      A.  Waterfall/Phase-                          Mode
                         should be able to:          Gate versus Agile   Cooperative                        e-Learning/
                         1. define waterfall         Development        learning                            Messaging
                           and Agile             B.  Product                                                 Platform
                           development               Development        Group work
                         2. make product             Trade-off Triangle                                     Computer/
                           trade-offs                                                                       Smartphone

                                                                                                            Reference
                                                                                                             materials
                  13     At the end of the   XI.  Product Launch:       Brainstorming         Distance        Module
                         unit, the students      Qualify Phase                                 Mode
                         should be able to:      A.  The Qualify Phase   Cooperative                        e-Learning/
                         1. explain how          B.  Putting the Beta   learning                            Messaging
                           success is built on       Program in Place                                        Platform
                           qualifying your       C.  Shipping the       Group work
                           product                   Product                                                Computer/
                         2. describe beta test                          Supplementary                       Smartphone
                           program                                      reading:
                         3. determine when to                           Ten Common                          Reference
                           ship the product.                            Product Launch                       materials
                                                                        Mistakes to Avoid





                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Marketing and
                                       Product
                                       Development
                                       Plan














 12   At the end of the   X.  Development Phase   Brainstorming   Distance   Module
 unit, the students   A.  Waterfall/Phase-     Mode
 should be able to:   Gate versus Agile   Cooperative      e-Learning/
 1. define waterfall   Development   learning   Messaging
 and Agile   B.  Product      Platform
 development   Development   Group work
 2. make product   Trade-off Triangle   Computer/
 trade-offs            Smartphone

                        Reference
                         materials
 13   At the end of the   XI.  Product Launch:   Brainstorming   Distance   Module
 unit, the students   Qualify Phase      Mode
 should be able to:   A.  The Qualify Phase   Cooperative      e-Learning/
 1. explain how   B.  Putting the Beta   learning   Messaging
 success is built on   Program in Place      Platform
 qualifying your   C.  Shipping the   Group work
 product   Product      Computer/
 2. describe beta test   Supplementary   Smartphone
 program   reading:
 3. determine when to   Ten Common   Reference
 ship the product.   Product Launch   materials
 Mistakes to Avoid





                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[14     At the end of the   XII. Planning and          Brainstorming         Distance        Module       Group Activity      Eighteenth
                         unit, the students      Executing an                                  Mode                        No. 8                 week
                         should be able to:      Effective Product      Cooperative                         Messaging      Work on
                         1. describe the         Launch                 learning                             Platform      developing your
                           important launch      A.  Setting Launch                                                        product launch
                           elements,                 Goals              Group work/                         Computer/      plan. Details will
                           including first       B.  Different Launch   Informal creative                   Smartphone     be included in
                           impressions               Types              groups                                             your marketing
                         2. establish            C.  Product Launch                                         Reference      plan. Submit a
                           quantifiable              Plan                                                    materials     transcript,
                           launch goals                                                                                    screenshot/video
                         3. determine what                                                                                 of your
                           type of launch to                                                                               brainstorming
                           execute                                                                                         session.
                         4. writing a launch
                           plan and                                                                                        Extension
                           comparing it with                                                                               Activity on
                           your goals                                                                                      Product
                                                                                                                           Launching
                 15-16  At the end of the    XIII.   Maximizing                                                            Group Activity      Eighteenth
                         unit, the students      Product’s Revenue or   Group work/                                        No. 9                 week
                         should be able to:      Profit                 Informal creative                                  Develop your
                         1. explain the          A.  The Basics of      groups                                             comprehensive
                           marketing                 Marketing                                                             marketing plan.
                           fundamentals          B.  Forecasting
                         2. use forecasting to   C.  Creating an
                           look ahead                Effective Marketing
                         3. create your              Plan
                           marketing plan the    D.  Monitoring Product
                           best it can be            Success Metrics
                         4. determine how to
                           track marketing
                           activities
                  17     At the end of the   XIV.    Retirement         Brainstorming         Distance        Module
                         unit, the students      A.  How to Retire a                           Mode
                         should be able to:          Product            Cooperative                         Messaging
                         1. define product       B.  Product Retirement  learning                            Platform
                           retirement and            Plan
                           explain why                                                                      Computer/


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[14   At the end of the   XII. Planning and   Brainstorming   Distance   Module   Group Activity   Eighteenth
 unit, the students   Executing an      Mode      No. 8      week
 should be able to:   Effective Product   Cooperative      Messaging   Work on
 1. describe the   Launch   learning   Platform   developing your
 important launch   A.  Setting Launch         product launch
 elements,   Goals   Group work/   Computer/   plan. Details will
 including first   B.  Different Launch   Informal creative   Smartphone   be included in
 impressions   Types   groups          your marketing
 2. establish   C.  Product Launch      Reference   plan. Submit a
 quantifiable   Plan     materials     transcript,
 launch goals                          screenshot/video
 3. determine what                     of your
 type of launch to                     brainstorming
 execute                               session.
 4. writing a launch
 plan and                              Extension
 comparing it with                     Activity on
 your goals                            Product
                                       Launching
 15-16  At the end of the   XIII.   Maximizing            Group Activity   Eighteenth
 unit, the students   Product’s Revenue or   Group work/   No. 9    week
 should be able to:   Profit   Informal creative   Develop your
 1. explain the   A.  The Basics of   groups   comprehensive
 marketing   Marketing                 marketing plan.
 fundamentals   B.  Forecasting
 2. use forecasting to   C.  Creating an
 look ahead   Effective Marketing
 3. create your   Plan
 marketing plan the   D.  Monitoring Product
 best it can be   Success Metrics
 4. determine how to
 track marketing
 activities
 17   At the end of the   XIV.   Retirement   Brainstorming   Distance   Module
 unit, the students   A.  How to Retire a      Mode
 should be able to:   Product   Cooperative      Messaging
 1. define product   B.  Product Retirement  learning   Platform
 retirement and   Plan
 explain why            Computer/


                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[products need to                             Group work/                         Smartphone
                           be retired                                   Informal creative
                         2. identify the                                groups                              Reference
                           elements of a                                                                     materials
                           product retirement
                           plan, including
                           special product
                           situations
                  18                                                           FINAL EXAMINATION
                                                                Oral Presentation of Comprehensive Marketing Plan
                                                                        COURSE REQUIREMENTS
                 Course Requirements:
                    1.  Business Case
                    2.  Comprehensive Marketing Plan
                    3.  Transcript of Brainstorming Sessions
                    4.  Individual and Group Activities
                 *All exams must follow a Table of Specifications (TOS) and Rubrics for evaluation of student’ performance or projects.

                                                                            GRADING SYSTEM

                     Activities (Individual and Group)      40%
                     Business Case                          30%
                     Comprehensive Marketing Plan           30%
                     Total                                   100%

                     STANDARD TRANSMUTATION TABLE FOR ALL COURSES

                        96.7 – 100.0            1.00
                        93.4 – 96.6              1.25
                        90.1 - 93.30             1.50
                        86.7 – 90.0              1.75
                        83.4 – 86.6              2.00
                        80.1 – 83.3              2.25
                        76.7 – 80.0              2.50
                        73.4 – 76.6              2.75
                        70.00 – 73.3            3.00
                        50.0-69.9                 4.00
                        Below 50                 5.00



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[products need to   Group work/   Smartphone
 be retired   Informal creative
 2. identify the   groups   Reference
 elements of a           materials
 product retirement
 plan, including
 special product
 situations
 18   FINAL EXAMINATION
 Oral Presentation of Comprehensive Marketing Plan
 COURSE REQUIREMENTS
 Course Requirements:
 1.  Business Case
 2.  Comprehensive Marketing Plan
 3.  Transcript of Brainstorming Sessions
 4.  Individual and Group Activities
 *All exams must follow a Table of Specifications (TOS) and Rubrics for evaluation of student’ performance or projects.

 GRADING SYSTEM

 Activities (Individual and Group)      40%
 Business Case            30%
 Comprehensive Marketing Plan      30%
 Total                         100%

 STANDARD TRANSMUTATION TABLE FOR ALL COURSES

 96.7 – 100.0            1.00
 93.4 – 96.6              1.25
 90.1 - 93.30             1.50
 86.7 – 90.0              1.75
 83.4 – 86.6              2.00
 80.1 – 83.3              2.25
 76.7 – 80.0              2.50
 73.4 – 76.6              2.75
 70.00 – 73.3            3.00
 50.0-69.9                 4.00
 Below 50                 5.00



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[INC                           Passed the course but lack some requirements.
                        Dropped                   If unexcused absence is at least 20% of the Total Class Hours.
                                                          Total Class Hours/Semester:   54
                                                                             CLASS POLICIES
                A.  Attendance
                    Students are not allowed to have 20% or more unexcused absences of the total face to face class hours; otherwise, they will be graded as “DROPPED”.
                B.  Classroom Decorum
                    During face to face mode
                         Students are required to:
                         1.  wear identification cards at all times;
                         2.  wear face mask at all times;
                         3.  observe physical/social distancing at all times;
                         4.  clean the classroom before and after classes;
                         5.  avoid unnecessary noise that might disturb other classes;
                         6.  practice good manners and right conduct at all times;
                         7.  practice gender sensitivity and awareness inside the classroom; and
                         8.  come to class on time.
                    During distance mode
                         Students are required to:
                         1.  sign an honor system pledge;
                         2.  avoid giving or receiving unauthorized aid of any kind on their examinations, papers, projects and assignments;
                         3.  observe proper netiquette during on-line activities; and
                         4.  submit take home assignments on time.
                C.  Examination/ Evaluation
                         1.  Quizzes may be announced or unannounced.
                         2.  Mid-term and Final Examinations are scheduled.
                         3.  Cheating is strictly prohibited. A student who is caught cheating will be given a score of ”0” for the first offense. For the second offense, the
                            student will be automatically given a failing grade in the subject.
                         4.  Students who will miss a mid-term or final examination, a laboratory exercise or a class project may be excused and allowed to take a special
                            exam, conduct a laboratory exercise or pass a class project for any of the following reasons:
                                  a.  participation in a University/College-approved field trip or activity;
                                 b.  due to illness or death in the family; and
                                  c.  due to force majeure or natural calamities.
                                                              REFERENCES & SUPPLEMENTARY READINGS
                 References:
                 Attolico, L. (2019). Lean development and innovation: hitting the market with the right products at the right time. Routledge
                 Lawley, Brian et al. (2017). Product management essentials. John Wiley & Sons, Inc.
                 Lemay, M. (2018). Product management in practice. O' Reilley Media, Inc.



                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[INC                           Passed the course but lack some requirements.
 Dropped                   If unexcused absence is at least 20% of the Total Class Hours.
                                   Total Class Hours/Semester:   54
 CLASS POLICIES
 A.  Attendance
 Students are not allowed to have 20% or more unexcused absences of the total face to face class hours; otherwise, they will be graded as “DROPPED”.
 B.  Classroom Decorum
 During face to face mode
      Students are required to:
 1.  wear identification cards at all times;
 2.  wear face mask at all times;
 3.  observe physical/social distancing at all times;
 4.  clean the classroom before and after classes;
 5.  avoid unnecessary noise that might disturb other classes;
 6.  practice good manners and right conduct at all times;
 7.  practice gender sensitivity and awareness inside the classroom; and
 8.  come to class on time.
 During distance mode
      Students are required to:
 1.  sign an honor system pledge;
 2.  avoid giving or receiving unauthorized aid of any kind on their examinations, papers, projects and assignments;
 3.  observe proper netiquette during on-line activities; and
 4.  submit take home assignments on time.
 C.  Examination/ Evaluation
 1.  Quizzes may be announced or unannounced.
 2.  Mid-term and Final Examinations are scheduled.
 3.  Cheating is strictly prohibited. A student who is caught cheating will be given a score of ”0” for the first offense. For the second offense, the
 student will be automatically given a failing grade in the subject.
 4.  Students who will miss a mid-term or final examination, a laboratory exercise or a class project may be excused and allowed to take a special
 exam, conduct a laboratory exercise or pass a class project for any of the following reasons:
 a.  participation in a University/College-approved field trip or activity;
 b.  due to illness or death in the family; and
 c.  due to force majeure or natural calamities.
 REFERENCES & SUPPLEMENTARY READINGS
 References:
 Attolico, L. (2019). Lean development and innovation: hitting the market with the right products at the right time. Routledge
 Lawley, Brian et al. (2017). Product management essentials. John Wiley & Sons, Inc.
 Lemay, M. (2018). Product management in practice. O' Reilley Media, Inc.



                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Pranam, A. (2018). Product management essentials. Apress
                 Thomas, Douglas et al. (2017). Product management in supply chain. Taylor and Francis Group

                                                                    REVISION HISTORY
                  Revision                      Date of Revision                         Date of Implementation               Highlights of Revision
                   Number
                      1                  Second Semester, AY 2019-2020               Second Semester, AY 2019-2020             OBE Revised Syllabus
                      2                         February 18, 2021                    Second Semester, AY 2020-2021           Shift to Blended Learning
                 Prepared by:                               Evaluated by:                                 Approved:


                 DEBBIE ROSE T. BANAG                       RITCH M. BANATE                               GIL D. RAMOS
                 Instructor                                 Chairperson                                   Campus Administrator
                 0935-179-6686                              Department of Management                      Campus: Tanza
                 debbiebanag@cvsu.edu.ph                    E-mail Address: ritchibels@gmail.com          Date Approved:  February 22, 2021
                 Department of Management                   Date Evaluated: February 20, 2021
                 Consultation Schedule: Tuesday 9am-11am
                 Date Prepared: February 18, 2021































                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[Pranam, A. (2018). Product management essentials. Apress
 Thomas, Douglas et al. (2017). Product management in supply chain. Taylor and Francis Group

 REVISION HISTORY
 Revision   Date of Revision   Date of Implementation   Highlights of Revision
 Number
 1   Second Semester, AY 2019-2020   Second Semester, AY 2019-2020   OBE Revised Syllabus
 2   February 18, 2021   Second Semester, AY 2020-2021   Shift to Blended Learning
 Prepared by:   Evaluated by:   Approved:


 DEBBIE ROSE T. BANAG   RITCH M. BANATE   GIL D. RAMOS
 Instructor   Chairperson   Campus Administrator
 0935-179-6686   Department of Management   Campus: Tanza
 debbiebanag@cvsu.edu.ph   E-mail Address: ritchibels@gmail.com   Date Approved:  February 22, 2021
 Department of Management   Date Evaluated: February 20, 2021
 Consultation Schedule: Tuesday 9am-11am
 Date Prepared: February 18, 2021































                                                          V02-2020-07-01]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[The BSBM students in their business simulated activities]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[The BSBM students in their business simulated activities]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[The BSBM students in their business simulated activities]]></page></pages></Search>