<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="59"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.7.            Research results are disseminated to


                        the target clientele.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Cavite State University Office of the

                      Vice President for Research and Extension

                                             Official  Newsletter]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[ISSN 2651-8023







                                                                 The official monthly newsletter of the Office of the Vice President for
                                                                 Research and Extension

          VOL. 5  No. 4                                                                                             April  2022

                    CvSU-ITSO receives Platinum Cluster Award


           Cavite  State  University  (CvSU)  received  a  position  in  the
   Platinum Cluster Category of the Intellectual Property Office of the
   Philippines (IPOPHL) 2021 Clustering Scheme of Innovation and
   Technology  Support  Office  (ITSO)  2.0.    The  award  was  given
   during the 2021 ITSO Cluster Awarding Ceremony conducted by
   IPOPHL via Zoom video conferencing last April 18.
           The  Platinum  Award  is  the  highest  recognition  given  by
   IPOPHL for ITSOs that have developed specific competencies or
   expertise over time and for those with the manpower to dispense
   such expertise.

           ITSO  2.0  program  was  designed  to  further  revitalize  the
   ITSO  network  to  cope  with  the  pressing  (continue on page 2)
                                                                              Certificate received by CvSU - ITSO

           BOR approves CvSU-TRAIN Project

                                                                                                  IN THIS ISSUE
           The  Cavite  State  University  (CvSU)  Board  of  Regents  (BOR)  approved  the  CvSU  -
   Technology Railway for the Acceleration of Innovation in the Nation (TRAIN) through BOR   NCRDEC upskills more coffee
   Resolution  No.  21,  series  of  2022,  dated  March  30,  2022.    CvSU-TRAIN,  a  five-million   stakeholders across the
   project,  is  the  new  extension  modality  of  the  University  to  provide  railways  for  faster   region     . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .     2
   technology transfer through various stations that will feature technologies developed by the
   University.  Specifically, CvSU-TRAIN aims to design three mobile wagon structures, each   Future Earth Phils spearheads
   will  be  intended  for  food  innovation,  coffee  processing,  and  instructional  materials   SDG Jumpstart workshop     . . . .   3
                                                                                        . . . . .
   development; conduct design analysis of the structures following the engineering standards in                       4
   structural design; fabricate the three mobile wagon structures; and conduct functionality and   KMC accomplishes PCO visit  . . .
   performance test of the three mobile wagon structures.  It was inspired  (continue on page 3)  SciCAT promotes native chicken   5
                                                                                        production    . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .

                    CvSU establishes MRDIRC                                             BAELS - Pragmaticus conducts   6
                                                                                        LRC 2022     . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
            Cavite State University (CvSU) established the Makapuno Research and Development,   CvSU Bee Program, CAS-DBS
    Innovation  and  Resource  Center  (MRDIRC),  a  new  unit  under  the  Office  of  the  Vice   hold Batch 19 beekeeping   7
    President  for  Research  and  Extension  (OVPRE).    The  establishment  of  the  center  was   webinar      . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
    approved by the CvSU Board of Regents with BOR Resolution no. 48, series of 2019.  This   CvSU - Carmona concludes   8
    will serve as a cutting-edge one-stop facility that will focus on discovering and realizing the   webinar series on technology    . .
    maximum  potential  of  makapuno  for  food  and  non-food  applications  through  innovative   DHum, LSC conduct Language
    research.   Dr. Hosea dL. Matel, faculty from the Department of Physical Sciences of the   HOUR with VELF     . . . . . . . . . . .   9
    College of Arts and Sciences and a faculty researcher, was appointed as its director.
                                                                                        University CS collaborates with
            The center aims to support the complete value chain of makapuno and provide relevant   GADRC on CvSU Policies for
    information  about  the  crop.    Makapuno  is  considered  as  a  crop  that  could  lead  to   New Security Provider   10
    economically viable and sustainable business start-ups through viable community extension   orientation    . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
    and  technology  commercialization  activities.    With  a  team  of  experts,  the  scientific   GADRC holds webinar on Solo   11
    breakthroughs  in  makapuno  tissue  culture  and  product  development  hope  to  support  the   Parent in the Workplace      . . . . .
    growing  makapuno  industry  ensuring  farmers,  processors,  and  other  (continue on page 4)





       The premier university in   Cavite State University shall provide excellent, equitable,   We Commit to the highest standards of education,
     historic Cavite recognized for      and relevant educational opportunities in the arts,   Value our stakeholders, Strive for continual
          excellence in the       sciences and technology through quality instruction and   improvement of our products and services, and
       development of globally       responsive research and development activities.   Uphold the University’s tenets of Truth, Excellence
       competitive and morally                                                     and Service to produce globally competitive and
         upright individuals.     It shall produce professional, skilled and morally upright   morally upright individuals.
                                         individuals for global competitiveness.

                                                                                                                   Page 1]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4


         NCRDEC  upskills more coffee stakeholders across the
                                                        region



           With  its  mandate  of  bringing  the  Philippine  coffee  back  to
   the  world  market,  the  National  Coffee  Research,  Development
   and  Extension  Center  (NCRDEC)  continuously  upskills  more
   coffee  stakeholders  across  the  region  through  the  conduct  of
   various skills training on coffee production and processing for the
   coffee producer organizations (POs) beneficiaries of its ongoing
   DOST-PCAARRD-funded  Coffee  Food  Value  Chain  (CFVC)
   extension project.

           In retrospect, NCRDEC through its CFVC project, was able
   to  provide  various  technical  assistance  to  its  valued  PO   CFVC Project Team together with the participants from G-CAFÉ
   beneficiaries  in  CALABARZON  to  elevate  the  knowledge  and
   skills  of  the  smallholder  coffee  farmers  and  small-scale  coffee
   processors in the region.  In its relentless pursuit of bridging the
   gap in coffee education in the region’s coffee sector especially in
   this  time  of  the  pandemic,  the  CFVC  project  team  went  to
   Guinayangan  and  Candelaria,  Quezon  last  March  22-24  and
   March 29-31 to provide an intensive training on coffee production
   and  processing  for  the  respective  farmer-members  of
   Guinayangan    Coffee   Growers   Association   and   Farm           Hands-on training led by Mr. Rodrigo H. Diloy (left)
   Entrepreneurs   (G-CAFÉ),   Inc.   and   Adarna   Agriculture                and Mr. Ronald P. Peña (right)
   Cooperative (AAC).
                                                                       The  three-day  activity  was  composed  of lecture-discussion
                                                               and  hands-on  training  on  the  different  know-hows  of  coffee
                                                               production and processing.  Topics on production encompassed
                                                               the  overview  of  the  coffee  industry,  the  coffee  plant,  coffee
                                                               nursery  establishment  and  management,  methods  of  coffee
                                                               propagation,  management  and  establishment  of  coffee
                                                               plantations,  management  of  coffee  pests  and  diseases,
                                                               economics of coffee production, and primary coffee processing.
                                                               The said topics were discussed by Mr. Rodrigo H. Diloy, resource
                                                               person  and  Education  Program  Specialist  II  of  NCRDEC.
                                                               Meanwhile,  Mr.  Ronald  P.  Peña,  NCRDEC  research  assistant,
                                                               spearheaded  the  discussion  of  the  topics  on  secondary  coffee
        CFVC Project Team with the members of Adarna Agriculture    processing including the coffee quality standards, coffee roasting
                  Cooperative in Candelaria, Quezon
                                                               and blending, and basic coffee cupping.   (continue on page 6)

   CvSU-ITSO secures  ...                (from page 1)
                                                               Tepora, has drafted and filed seven invention patents in 2021, a
    demands  of  the  Fourth  Industrial  Revolution  (4IR).    Under  the   requirement  for  Platinum  Cluster  Category  in  ITSO  2.0.    Also,
    program,  ITSOs  were  clustered  accordingly  based  on  set   CvSU  had  successfully  commercialized  its  utility  model  titled,
    parameters.                                                "Production of Kaong (Arenga pinnata) Brown Sugar” through a

            Despite  the  challenges  brought  about  by  COVID-19  licensing  agreement  with  Magallanes  Women's  Club  Multi-
    pandemic,  CvSU-ITSO  headed  by  its  manager,  Dr.  Teddy  F.  purpose Cooperative (MAWCO).  (Teddy F. Tepora)























           Dr. Teddy F. Tepora during the recognition ceremony       Screenshot of Dr. Teddy F. Tepora with other participants


                                                                                                                  Page 2]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4


         Future Earth Phils spearheads SDG Jumpstart workshop


           Future  Earth  Philippines  (FEP)  spearheaded  its  university  SDG
   action  network (USAN)  workshop  with  Cavite  State  University,  Eastern
   Visayas  University,  and  Mindanao  State  University-Iligan  Institute  of
   Technology on  April 11 via Zoom conference.  The said workshop aimed
   to  conduct  a  preliminary  assessment  on  where  the  universities  are  in
   terms of their Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) practices.
           Prior  to  the  said  workshop,  the  CvSU  SDG  core  group  members
   conducted its own writeshop on April 5 in preparation for the preliminary
   assessment on the jumpstart workshop.
           During the workshop, each university was given a chance to give an
   opening message and have a 15-minute presentation on the overview of
   its policies, practices, and processes.  Dr. Agnes C. Francisco, director of   Ms. Gierone Lianni A. Reyes during her presentation in the
                                                                                           workshop
   the Knowledge Management Center (KMC), gave the opening speech for
   the  university.  Her  message  highlighted  the  (continue on page 7)
















                                                                       Ms. Emeline C. Guevarra, Dr. Almira G. Magcawas, and Dr.
                                                                       Maria Soledad Mojica-Lising (left), Dr. Ammie P. Ferrer, Mr.
                                                                       Junser P. Magpantay, Dr. Agnes C. Francisco, Dr. Susan G.
                                                                         Tan, and Ms. Raecel A. Estebat (right) during the April 5
                                                                       writeshop in preparation for the jumpstart workshop of Future
       Future Earth Philippines and its University SDG Action Network members           Earth Philippines



   BOR approves ...         (from page 1)
                                                               Meanwhile, the Extension Services unit  will be in-charge in its
   by DOST Technology in the Region for Upscaling of Community  monitoring and evaluation.
   Knowledge (DOSTRUCK),  an  on-going  extension  project  of  the           The project management team is composed of Dr. Almira G.
   Department of Science and Technology (DOST) IV-A and CvSU   Magcawas as project leader with Dr. Ruel M. Mojica, Engr. Gerry
   which is expected to run for one year.
                                                               M.  Castillo,  Dr.  Ammie  P.  Ferrer,  Engr.  Rosalie  A.  Pelle,  Engr.
           The College of Education (CEd), National Coffee Research  Arthur C. Eraña, and Ms. Bernadette S. Amparo as project staff.
   Development  and  Extension  Center  (NCRDEC),  and  Hostel  Ms. Bernadette S. Morelos and Ms. Aiza E. Mojica serve as its
   Tropicana  are  the  initial  colleges/units  involved  in  this  project.  project support staff.  (Bernadette S. Amparo)































                  The CvSU-TRAIN project (Photo grabbed from the CvSU FB page)               Photo of the BOR resolution



                                                                                                                  Page 3]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4



                                   KMC accomplishes PCO visit


           The  Knowledge  Management  Center  (KMC)  successfully
   accomplished  the  scheduled  visit  and  hands-on  exercise  of  the
   University Pollution Control Office (PCO) last April 12.  As part of
   the  Training/Workshop  on  Waste  Management  for  Pollution
   Control Coordinators (PCCs) conducted on November 18, 2021,
   PCO  resumed  its  onsite  visit  and  hands-on  exercise  to  all
   colleges, offices, and units of the university.
           KMC, led by Dr. Agnes C. Francisco, director, and Ms. Aiza
   R.  Javier,  PCC,  was  able  to  satisfactorily  comply  with  the
   guidelines  regarding  waste  management  in  the  office.   The  visit
   was led by Mr. Junser P. Magpantay, University Pollution Control
   Officer,  along  with  his  staff.    Infographic  materials  and  posters
   were distributed by the PCO to increase awareness about proper
   waste  management and environmental conservation.  (Jacob M.   Mr. Junser P. Magpantay with Dr. Agnes C. Francisco and KMC staff
                                                                                    during the PCO visit
   Gomez)

   CvSU establishes ...            (from page 1)               other  clients  engaged  in  makapuno  R&D;  identify  critical  R&D

   stakeholders  of  additional  sources  of  income  while  addressing   areas  that  will  immediately  cater  to  the  development  of  the
   the growing demand for makapuno products.  Once processing   makapuno  industry;  develop  and  innovate  functional  food  and
   equipment  and  facilities  are  completed,  these  will  be  made   non-food  products  from  makapuno  galactomannan  and  other
   available  to  stakeholders  who  are  in  need  of  assistance  and   makapuno  by-products;  formulate  and  implement  extension
   support.                                                    programs  to  effectively  transfer  makapuno  technologies  to
                                                               coconut  farmers  and  prospective  entrepreneurs;  organize
           The  center  works  with  its  mission  to  initiate  conduct  of   scientific  and  technological  meetings  for  exchange  of  research
   researches  towards  the  development  of  various  food  and  non-  results  and  experiences,  assessment  of  progress  in  R&D
   food products and provide relevant trainings and technologies to   endeavors,  formulating  R&D  plans,  and  mapping  out  industry
   communities  who  can  eventually  utilize  them  as  business   development directions; and  foster collaborations with both local
   enterprises.                                                and  foreign  agencies for  the  exchange  of  technical information
           It is envisioned to be a leading institution not only in different  and expertise on makapuno.
   makapuno-related R & E activities but also in the establishment           For more information, interested individuals may contact Dr.
   of sustainable businesses that promote innovative products.
                                                               Hosea  dL.  Matel,  director  of  the  Makapuno  Research  &
                                                                                                                        th
           Moreover,  the  center  aims  to  facilitate  the  conduct  of  all  Development, Innovation and Resource Center located at the 5
   researches  on  makapuno  covering  the  entire  value-chain  from  floor  of  the  Inter-Disciplinary  Research  Building,  CvSU  Don
   primary  production  to  commercialization  and  to  supplement  the  Severino delas Alas Campus, Indang, Cavite, Philippines 4122.
   efforts  of  various  organizations  working  for  the  makapuno  They may also be reached through their telephone number (046-
   industry.  Specifically, the Center aims to establish a state-of-the-  8901-080) and email address (makapuno_center@cvsu.edu.ph).
   art  facility  to  accommodate  faculty,  students,  researchers,  and  (Dr. Hosea D. Matel)

































                                          Organizational Chart of the Makapuno Center



                                                                                                                  Page 4]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4


                                        After benchmarking in farms
                    SciCAT promotes native chicken production


           This  April  2022,  the  team  of  the  project  Science  for  the
   Convergence  of  Agriculture  and  Tourism  (SciCAT)  focused  on
   native chicken production which is part of the implementation of
   Phase II called, “SciCAT AVENUES: Access to Value-adding and
   Engaging  iNnovations  towards  sUstainability  of  agri-Education
   and agri-touriSm”.
           After  visiting  Bukid  ni  San  Pedro  Calungsod  in  Tiaong,
   Quezon  last  April  12,  the  team  from  CvSU  and  Silan  AgriFarm
   headed by Dr. Lilibeth P. Novicio, project leader, learned how the
   group raises darag native chicken.  With the assistance of Atty.
   Raul  Ancheta  and  Mr.  Emman  Ancheta,  managers  of  the  farm,
   the  team  was  oriented  on  the  best  practices  of  the  said  farm
   along with a tour in its facilities managed with a vision of fusing
   “faith and farming”.  A week before this, the group also conducted
   a  benchmarking  visit  at  Luntiang  Republika  located  in  Alfonso,   SciCAT team’s visit at Bukid ni San Pedro Calungsod
                                                                                     in Tiaong, Quezon
   Cavite  where  various  processed  agricultural  products  are  being
   sold.
           In  addition,  the  team  also  launched  “Kwentuhan  sa
   Manukan” in their SciCAT – Silan AgriFarm Facebook page and
   SciCAT-Silan AgriFarm YouTube account featuring three videos:
   1) native chicken production at Silan AgriFarm, 2) Preparation of
   feeds  for  native  chicken,  and  3)  Mr.  Richard  Pinpin’s  backyard
   farming (an adopter’s story).
           The  SciCAT  project  is  being  funded  by  the  Department  of
   Science  and  Technology  -  Philippine  Council  for  Agriculture,
   Aquatic  and  Natural  Resources  Research  and  Development
   (DOST-PCAARRD). (Lady Aileen A. Orsal)                              SciCAT team’s visit at Luntiang Republika in Alfonso


      The CvSU Research Journal is now online @crj.ovpre.com    The  first  quarter  of  2022  for  the  Knowledge  Management
              Email @ researchjournal@cvsu.edu.ph               Center does not speak of numbers, but rather on the impact of
                                                                each small accomplishment to stakeholders.















































                                                                                                                  Page 5]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4


                       BAELS-Pragmaticus conducts LRC 2022



           Pragmaticus,  the  official  student  organization  of  the
   Bachelor of Arts in English Language Studies (BAELS) program
   of  the  College  of  Arts  and  Sciences,  conducted  its  second
   Language  Research  Conference  titled,  “NGL  It’s  Confusing!:
   Exploring  Gender  Fair  Language  Through  Research”  last  April
   28 via Google Meet and streamed on Facebook Live.  The event
   was graced by Dr. Jovito B. Madeja, director for Extension and
   linguistics professor of the Eastern Visayas State University, as
   the plenary speaker.  He discussed the topic, “Sexist Language
   in  Academic  Discourse:  Insights  on  Gender-Fair  Language  in   Dr. Agnes C. Francisco (left) introduces the panel of evaluators and
                                                                     Ms. Ayesha Mari M. Gianan (left) during her presentation
   Research”.    Meanwhile,  Ms.  Arlene  L.  Estrada,  Arts  and   E.  De  Paz,  Ms. Ma.  Theresa  A.  Miguel,  and  Mr.Jaime  Raphael
   Sciences  Department  chair  and  Gender  and  Development   Miranda.  The panel of evaluators were Ms. Catherine R. Mojica,
   coordinator  of  the  Cavite  State  University-Trece  Martires  City   Ms.  Lerry  Anne  A.  Virtuso,  and  Mr.  Edgielson  D.  Nueva.
   Campus, was invited as the resource speaker.  She presented   Comments and suggestions were given to the presenter after the
   the topic titled, “Gender Fair Language and Research”.
                                                               presentation and a certificate of recognition was awarded to Ms.
           In the afternoon, Ms. Ayesha Mari M. Gianan, BAELS 2-1  Gianan.  The event was successfully held under the supervision
   student,  presented  the  paper  titled,  “Signs  and  Symbolisms:  A  of Dr. Agnes C. Francisco and Ms. Emeliza T. Cruz, Pragmaticus
   Semantic Analysis of Emojis on Facebook”.  The study aimed to  advisers;  Prof.  Rosa  R.  Hernandez,  chair  of  the  Department  of
   identify  and  categorize  emojis  seen  in  selected  social  media  Humanities; and Dr. Bettina Joyce P. Ilagan, dean of the College
   posts,  generate  the  meanings  of  emojis,  and  provide  reasons  of Arts and Sciences.  (Ma. Angelica F. Naranja, BAELS 3-1)
   that may explain why emojis are used in social media.  It was co-
   authored by Mr. John Mark Vincent G. Almonte, Mr. Benz Louijie














       Dr. Jovito B. Madeja (left), keynote speaker, and Prof. Arlene L.
     Estrada (right), resource speaker, during the first part of the activity   Screenshot of the participants in the second part of the event

   NCRDEC  upskills  ...                  (from page 2)

           To stay in the know, the same activity was conducted on April 26-28
   at  the  Cavite  State  University  (CvSU)  NCRDEC  Training  Hall  for  the
   project’s  beneficiaries  in  Cavite  and  Laguna.    The  three-day  in-house
   training  was  attended  by  17  farmer-members  of  Bailen  Coffee  Growers
   Association (BCGA) from General Emilio Aguinaldo, Cavite; Minantok East
   Coffee Growers Association (MECGA) from Amadeo, Cavite, and Casile-
   Guinting Upland Marketing Cooperative (CGUMC) from Cabuyao, Laguna.
   The activity concluded the project’s endeavor of equipping its beneficiaries
   with  right  knowledge  and  technicalities  on  both  coffee  production  and
   processing  while  simultaneously  introducing  state-of-the-art  coffee
   technologies  and  interventions  that  will  be  of  great  help  in  attaining  an
   enhanced coffee value chain in the region. (Gizelle D. Crema)


















                                                                         Hands-on training on coffee production with Mr. Rodrigo H.
            The project team together with the participants from the POs in    Diloy (top) and on secondary coffee processing with Mr.
                              Cavite and Laguna                                       Ronald P. Peña (bottom)


                                                                                                                  Page 6]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4



      CvSU Bee Program, CAS-DBS hold Batch 19 beekeeping webinar


           The CvSU Bee Program, in collaboration with the Extension  Dimero,  Prof.  Alcona  Mae  P.  Baltazar,  and  Prof.  Michele  T.
   Unit  of  the  College  of  Arts  and  Sciences  -  Department  of  Bono, respectively.  The webinar ended with the closing remarks
   Biological  Sciences  (CAS-DBS),  held  a  two-day  beekeeping  delivered by Prof. Dimero.  The event was hosted by Mr. John
   webinar,  Batch  19  of  its  “Beeyond  the  Hive:  Introduction  to  Rex N. Baldomero, DBS faculty.
   Beekeeping Webinar Series 5” last April 18-19 via Zoom video           It  was  a  very  informative  and  comprehensive  lecture
   conferencing.  The activity intended to introduce beekeeping to   attended by 113 participants who benefited a lot from the topics
   interested  participants  who  want  to  learn  the  process  and   presented.      The  CvSU  Bee  Program  and  the  Department  of
   eventually establish their own meliponary or apiary and enter into   Biological  Sciences  have  high  hopes  that  this  small  endeavor
   its business side.                                          would  be  the  start  of  something  big  for  the  future  beekeepers.
           The first day was conducted on April 18.  Dr. Ma. Veronica  (Liwayway P. Taglinao)
   P. Peňaflorida, DBS chair, delivered the opening remarks.  Prof.
   Michele T. Bono, head of the CvSU Bee Program, Prof. Sherine
   M. Cruzate, and Prof. Jamaica Q. Espineli, faculty members of
   the  department,  were  the  invited  speakers.    Topics  discussed
   were “The CvSU Bee Program, Introduction to Apis cerana, and
   Beescape”,  respectively.  It  was  a  very  fruitful  day  and  the
   participants  were  highly  participative  especially  in  the  open
   forum.

           On  the  second  day,  the  discussion  focused  on  Stingless
   Beekeeping, Pollination and the Bees, and Issues and Concerns
   in  Beekeeping  which  were  discussed  by  Prof.  Dickson  N.            Prof. Michele T. Bono while delivering her lecture







































                                               Some of the participants in the webinar




   Future Earth Phils spearheads  ...     (from page 2)                After  each  presentation,  the  workshop  continued  with  the
                                                               problem and solution tree analysis to further understand and look
   importance  of  partnership  in  achieving  the  sustainable  into  the  needs  of  each  participant  to  be  an  SDG-aligned
   development goals as well as gratefulness for the opportunity to  university.  It was divided into five sectors of the society, namely:
   continuously  improve  and  align  the  university’s  goals  and  political,  economic,  socio-cultural,  technological,  legal,  and
   objectives with SDGs.                                       ecological (PESTLE).

           The  presentation  was  discussed  by  Ms.  Gierone  Lianni  A.          Moreover,  after  identifying  the  problems  and  solutions,
   Reyes.  The university mission, the current programs, practices,  strategies on how to achieve them were also formulated.  These
   and  policies  that  were  deemed  aligned  with  the  SDGs  were  all  will all be elaborated on in the next presentation and discussion
   presented.                                                  on April 27.  (Gierone Lianni A. Reyes)



                                                                                                                  Page 7]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4


        CvSU-Carmona concludes webinar series on technology



           The  Extension  Services  Office  and  the  Department  of
   Industrial and Information Technology (DIIT) of the Cavite State
   University-Carmona   Campus,   in   collaboration   with   the
   Association  of  Computer  Engineering  Students,  Effective
   Leaders  in  Technological  Endeavors,  Information  Technology
   Elite  Confederacy,  and  Young  Programmers  and  Developers
   Society,  concluded  its  webinar  series  on  technology  with  the
   theme,   “Upskilling   the   Community’s   Knowledge   and
   Familiarization  in  Technology”  as  part  of  the  extension  projects
   titled,   “Kakayahang   Teknikal   Tungo   sa   Magandang
   Kinabukasan” and “Project Kompyuter”.
           The last of the webinar series titled, “Leveraging the Power
   of Open-Source Technology in the Academe” was conducted on
   April  22.    Mr.  Jolly  Jose  R.  Villaviza,  manager  at  Linux
   Professional Institute, was invited to talk about the free and open-
   source software that can be used in the academe.  Mr. Villaviza
   discussed the meaning of  open-source, its four freedoms, limits
   of proprietary software, modern open-source movement, and the
   reasons for choosing and using free and open-source software.
   The second lecture was discussed by Mr. Richard L. Hernandez,
   CvSU-Carmona  faculty.    He  introduced  OpenOffice  and
   demonstrated the features of OpenOffice writer.
           The  first  episode  titled,  “Computer-Aided  Design  (CAD)”
   was conducted on December 11, 2021.  The lecture on CAD 2D
   and  Floor  Plan  was  discussed  by  Mr.  Joshua  P.  Garcia,  DIIT
   faculty.    He  presented  the different  tools  and  functions  of  CAD
   software  and  its  importance  in  designing  floor  plans.    He  also
   demonstrated  how  to  draw  a  simple  floor  plan  using  the  same
   software.  Meanwhile, Mr. Mark Anthony R. Abril, who is also a
   DIIT  faculty,  delivered  the  lecture  on  CAD  3D  and  Basic  3D
   Printer with Modeling where he demonstrated how CAD is used
   in 3D printing.                          (continue on page 9)            Screenshots of some of the presentations

                                               ANNOUNCEMENTS












































                                                                                                                  Page 8]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4


                DHum, LSC conduct Language HOUR with VELF


           In  partnership  with the Language  Study  Center  (LSC),  the
   Department of Humanities (DHum) Extension Unit of the College
   of  Arts  and  Sciences  (CAS)  conducted  the  second  session  of
   Language  HOUR  (Honing  Opportunities in  LangUage Teaching
   through Roundtable Discussions) via Zoom last April 28.
           The  said  online  activity  with language  teachers  inside and
   outside the university was part of the Virtual English Language
   Fellowship (VELF) Program hosted by  CAS in coordination with
   the US Department of State’s Regional English Language Office
   (RELO) in Manila.  Ms. Vivien Valles Thomas, this year’s VELF,
   served  as  the  speaker  focusing  on  language  proficiency  and
   ways  on  how  to assess  competence  of  students in  the  English
   language.
           The first session of the discussion started last March 31 with
   the  topic,  “Language  and  Technology”  as  she  shared  how
   technology  affects  language  learning  in  the  new  normal.    The
   third session is scheduled on May 26, while the fourth will be held
   before the semester ends.

           Ms.  Thomas  earned  her  Bachelor  of  Arts  in  English  and
   Communication  degree  from  St.  Mary's  University  of  San
   Antonio,  and  her  Master  of  Arts  in  Applied  Linguistics  in  2014
   from the University of Texas at El Paso, Texas, USA.  Currently,
   she  is  teaching  ENLS  116  -  ELT  Approaches  and  Methods  to
   students of the BA English Language Studies program of CAS.
   Meanwhile,  the  RELO  in  Manila  oversees  English  language
   programs  in  the  Philippines,  Japan,  Korea,  Taiwan,  and  the   Online round table discussions with VELF and faculty
   Pacific Island countries. (Lady Aileen A. Orsal)

   CvSU-Carmona concludes ...                 (from page 8)    programs.  Meanwhile, Mr. Tabucol covered the basic syntax of
                                                               Arduino  programming,  Arduino  pictorial  diagram,  Arduino
                                                               program construction using Arduino IDE, and Arduino Sequence
            The  second  episode  titled,  “Introduction  to  Arduino”  was
    conducted  on  January  22.    Lectures  on  “Theories  and   Simulation using TinkerCAD.
    Fundamentals”  and  “Simulation  using  Arduino  IDE  and           The webinar series was headed by Ms. Janine B. Bacosmo,
    TinkerCAD Circuits” were delivered by Engr. Christian John R.   campus  extension  coordinator,  Mr.  Mark  Anthony  R.  Abril  and
    Cadag  and  Mr.  Dennis  J.  Tabucol,  respectively.    Engr.  Cadag   Mr.  Joe  Marlou  A.  Opella,  department  extension  coordinators,
    discussed  the  definition  of  Arduino,  its  offline  and  online   under  the  supervision  of  Dr.  Cristina  M.  Signo,  campus
    Integrated   Development   Environment    (IDE),   Arduino   administrator.    A  total  of  550  participants  entered  the  WebEx
    development  boards,  and  Arduino  shields.  He  also  showed  a   space,  and  almost  3,800  viewers  watched  the  engagement
    walkthrough  of  the  IDE  and  presented  some  sample  working   through Facebook Live. (Janine B. Bacosmo)



































                                  Screenshots of the posters of the three episodes of the webinar series


                                                                                                                  Page 9]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4


       University CS collaborates with GADRC on CvSU Policies

                           for New Security Provider orientation


           The  University  Civil  Security  (UCS)  unit  collaborated  with
   the Gender and Development Resource Center (GADRC) in an
   orientation  on  CvSU  security  policies  for  the  new  security
   provider  held  last  April  30  at  the  S.M.  Rolle  Hall,  Cavite  State
   University (CvSU) main campus, Indang, Cavite.
           Mr. Romulo L. Gomez, director of the CvSU Civil Security
   Unit,  delivered  the  welcome  remarks.    He  extended  his  warm
   welcome and hoped that everyone would enjoy and learn at the
   same time.  Ms. Raecel A. Estebat, in-charge for GAD Planning,
   Monitoring and Evaluation, spoke about gender sensitivity.  She
   thoroughly  discussed  the  difference  between  sex  and  gender,
   gender  division  of  labor,  agents  of  gender  socialization,  and   Dr. Susan G. Tan (left) discussing Safe Spaces Act and

   gender  issues  in  the  society.   Meanwhile,  Dr.  Susan  G.  Tan,   Ms. Raecel A. Estebat (right) discussing Gender Sensitivity
   director  of  GADRC,  talked  about  the  Safe  Spaces  Act.    She
                                                                briefly highlighted the origin of this law, the concept of sexual
                                                                harassment as well as its different forms.  She also warned all
                                                                the security personnel to be mindful of their words and actions.
                                                                        Lastly,  Ms.  Joeneth  R.  Reblora,  Administrative  and
                                                                Logistics  Manager  of  Advanced  Remote  Managed  Security
                                                                Services,  Inc.  (ARMSS),  made  the  closing  remarks.    She
                                                                reminded  the  security  personnel  that  they  are  the  partners  of
                                                                ARMSS’s  in  ensuring  safety  and  protection of  the  university’s
                                                                stakeholders.

                                                                        Ms.  Maria  Czarina  P.  Sioco,  in-charge  for  Data  Banking
                                                                and  Publication  of  GADRC,  moderated  the  orientation  which
    A group photo of the speakers and the personnel of UCCS and
                             ARMSS                              was  attended  by  50  newly  hired  security  providers.  (Maria
                                                                Czarina P. Sioco)

          GADRC holds webinar on Solo Parent in the Workplace


            The Gender and Development Resource Center (GADRC)  generously contributed their time and expertise.  She stated that
    held a webinar titled, "Webinar on Solo Parent in the Workplace"  the  institution  would  continue  to  support  such  provisions,  and
    on April 30 via Zoom video conferencing and Facebook live.  The  she  congratulated  all  single  parents  for  their  efforts  and
    webinar aimed to raise awareness about Republic Act 8972: Solo  sacrifices on behalf of their children.
    Parent's  Welfare  Act  2000  and                                  Ms.  Darylvy  R.  Avila,  CAS
    Women's Occupational Hazards.                              faculty, spoke about Republic Act

            Dr.  Bettina  Joyce  P.  Ilagan,                   8972:  Solo  Parents’  Welfare  Act
    dean  of  the  College  of  Arts  and                      of  2000.  She  discussed  the
    Sciences  (CAS),  delivered  the                           contents  of  this  law  by  providing
    opening remarks.  She expressed                            its   definition,   conditions   of
    her  heartfelt  gratitude  to  all  the                    termination,  criteria  of  support,
    attendees and guests as well as   Dr. Bettina Joyce P. Ilagan   and  the  steps  to  avail  the   Ms. Darylvy R. Avila
    the  resource  speakers  who                               package.     (continue on page 11)























                                                                                                                  Page 10]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4


    GADRC holds webinar on ...                 (from page 8)
                                                                 Soon, CvSU wears one of Cavite's long-standing traditions of
                                                                                      craftsmanship
            Ms.   Alma   Flor   Caurel-
    Molina,  director  of  Patient  Care
    Services   of   Perpetual   Help
    Medical  Center,  discussed  the
    Reproductive    Health     and
    Occupational  Hazards  among
    Women Workers.  She went over
    the key points of the Responsible
    Parenthood  and  Reproductive
    Health  Act  of  2012,  also  known   Ms. Alma Flor Caurel-Molina
    as RA 10354, as well as the law's
    legislative aim and purpose.  She also listed the various types
    and  causes  of  hazard,  special  occupational  hazards  that
    women face, as well as the applicable laws enacted to defend
    women's rights.
            Dr.  Mary  Jane  D.  Tepora,
    director  of  the  Human  Resource
    Development  Office,  made  the
    closing remarks.  She expressed
    her  gratitude  to  GADRC  as  well
    as  the  resource  speakers  for
    sharing  their  knowledge  and
    expertise.    She  also  hoped  that   Dr. Mary Jane D. Tepora
    participants  would  share  what
    they  had  learned  about  improving  everyone's  well-being  and
    that CvSU would remain gender responsive.

            Ms. Joy M. Peji, faculty of the College of Engineering and
    Information Technology, was the moderator during the webinar
    attended by more than a hundred participants. (Maria Czarina
    P. Sioco)

    Let us all reunite as the Research Center’s Webinar Series will hold its second webinar with not just one, but two (2)
    very  informative  topics  to  be  discussed  by  two  of  CvSU’s  most  respected  faculty  researchers:  Dr.  Agnes  B.
    Alimboyoguen, Head of Technical Services Division of Research Center and Dr. Yolanda A. Ilagan, professor at the
    College of Arts and Sciences - Department of Biological Sciences.











































                                                                                                                  Page 11]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[April 2022 | Vol. 5 No. 4





















                                                                 Interested in making videos for your class?


                                                                 The  Knowledge  Management  Center  offers  an
                                                                 online Short Course designed for you, teachers and
                                                                 faculty  members,  who  want  to  learn  how  to  make
                                                                 simple lecture videos without being a "techie."  It is
                                                                 asynchronous and self-paced so you can work on it
                                                                 and finish it anytime you want.

                                                                 Open  for  all  CvSU  and  non-CvSU  teachers  and
                                                                 faculty members.

                                                                 Register now at: https://bit.ly/3FIqnnq





                                                                          Editorial Staff


                                                                Editor-in-Chief :       Catherine R. Mojica

                                                                Associate Editor :    Erica Charmane B. Hernandez
                                                                Layout Artist:         Melinda B. Eugenio
                                                                Contributors:


                                                                        Teddy F. Tepora
                                                                        Bernadette S. Amparo
                                                                        Hosea dL. Matel
                                                                        Gizelle D. Crema
                                                                        Gierone Lianni A. Reyes
                                                                        Jacob M. Gomez
                                                                        Lady Aileen A. Orsal
                                                                        Ma. Angelica F. Naranja
                                                                        Liwayway P. Taglinao
                                                                        Janine B. Bacosmo
                                                                        Maria Czarina P. Sioco


                                                                Head of Publication and
                                                                Communication Division:   Dr. Alvin William A. Alvarez

                                                                Consultants:    Dr. Agnes C. Francisco
                                                                               Dr. Melbourne R. Talactac
                                                                                   Dr. Hernando D. Robles


                                                                                     Publication Office
                                                                              Knowledge Management Center
                                                                                   Research Center Bldg.
                                                                                   Cavite State University
                                                                                      Indang, Cavite
                 The CvSU Research Journal FB page                 Tel. No.  +6346 8621654           E-mail: renewsletter@cvsu.edu.ph



                                                                                                                 Page 12]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[CvSU T3 Campus Official Faculty Newsletter]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Volume 1, Issue 1            T h e   O f f i c i a l   F a c u l t y   N e w s l e t t e r   o f
             2nd Semester AY 2018-2019     C a v i t e   S t a t e   U n i v e r s i t y - T 3   C a m p u s



                           T3 NEWSLETTER






             T3 faculty and staff organize capability enhancement

             seminar at CvSU-Main Campus to upgrade skills



                                                              (introduced by Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian, T3
                                                              Teacher  Education  Department  Chair),  dis-
                                                              cussed his topic on Syllabus Preparation.
                                                                     For the afternoon session of Day 1, sec-
                                                              ond resource person and Dean of the College of
                                                              Education,  Dr.  Cecilia  A.  Banaag  (introduced
                                                              by Ms. Joyce Erika S. Senaris, T3 Department
                                                              of  Information  Technology  Chair),  delivered
                                                              her topic on Teaching Strategies and Classroom
                                                              Management.
                                                                     For Day 2 of the seminar, third resource
                                                              person and CED Student Teaching Supervisor,
                                                              Dr.  Florencio  R.  Abanes  (introduced  by  Ms.
                                                              Kristel  Shane  C.  Paminter,  T3  Department  of
                                                              Hospitality  and  Tourism  Management  Chair),
                                                              talked about his topic on Test Construction, Ta-
                                                              ble of Specifications, and Rubrics Preparation,
             T3 faculty brainstorm to produce better syllabi for the stu-  followed by fourth resource person and Faculty
             dents                                            Researcher  for  CvSU-Naic  Campus,  Dr.  Leah
                                                              C. Navarro (introduced Prof. Arlene L. Estrada,
                       On January 30-31, 2019, the teachers and   T3 General Education Department Chair), who
                                                              discussed  her  topic  on  Assessment  of  Evalua-
             staff  of  T3  Campuses  joined  together  for  this   tion of Students’ Performance.
             semester’s  Teachers’  Capability  Enhancement          In the afternoon session of Day 2, fifth
             Seminar Workshop at International House I, Ca-   resource  person  and  T3  Management  Infor-
             vite  State  University,  Indang  Cavite  from  8:00   mation System and Public Information Officer,
             a.m. to 5:00 p.m.                                Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio (introduced by Cris-
                       The  opening  prayer  was  led  by  General   tza  De  Ocampo-Manlapig,  T3  Department  of
             Education  Department  faculty,  Mark  Joel  C.   Management Chair), gave his talk on Education
             Sibulo, while the welcome remarks were given     4.0,  which  focused  on  new  technology  and
             by Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3 Campus Adminis-      global trends for teachers.
             trator. Vice President for Academic Affairs Dr.             The capability enhancement seminar was
             Camilo  A.  Polinga,  thru  Ms.  Agnes  Nuestro,   designed  to  promote  the  continuous  develop-
             gave  his  inspirational  message  to  all  seminar   ment of teachers as they gear up for the second
             participants.                                    semester of school year 2018-2019. The guest
                    Prof. Vienna Mi A. Feranil, T3 Curricu-   speakers tackled various topics that centered on
             lum  Development  and  Instruction  Head,  gave   becoming  effective  teachers  in  our  country’s
             her talk on leveling the expectations and objec-  relatively new period of outcomes-based educa-
             tives of the T3 faculty in order to properly align   tion  and  technology-driven  teaching  strategy.
             themselves with the goals of the University, the   The  organizers  of  the  seminar  successfully
             campus, as well as their respective departments.   prepped  and  motivated  the  T3  faculty  in  their
             The  closing  remarks  were  also  given  by  Prof.   various  departments  for  the  many  challenges
             Feranil.                                         that were awaiting them this semester.
                       The  two-day  seminar  workshop  featured
             five guest speakers who covered various topics
             promoting  the  growth  and  development  of
             teachers in the academe.
                    For Day 1 of the seminar, first resource
             person  and  Chair  of  CED  Teacher  Education
             Department,  Prof.  Jayson  R.  Maniacop

                              CvSU Vision                                     CvSU Mission
                    The premier university in historic Cavite        Cavite State University shall provide excellent, equita-
             recognized for excellence in the development of   ble, and relevant educational opportunities in the arts, sciences and
                                                              technology through quality instruction and responsive research and
             globally  competitive  and  morally  upright  indi-  development activities.
             viduals.                                                It shall produce professional  skilled and morally upright
                                                              individuals for global competitiveness.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[PAGE 2                                                                                      INFO-D



             T3 Campuses celebrate their                       istrative Support and Support Services, repre-
                                                               senting University President Dr. Hernando D.
                                                               Robles, Mr. Rodel Vincent T. Bae, Director of
             Foundation Days in February                       Provincial Youth and Sports Development Of-
                                                               fice, representing Cavite Governor Hon. Jesus
                                                               Crispin C. Remulla, Mayor of Trece Martires
                                                               City Hon. Melandres G. De Sagun and Com-
                                                               munity  Relations  Regent  Hon.  Ed  Silan.  The
                                                               closing remarks were given by  Dr.  Henry  O.
                                                               Garcia, after which the program was conclud-
                                                               ed  with  Instructor  Pamela  Daphne  R.  Busog
                                                               singing the CvSU Hymn.
                                                                      For lunch, food and refreshments were
                                                               provided to the students and teachers. The pro-
                                                               gram  resumed  an  hour  later  with  the  Socio-
                                                               Cultural  and  Arts  Competition  that  included
                                                               the following categories: Photo Contest, Quiz
                                                               Bowl,  Charcoal  Rendering,  Pencil  Drawing,
                                                               Painting, On-the-Spot Poster-Making Contest,
                                                               Pagsulat ng  Sanaysay, Short and Sweet Play,
                                                               Essay Writing, Dagliang Talumpati, Extempo-
                                                               raneous Speech, Pagkukuwento, Story Telling,
                                                               Radio  Drama,  Instrumental  Solo,  Pop  Solo,
                                                               and Vocal Duet.
                                                                      The  different  contest  categories  were
             Trece Martires City Mayor Hon. Melandres G. De Sagun   held simultaneously in the different rooms of
                                                               the CvSU-Trece Campus Building, starting at
             gives his message for T3                          1:00 p.m. and ending at 4:00 p.m., with desig-
                                                               nated  facilitators  assigned  to  each  category,
                    On February 15-16, 2019, the T3 Cam-       and coaches on standby to give their support to
             puses celebrated their foundation days with the   the  respective  participants  from  each  of  their
             theme, “Breaking Grounds Towards  Globaliza-      campuses.
             tion.” The Trece Martires City Campus celebrat-             The celebration continued on its second
                                                 th
                     th
             ed its 13  year, Tanza Campus its 11  year, and  day,  beginning  with  the  usual  registration  at
                                            th
             General Trias City Campus its 6  year.            7:00  a.m.,  followed  by  everyone’s  much-
                       The first day of the celebration was held   awaited  category,  the  Mr.  and  Ms.  T3  2019
             at  the  CvSU-Trece  Campus  Grounds,  with  the   (both  won  by  CvSU-Trece  Campus).  After
             registration  starting  at  7:00  a.m.,  followed  by   lunch break, the celebration resumed with the
             the Ecumenical Service and the Blessing of the    Students’ Recognition Program, wherein cam-
             Trece  Martires  City  Campus  Building  at  8:00   pus  scholars  received  their  certificates  of
             a.m. The mass was presided by Rev. Fr. Henrico    recognition. The T3 Most Outstanding Student
                                                                                                           th
             T.  Tagalog  of  the  San  Lorenzo  Ruiz  Pastoral   was  awarded  to  Jolina  P.  Pacamparra,  a  4
             Center in Dasmarinas City.                        year  Business  Management  student  from
                    The Call to Worship was led by Instruc-    CvSU-Tanza Campus.
             tor Rose Ann R. Tobias, followed by the Open-            The  recognition  ceremony  was  fol-
             ing Hymn sung by Instructor Pamela Daphne R.      lowed  by  the  Battle  of  the  Bands  (won  by
             Busog.  Aftwards,  Department  of  Management     CvSU-Tanza Campus) in the late afternoon to
             Chairperson Cristza De Ocampo-Manalpig read  help  amplify  the  attendees’  festive  mood  for
             the Gospel. A series of prayers were said for the   the  highly  anticipated  Solidarity  Night  and
             following  intentions:  University,  Administra-  Ballroom Dancing. The celebration drew to a
             tion,  Employees,  and  Students  led  by  Pastor   close  with  the  awarding  of  the  following
             Mark  Joel  C.  Sibulo  of  the  Crown  of  Glory   awards: Best Dressed of the Night, King and
             Presbyterian  Church,  the  Family,  Sick,  and   Queen of the Night, Mr. and Ms. Valentine’s,
             Needy  Persons  led  by  Bro.  Keno  A.  Villavi-  and Adonis & Aphrodite of the Night.
             cencio of the United Pentecostal Church in Ta-           The night ended with a lot of dancing
             gaytay  City,  and  the  Political  Leaders  and  Ca-  and  partying  among  the  teachers,  staff,  and
             lamity Victims by Rev. Fr. Henrico T. Tagalog     students  whose  presence  for  the  night  rein-
             himself.  The  Closing  Hymn  was  sung  by  In-  forced the camaraderie, support, and solidarity
             structor Melona O. Igmasine.                      that the T3  campuses  meant  to  foster  for  the
                       After the ecumenical mass, Rev. Fr. Taga-  said foundation days celebration.
             log  proceeded  with  the  blessing  of  the  CvSU-
             Trece Campus Building. The opening ceremony
             was led by Instructors Czerina Mae S. Antonio
             and Justine Angelo C. Libunao. T3 Campus Ad-
             ministrator  Noel  A.  Sedigo  gave  the  welcome
             remarks  and  afterwards,  the  linkage  partners
             were recognized.
                    The  inspirational  messages  were  given
             by the following T3 Campuses guests of honor:
             Dr. Henry O. Garcia, Vice President for Admin-



                        “Breaking Grounds Towards Globalization”]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[PAGE 3                                                                                      INFO-D



             Trece wins award at CvSU-                         First faculty and staff

             Main Campus Trade Fair                            meeting for second

             and Exhibit                                       semester held at General

                                                               Trias Campus
























             Trece Campus showcases their projects to Dr. Ruel M.
             Mojica, Vice President for Research and Extension   Prof. Vienna Mi A. Feranil, Trece Campus Coordinator,
                                                               discusses the T3 status report for the last semester
                    Cavite State University’s 113th year was
             celebrated in the month of February with a week-
             long exhibit from various sectors, satellite cam-        On  January  15,  2019,  T3  Campuses
             puses  and  colleges.  The  softball  field  was  con- held its first meeting for the 2nd Semester of
             verted into fairgrounds from February 11 to 14.   AY 2018-2019. The meeting started at around
                    The T3 Campuses, which included Tanza,  8:00  a.m.  and  ended  at  12:00  noon  and  took
             General Trias City, and Trece Martires City, all  place  at  the  roof  deck  of  the  CvSU-General
             had their booths set up, with Trece Campus at the  Trias  City  Campus  building.  Breakfast  was
             frontline  showcasing  their  various  technological  served  to  the  attendees  while  waiting  for  the
             innovations. The three campuses had diverse of- program to start.
             ferings such as malunggay processed foods, ubod          The meeting, presided by Campus Ad-
             salad, simulation models for disaster risk reduc-  ministrator  Noel  A.  Sedigo,  began  with  the
             tion, eco-friendly slippers, and various household   brief  status  reports  delivered  by  the  various
             concoctions,                                      department chairpersons and campus adminis-
                    The  closing  program  was  attended  by   trators,  followed  by  a  demonstration  of  the
             University officials and the participating booths.   MIS Team’s electronic databank, which could
             Trece Campus bagged third place for best booth  now           be        accessed        through
             from a satellite campus. It was another achieve-  www.classroom.google.com. Afterwards came
             ment under T3 campus’ belt.                       the  presentation  of  the  proposed  calendar  of
                    The week-long exhibit was supported by  activities  for  2019,  which  included  a  brief
             selected faculty and students who worked hard to   overview of the scheduled activities and events
             represent  their  campuses  by  manning  their  re-  for each month.
             spective  booths  for  three  consecutive  days  and             The meeting ended on a hopeful note for
             educated  visitors  regarding  their  featured  prod-  all the faculty and staff after plans for the next
             ucts.  The  T3  people  on  duty  during  that  entire
             week were able to participate alongside different   two  semesters  were  meticulously  laid  out  in
                                                               the hope of reminding everyone of the collec-
             colleges and sectors that also had equally inter-
             esting  displays  and  products  to  sell.  These  in-  tive  goals  of  the  T3  campuses  for  the  entire
                                                               calendar year. This year was also said to be the
             cluded  plants,  organic  vegetables,  coffee,  wine,   final  year  of  Prof.  Sedigo’s  term  as  Campus
             and other sustainable products.                  Administrator of the T3 Campuses.








               “The doers are the major thinkers. The people that really create the things
                that change this industry are both the thinker and doer in one person.”
                                                     - Steve Jobs]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[PAGE 4                                                                                      INFO-D



             TED faculty Dr. Noel                              General Trias Campus hosts

             Manarpiis receives 15-year                        thanksgiving service for

             service award                                     graduating Education

                                                               students



                                                                      On April 15, 2019, CvSU-General Tri-
                                                               as  City  Campus  hosted  a  small  thanksgiving
                                                               service for the graduating students of Teacher
                                                               Education  Department  at  the  roof  deck  of
                                                               CvSU-GenTri  Bldg.  from  8:00  a.m.  to  12:00
                                                               noon.  The  program  was  attended  by  selected
                                                               T3 Campuses officials Teacher Education De-
                                                               partment chair and faculty members, who were
                                                               there to recognize their students who had just
                                                               completed their practice teaching hours at their
                                                               respective schools.
                                                                      Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3 Campus Ad-
                                                               ministrator,  gave  his  inspirational  speech  to
                                                               congratulate and motivate the future teachers.
                                                               Other  key  officials  and  faculty  who  spoke
                                                               were Alelie B. Diato, GenTri Campus Coordi-
                                                               nator, Erwin JoelB. Layug, GenTri Instructor,
             T3 campus’ Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis receives his award for 15   Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis, former Tanza Campus
                                                               Coordinator and TED Professor, and Mildred
             years of service                                  A.  Sebastian,  TED  Department  Chairperson.
                                                               They gave their respective words of wisdom to
                       February  13,  2019  was  the  day  Cavite   the would-be teachers on how to be more effi-
             State  University  awarded  loyalty  and  persever-  cient and successful in the academe as well as
             ance. It was a huge affair. The gymnasium was     some noteworthy advice on how to handle the
             packed with people all dressed up and smiling in   pressure that most young teachers encounter at
             anticipation for their turn to go on stage. It was   the start of their careers.
             the  awarding  ceremony  for  the  years  of  service      Afterwards,  the  two  graduating  stu-
             they had given to CVSU.                           dents from each of their respective campuses
                       Before  University  President  Hernando  D.   gave personal accounts of their very own ad-
                                                               ventures  as  practice  teachers.  A  common
             Robles introduced the guest of honor, CHED Di-    theme of their testimonials was the challenging
             rector for Region IV, he told everyone that this   experience of handling multi-faceted personal-
             year  was  different.  It  was  the  start  of  a  new   ities  of  adolescents,  who  each  had  different
             scheme that would benefit the retirees and award-  needs  in  terms  of  learning.  By  using  a  more
             ees for their 40 years of service.                tailor-fit approach to suit the needs of their stu-
                       The first ones called on stage were the re- dents,  the  practice  teachers  were able  to  sur-
             tirees. They were introduced one by one and all  pass the said difficulty and became successful
             of their achievements were announced to the au- by  building  rapport  with  their  students  and
             dience. Then, in descending order, the awardees  emerging wiser from their trial run as second-
             were  asked  to  come  up  the  stage.  CvSU-Tanza  ary education teachers and better equipped for
             Campus’  very  own  TED  faculty  Dr.  Noel  B.  the real world.
             Manarpiis was recognized for his 15 years of ser-        The  Teacher  Education  Department,
             vice and congratulated by everyone.               headed by Department Chairperson Mildred A.
                       In his interview, Dr. Manarpiis said that his   Sebastian,  together  with the  rest  of  T3 Cam-
             most memorable moment of the ceremony were  puses, is hopeful that the graduating students
             the words of former University President Ruperto   will pass the board exam with much ease be-
             S.  Sanggalang,  whose  sage  words  were  that  of   cause of their reputation for being diligent and
             the awardees’ recognition being  well-deserved:   hardworking. Because of their persistence and
             “Rendering years of service for CVSU is a Her-    determination,  which  they  had  proven  time
             culean  feat.  For  that  reason,  the  administration   and again in all those four years in college spe-
             should be the one thankful for the awardees and   cializing in English and Mathematics, the fu-
             not  the  other  way  around.  Nonetheless,  I  urge   ture T3 Campuses alumni and soon-to-be high
             you to move on and finish what you’ve started.”   school teachers are sure to make their instruc-
                       The entire T3 Campuses proudly congratu-  tors proud someday.
             lates Doc Noel for his many years of service to
             the school.






                             “Without ambition one starts nothing. Without work one finishes nothing.
                                      The prize will not be sent to you. You have to win it.”
                                                  - Ralph Waldo Emerson]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[PAGE 5                                                                                      INFO-D



             T3 hosts refresher course on                      submitted on time also meant that they would
                                                               have the chance to submit the students’ grades
                                                               on time. The seminar indeed helped emphasize
             thesis writing                                    the  importance  of  efficiency,  which  would
                                                               make  the  lives  of  both  students  and  teachers
                                                               easier as the school year was already drawing
                                                               to a close.


                                                               Students’ leadership

                                                               seminar held at CCAT















             T3 Campus Administrator Prof. Noel A. Sedigo leads the
             session on thesis writing
                    On  April  5,  2019  at  the  CvSU-Main
             Campus  Quadrangle,  students  participated  in  a
             refresher  seminar  on  thesis  writing  entitled,
             “CvSU Form and Style for Manuscript Writing”
             from 8:00 a.m. to 12:00 noon.                     T3 students attend the seminar on leadership held at
                    The resource persons were Prof. Noel A.    CCAT, CVSU Rosario
             Sedigo,  T3  Campus  Administrator,  Prof.  Jason
             R.  Maniacop,  College  of  Education  Key  Offi-        The  CvSU-Trece  Martires  City  Cam-
             cial,  and  Prof.  Allan  Robert  C.  Solis,  Director   pus Central Student Government (CSG) orga-
             for Public Affairs and Communications Office.     nized the Student Leaders Interactive Capabil-
             They  gave  their  talk  on  the  following  topics:   ity  Enhancement  Workshop  on  April  4-5  at
             CvSU  Form and Style, Narrative Writing, Stu-     CvSU-CCAT Campus in Rosario, Cavite. The
             dent Teaching Portfolio Writing.                  aim of the said event was to help student lead-
                    The main objective of the seminar was to   ers to turn their own visions for their respec-
             provide a short review session for the third and   tive  organizations  into  reality  through  self-
             fourth year students of the T3 Campuses regard-   motivation and goal setting.
             ing the CvSU Form and Style for thesis writing.          The speakers of the leadership seminar,
             The highlight of the said event was the open fo-  Xian  Lozares,  Lucky  Cedric  Guyamin,  Keno
             rum, where students had the chance to ask ques-   Villacencio, and Niel Reyes, discussed topics
             tions  and  obtain  professional  advice  for  the   concerning  the  privileges  of  students,  their
             guest  speakers  on  how  to  effectively  write  a   goals, and how character formation was detri-
             manuscript following the CvSU standards.          ment  to  the  development  of  a  progressive
                    One  of  the  challenges  encountered  dur-  school  such  as  Cavite  State  University.  They
             ing the seminar was that some students forgot to   also gave the students a chance to be informed
             bring their manuscripts with them, thereby ren-   and  encouraged  to  become  more  driven  in
             dering  the  revision  process  more  difficult  and   terms of achieving their objectives as well as
             time-consuming.  Another  challenge  was  the     to build rapport with their colleagues and fel-
             limited time for students to process all the rec-  low students. The main goal of the said event
             ommendations  of  the  speakers  and  ask  further   was  for  the  student  leaders  to  develop  their
             questions  that  would  help  them  quickly  revise   confidence in order to become more effective
             their theses.                                     leaders in their own campuses.
                    One of the attendees of the seminar and           Testimonies  from  the  current  CSG
             CvSU-Tanza  Campus  Teacher  Education  De-       Presidents of CCAT, Silang, and Tanza Cam-
             partment  Instructor,  Mary  Joy  Angelique  R.   puses  were  shared  with  the  audience,  high-
             Mojica, found the refresher session particularly   lighting challenges they had overcome during
             helpful  for  students  who  were  racing  against   their  terms.  Despite  the  many  difficulties  in
             time and experiencing a great deal of pressure in   their  collective  experience  being  head  of  the
             terms  of  the  writing  process:  “The  seminar   student government, they were able to endure
             served as a quick guide for the students. It will   them  and  even  attested  to  how  essential  stu-
             allow  them  to  finish  their  manuscripts  in  time   dent leaders were to the school’s success. They
             for the deadline.”                                could help others in meeting their needs, espe-
                    Meeting the deadline was also a signifi-   cially  when  it  came  to convenience  and  effi-
             cant thing to consider among teachers. Theses     ciency  in  all  matters  concerning  their  educa-
                                                               tion. (Continued on next page)]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[PAGE 6                                                                                      INFO-D



             Leadership seminar… From p. 5                     Employment (DOLE), T3 Campuses Secretary
                                                               and  Gender  and  Development  Coordinator,
                    The officers who participated in the semi-  Arlene L. Estrada, and Mr. Philip Azur, a Tal-
             nar  were  recognized  for  their  innate  leadership   ent  Acquisition  Associate  of  VXI  Global
             capabilities, and only minimal supervision was in   Holdings, B.V.
             fact needed from their respective advisers. Gide-        The  certificates  were  awarded  to  the
             on  Luke  P.  Ty,  CSG  Adviser  of  CvSU-Trece   speakers by some of the key officials of the T3
             Martires City Campus said, "They already exhib-   Campuses, Prof. Sedigo, Office of Student Af-
             it great potential. All I have to do is give them   fairs  and  Services  (OSAS)  Head  and  Job
             advice  to  ensure  that  there  is  always  a  strong   Placement Coordinator Lilian O. Sidamon, and
             sense  of  leadership.”  Nonetheless,  the  seminar   Events  Management  Instructor  Aldrin  Ro-
             helped reinforce the student officers’ call to lead   deros. The closing remarks were delivered by
             and  most  certainly  prepared  them  for  the  chal-  Ms. Sidamon while the CvSU Hymn was led
             lenges  that  came  with  their  significant  roles  in   by Events Management Representative Trisha
             the lives of the students of the T3 Campuses.    Mae Bilan. The seminar was presided by Ger-
                                                               ald Boridas and Francheska Maureen Castro.
                                                                      The said seminar was an important as-
                                                               pect of the fourth year students’ pre-graduation
             Pre-employment seminar                            requirements, with an aim to prepare the cam-
                                                               pus’ would-be alumni to make their job hunt-
                                                               ing  experience a  worthwhile  endeavor  and  at
             organized for third and                           the same time help build their foundation for a
                                                               solid career in their chosen degree programs.
             fourth year students






                                                               IT program spearheads first

                                                               Arduino technology forum

                                                               and exhibit at Rolle Hall







             Guest speakers of the pre-employment seminar pose for a
             photo in front of the third and fourth year students

                    On  April  1,  2019,  the  students,  together
             with selected faculty of the T3 Campuses (Tanza,
             General Trias City, and Trece Martires City) at-
             tended  the  pre-employment  seminar  entitled,
             “Understanding  Career  Opportunities:  A  Big
             Step to Start Your Future.” The event was held at
             Santiago M. Rolle Hall of CvSU-Main Campus
             from 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. Trece Martires City   (From left) Dr. David L. Cero, Dr. Camilo A. Polinga, Mr.
             faculty  member  and  Hospitality  and  Tourism
             Management  Department  Chairperson,  Kristel     Richard Progalidad, and Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
             Shane  M.  Paminter  gave  the  opening  remarks,
             followed  by  an  inspirational  message  from  T3       The  1   Cavite  Arduino  Technology
                                                                             st
             Campus Administrator, Prof. Noel A. Sedigo.       Research Forum and Exhibit was held on April
                    The seminar featured five guest speakers   22,  2019  from  8:00  a.m.  to  5:00  p.m.  at  the
             who each gave a talk on specialized topics rang-  Santiago M. Rolle Hall, CvSU-Main Campus,
             ing  from  job  interview  tips,  applying  one’s   Indang Cavite. The event was organized by the
             knowledge, skills, and other abilities upon gradu-  Office of the Vice-President for Research and
             ation, and making it in the real world. The speak-  Extension (OVPRE) and College of Engineer-
             ers  gave  various  personal  testimonies  on  what   ing and Information Technology, with the help
             they did to land their current jobs and what steps   of  a  number  of  sponsors:  American  Spaces
             they  took  in  order  to  cultivate  their  careers.   Philippines,  Fablab  Manila,  Sparkfruit  Elec-
             Among the noteworthy specialists who made the     tronics,  LEENTECH  Network  Solutions,  Ro-
             seminar  possible  were  Mr.  Keno  A.  Villavi-  boRAVE Philippines, and LITL.
             cencio,  T3  Campuses  Management  Information           The said activity’s aim was to expose
             Officer, Mr. Joshua Pascual, HR Officer, Junior   students and teachers to an event where they
             Corporate  Trainer,  Junior  HR  Consultant  and   could accomplish the following goals:
             Registered  Psychometrician,  Ms.  Ruth  E.  Are-  (Continued on next page)
             valo, Labor and Employment Officer 3 and La-
             bor  Inspector  of  the  Department  of  Labor  and]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[PAGE 7                                                                                      INFO-D



             IT program… From p. 6                             System Design for  Sparkfruit Electronics En-
                                                               terprise  and  Fablab  Manila).  The  certificates
             exhibit and present their Arduino-based research,   were  then  awarded  by  Prof.  Noel  A.  Sedigo,
             interact and collaborate with other Cavite schools   Pamela Daphne R. Busog, adviser for the stu-
             as well as nearby cities and provinces, and update   dent organization, League of IT Leaders, Ron-
             themselves on the current application of Arduino   cesvalle J. Caipang, T3 Research Coordinator,
             technology  in  instruction,  research,  enterprise,   and Joyce Erika S. Senaris, T3 Chairperson for
             and  information  technology.  The  local  research   the Department of Information Technology.
             forum was conducted in preparation for a much            The awards for the winners of the Ar-
             bigger event in the near future: an international   duino-based  Oral  Presentation  Competition,
             conference to be held at CvSU in 2020. The said   the Arduino-based Display Presentation Com-
             future project was meant to be accomplished in    petition, and the Arduinothon were given after
             partnership  with  the  American  Center,  Manila   the  awarding  of  the  certificate  to  the  second
             and American Spaces Philippines.                  keynote  speaker,  while  the  closing  remarks
                    The program began with a doxology led      were  given  by  Keno  A.  Villavicencio,  the
             by Pamela Daphne R. Busog, CvSU-Trece Mar-        overall in-charge of the said event. The forum
             tires  City  Campus  Extension  Coordinator,  fol-  and  exhibit  was  concluded  by  the  singing  of
             lowed by the singing of the Philippine National
             Anthem  led  by  Steven  G.  Quisto,  a  BS  Infor-
             mation  Technology  student.  The  opening  re-
             marks were given by T3 Campus Administrator,
             Prof. Noel A. Sedigo and the introduction of the
             CvSU  Administration  Council  by  Prof.  Allan
             Robert  C.  Solis,  Director  of  the  Public  Infor-
             mation and Community Relations Office.
                    Messages  to  the  seminar’s  participants
             were given by the following guest speakers: Dr.
             David L. Cero, Dean of the College of Engineer-
             ing and Information Technology, Dr. Camilo A.
             Polinga,  Vice  President  for  Academic  Affairs,
             Dr. Ruel M. Mojica, Vice President for Research
             and  Extension,  and  the  University’s  very  own
             president,  Dr.  Hernando  D.  Robles.  The  certifi-
             cate for the keynote speaker was awarded by the
             University  President  himself,  together  with  the
             T3 Campus Administrator, Prof. Sedigo.             The CvSU Academic Council  with Keynote Speaker
                    T3  MIS  Officer  Keno  A.  Villavicencio   Mr. Richard F. Progalidad, Leentech Network Solutions
             introduced the first keynote speaker, Richard  F.   President
             Prodigalidad, President and CEO of LEENTECH
             Network Solutions, a company that specializes in
             mobile application design and development, digi-  the  CvSU  hymn  led  by  Pamela  Daphne  R.
             tal marketing and consultation, and cloud server   Busog.
             and management solutions.                                The  theme  of  the  event,  “Translating
                    A  Memorandum  of  Agreement  (MOA)        Ideas into Innovation” paved the way for inter-
             between LEENTECH and Cavite State Universi-       esting avenues for discussion among IT practi-
             ty  was  signed  afterwards.  The  morning  plenary   tioners and aspiring professionals, which gave
             session  featured  the  following  topics:  Arduino,   the participants of the forum a glimpse into the
             Education,  and  Training  (led  by  guest  speaker   competitive  world  of  the  IT  industry.  Joseph
             Arvin  S.  Buendia,  Robotics  Specialist  for  the   O.  Sabaybay,  CvSU-Tanza  Campus  IT  In-
             CIIT College of Arts and Technology and author    structor and participant of the Arduino forum,
             of a few Arduino-based robotics textbooks), Ar-   had great things to say about his experience of
             duino Integration on Laboratory Instruction (led   the said event: “The first Cavite Arduino tech-
             by Keno A. Villavicencio, IT instructor of CvSU-  nology research forum and exhibit was a great
             T3 and Arduino-based research presenter for the   and  informative  seminar  as  well  as  a  good
             2019 International Conference on Open and Dis-    platform for students to showcase their talents
             tance e-Learning in Taiwan), Arduino Local and    and passion for robotics and the like, especial-
             International  Competitions  (led  by  Mervin  A.   ly  for  the  younger  students—those  in  senior
             Boco,  Robotics  Coordinator  of  Tagaytay  City   high  school.  Through  the  effort  of  Sir  Keno,
             Science  High  School  and  International  and  Na-  we  became  connected  and  had  a  MOA  with
             tional  Robotics  Competitions  Champion  and     local and international companies and the gov-
             Awardee in Australia, Singapore, Taiwan, Indo-    ernment that deals with Arduino technology.”
             nesia, and the Philippines).                             The  event  was  indeed  a  success  as  it
                    For  the  afternoon  session,  participating   established  solidarity  among  students,  practi-
             schools  and  companies  featured  their  works  in   tioners, and enthusiasts of Arduino technology
             the Arduino oral-based and display-based project   in the IT industry—a hopeful turnout at a time
             presentation portion, followed by the competition   where young professionals are expected to be-
             named “Arduinothon.”                              come more competitive in the digital world.
                    The next keynote speaker was Jeanie M.
             Duwan, Assistant Cultural Affairs Officer for the
             US Embassy, who was later succeeded by a new
             set of guest speakers for the following topics for
             discussion:  American  Spaces  (led  by  Xavier  E.
             Lara, Director of American Spaces Philippines),
             Arduino  International  Association  and  Events
             (led by Michael Julius G. Hayag, Director of Ro-
             boRAVE Philippines), and Arduino Fabrication,
             Enterprise, and Markets (led by Engr. Cezar R.
             Calayo,  General  Manager  of  CRV  Embedded]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[PAGE 8                                                                                      INFO-D



             T3 Campuses faculty and                           ficial research proposal format of the Universi-
                                                               ty, which consisted of the following: overview,
                                                               problem,  importance,  literature,  objectives,
             staff attend capability                           and time and place.
                                                                    Finally, Dr. Ilagan tackled how to write

             building seminar at IH 1 in                       quality  research  proposals  for  possible  fund-
                                                               ing, as well as crafting a convincing introduc-
             Indang, Cavite                                    tion that included the rationale and objectives.
                                                               She credited Dr. Bautista’s book on technical
                                                               writing for  the contents of her lecture on the
                                                               principles of writing a good research proposal
                                                               and  concluded  her  talk  by  emphasizing  that
                                                               researchers  needed  to  cherish  their  work  and
                                                               that there was no actual recipe for success but
                                                               just “simple rules, dedication, and hard work.”
                                                                    The  second  speaker,  Dr.  Isaias  A.
                                                               Banaag, Faculty Researcher of the College of
                                                               Education (CED), gave his talk on how to cre-
                                                               ate a viable theoretical and conceptual frame-
                                                               work  for  research.  He  talked  about  the  com-
                                                               mon error regarding the Input-Process-Output
                                                               (IPO),  which  was  in  fact,  a  model  or  frame-
                                                               work  and  not  a  method.  He  further  said  that
                                                               the framework was actually different from the
                                                               research  paradigm—a  source  of  difficulty  in
                                                               most research papers. The difficulty, he  said,
                                                               was  actually  rooted  in  problem  building,  the
                                                               challenge being the driving force behind a re-
                                                               search, which should be geared to address gaps
                                                               between what was happening and what should
                                                               be happening. Structure or maps were needed
                                                               in  order  to  come  up  with  broad  areas  to  be
                                                               covered  in  the  research.  This  would  help  the
             Dr. Renato N. Pelorina, Faculty Researcher of the College   researcher  to  emerge  from  chaotic  thinking
             of Arts and Sciences  receives his certificate of apprecia-  and  into a  more logical,  organized  viewpoint
                                                               for the research problem at hand.
             tion from T3 Campus Administrator Noel. A. Sedigo      Dr. Banaag also explained the difference
                                                               between  a  theoretical  framework  and  a  con-
                  On  March  28-29,  2019,  the  faculty  and  ceptual  framework:  a  theoretical  framework
             staff of the T3 Campuses (Trece Martires City,    was used when there was only one theory fea-
             General  Trias  City,  and  Tanza  Campuses)  at-  tured in a basic research, whereas a conceptual
             tended the seminar entitled, “T3 Faculty Capaci-  framework was used when there were multiple
             ty  Building  Seminar  for  Research”  at  Interna-  theories  and  other  personal  observations  that
             tional  House  1,  CvSU-Main  Campus,  Indang,  needed  to  be  synthesized  in  a  more  complex
             Cavite  from  8:00  a.m.  to  5:00  p.m.,  with  Ms.   type of research. He also distinguished a con-
             Leslie  Anne  N.  Gatdula,  CvSU-General  Trias  struct  from  a  variable—the  construct  being  a
             City Instructor, as in-charge of the ceremonies.   concept with a deliberate and invented mean-
                  Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3 Campus Admin-       ing, while a variable being a construct with an
             istrator, gave the welcome message, which em-     assigned numerical value.
             phasized the importance of research in teaching,       Dr Banaag ended his discussion by sum-
             saying that most educators were accustomed to     marizing the differences between a theoretical
             using  materials  culled  from  other  countries   framework and a conceptual framework: a the-
             when one of the major components of life in the   oretical framework was “adopted from a pre-
             academe  was  innovation  through  research.  He   existing  theory  or  theoretical  perspective,  an
             said that this was how teachers should be teach-  application of a theory as a whole or in part,
             ing their corresponding subject matters. He also   and with a literature research that was deduc-
             mentioned that  it  took  years  for  him  to finally   tive,”  while  a  conceptual  framework  was
             find his own niche in his field.                  “created from a variety of conceptual and the-
                  The first speaker, Dr. Yolanda A. Ilagan,    oretical  perspective,  a  synthesis  of  relevant
             Director  of  the  Research  Center,  discussed  the   concepts, and with research literature that was
             importance of research to the University and its   usually inductive.”
             faculty  members.  She  emphasized  how  hard          The  third  speaker,  Dr.  Renato  N.
             work played an important role in one’s commit-    Pelorina, Faculty Researcher of the College of
             ment to research and that workload should not     Arts and Sciences, discussed how to write the
             be  a  hindrance.  She  further  mentioned  that  by   review of related literature and the methodolo-
             the  year  2025,  innovation  would  be  the  main   gy  portion  of  a  research  proposal.  He  talked
             focus of the University. The importance of re-    about the most common sources available for
             search  was  personal  satisfaction,  points  in  the   (Continued on next page)
             NBC evaluation, additional income, networking
             and  collaboration,  and  travel.  She  encouraged
             interdisciplinary research.
                  Dr.  Ilagan  also  tackled  the  different  the-
             matic areas of the research and extension agenda
             of CvSU: agri-fisheries and food security, biodi-
             versity  and  environmental  conservation,  smart
             engineering, ICT and industrial competitiveness,
             public health and welfare, and societal develop-
             ment and equality. She also talked about the of-]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[PAGE 9                                                                                      INFO-D


             T3 Campuses faculty… From p. 8                    portion of the research would answer questions
                                                               on how the data should be collected or gener-
                                                               ated and then analyzed, and clearly articulated
             use in a researcher’s review of related literature.   the reasons why a researcher would choose a
             He  emphasized  the  importance  of  reading  and   particular procedure or technique.
             mobility, spending time going over various ref-        Dr. Francisco further stated that this sec-
             erences and going to different places in order to   tion  specifically  featured  how  the  data  gath-
             find  relevant  material  for  one’s  research.  He   ered should be treated in order to achieve the
             said  that  the  best  materials  were  those  articles   objectives  of  the  research.  It  also  discussed
             published within the last five years, on a case-to  problems  that  were anticipated and  how  they
             -case basis, depending on the field. Non-referred  could be minimized through the chosen meth-
             (i.e.,  not  peer-reviewed)  journals,  newsletters,   ods. For her, this was very important because
             and  magazines  were  considered  unreliable      the method a researcher chose affected the re-
             sources  of  literature.  He  stated  that  the  most   sults.  Thus,  “an  unreliable  method  produced
             common  problem  in  research  was  the  lack  of   unreliable  results.”  A  faulty  methodology
             available literature. When literature was limited,   could bring about a “domino effect,” affecting
             he said, a researcher may conduct field work or   all other aspects of the research and lessening
             interviews  to  determine  whether  the  topic  was   the value of one’s findings.
             worth  pursuing;  if  not,  then  the  researcher      Dr. Francisco further elaborated the im-
             should  consider  changing  the  topic.  He  also   portant  sections  of  the  methodology  section:
             highlighted  several  key  points  such  as  always   the  research  design  (whether  quantitative  or
             thinking of what one’s research could contribute   qualitative, including the specific type or types
                                                               to be used), the sampling technique (how the
                                                               data will be collected and what safeguard tech-
                                                               niques  will  be  used),  the  respondents/
                                                               participants or source/corpus for those studies
                                                               involving discourse (who will participate and
                                                               how many) the research instrument, the unit of
                                                               analysis  (for  coding  in  discourse),  the  data
                                                               gathering procedure, and the data analysis por-
                                                               tion.  She  emphasized  the  importance  of  ano-
                                                               nymity in this section, especially for respond-
                                                               ents  who  had  already  been  interviewed,  and
                                                               other  agencies  involved  in  the  data-gathering
                                                               portion.
                                                                    Moreover, Dr.  Francisco further recom-
                                                               mended  that  30%  of  the  existing  population
                                                               was enough for a qualitative research and 8-10
                                                               respondents  for  a  qualitative  one  in  order  to
                                                               ensure that the chosen sample was a good rep-
                                                               resentative  of  the  population,  with  the  inclu-
                                                               sion of corresponding profiles and justification
             Dr. Isaias A. Banaag, Faculty Researcher of the College of   for  being  selected.  She  reminded  everyone
             Education (CED), explains the importance of  constructs   about  the  importance  of  pre-testing  for  self-
                                                               made  instruments  and  to  make  sure  that  the
                                                               tool  specifically  addressed  the  objectives  and
             to  the  field  and  avoiding  duplication  in  order   problem of the research.
                                                                    Other reminders given by Dr. Francisco

             “locate one’s research within the context of ex-  were regarding the use of free, prior-informed
             isting literature.” He further said that a literature   consent (FPIC) or waivers for sensitive topics
             review could be arranged either chronologically   with ethical issues involved and avoiding the
             or  thematically,  and  that  citation  provide  evi-  unnecessary inclusion of definitions.
             dence  of  the  researcher’s  interpretation  of  the      Overall, Dr. Francisco recommended the
             sources gathered. Being selective was very im-    following components of an effectively written
             portant, in that the researcher must choose only   methodology  section:  a  clear  methodological
             the most important points to be included in the   approach,  a  justification  for  how  the  chosen
             review.                                           approach  would  fit  the  research  design,  the
                  Dr. Pelorina said that caution must be ex-   specific  methods  to  be  used,  the  manner  in
             ercised when paraphrasing to avoid plagiarism.    which the data would be analyzed, a solid ra-
             It was also important to keep one’s “voice” and   tionale  for  the  methodologies  to  be  used,  a
             restrain oneself from being a collection of dif-  well-supported  reason  for  the  choice  of  re-
             ferent  authors’  voices  despite  the  fact  that  the   spondents,  and  a  comprehensive  yet  concise
             review  should  definitely  include  the  “big    scope and limitations section.
             names” or experts on the field. The review must        The  fourth  speaker,  Dr.  Agnes  B.  Al-
             be  punctuated  with  one’s  own  perspective  and   imboyuguen,  Faculty  Researcher  of  the  Col-
             interpretation of the new knowledge presented.    lege of Arts and Sciences, talked about meth-
                  Furthermore,  Dr.  Pelorina  also  discussed   ods  and  methodology  in  the  field  of  natural
             common mistakes such as not relating clearly to   sciences. (Continued on next page)
             the research problem, not taking sufficient time
             to identify the most relevant sources to use, not
             relying  on  primary  research  studies,  and  only
             including  sources  that  validated  one’s  assump-
             tions rather than those that refuted them.
                  For the fourth speaker, Dr. Agnes C. Fran-
             cisco, Faculty Researcher of the College of Arts
             and Sciences, talked about methods and method-
             ology  in  the  field  of  social  sciences.  She  first
             distinguished a method, a technical step taken to
             do research, from the methodology, a discussion
             of the underlying reason why particular methods
             would  be  used.  She  said  that  the  methodology]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[PAGE 10                                                                                     INFO-D



             T3 Campuses faculty… From p. 9                    building  seminar:  the  budgetary  requirements
                                                               and  work  plan,  the  major  activities  and  ex-
                                                               pected  output,  and  the  potential  impact  and
             This area described the activities necessary for   target beneficiaries of the given research.
             the  completion  of  a  project,  mainly  because  it      Ms.  Roncesvalle  J.  Caipang,  T3  Re-
             provided information that allowed the reader to   search Coordinator who spearheaded and orga-
             validate the results and the conclusion. She said   nized the capability building seminar, gave her
             that  some  key  requirements  of  a  good  natural   closing remarks by thanking everyone for their
             science  research  were  the  following:  under-  attendance and for a very productive day. Af-
             standable  and  repeatable,  conforms  to  objec-  terwards, Prof. Sedigo announced that on April
             tives, and confined to the procedures and meth-   1-2, he would be evaluating all proposals be-
             ods.                                              fore endorsing them to the Research Center on
                  Dr.  Alimboyuguen  further  said  that there   April 3, 2019, not later than 6:00 p.m. All re-
             were specific details to be included such as the   search titles were then submitted by the faculty
             manufacturer or model of the specialized equip-   members  who  no  doubt  became  inspired  and
             ment to be used, the sample to be used, time and   motivated at the end of the two-day capability-
             place, replications, and conditions of the experi-  building seminar.
             ment, data analysis, statistical analysis. She con-
             cluded  her  talk  by  emphasizing  that  research





                                                               T3 Campus holds meeting

                                                               in preparation for 2019

                                                               AACUP visit


















             Dr. Agnes C. Francisco, Faculty Researcher of the Col-  T3 Campus Administrator Noel A. Sedigo discusses the
             lege of Arts and Sciences, talks about the key components   goals of the different programs of the three campuses
             of writing an effective methodology section              A  faculty  and  staff  meeting  was  held
             impact,  academic  consequences,  and  societal   on March 4, 2019 at the Trece Martires City
             consequences  were  three  major  considerations   Campus Reading Room to discuss the upcom-
             in research in the natural sciences. The value of   ing Accrediting Agency of Chartered Colleges
             one’s research in terms of its long-term benefits   and  Universities  in the  Philippines  (AACUP)
             was what counted, essentially.                    visit next semester.
                  For  Dr.  Alimboyuguen,  the  beneficiaries         The  meeting  included  discussions  of
             should be the students, faculty and staff, farm-  plans in preparation for the Preliminary Survey
             ers, government and private institutions, indus-  Visit (PSV) of the Internal Assessment Body
             try  and  other  clientele  outside  the  CvSU  com-  (IAB), the accreditors from Cavite State Uni-
             munity.  Publishable  and  patentable  work  was
             what they were looking for in this field. Impact   versity, for evaluation of the IT Program, and
                                                               for  Level  1  Accreditation  of  the  Business
             assessment  was  no  longer  the  measure  of  suc-
             cess in research but whether there was a policy   Management Program and the Secondary Edu-
                                                               cation Program this coming September 16 and
             that was developed out of the research. She en-   October 25. The AACUP visit is scheduled on
             couraged everyone to copyright their works.       November  25-29  this  upcoming  academic
                  Towards  the  end  of  Dr.  Alimboyuguen’s   school year 2019-2020.
             discussion, it was established, through the mod-
             eratorship of Prof. Sedigo, that the T3 Campuses
             should focus on these specific programs: Infor-
             mation and  Computer  Technology  (ICT),  Edu-
             cation,         Business          Management                      T3 Newsletter
             (Entrepreneurship),  Hospitality  Management                  2nd Semester AY 2018-2019
             (Product Development).                                Editing/Layout:   Suzette A. Quesada-Magano, Ph.D.
                  Further discussions on the following top-           Writers: Suzette A. Quesada-Magano, Ph.D.
             ics  ensued  throughout  the  faculty  capability-               Martin Rigor B. Magano, R.N.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Sample Flyers to Disseminate Research Outputs]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE

                                                                                                                                        UNIVERSITY

                                                                                                                                          Tanza Campus































                                                                         Extension Services Unit
                                                                          Cavite State University
                                                                              Tanza Campus
                                                                            Tanza, Cavite 4108
                                                                                Philippines
                                                                         Tel No. (046) 414—3979
                                                                       Email:cvsutanza@cvsu.edu.ph]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE

                                                    UNIVERSITY

                                                      Tanza Campus































 Extension Services Unit
 Cavite State University
 Tanza Campus
 Tanza, Cavite 4108
 Philippines
 Tel No. (046) 414—3979
 Email:cvsutanza@cvsu.edu.ph]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[UNIVERSITY VISION

             The premier University in historic Cavite recognized for
          excellence  in  the  development  of  globally  competitive  and
          morally upright individuals.

                                                                              agtas ay    asenso at      iginhawa kung      ayo    y    ama-sama
                                UNIVERSITY MISSION
               Cavite  State  University  shall  provide  excellent,
           equitable  and  relevant  educational  opportunities  in
           the  arts,  sciences  and  technology  through  quality
           instruction  and  responsive  research  and  develop-
           ment activities. It shall produce professional, skilled
           and  morally  upright  individuals  for  global  competi-
           tiveness.


                                  QUALITY POLICY

                                                                     This  program  aims  to  promote  and  en-
                We Commit to the highest standards of education,   hance  the  use  of  technology  tools,  espe-  This  program’s  main  objective  is  to  appreciate
            value  our  stakeholders, Strive  for  continual  improve-  cially the use of MS Office applications and   the importance of literacy and numeracy among
            ment of our products and services, Uphold the Univer-  their benefits and utilize  skills for employ-  the participants, thereby persuading them to en-
            sity’s  tenets  of  Truth,  Excellence  and  Service  to  pro-  ment  and  small  time  business  opportuni-  roll in a formal school.
            duce globally competitive and morally upright individu-  ties.
            als.



                                   EXTENSION SERVICES VISION


                Alleviating the standard of living of the economically
            and socially disadvantaged sectors of society.



                                   EXTENSION SERVICES MISSION


               To engage in the improvement of the quality of life   This   program’s
           of farmers/fishers folks, women, out-of-school youths,
           local  government  employees,  and  other  clients   main  objective  is
           through  the  conduct  of  relevant  education  and  train-  to  inculcate  the
           ing; farm and business advisory services; demonstra-
           tion  services;  and  information  communication  and   importance   of
           technology services.                               health  and  well-                              This program aims to educate the participants
                                                              ness  among  the                           on how to start a small business through series
                                                              participants.                              of training on food processing and other innova-
                                                                                                         tive products that could help them generate addi-
                                                                                                         tional income.]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[UNIVERSITY VISION

 The premier University in historic Cavite recognized for
 excellence  in  the  development  of  globally  competitive  and
 morally upright individuals.

 agtas ay   asenso at   iginhawa kung   ayo    y    ama-sama
                     UNIVERSITY MISSION
 Cavite  State  University  shall  provide  excellent,
 equitable  and  relevant  educational  opportunities  in
 the  arts,  sciences  and  technology  through  quality
 instruction  and  responsive  research  and  develop-
 ment activities. It shall produce professional, skilled
 and  morally  upright  individuals  for  global  competi-
 tiveness.


                     QUALITY POLICY

       This  program  aims  to  promote  and  en-
 We Commit to the highest standards of education,   hance  the  use  of  technology  tools,  espe-  This  program’s  main  objective  is  to  appreciate
 value  our  stakeholders, Strive  for  continual  improve-  cially the use of MS Office applications and   the importance of literacy and numeracy among
 ment of our products and services, Uphold the Univer-  their benefits and utilize  skills for employ-  the participants, thereby persuading them to en-
 sity’s  tenets  of  Truth,  Excellence  and  Service  to  pro-  ment  and  small  time  business  opportuni-  roll in a formal school.
 duce globally competitive and morally upright individu-  ties.
 als.



                     EXTENSION SERVICES VISION


 Alleviating the standard of living of the economically
 and socially disadvantaged sectors of society.



                     EXTENSION SERVICES MISSION


 To engage in the improvement of the quality of life   This   program’s
 of farmers/fishers folks, women, out-of-school youths,
 local  government  employees,  and  other  clients   main  objective  is
 through  the  conduct  of  relevant  education  and  train-  to  inculcate  the
 ing; farm and business advisory services; demonstra-
 tion  services;  and  information  communication  and   importance   of
 technology services.   health  and  well-        This program aims to educate the participants
 ness  among  the   on how to start a small business through series
 participants.      of training on food processing and other innova-
                    tive products that could help them generate addi-
                    tional income.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Use of Social Media, Exhibits, and TV Ads

                                to Disseminate Research Outputs]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Appendix figure 1. Facebook page of Gourmet de Tanza





















                                     Appendix figure 2. Gourmet de Tanza’s products]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Appendix figure 3. The business proponents during their product exhibit
























                  Appendix figure 4. The business proponents during their production of gourmet products]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Appendix figure 5. Customer of Gourmet de Tanza























                                   Appendix figure 6. Customers of Gourmet de Tanza]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Appendix figure 7. Ms. Compuesto during her cooking demo for Umagang Kay Ganda
























               Appendix figure 8. The proponents during while closing their bank accounts in AllBank]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                     CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                              Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                      235-7997 ǀ 410-5247 ǀ 437-0693
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                           DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT

                       Accomplishment Report for Entrepreneurial Development Project (EDP)

                                           Second Semester, AY 2019 – 2020


                Name of Student(s)  :  RINA D. COMPUESTO
                                         MARVIN G. HOBANIL
                                         JENNY V. COMODAS
                                         JENELYN R. RELADO

                Name of Business      :  GOURMET DE TANZA



               I. SHORT BACKGROUND / DESCRIPTION OF THE STUDY

                       Gourmet is a cultural idea associated with the culinary arts of fine food and drink which

               characterized  by  refined,  even  elaborate  preparations  and  presentations  of  aesthetically

               balanced meals of several contrasting, often quite rich courses. Historically, the ingredients


               used in the meal tended to be rare for the region, which would also be impacted by the local

               state and religious customs. The term and its associated practices are usually used positively

               to  describe  the  people  of  refined  taste  and  passion.  Gourmet  food  tends  to  be  served  in

               smaller, more expensive portions. There are also cross-cultural interactions when it comes to

               gourmet that introduced new ingredients, materials and practices.

                       Gourmet  de  Tanza  is  in  a  partnership  form  of  business.  It  is  established  by  four

               business partners namely: Rina D. Compuesto, Jenny V. Comodas, Jenelyn R. Relado and


               Marvin G. Hobanil, who agreed to contribute an equal amount of capital to start the venture.

                       Gourmet  de  Tanza  was  conceptualized  through  the  rich  seafood  produce  of  the

               Municipality of Tanza. The business offers variety of products such as Gourmet Alamang in

               pork adobo, spicy adobo, adobo tinapa and spicy adobo tinapa flavors and Gourmet Tinapa.

               The Municipality of Tanza is also known for its fresh alamang and tinapa production since]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[most of its barangay are part of coastal areas. The proponents came to an idea of utilizing

               these products into gourmet products as these are in-demand products and to add as one of

               the distinguished products in the Municipality. The business also aims to help the non-working

               women of Bagtas to have additional income by incorporating the procedure on how to make


               the products through the trainings that will be provided by the Extension Services of Cavite

               State University – Tanza Campus.

                       The proponents do not have a physical store. It is an online and direct selling business.

               During the operation, the members have no delivery charge. The production area is located

               in Carissa Homes, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite.


                       The target market of the product include the “pasalubong” centers, consumers who

               love gourmet products and other people who want to retail the products of Gourmet de Tanza.

               II. OBJECTIVES OF THE PROJECT

                       The  proponents  decided  to  conduct  an  entrepreneurial  development  project  to

               experience  how  to  handle  and  to  make  the  business  profitable  to  use  their  skills  and

               knowledge as a marketer.

                       Specifically, it aimed to:

                          1.  introduce and make gourmet products known to the market;

                          2.  learn the process in producing and selling gourmet products;

                          3.  determine the profitability and marketability of gourmet business; and

                          4.  identify  and  apply  necessary  solutions  to  the  problem  that  could  be

                              encountered during the operation of the business.]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[III. DETAILED ACCOMPLISHMENT REPORT

               Table 1. Accomplishment Report
                  TIME FRAME           ACTIONS TAKEN            ACCOMPLISHMENT             REMARKS
                                                                     / OUTPUT
                     Week 1        •  Opened a bank            •  The proponents           Completed
                 January 27 – 31,
                      2020             account in AllBank at       started their

                                       Vista Mall Tanza            business operation

                                   •  Canvassed possible           and has 300

                                       suppliers for the           orders.

                                       materials and

                                       ingredients needed for

                                       the product.


                                   •  Bought kitchen

                                       equipment and other

                                       materials to be used in

                                       the production

                                   •  Created Facebook


                                       page for online

                                       promotion and orders.

                     Week 2        •  Received 300 bottles     •  Delivered 300            Completed
                 February 3 – 7,
                      2020             orders from customers       bottles of Gourmet

                                       and retailers.              de Tanza products


                                   •  Ordered 300 bottles          and breakdown as

                                       from their supplier         follows:   52 bottles

                                   •  Bought the needed            of Gourmet

                                       ingredients from their      Alamang Adobo

                                       suppliers and started       flavor , 52 bottles

                                       the production.             Spicy Adobo]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[•  300 bottles were             flavor, 52 Bottles

                                       produced and packed         Adobo Tinapa ,54


                                       for delivery.               bottles of Spicy

                                                                   Adobo Tinapa, 45

                                                                   bottles of gourmet

                                                                   Bangus and 45

                                                                   bottles gourmet

                                                                   Galunggong



                     Week 3        •  Received 188 orders      •  188 bottles were         Completed
                  February 10 –
                     14, 2020          from customers and          produced and

                                       retailers.                  packed for

                                   •  Ordered 188 bottles          delivery.

                                       from their supplier


                                   •  Bought the needed

                                       ingredients from their

                                       suppliers and started

                                       the production.

                     Week 4        •  Delivered188 bottles     •  188 bottles of           Completed
                  February 17 –
                     21, 2020          to customers who            Gourmet Products

                                       ordered online.             were delivered

                                                                   and breakdown as

                                                                   follows: 46 bottles

                                                                   of Gourmet

                                                                   Alamang Adobo,

                                                                   50 bottles Spicy


                                                                   Adobo, 49 bottles

                                                                   Adobo Tinapa ,43]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[bottles of Spicy

                                                                   Adobo Tinapa.


                     Week 5        •  Looked for additional    •  Closed a deal with       Completed
                  February 24 –
                     28, 2020          suppliers for bottles       a new supplier and

                                       and sealers.                reseller.

                                   •  Made online              •  There are 488

                                       promotions for              bottles sold for the

                                       resellers.                  month of


                                   •  Conducted month-end          February.

                                       inventory

                                   •  Received 284 orders      •  284 bottles were         Completed
                     Week 6
                   March 2 – 6,        from customers and          produced and
                      2020
                                       retailers.                  packed for


                                   •  Ordered 188 bottles          delivery.

                                       from their supplier     •  Demonstrated the

                                   •  Bought the needed            procedure of

                                       ingredients from their      making Gourmet

                                       suppliers and started       De Tanza products


                                       the production.             to the viewers of

                                   •  Prepared for the live        Umagang Kay

                                       cooking demo for            Ganda.

                                       Umagang Kay Ganda,

                                       a morning segment of


                                       ABS-CBN.]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Week 7        •  Delivered 284 bottles    •  284 bottles of           Completed
                  March 9 – 13,
                      2020             to customers who            Gourmet Products

                 *Start of ECQ         ordered online.             were delivered


                                                                   and breakdown as

                                                                   follows: 74 bottles

                                                                   of Gourmet

                                                                   Alamang Adobo,

                                                                   90 bottles Spicy

                                                                   Adobo, 60 bottles


                                                                   Adobo Tinapa, 60

                                                                   bottles of Spicy

                                                                   Adobo Tinapa.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[IV. FINANCIAL ANALYSIS

                   1.  Projected Monthly Income

                   Table 2. Projected monthly income
                                                       GOURMET DE TANZA
                                                     STATEMENT OF INCOME
                                                For the third month ended March 2020
                                                              (In Peso)
                    Sales:

                           Gourmet Tinapa                                          12,600.00
                           Gourmet Alamang                                         54,560.00     67,160.00
                    Less: Cost of Goods Sold                                                     (28,490.00)

                    Gross Profit                                                                 38,670.00
                    Less: Operating Expense
                           Direct Supplies                                         21,550.00

                           Indirect Supplies                                       1,340.00
                           Advertising Expense                                     2,600.00
                           Transportation Expense                                  1,041.00

                           Utilities Expense                                       2,820.00
                    Total Operating Expense                                                      (29,351.00)

                    Net Income before Interest and Taxes                                         9,319.00

                   2.  Cost of Raw Materials
                    Table 3. Raw Materials Cost
                                                                                    AMOUNT
                                 PARTICULARS
                                                                                      (Php)
                    Direct materials                                                21,550.00


                    Indirect materials                                               1,340.00

                    Packaging Equipment                                              1,299.00


                    Kitchen Equipment                                                4,890.00


                                      TOTAL                                         19,115.75]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[3.  Operating Cost
                   Table 4. Operating Cost
                                                                                    AMOUNT
                                 PARTICULARS
                                                                                      (Php)
                    Advertising Expense                                              2,600.00


                    Utilities Expense                                                2,820.00

                    Transportation Expense                                           1,041.00



                                      TOTAL                                          6,461.00


                   4.  Net/Profit Loss

                    Table 5. Statement of changes in partner’s equity
                                                       GOURMET DE TANZA
                                        STATEMENT OF CHANGES IN PARTNERS’ EQUITY
                                                For the third month ended March 2020
                                                              (In Peso)
                                            Compuesto      Hobanil     Comodas       Relado           Total

                    Capital, January         10,000.00    10,000.00    10,000.00    10,000.00       40,000.00
                    2020

                    Add: Net Income           2,329.75     2,329.75    2,329.75     2,329.75        9,319.00

                    Capital, March 2020      10,239.75    10,239.75    10,239.75    10,239.75       49,319.00]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[V. INSIGHTS

                       Being an entrepreneur is really a hard task as they need to have business acumens in

               handling every aspect of operation and strategies on how to solve problem as it might affect

               their business. Aside from these, entrepreneur should have the necessary skill set in running


               their  enterprise  including  the  ability  to  work  with  their  business  partners  and  other

               stakeholders. During the start of their enterprise, the proponents were really nervous as they

               need to effectively and efficiently utilize their initial capital to avoid loss and to earn greater

               amount of money for 88 days. They studied well on how they will effectively manage their

               enterprise.  Using  some  online  platforms,  the  proponents  were  able  to  find  suppliers  and


               customers for their business. They used some social media platforms to sell their products as

               they decided to sell it online as their products has high online demand and they will save some

               financial resources intended for their physical store. During their first production, they were

               overwhelmed by the orders of their customers after they posted their products on their social

               media page. This made them realized that there were so much advantages of using some

               online platforms. After their first production, their realized some things that will help them on

               improving their products based from the suggestions and comments of their customers. Over-


               all,  the  comments  and  suggestions  of  their  customers  were  positive  but  they  need  to

               incorporate it to improve more their products.

                       The proponents were overwhelmed by the news that their products will be featured in

               Umagang Kay Ganda, a morning segment of one of the TV giant in the country which is ABS-

               CBN. After their exposure, there were so much inquiries and orders for their products that


               made them completely off-guarded. But because of their adviser, they were able to supply the

               needed demand for their products. The exposure also gave them the realization that they must

               strategize well on the logistics and distribution aspects of their business as they have orders

               outside Luzon and some part of Mindanao.

                       When there are more demands for their products, a global pandemic which is known

               as  COVID—19  affected  most  of  the  businesses  around  the  world  including  their  venture.

               These pandemic gave them some problems such as the increase on the price of materials]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[and ingredients used for their products, difficulty on the delivery of orders and materials used

               for making the products, and sudden decrease in orders as the business cannot commit to

               deliver the orders of their customers. But despite of the effect of COVID—19 in their business,

               they were able to sell some of their remaining stocks. They sell some of their products through


               an online shipping app where it will pick-up the products from their production and deliver to

               their customers. These courier are allowed by the government to operate to secure that online

               businesses will still operate during the pandemic.

                       Entrepreneurs were hit hard, but they are still fighting, and they are ready to get their

               doors open. Once stay-at-home restrictions are lifted, entrepreneurs plan to open immediately.


               However,  entrepreneurs  think  that  operation  will  return  to  normal  and  can  provide  to  the

               customers demand and even COVID until September or later they are adapting to the new

               normal and are ready to make the changes necessary to keep entrepreneurs and customers

               safe. They are willing and ready to institute what is needed to allow for a safe experience for

               customers and employees. This will include wearing gloves, masks, and social distancing.

               Hopefully they will get some relief before the fall.

                       The entrepreneurs realized that they should be creative on finding ways on how they


               will continue their business operation during the pandemic. Thus, this pandemic gave them a

               wide perspectives about their business and other businesses as well. For them, they need to

               prioritize on having back-up plans for this unexpected problems as this will really hit their

               business  to  the  point  of  bankruptcy.  Every  successful  business  should  remain  steadfast

               through their plans to avoid losses and retrench if needed but prioritizing their employees who


               were mostly affected by this pandemic.

                       As the business continue to operate, most of their customers were asking reduction in

               the price of their products. This made them realized that business is not only about gaining

               profit but it should become sensitive to the needs of their customers. They have decided to

               reduce the price of their products so that their customers can still buy their products.

                       Even  the  businesses  around  the  world  were  slightly  or  totally  impaired  by  this

               pandemic, this crisis taught the business community on how to find ways on how they will]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[continue  the  operation  of  their  businesses.  Most  of  the  businesses  were  realigning  their

               business operation online as most of their customers were staying at home and  giving so

               much time in using social media. This paved a way for an increase in sales of online products

               and other means of transporting their products. These were also used by the entrepreneurs


               to ensure that Gourmet de Tanza’s products are still available during the pandemic. Over-all,

               the entrepreneurs learned so much from this global crisis. They were able to find ways on

               securing the continuance of their business operation. As a matter of fact, they are motivated

               to continue this enterprise development project as this will help them to continue harnessing

               their business skills aside from its financial advantage.]]></page></pages></Search>