<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.1.            The College/Academic Unit implements


                        curriculum/program of study in


                        consonants with CHED Memo No. 27, s

                        2001, as follows:


                        I.1.1.         General Education    -   51 units]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                            Tanza Campus
                                                            (046) 414 – 3979
                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph

            Curriculum                   :      BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION
            Major                        :      Marketing Management
            No. of Years                 :      Four (4) Years
            Responsible Department       :      DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT (DOM)

                              COMPARISON OF PROPOSED CURRICULUM WITH CHED STANDARDS AND/OR
                                            MINIMUM REQUIREMENTS IN TERMS OF UNITS



                                                                                        UNITS
                                                               CHED Minimum              Existing Curriculum
                         COURSES
                                                             Standard (CMO 17,                   Units
                                                                   s.2017)
             General Education Courses                                36                          40
             Common Business and Management                            6                           9
             Education Courses
             Business Administration Core Courses                     24                          24
             Professional Major Courses                               24                          24
             Electives                                                12                          12
             Internship                                                6                           6
             Physical Education Courses                                8                           8
             National Service Training Program                         6                           6
                               TOTAL                                 122                          129






            Prepared by:


            RITCH M. BANATE
            Department Chairperson


            Noted:


            GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
            Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Form B

                                                      Republic of the Philippines
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                            Tanza Campus
                                                            (046) 414 – 3979
                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph

            Curriculum                   :      BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS MANAGEMENT
            Major                        :      Marketing Management
            No. of Years                 :      Four (4) Years
            Responsible Department       :      DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT (DOM)

                                                    BREAKDOWN OF COURSES

              COURSE                        COURSE TITLE                          LEC         LAB       CREDIT
                CODE                                                             HOURS       HOURS       UNITS
             I.   General Education Courses
             GNED 01       Art Appreciation                                         3           0           3
             GNED 02       Ethics                                                   3           0           3
             GNED 03       Mathematics in the Modern World                          3           0           3
             GNED 04       Mga Babasahin Hinggil sa Kasaysayan ng Pilipinas         3           0           3
             GNED 05       Purposive Communication                                  3           0           3
             GNED 06       Science Technology and Society                           3           0           3
             GNED 07       The Contemporary World                                   3           0           3
             GNED 08       Understanding the Self                                   3           0           3
             GNED 09       Life and Works of Rizal                                  3           0           3
             GNED 10       Gender and Society                                       3           0           3
             GNED 11       Kontekstwalisadong Komunikasyon sa Filipino              3           0           3
             GNED 12       Dalumat Ng/Sa Filipino                                   3           0           3
             GNED 14       Panitikang Panlipunan                                    3           0           3
             ORNT 1        Institutional Orientation                                1           0          (1)
                                          TOTAL                                                            40

             II.   Common Business and Management Education Courses
             BMGT 22       Quantitative Techniques in Business                      3           0           3
             BMGT 25       Operations Management                                    3           0           3
             BMGT 30       Strategic Management                                     3           0           3
                                          TOTAL                                                             9

        I.   III.      Core Courses
             BMGT 21       Basic Microeconomics                                     3           0           3
             BMGT 23       Human Resource Management                                3           0           3
             BMGT 24       Business Law (Obligations and Contracts                  3           0           3
             BMGT 26       International Trade and Agreements                       3           0           3
             BMGT 27       Good Governance and Social Responsibility                3           0           3
             BMGT 28       Taxation (Income and Taxation)                           3           0           3
             BMGT 29       Business Research                                        3           0           3
             BMGT 199      Practicum Integrated Learning (600 hours)                6           0           6
             BMGT 200a  Research/EDP Proposal                                       1           0           1
             BMGT 200b  Research/EDP Final Manuscript                               2           0           2
                                          TOTAL                                                            30]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Form B


             IV.    Professional Major Courses
             MKTG 50       Consumer Behavior                                        3           0           3
             MKTG 55       Market Research                                          3           0           3
             MKTG 60       Product Management                                       3           0           3
             MKTG 65       Retail Management                                        3           0           3
             MKTG 70       Advertising                                              3           0           3
             MKTG 75       Professional Salesmanship                                3           0           3
             MKTG 80       Marketing Management                                     3           0           3
             MKTG 85       Special Topics in Marketing Management                   3           0           3
                                          TOTAL                                                            24

             V.   Elective Courses
             MKTG 101      Distribution Management                                  3           0           3
             MKTG 106      International Marketing                                  3           0           3
             MKTG 111      E-Commerce and Internet Marketing                        3           0           3
             MKTG 116      Service Marketing                                        3           0           3
                                          TOTAL                                                            12

             VI.   Physical Education Courses
             FITT 1        Movement Enhancement                                     2           0           2
             FITT 2        Fitness Exercises                                        2           0           2
             FITT 3        Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness I         2           0           2
             FITT 4        Physical Activities towards Health and Fitness II        2           0           2
                                          TOTAL                                                             8

             VII.  National Service Training Program
             NSTP 1        CWTS / LTS / ROTC                                        3           0           3
             NSTP 2        CWTS / LTS / ROTC                                        3           0           3
                                          TOTAL                                                             6


                                                    TOTAL NUMBER OF UNITS                            129]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Form C


                                                  Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                        Tanza Campus
                                                        (046) 414 – 3979
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph

               Curriculum                   :      BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION
               Major                        :      Marketing Management
               No. of Years                 :      Four (4) Years
               Responsible Department       :      DEPARTMENT OF MANAGEMENT (DOM)

                                                COURSE DESCRIPTION



               I. GENERAL EDUCATION COURSES

                  COURSE          COURSE TITLE                          COURSE DESCRIPTION
                    CODE
                 GNED 01        Art Appreciation       Art  appreciation  is  a  three-unit  course  that  develops
                                                       students’ ability to appreciate, analyze and critique works of
                                                       art. Through interdisciplinary and multimodal approaches,
                                                       this course equips students with a broad knowledge of the
                                                       practical, historical, philosophical, and social relevance of
                                                       the  arts  to  hone  students’  ability  to  articulate  the
                                                       understanding  of  the  arts.  The  course  also  develops
                                                       students’  competency  in  researching  and  curating  art  as
                                                       well  as  conceptualizing,  mounting,  and  evaluating  art
                                                       productions.

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 02        Ethics                 Principles of ethical behavior in modern society at the level
                                                       of  the  person,  society  and  in  interaction  with  the
                                                       environment and other share resources.

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 03        Mathematics in the     This course deals with nature of mathematics, appreciation
                                Modern World           of its practical, intellectual, and aesthetic dimensions, and
                                                       application of mathematical tools in daily life. The course
                                                       begins with an introduction to the nature of mathematics as
                                                       an exploration of patterns (in nature and the environment)
                                                       and as an application of inductive and deductive reasoning.
                                                       By exploring these topics, students are encouraged to go
                                                       beyond the typical understanding of mathematics as merely
                                                       a set of formulas but as a source of aesthetics in patterns of
                                                       nature, for example, and a rich language in itself (and of
                                                       science) governed by logic and reasoning. The course then]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Form C


                                                       proceeds to survey ways in which mathematics provides a
                                                       tool for understanding and dealing with various aspects of
                                                       present-day  living,  such  as  managing  personal  finances,
                                                       making  social  choices,  appreciating  geometric  designs,
                                                       understanding  codes,  used  in  data  transmission  and
                                                       security, and dividing limited resources fairly. These aspects
                                                       will provide opportunities for actually doing mathematics in
                                                       a  broad  range  of  exercises  that  bring  out  the  various
                                                       dimensions of mathematics as a way of knowing, and test
                                                       the students’ understanding and capacity.
                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 04        Mga Babasahin          Sinusuri ng kurso ang kasaysayan ng Pilipinas mula sa iba’t
                                Hinggil sa             ibang  perspektiba  sa  pamamagitan  ng  pilìng  primaryang
                                Kasaysayan             batis na nagmula sa iba’t ibang disiplina at iba’t ibang genre.
                                                       Binibigyan ng oportunidad ang mga mag-aaral na masuri
                                                       ang  karanasan  ng  may-akda  at  mga  pangunahing
                                                       argumento,  mapaghambing  ang  iba’t-ibang  pananaw,
                                                       matukoy  kung  may  pagkiling,  at  masuri  ang  mga
                                                       ebidensiyang  inilatag  sa  dokumento.  Tatalakayin  sa  mga
                                                       diskusyon ang mga tradisyonal na paksa sa kasaysayan at
                                                       iba  pang  temang  interdisiplinaryo  na  magpapalalim  at
                                                       magpapalawak  sa  kanilang  pag-unawa  sa  kasaysayang
                                                       pampolitika,  pang-ekonomiya,  pangkultura,  panlipunan,
                                                       pang-agham,  at  panrelihiyon  ng  Pilipinas.  Binibigyan  ng
                                                       priyoridad ang pangunahing materyales na makatutulong sa
                                                       mga mag-aaral na mapaunlad ang kanilang kasanayan sa
                                                       pagsusuri  at  komunikasyon.  Sa  pagtatapos,  inaasahang
                                                       mapaunlad ang kamalayang pangkasaysayan at mapanuri
                                                       ng  mga  mag-aaral  upang  sila  ay  maging  mahusay,
                                                       madaling  maintindihan,  magkaroon  ng  malawak  na  pag-
                                                       iisip, at maging matapat at responsableng mamamayan.

                                                       Kasama  sa  kursong  ito  ang  mahahalagang  paksa  sa
                                                       Saligang-Batas ng Pilipinas, repormang panlupa, at sistema
                                                       ng buwis.

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 05        Purposive              Writing, speaking and presenting to different audiences and
                                Communication          for various purposes.

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 06        Science, Technology    The  course  deals  with  interactions  between  science  and
                                and Society            technology  and  social,  cultural,  political,  and  economic
                                                       contexts  that  shape  and  are  shaped  by  them.  This
                                                       interdisciplinary  course  engages  students  to  confront  the]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Form C


                                                       realities brought about by science and technology in society.
                                                       Such  realities  pervade  the  personal,  the  public,  and  the
                                                       global  aspects  of  our  living  and  are  integral  to  human
                                                       development.  Scientific  knowledge  and  technological
                                                       development  happen  in  the  context  of  society  with  all  its
                                                       socio-political,  cultural,  economic,  and  philosophical
                                                       underpinnings at play. This course seeks to instill reflective
                                                       knowledge in the students that they are able to live the good
                                                       life  and  display  ethical  decision  making  in  the  face  of
                                                       scientific  and  technological  advancement.  This  course
                                                       includes  mandatory  topics  on  climate  change  and
                                                       environmental awareness.
                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 07        The Contemporary       This course introduces students to the contemporary world
                                World                  by examining the multifaceted phenomenon of globalization.
                                                       Using  the  various  disciplines  of  the  social  sciences,  it
                                                       examines the economic, social, political, technological, and
                                                       other  transformations  that  have  created  an  increasing
                                                       awareness of the interconnectedness of peoples and places
                                                       around  the  globe.  To  this  end,  the  course  provides  an
                                                       overview  of  the  various  debates  in  global  governance,
                                                       development,  and  sustainability.  Beyond  exposing  the
                                                       student  to  the  world  outside  the  Philippines,  it  seeks  to
                                                       inculcate  a  sense  of  global  citizenship  and  global  ethical
                                                       responsibility.

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 08        Understanding the      Nature  of  identity;  factors  and  forces  that  affect  the
                                Self                   development and maintenance of personal identity.

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 09        Rizal’s Life and       Sang-ayon sa ipinag-uutos ng Batas Republika 1425, sákop
                                Works                  ng  kursong  ito  ang  búhay  at  mga  akda  ng  pambansang
                                                       bayani ng bansa, si Jose Rizal. Ilan sa mga paksang sákop
                                                       ay ang talambuhay ni Rizal at kaniyang mga isinulat, lalo na
                                                       ang mga nobela niyang Noli me tangere at El filibusterismo,
                                                       ilang mga sanaysay, at iba‟t ibang liham.

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       GNED 04
                 GNED 10        Gender and Society     Gender  as  a  social  construction,  its  role  and  impact  on
                                                       different facets of societal life.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Form C


                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 11        Kontekstwalisadong     Ang KOMFIL ay isang praktikal na kursong nagpapalawak
                                Komunikasyon sa        at  nagpapalalim  sa  kontekstwalisadong  komunikasyon  sa
                                Filipino               wikang  Filipino  ng  mga  mamamayang  Pilipino  sa
                                                       kanikanilang  mga  komunidad  sa  particular,  at  sa  buong
                                                       lipunang Pilipino sa pangkalahatan. Nakatuon ang kursong
                                                       ito sa makrokasanayang pakikinig at pagsasalita, gayundin
                                                       sa  kasanayan  sa  paggamit  ng  iba’t  ibang  tradisyonal  at
                                                       modernong midya na makabuluha sa kontekstong Pilipino
                                                       sa iba’t-ibang antas sa larangan.
                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 GNED 12        Dalumat Ng/Sa          Isang maagwat na kursong nagpapalawak at nagpapalalim
                                Filipino               sa kasanayan sa malalim at mapanuring pagbasa, pagsulat,
                                                       at pananaliksik sa wikang Filipino sa iba’t ibang larangan,
                                                       sa  konteksto  ng  kontemporaryong  sitwasyon  at  mga
                                                       pangangailanagan ng bansa at ng

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       GNED 11
                 GNED 14        Panitikang             Isang kurso sa pag-aaral at paglikha ng panitikang  Filipino
                                Panlipunan             na  nakatuon  sa  kabuluhang  panlipunan  ng mga  tekstong
                                                       literari  sa  iba’t-ibang  bahagi  ng  kasaysayan  ng  bansang
                                                       Pilipinas.  Sinasaklaw  nito  ang  mga  isyung  panlipunan  na
                                                       tinatalakay  ng  mga  akdang  Filipino  tulad  ng  kahirapan,
                                                       malawak na agwat ng mayayaman at mahirap, reporma sa
                                                       lupa, globalisason, pagsasamantala sa mga manggagawa,
                                                       karapatang  pantao,  isyung  pangkasarian,  sitwasyon  ng
                                                       mga pangkat minorya at/omarhinalisado, at iba pa.

                                                       Credit         :      3 units
                                                       Lecture               3 hours/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none
                 CvSU 101       Institutional          Basic information of the University including vision, mission
                                Orientation            and  objectives,  program  offerings,  academic  policies  and
                                                       guidelines,  classroom  management  and  student  norm  of
                                                       conduct.

                                                       Credit         :      (1) unit
                                                       Lecture               1 hour/week
                                                       Laboratory     :      0 hour/week
                                                       Prerequisite  :       none]]></page></pages></Search>