<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="20"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[AREA IV












                           SUPPORT TO






                                STUDENTS]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[PARAMETER E












                               RESEARCH,





            MONITORING AND






                           EVALUATION]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[OUTCOME/S]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[O.1.            Research outputs are presented and


                        published.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                       CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                  Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                        Indang, Cavite
                                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph

                         OFFICE OF THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH AND EXTENSION

                                               RESEARCH CENTER

               April 22, 2021


               PROF. MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Faculty Researcher
               Tanza Campus
               This University


               Dear Prof. Saquin:

               The Research Center will conduct a Research Proposal Presentation on April 27, 2021 via
               Cisco Webex.

               In  this  regard,  may  we  invite  you  to  present  your  research  proposal  entitled  “Workplace
               Performance of CvSU-Tanza Graduates: Inputs to Curriculum Development”.

               During the presentation, only a maximum of 10 slides  will be allowed to  include Rationale,
               Objectives, Summary of Methodology, Expected Outputs (6Ps), Workplan and LIB. Ten (10)
               minutes will be allotted for presentation and ten (10) minutes for question and answer.

               Kindly  submit  your  PowerPoint  Presentation  to  cvsurcmande@cvsu.edu.ph  on  or  before
               April 26, 2021. Mechanics of presentation, program of activities and Cisco Webex link shall be
               sent to all not later than April 23, 2021.

               Should you have any queries, please contact us thru mobile number 09069453267.

               Thank you


               Sincerely,



               KHAY B. ARANDIA
               Head, Monitoring and Evaluation Division



               Noted:



               MIRIAM D. BALTAZAR
               Director]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                           Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                     (046) 862-1654
                                                       cvsu.edu.ph


                                               Ethics Review Board
                                      Short Description of the Research Proposal

        Study                    Research Proposal Titles                     Exempted        For        For
         No.                                                                      For      Expedited     Full
                                                                               Review       Review     Review
                Title:
                Workplace Performance of CvSU-Tanza Graduates:
                Inputs to Curriculum Development

                Background:
                        Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus,  being  a
                primary  tertiary  education  in  the  municipality  of  Tanza,
                Cavite,  aims  to  ensure  that  graduates of  the  campus  have
                extensive  education  and  training  for  them  to  be  equipped
                with  competencies,  knowledge  and  skills  in  their  field  of
                study  and  be  prepared  to  become  part  of  their  chosen
                industry.  In order for the campus to monitor its graduates on
                a  periodic  basis,  the  conduct  of  tracer  study  is  necessary.
                Hence,  a  graduate  tracer  study  is  being  proposed  to
                determine  the  workplace  performance  of  CvSU  –  Tanza
                Campus  graduates.  Consequently,  the  study  could  provide
                insights  about  the  level  of  workplace  preparedness  and
                attitude  of  its  graduates  as  well  as  the  employers’
                satisfaction on the workplace performance and attitudes. In
                addition,  the  study  will  also  determine  the  relevance  and
                responsiveness  of  CvSU  –  TC  curricular  programs  to  the
                needs  of  the  industry  based  on  its  graduates’  quality  of
                performance. Moreover, the results of the findings will serve
                as  significant  inputs  to  the  curriculum  development  of  the
                University  to  meet  local  and  global  demands  for  a  highly
                skilled labor force.

                Objectives:
                Level of Workplace Preparedness and Attitudes of  CvSU –
                Tanza  Graduates

                1.  Determine  the  profile  of  CvSU  –  Tanza  graduates  in
                    terms of:
                     a. age;
                     b. sex;
                     c.  civil status;
                     d. educational attainment;
                     e. status of employment;
                     f.  nature of employment;
                     g. area of employment;
                     h. job title;
                     i.  monthly income;
                2. Determine the level of workplace preparedness in terms of]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[following competencies, as perceived by the graduates:
                     a.  Effective Communication Skills;
                     b.  Self-awareness;
                     c.  Critical Thinking Skills;
                     d.  Data Analyzing Skills and Use of Technology;
                     e.  Problem Solving;
                     f.  Working Effectively with others;
                     g.  Initiative and Enterprise Development;
                     h.  Self-management;
                     i.  Social responsibility;
                     j.  Professionalism;
                3. Determine the level of attitudes of graduates towards their
                    workplace; and
                 4.  Identify  competencies  and  attitudes  that  needs  to  be
                    included/enhanced  in  the  curriculum,  based  on  the
                    findings.

                Employers’ Satisfaction on the Workplace Performance and
                Attitudes of CvSU -Tanza Graduates

                1.  Determine the organization's profile in terms of:
                    a. nature of organization;
                    b. location;
                    c.  size;
                2.   Determine  the  employer's  satisfaction  on  the  quality  of
                    workplace  performance  of  CvSU-Tanza  graduates  in
                    terms of:
                     a. effective communication skills;
                     b. self-awareness;
                     c.  critical thinking skills;
                     d. data analyzing skills and use of technology;
                     e. problem solving;
                     f.  working effectively with others;
                     g. initiative and enterprise development;
                     h. self-management;
                     i.  social responsibility;
                     j.  professionalism; and
                3. Determine  the  employer's  satisfaction  on  the  attitude
                   towards work of CvSU-Tanza graduates.

                Employers’ Perceived Quality of Workplace Performance of
                CvSU     –    Tanza    Graduates    and    Relevance    and
                Responsiveness of Curricular Programs to Industry Needs

                1. Characterize CvSU-Tanza graduates’ workplace
                   performance as perceived by employers in terms of:
                    a.  Effective Communication Skills;
                    b.  Self-awareness;
                    c.  Critical Thinking Skills;
                    d.  Data Analyzing Skills and Use of Technology;
                    e.  Problem Solving;
                    f.  Working Effectively with others;
                    g.  Initiative and Enterprise Development;
                    h.  Self-management;
                    i.  Social responsibility;
                    j.  Professionalism; and]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[2. Determine the relevance and responsiveness of curricular
                   programs as perceived by CvSU – Tanza Graduates and
                   their respective employers in terms of:
                    a. attainment of program objectives;
                    b. adequacy of quality training in preparing students;
                    c.  adequacy of course experience;

                3.  Determine the level of attainment of CvSU-Tanza
                    curricular program objectives based on the employers’
                    perception of CvSU-Tanza graduates’ workplace
                    performance; and

                4.  Recommend intervention activities to improve curricular
                    programs based on graduates’ and employer’s feedback.


                Research Paradigm:
















                Methodology:

                Research Design
                        The study will use quantitative research in determining
                the workplace performance of the graduates.

                Population and Sampling
                     A total of 217 graduates will be considered in this study
                as  well  as  their  respective  employers.  The  study  will  use
                complete enumeration sampling technique.

                Participants
                       Participants  of  the  study  includes  graduates  of  CvSU-
                Tanza, from 2016-2020, and their respective employers.

                Ethical Consideration
                        Informed consent will be distributed to the participants
                prior to their participation to the study.  To protect their basic
                rights, privacy, and confidentiality, all direct identifiers will be
                removed.  This  is  an  important  step  that  none  of  the
                participants  will  be  recognizable.    Data  will  be  filed  in
                separate secure locations to protect all  participants against
                indirect identification.  Pseudonyms will also be used in the
                discussion of results.

                Instrument/s
                     There  will  be  two  questionnaires  to  be  used  in  this
                study.  The first questionnaire, The Workplace Preparedness]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[and Attitudes Inventory (please see Appendix 1), has three
                parts and will be answered by the CvSU TC Graduates.  The
                first part will determine the profile of CvSU TC graduates as
                to their status, nature and area of employment.  The second
                part  is  expected  to  determine  the  level  of  workplace
                preparedness  and  attitudes  of  CvSU-TC  Graduates.    This
                was  adapted  from  the  Employability  Skills  Framework  by
                Jackson,  D.,  Sibson,  R.  &  Riebe,  L.  (2013).  The  third  part
                determines the graduates’ workplace attitudes using the ten
                personal  qualities  of  employees  adapted  from  the  study  of
                Plantilla in 2017.The fourth part determines their perception
                of relevance and responsiveness of their curricular program
                to their current employment.
                      The second questionnaire, The Employer’s Feedback
                (please see Appendix 2), is intended for the employers of the
                CvSU-TC  Graduates.    It  has  three  parts.    The  first  part
                contains information relative to the employer’s profile.  The
                second  questionnaire  determines  their  perception  and
                satisfaction  towards  quality  of  workplace  performance  of
                CvSU  TC  graduates  who  were  employed  in  their
                organization which was also adapted from the Employability
                Skills  Framework  (Jackson,  et.al,  2013).      The  third  part
                determines     their   perception    of    relevance    and
                responsiveness of the CvSU-TC curricular programs based
                on the workplace performance of the latter’s graduates.

                Data Gathering Procedure:
                        Prior to the actual distribution of the instrument, the
                 developed  questionnaire  will  be  pre-tested  to  selected
                 graduating  students  and  some  organization  leaders  who
                 were  not  part  of  the  study  to  determine  its  validity  and
                 reliability.  Once validity and reliability are established, this
                 will  be  sent  to  the  graduates  and  their  employers.
                 Simultaneously,  each  graduate  will  be  contacted  through
                 any communication forms available such as, but not limited
                 to, texts, social media sites, and emails.  An online form (or
                 a  mobile  application)  of  these  questionnaires  will  be
                 prepared  to  reduce  the  cost  of  transportation  and
                 reproduction of research instruments.

                Data/Statistical Analysis
                        The  developed  questionnaires  will  be  subjected  to
                 validation  by  some  experts  in  the  field.    Cohen’s  Kappa
                 coefficient will be used to measure the inter-rater reliability
                 or  agreement  between  two  or  more  experts  to  assess  the
                 validity of these documents.  On the other hand, Cronbach’s
                 alpha will be used to determine the internal consistency of
                 the  constructs  used  in  the  survey  when  answered  by  a
                 group of participants.
                        All  data  to  be  gathered  will  be  tabulated  and
                 analyzed accordingly.  Descriptive statistics such as, but not
                 limited  to,  frequency  counts,  ranks,  means,  and
                 percentages, will be used to describe the primary data that
                 will  be  collected  among  the  graduates  and  employers.
                 Likert  scales  will  be  used  to  describe  the  variables  in  this
                 study.  Furthermore, correlation tests will be used to explore
                 relationships  among  the  variables  involved  in  this  study.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[The data will be analyzed using the Statistical Packages for
                 Social Sciences v. 22.
                Weighted means will be computed based on the participants’
                responses and will be converted accordingly.

                Tools for Gathering Data i.e. interview schedule, scale,
                inventory, and the like
                The study will use survey questionnaires in gathering the
                data from the graduates and employers.

                In addition, a set of criteria for evaluating the proposed
                graduate tracing mobile application will also be used.


               Student Researcher/s


               MELONA I. SAQUIN                RITCH M. BANATE                DEBBIE ROSE T. BANAG
               Name and Signature              Name and Signature             Name and Signature




               JOYCE ERIKA S. SENARIS          GIL D. RAMOS                   MARY ROSE E. ELAMPARO
               Name and Signature              Name and Signature             Name and Signature




               MARK JOEL C. SIBULO
               Name and Signature





               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN            GERRY MAE T. SI/VERO           MARY JOY ANGELIQUE R. MOJICA
               Name and Signature              Name and  Signature            Name and Signature



               CHARMAINE T. BANAG              JEFFREY F. DELGADO             ERIKA PRECIA
               Name and Signature              Name and Signature             Name and Signature




               Screened by:


               DR. BERNADETTE A. SAPINOSO
                                  Chair]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                              CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                           Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                     Indang, Cavite
                                                    (046) 862-1654
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


               Form 03. Informed Consent Approval Sheet

                                                          Title:
               Workplace Performance of CvSU-Tanza Graduates: Inputs to Curriculum Development


               Description of the research and your participation
                       The  research  aims  to  determine  the  workplace  performance  of  the  graduates  of
               CvSU-Tanza. Data gathered will be used as basis in developing inputs to improve curricular
               programs.

               Participants
                       Participants of the study  includes graduates of CvSU-Tanza, from 2016-2020, and
               their respective employers.

               Risks and discomforts
                       In  accomplishing  the  survey  form,  you will  be  asked  to  share  information  that you
               may feel uncomfortable.  However, you may not answer any question if you do not wish to
               do so.  You would not be compelled to give any reason for not responding to any question.
               The researchers seek no other risks involve in their participation.

               Potential benefits
                       On the personal level, you may benefit from participating in the study by having an
               opportunity to reflect on the workplace performance of the graduates. This may also benefit
               the university and curriculum development unit in obtaining better understanding and
               improving the curriculum as a result of finding the answers to the research objectives.

               Utilization of the Results of this study
                       The  results  of  the  study  will  be  used  to  further  the  understanding  of  workplace
               performance  of  the  graduates.    The  information  derived  from  the  study  will  be  used  to
               recommend intervention activities to improve curricular programs based on graduates’ and
               employer’s feedback.

               Protection of confidentiality
                       Your participation in this study may draw attention and may be asked by others. It is
               the researchers’ utmost commitment to not share the information about you to anyone. Also
               the data that will be collected will be used solely to better understand this research endeavor
               alone. The data will be handled with utmost confidentiality and will be kept in private. Only
               the researchers will know the identity of each assigned code to the participants.

               Voluntary participation
                       Participation in the study is entirely voluntary.  You have the right to withdraw from
               participation whenever you uncomfortable with the situation even if you had agreed earlier.
               You may also request that the information provided be not used in the study.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Contact information (Contact Number of Proponent/s and ERB Chairman)

               MELONA I. SAQUIN  (046) 414 – 3979 / 0930-095-8194

               DR. BERNADETTE A. SAPINOSO (046) 862-1654


                                    A copy of this consent form should be given to you.

                                                        Consent

               I have read this consent form and have been given the opportunity to ask questions.


               I give my consent to participate in this study.


               Participant’s signature: ____________________________               Date:  ___________
               Contact number: _________________________________



               Principal Investigator’s signature: ___________________             Date:  ___________
                                 046 414 – 3979 / 0930-095-8194
               Contact number: ________________________________



               Approved:


               Name: __________________________
               Ethics Review Board Chair
               Contact number: __________]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Research center

          Research Proposal





                                                          review





















                                     APRIL 27, 2021

                                     8:00AM - 4:00PM
                                     via       Cisco webex]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Program of activities





         TIME


        8:00-8:15   Registration/webex log-in


        8:16AM   OPENING program

                 Invocation                          AVP

                 Welcome Remarks                      Dr. Miriam D. Baltazar
                                                     Director for Research
                                                     Dr. Melbourne R. Talactac
                 Inspirational Message               Vice President for Research and
                                                     Extension
                 Introduction of Evaluators

                 Guidelines/Reminders

        8:50AM   PRESENTATION OF RESEARCH PROPOSALS    (Breakout Sessions)
                                                     Moderators
                 Breakout Session 1: ICT and         Kris Rowell S. Garcia

                 Engineering
                                                     Mark Jayvee M. Mojica
                 Breakout Session 2: Agriculture

                 Breakout Session 3: Social Science   Antonette L. Magcamit

                 (Entrepreneurship)
                 Breakout Session 4: Social Science   Khay B. Arandia

                 (Psychology)
                 Breakout Session 5: Social Science
                 (Education, DRM, Sociology, Health     Rene R. Marasigan
                 Nursing and Anthropology)

        3:30PM   Closing program                      Dr. Miriam D. Baltazar
                                                     Director for Research


                                     Mr. Kris Rowell S. Garcia
                                        Master of Ceremony]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Program of activities




                         Breakout session 1: ICT and Engineering



       8:50-9:00   Development of Guidance and Counseling Decision      Jo Anne C. Nuestro, Marlon R. Perena,
      9:01-9:15*   Support System for Cavite State University   and Andy A. Dizon (CEIT)


               Development of eStudent Portfolio and Job Placement
       9:16-9:25   Application: An online platform used to predict and      Mildred T. Apostol and Anabella C.
      9:26-9:40*   measure employment graduates demand in Cavite State   Doctor (Imus Campus)
               University-Imus Campus thru Data Mining Approach

                                                         Jocelyn L. Reyes, Roselyn A. Ymana,
       9:41-9:50   Development of 2-in-one Mobile App  Reviewers in    Lemellu Nida L. Sarmiento, Rosemarie
               Licensure Exam for Teachers  and  Board Examination for
      9:51-10:05*   Psychometrician                      N. Pragacha, Joseph S. Callanta, and
                                                         Ethel R. Chua (Silang Campus)
      10:06-10:15                                        Ace Amiel E. Malicsi, Joy M. Peji, and
               Document Tracking System for Cavite State University
     10:16-10:30*                                        Lenard Paulo V. Tamayo (CEIT)
      10:31-10:40  Development of a Machine-Vision Based Multi-Crop
     10:41-10:55*  Feature Extractor                     Edwin R. Arboleda (CEIT)
       *Q and A


                                   Mr. Kris Rowell S. Garcia
                                         Moderator]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Program of activities




                             Breakout session 2: AGRICULTURE


                                                         Lynn G. Penales, Ma. Fatima B. Zuniga,
       8:50-9:00                                         Florence R. Jimenez, Evangelina B.
               Development of Cacao Pod Husk Processing Machines
      9:01-9:15*                                         Mora, Analyn A. Mojica, Ma. Corazon V.
                                                         Herrera, and Lani S. Rodis (CAS, CEIT)
                                                         Al Eugene L. Torres, Maowel A.
       9:16-9:25   Analysis of the Growth Response of Coffea canephora   Villanueva, Mark Jayvee M. Mojica, Ric
               Trees to Different Irrigation Water Supply Levels Using the
      9:26-9:40*                                         Karl T. Flores, Jonathan A.Flores
               IoT-based Automated Drip Irrigation System
                                                         (NCRDEC, RC)
                                                         Joan L. Fortuna, Shiela L. Vidallon, Maria
               Product Development, Acceptability and Marketability of
       9:41-9:50   Guyabano-Black Rice Grain Tea and Calamansi-Ginger-  Andrea C. Francia, Still John F. Reyes,
      9:51-10:05*  Pandan Concentrate: Immune System enhancers in this     Marvin D. Sibucao, Gretchen Macaranas,
               COVID-19 Pandemic                         Jocelyn B Siochi, Cristina M. Signo
                                                         (Carmona Campus)
                                                         Miriam D. Baltazar, Jermaine Marie Ann
      10:06-10:15  Leaf and Seed Characterization of Commercially-
                                                         O. Fabella, Maowel A. Villanueva (RC,
     10:16-10:30*  Cultivated Coffee in the Philippines   NCRDEC)
       *Q and A

                                  Mr. Mark Jayvee M. Mojica
                                         Moderator]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Program of activities




                  Breakout session 3: SOCIAL SCIENCE (Entrepreneurship)



       8:50-9:00   Womentrepreneurs: Rebuilding Female Owned Cocoa      Hermilina A. Mendoza, and Ma. Cristina
      9:01-9:15*   Enterprises in Upland Cavite in the New Normal   Bayla (Silang Campus)


                                                         John Joseph P. Villa, Ronalyn Garcia,
       9:16-9:25   Entrepreneurial Competencies and Skills of BS   Luisita A. Marzan, Baby Kharen Cristal,
               Entrepreneurship Students of Cavite State University-Imus
      9:26-9:40*   Campus                                Liane Vina G. Ocampo, Albert Teido
                                                         (Imus Campus)
       *Q and A


                                   Ms. Antonette L. Magcamit
                                          Moderator




                     Breakout session 4: SOCIAL SCIENCE (psychology)



                                                         Maria Andrea C. Francia, Carlo Emil B.
       8:50-9:00   Stress and Study Habits: Its Effects to Students' Academic   Mañabo, Cristina M. Signo Jocelyn B.
      9:01-9:15*   Performance in CvSU-Carmona Campus       Siochi, Regene B. Hernandez, and
                                                         Janine B. Bacosmo (Carmona Campus)

                                                         Louziela P. Masana, Keithlyn M. Baybay,
       9:16-9:25   An Assessment of the Effects of COVID-19 to Faculty and   Shaine C. Hayag, Florindo C. Ilagan,
      9:26-9:40*   Students: Basis for Intervention Programs      John Riel P. Labiang, and Efrelhet N.
                                                         Siarez (Gen. Trias Campus)

                                                         Jessie Anne T. Demetillo, Rosario B.
               Capabilities, Challenges and Coping Mechanisms Among
       9:41-9:50                                         Gumban, Liane Vina G. Ocampo, Tita C.
               FAculty Members in Performing their Three-Fold
      9:51-10:05*   Functions in the New Normal          Lopez, and Jaysi T. Corpuz (Trece
                                                         Campus, Imus Campus and CEMDS)
       *Q and A


                                     Ms. Khay B. Arandia
                                          Moderator]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Program of activities



             Breakout session 5: social science (education, DRM, SOCIOLOGY,
                            HEALTH NURSING AND Anthropology)



                                                         Ronlie RJ A. Espeleta, Jocelyn B. Siochi,
       8:50-9:00   Sexism in Learning Materials: An Analysis of Gender Bias   Cristina M. Signo, Still John F. Reyes,
               and Stereotypes in the English Language Learning
      9:01-9:15*                                         Shiela L. Vidallon, and Maria Rizalyn C.
               Materials of Cavite State University
                                                         Flores (Carmona Campus)
               Strengthening Health Risk Management of Healthcare
       9:16-9:25                                         Caridad C. Lintao, Evelyn M. Del Mundo,
               Personnel on Preventing COVID 19 Using Ugnayan
      9:26-9:40*                                         and Rolando P. Antonio (CON)
               Program; Implication to Create Policy and Guidelines
                                                         Julie Anne C. Lontoc, Ezra Marie F.
       9:41-9:50   Implementation of CvSU E-Learning System in Cavite   Ramos, Marlon R. Pereña, Myleen P.
      9:51-10:05*  State University: An Assessment        Legaspi, Bernard S. Feranil, and Marissa
                                                         C. Lontoc (CEIT, CED, CAS, CCJ)
                                                         Mildred A. Sebastian, Ritch M. Banate,
                                                         Audreyson H. Borilla, Ivory P, Mojica, Gil
      10:06-10:15  Assessment Strategies in the New Normal: Inputs to   D. Ramos, Gerry Mae T. Silvero, Mary
     10:16-10:30*  Curriculum Design                      Joy Angelique R. Mojica, Joyce Erika S.
                                                         Senaris, Maria Cristina C. Tagle, and
                                                         Estelita A. Villa (Tanza Campus)
                                                         Ron Erik C. Frontuna, Yolanda L.
                                                         Satiada, Leonard V. Paunil, Michael
      10:31-10:40  Graduates’ Employability: A Tracer Study of Cavite State
                                                         Cosignado, Maria Andrea C. Francia,
     10:41-10:55*  University Carmona Campus Graduates   Regene G. Hernandez, and Jocelyn B.
                                                         Siochi (Carmona Campus)
      10:56-11:05   Analysis of the Licensure Examination for Teachers   Maria Cristina J. Baesa, Lambert Diokno,
               Performance of the Teacher Education Graduates of     and Jeremias L. Jangad (Cavite City
     11:06-11:20*   Cavite State University              Campus)

                                                         Melona I. Saquin, Ritch M. Banate,
                                                         Debbie Rose T. Banag, Joyce Erika S.
                                                         Senaris, Gil D. Ramos, Mary Rose E.
      11:21-11:30  Workplace Performance of CvSU-Tanza Graduates:   Elamparo, Mark Joel C. Sibulo, Mildred

     11:31-11:45*  Inputs to Curriculum Development      A. Sebastian, Mary Joy Angelique R.
                                                         Mojica, Gerry Mae T. Silvero, Charmaine
                                                         T. Banag, Jeffrey F. and Delgado, Erika
                                                         Precia (Tanza Campus)
       *Q and A
               LUNCH BREAK

                                   Engr. Rene R. Marasigan
                                         Moderator]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Program of activities




             Breakout session 5: social science (education, DRM, SOCIOLOGY,
                            HEALTH NURSING AND Anthropology)


                                                         Lilian O. Sidamon, Khenilyn P. Lewis,
                                                         Cristza D.O. Manlapig, Arlene L. Estrada,
     1:00-1:10PM  Performance Assessment of 2019 Graduates of Cavite     Rose Anne Tobias, Vienna Mi A. Feranil,
      1:11-1:25*   State University – Trece Martires City Campus
                                                         Kristel Shane C. Paminter, and Jessie
                                                         Anne T. Demetillo (Trece Campus)
                                                         Silkie C. Tuguinay, Fevelyn F. Ongyod, V
       1:26-1:35   Disaster Risk Management Program in In-Migration Areas   -Jay S. Eusebio, Clinton G. Bedso,
      1:36-1:50*   in the Province of Cavite              Darius R. Campos, Marissa C. Lontoc,
                                                         and Alexis R. Alcantara (CCJ)
                                                         Hermilina A. Mendoza, Haziel T. Alvarez,
               Skills and Capabilities of Persons With Disability as   Zarah Jane R. Centeno, Ma. Cristina D.
       1:51-2:00
               Potential Entrepreneurs: Basis For PWD Business     Bayla, Emy Grace B. Patambang, Wendy
      2:01-2:15*
               Development Program                       D. Sadang, and Aileen Cervantez (Silang
                                                         Campus)
       2:16-2:30   Peer Blood Pressure Monitoring Program Among Adult     Karen Louela R. Rint  (CON)
      2:31-2:45*   Residents of Ternate Cavite

                                                         Rhodora S. Crizaldo, Jovan B. Alitagtag,
       2:46-2:55   Quality of Work Life in State Universities and Colleges in
      2:56-3:10*   Southern Luzon                        Jake Raymund F. Fabregar, and Jane J.
                                                         Reyes (CED)

       *Q and A


                                   Engr. Rene R. Marasigan
                                         Moderator]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[RESEARCH PROPOSAL PRESENTATION
                                             April 27, 2021 via CISCO Webex]]></page></pages></Search>