<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="3"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.1.         The following fringe benefits are granted:


                    I.1.5.  tuition discount for faculty and

                                dependents;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  66


                              c)  Filial  obligations  to  cover  the  employee’s  moral  obligation
                                 towards his parents   and siblings for their medical and social
                                 needs.

                              d) Domestic emergencies such as sudden urgent repairs needed at
                                 home, sudden absence of “yaya” or maid and the like.

                              e)  Personal  transactions  to  cover the  entire  range of  transactions
                                 an individual does with government and private offices such as
                                 paying taxes, court appearance, arranging a house loan, etc.

                              f)  Calamity,  accident,  hospitalization  leave  pertains  to  force
                                 majuere  events  that  affect  the  life,  limb  and  property  of  the
                                 employee or his immediate family.

                              g)  An  employee  can  still  avail  of  his  birthday  or  wedding
                                 anniversary leaves if such occasion falls on either a Saturday,
                                 Sunday or holiday either before or after the occasion.

                              h) Employees applying for special leave privileges shall no longer be
                                 required to present proof that they are entitled to avail of such
                                 leaves.

                              i)  Three- day limit for a given year shall be strictly observed; an
                                 employee can avail of one special privilege leave for three days
                                 in  a  given  year.  Special  privileges  are  non-cumulative  and
                                 strictly non-convertible to cash.

                              j)  Immediate family refers to spouse, children, parents, unmarried
                                 brothers and sisters or any relative living under the same roof
                                 or dependent upon the employee for support.

                   Article  16.  Study  Privileges.  Members  of  the  faculty,  officers  and
                       employees  shall have the privilege of enrolling in the University for not
                       more than nine (9) units a semester on undergraduate courses, or six (6)
                       units  for  graduate  courses,  shall  be  exempted  from  tuition  and  other
                       fees; provided, that the courses in which they are enrolled shall redound
                       to the benefit of their regular work in the University.

                          Children,  wife  or  husband  of  permanent  full-time  faculty  and
                       personnel  including  those  on  daily  wage  basis,  who  have  served
                       continuously  for  a  period  of  one  (1)  year  in  the  University  shall  be
                       exempted from the payment of tuition and other fees, upon enrollment,
                       subject  to  renewal  from  semester  to  semester  if  they  pass  at  least  12
                       units  or  three-fourth  of  the  total  units  enrolled  in  the  last  semester
                       attended;  provided,  that  corresponding  tuition  and  other  fees  for  failed
                                                                                                           66]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  67


                       subjects shall be paid for.  In the case of the high school student, he/she
                       must have passed in order to renew the privilege of tuition and other fee
                       exemptions.

                   Article  17.  Special  Detail.  A  member  of  the  academic  staff  or  an
                       administrative staff may be assigned by the President of the University
                       on special detail elsewhere in the Philippines or abroad for the benefit of
                       the University or any of its units and under certain conditions to be fixed
                       by him in each case, provided, that a faculty member who is married at
                       the  time  of  the  detail  shall  be  granted  an  additional  monthly  family
                       allowance to commence on the date of departure up to date of return to
                       the University.

                          The following specific rules on special detail shall be followed by the
                       University:

                                 a)        Upon  the  request  of  another  agency  or  entity  of  the
                                 government and when the resources of the University so permit,
                                 University personnel may be authorized to go on special detail
                                 with the requesting agency, subject to the following conditions:

                                 b)       No special detail shall be authorized for a period of more
                                 than one year at a time. Special detail leave for one (1) year may
                                 be  renewed  only  once  to  members  of  the  faculty  and  non-
                                 academic  personnel  who  accept  career  positions  in  the
                                 Government or Government-owned or controlled corporations;

                                 c)          Renewal  shall  be  granted  only  in  exceptional  cases  as
                                 determined by the President of the University;

                                 d)         No  special  details  shall  be  granted  to  faculty  and
                                 employees       who     are    enjoying     fellowships     and     similar
                                 arrangements;

                                 e)      Persons  granted  special  detail  shall  submit  a  complete
                                 and  detailed  report  of  their  work  within  45  days  after  their
                                 return to duty;

                                 f)      Special detail of any personnel of the University shall be
                                 for the good of the service and with the consent of the person
                                 concerned;






                                                                                                           67]]></page></pages></Search>