<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.4.            The College/Department of


                        Undergraduate Teacher Education


                        (BSEd) assists the graduating students

                        with academic deficiencies, disciplinary


                        cases, and other problems which hinder


                        issuance of clearances.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Proposal to Offer Practice Teaching


                    during the Second Semester


         AY 2020-2021 to ensure that graduating



                   students will graduate on time]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[••* ^.






                                                Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSI

                                                       Tanza Campus
                                                    Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                      ffi (046) 414 - 3979
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                                           03 February 2021



                 DR. MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO
                 Vice President for Academic Affaire
                 This University

                 Dear Dr. Nuestro:

                         I would like to respectfully request the kind approval of your good office on the offering of
                 selected laboratory courses for selected programs, which do not require face-to-face training to
                 master the skills to be taught; as well as on-the-job-training program and practice teaching that
                 can be done in a work from home arrangement at CvSU - Tanza Campus during the Second
                 Semester, AY 2020 - 2021 which can be conducted online and on work-from-home arrangement.
                 The offering of such classes will also complement the completion of graduation requirements of
                 graduating students who were not able to enroll laboratory classes during the preceding semester.

                         Thank you very much for your usual kind approval.



                                                                           Respectfully yours,


                                                                                            ^AHisto
                                                                           Campus Administrator



                  Approved:




                  MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
                  Vice President for Academic Affairs


















                                                     l]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                        Tanza Campus
                                                     Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                        ^ (046)414-3979
                                                        www.cvsu.edu.ph



                  I.TITLE:  PROPOSAL TO OFFER SELECTED LABORATORY CLASSES AT CvSU -
                                TANZA CAMPUS FOR THE SECOND SEMESTER, AY 2020 - 2021

                  II.PROPONENT: CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY - TANZA CAMPUS


                  III.RATIONALE:

                              The emergence of COVID-19 pandemic and the imminent presence of the UK
                      COVID-19 variant brought unforeseen disruptions in the lives of people all over the world.
                      The Philippine higher education institutions (HEIs) are no exemption in facing such critical
                      situations. To ensure the continuity of learning among tertiary students while avoiding and/or
                      limiting the risks of infection in the community, HEIs explored and shifted to other innovative
                      learning modalities that transmigrate the conduct of classes from traditional to flexible
                      learning modalities, which gave students the option to choose the most convenient delivery
                      modes to them. This flexible learning modality emerged during the First Semester of
                      Academic Year 2020-2021 where it was used for the conduct of lecture classes, leaving
                      behind the conduct of laboratory classes that require a more rigid training for students in
                      face-to-face classes.
                             While flexible learning modality allows flexibility in time, place, and audience, including
                     (but not solely reliant on) the use of technology, its conduct varies on the levels of technology,
                     availability of devices, internet connectivity, level of digital literacy and approaches (CMO 04,
                     s. 2020). As it should complement outcomes-based education approach, HEIs are also given
                     flexibility to employ various means of delivery and assessment modes as long as they can
                     achieve the set of learning outcomes for each course/subject for the program. With this, each
                      HEI was tasked to review their curricular offerings and make necessary adjustments or
                      modifications in the course contents/requirements, determine alternative options in the
                     design, delivery, pedagogy, and assessment mechanism that can be delivered to the students
                     through various modalities.
                             Given that Cavite State has come up with flexible learning modalities in the conduct of
                      lecture classes, it can also be the case for the conduct of laboratory classes as long as it can
                      come up with a solid learning plan for this matter. Hence, we propose to offer selected
                      laboratory classes for selected programs at CvSU - Tanza Campus for the Second Semester,
                     AY 2020-2021.



                  IV. OBJECTIVES:

                              This proposal aims to allow the CvSU - Tanza Campus to offer selected laboratory
                      classes for selected programs, which do not require face-to-face training to master the skills
                      to be taught; as well as on-the-job-training program and practice teaching that can be done
                       in a work from home arrangement. Also, the offerings of such classes will complement the]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[completion of graduation requirements of students who were not able to enroll laboratory
                      classes during the preceding semester.

                  V. MECHANICS OF IMPLEMENTATION
                              On-the-Job Training (OJT) Program and Practice Teaching must only be done in a
                      work-from-home arrangement and there must be LIMITED or NO face-to-face interaction
                      between the student-trainees and the employees of the linkage where he/she is assigned.

                             As for the conduct of online laboratory classes, the following guidelines shall be
                      followed:

                      A. Course/s to be Offered and Relevant Materials to be Used
                                                                    NO. OF
                                                                  TEACHING            AVAILABILITY AND
                            DISCIPLINE/     COURSE CODE           CONTACT             ACCESSIBILITY OF
                           DEPARTMENT           & TITLE
                                                                LABORATORY                RESOURCES
                                                                    HOURS
                           Information                                            Android apps available such
                           Technology                                             as: Linux terminal, CMD
                                           ITEC65-Open
                                                                                  console; Project in
                                           Source                      3
                                           Technology                             collaboration with a repository
                                                                                  in open source
                                                                                  platform/community
                                                                                  Any programming languages
                                                                                  can be used (Compiler and
                                           ITEC 55 - Platform                     Interpreters Compiler and
                                                                       3
                                           Technologies                           Interpreters (Android Apps
                                                                                  available)); 8086 Emulator
                                                                                  (Android Apps available)
                                           ITEC 80-
                                           Network                     3          Cisco packet tracer
                                           Management
                                           DCIT 25 - Data
                                                                                  Emu8086 App (Android Apps
                                           Structures and              3
                                           Algorithms                             available)
                                           INSY 55 - System
                                                                                  Lab activities are case
                                           Analysis and                3
                                           Design                                 analysis
                                           DCIT 21 -
                                           Introduction to             3          MS Office applications only
                                           Computing
                                           DCIT 22-
                                                                                  QPython 3L(Python engine
                                           Computer                    6          for Android)
                                           Programming 1
                                           ITEC 101-e-                            social media (FB page) will
                                                                       3
                                           Commerce                               be used
                                           iTEC50-Web                             using <Acode>, a lightweight
                                           System and                  3          yet powerful web IDE for
                                           Technologies 1                         Android]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[using Termux, an android
                                           DCIT 55 -                              terminal emulator and Linux
                                           Advanced                    3          environment app that works
                                           Database System                        directly with no rooting or
                                                                                  setup required.
                                                                                  various free downloadable
                                           ITEC70-
                                                                                  photo editing mobile
                                           Multimedia                  3
                                                                                  application/ can also be
                                           Systems
                                                                                  presented through video
                                           COSC 65-
                                           Programming                 3          VScode App
                                           Languages
                                           DCIT24-
                                           Information                 3          XAMP and cmd
                                           Management
                                           COSC 199-                              Work from home        ^
                                                                   240 hours      arrangement            ^
                                           OJT/Practicum
                                           DCIT 111-
                                           Advanced                    3          JVDroid and AIDE
                                           Programming
                                           ITEC 80 -
                                           Introduction to
                                                                       3          anWriter
                                           Human Computer
                                           Interaction
                           Psychology      BPSY 55 -
                                                                                  SPSS, R, Python, scientific
                                           Psychological               6          calculator, modules
                                           Statistics
                           Hospitality     BSHM 141-Cost               6          Calculators
                           Management      Control
                                                                                  Travel and Tourism Service
                                                                                  Online Application,
                                           BSHM 23 -                              Management Information
                                           Applied Business                       System, Hotel Property
                                           Tools and                   3          Management System
                                           Technologies                           Application, Digital Payment
                                           (GDS) with Lab                         System Application,
                                                                                  Hospitality System
                                                                                  Application
                                           BSHM 23 -
                                           Ergonomics &
                                                                                  Sketch Up Application, Adobe
                                           Facilities Planning         3
                                                                                  Photoshop
                                           for the Hospitality
                                           Industry
                           Teacher                                                Online Practice Teaching with
                           Education       EDFS 27 -                              Secondary High Schools
                                           Practice Teaching           6          (Work from home
                                                                                  arrangement)

                      B. Class Size
                                 The maximum class size of forty (40) students shall be observed.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[C.Schedule of Classes and Class Meetings
                              1.Class meetings shall be done virtually.
                             2.Classes shall be scheduled as to the number of laboratory hours per week.
                                 However, a maximum of one (1) hour is required for each online meeting for every
                                 3-hour laboratory classes; maximum of two (2) hours for every 6-hour laboratory;
                                 and maximum of three (3) hours for every 9-hour laboratory.
                             3.If possible, students should only come to university for retrieval and/or submission
                                 of modules and/or outputs. Shall they come to school for this purpose, they will
                                 be allowed to come to the campus at a maximum of 15 minutes only.
                             4.Online consultation with the faculty shall only be allowed.
                              5.Homeroom assignments shall be implemented.

                      D.First Day of Classes
                              1.During the first day of classes, students shall be provided with a copy of course
                                 syllabus.
                             2.Faculty members should discuss the content of the course syllabus particularly
                                 the course objectives, course content,  instructional approaches, learning
                                 activities, learning resources and location, course requirements, bases for
                                 evaluating students' performance and technology to be used.
                              3.Faculty members should also give copies of installers/platforms/resources/
                                 materials to be used for the laboratory classes FOR FREE. They should also
                                 orient their students on how to install/use them as the classes proceed.
                             4.Faculty members are encouraged to provide advanced copy of learning materials
                                 to be used for the entire semester.

                      E.Modes of Teaching and Learning
                              1.Classes shall be conducted using the blended modes of teaching and learning.
                              2.Laboratory exercises shall be prepared for each skill to be demonstrated.
                              3.It is the responsibility of the faculty member to ensure that these exercises can
                                 be done at home and with no hazards with the students if they will do it without
                                 the actual supervision of the faculty.

                      F.Assessment and Evaluation of Students' Performance in the Laboratory
                              1.Assessment/evaluation for remote/distance mode shall be conducted using
                                 alternative strategies such as, but not limited to:
                                 a.Actual video demonstration through synchronous sessions via screen sharing
                                 b.Record video demonstration during asynchronous session.
                                 c.Other alternative strategies used for remote/distance mode
                              2.Ask students to sign an honor system pledge.

                      CONDUCT OF ON-THE-JOB TRAINING AND PRACTICE TEACHING
                       \,  The conduct of ONLINE OJT and practice teaching shall only be allowed.
                      2. Students enrolled to OJT and Practice Teaching courses are required to submit the
                          following documents:
                          a.Recommendation Letter from the OJT adviser indicating that the trainee must only
                              render WFH tasks.
                          b.Waiver signed by the student-trainee and his/her parent/guardian emphasizing that
                              they can only render WFH tasks.
                          c.Memorandum of Understanding stipulating that the conduct of OJT and Practice
                              Teaching shall be purely online and that trainees must work from home (WFH).]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[d. Honor Pledge indicating that the student-trainee shall abide by the rules and
                           regulations in the conduct of OJT and/or Practice Teaching in a WFH basis.
                       Ail outputs, assigned tasks and other relevant documents pertaining to the conduct of
                       OJT and practice teaching MUST only be submitted online to ensure NO face-to-face
                       encounter shall be made by the trainee with the training institution and its employees.


               Prepared by:



               MILDR^D A. SEBASTIANRITE
               Chairperson, TEDCM


                Recommending Approval:



                                   ffisto
               Campus Administrator





               Approved:


                MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Vice President for Academic Affairs]]></page></pages></Search>