<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="5"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.13.           The institution has well equipped


                        offices.


                        S.13.1.  Culture and Arts;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Manual of Operation]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[21


                              2.2.9.  CvSU  Scholarship  Privilege.  This  scholarship  is  awarded  to
                                       employees of the University and their dependents provided that
                                       such  employees  have  rendered  at  least  one  year  of  continuous
                                       service to the University, irrespective of their employment status.
                       2.3.   In  general,  the  criteria  in  the  selection  of  financial  awardees  include:
                              good  moral  character;  economic  background  of  parents  or  guardians;
                              willingness  to  work;  and  academic  performance.  The  University  shall
                              promulgate  the  details  of  selection  criteria  and  the  mechanics  of
                              implementation and revise the same accordingly, as the need arises.
                       2.4.    The  benefits  to  the  awardees  of  the  financial  assistance  program
                              include:
                              2.4.1.  either free tuition or discounts in tuition;
                              2.4.2.  monthly stipend; allowance per semester;
                              2.4.3.  book allowance and others.
                              2.4.4.  In  addition,  some  types  of  financial  assistance  include  priority
                                       booking in the University Dormitory.
                       2.5.   The responsibilities of the recipients include maintaining high academic
                              standards;  and  also  rendering  some  types  of  service  work  to  the
                              University.  The  University  shall  issue  from  time  to  time,  update
                              guidelines on these aspects of the program.
                       2.6.   The  financial  assistance  is  automatically  terminated  if  a  student
                              recipient  is  involved  in  any  misdemeanor  in  contravention  of  the
                              University  Student’s  Norm  of  Conduct  or  any  other  University  policies,
                              rules  and  regulations.  In  addition,  student  recipients  whose  grades  fall
                              below  the  required  academic  requirements  by  the  type  of  financial
                              assistance shall also forfeit the benefits and/or allowances.

                       Section 3. Culture and Arts Program
                       3.1.   The Office of Student Affairs and Services shall implement a culture and
                              arts  program  geared  towards  the  development,  enhancement  and
                              promotion  of  CvSU  talents  through  their  artistic  expression  and
                              creativity  with  enriched  appreciation  and  conservation  of  national
                              culture.
                       3.2.   Specifically,  the  culture  and  arts  program  shall  have  the  following
                              objectives:
                              3.2.1.  develop  students’  talents  and  interest  to  ensure  social  and
                                       cultural growth
                              3.2.2.  create  meaningful  opportunities  for  students  to  show  off  and
                                       share their artistic talents
                              3.2.3.  promote appreciation of culture and arts in the University
                       3.3.   In  order  to  achieve  the  above-mentioned  objectives,  the  following
                              functions must be performed:
                              3.1.1.  organize arts groups with qualified trainers and staff
                              3.1.2.  implement regular cultural activities
                              3.1.3.  collaborate cultural activities with various university offices
                              3.1.4.  create avenues for showcase of talents
                              3.1.5.  organize cultural activities for community involvement]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Vicinity and Building Map]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[The Office of Student Affairs serves as the Office of Culture and Arts]]></page></pages></Search>