<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="37"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.2.            The Student Affairs Services (SAS)


                        program is consistent with the vision


                        and mission of the institution, goals of

                        the College/Academic Unit and


                        objectives of the program.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[1


                                                         RULE VII

                                          STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES

               Article 1. Office of Student Affairs and Services.

                       The student services unit of Cavite State University shall be known as the Office
               of Student Affairs and Services (OSAS).  It shall provide relevant programs for student-
               centered activities and mandated services in support of academic instruction intended
               to facilitate well-rounded student development.

               Article 2. Vision, Mission and Objectives

                       Section 1. Vision

                              The  OSAS  shall  be  a  resource  of  high  quality  student  welfare  and
                       development  programs,  efficient  services  and  relevant  opportunities  geared
                       towards  the  development  of  morally  upright  and  globally  competitive
                       professionals.

                       Section 2. Mission

                              The  OSAS  shall  provide  an  atmosphere  where  students’  talents,
                       interests,  and  values  are  developed  to  the  fullest,  and  shall  deliver  efficient
                       student  services  which  can  contribute  to  the  achievement  of  academic
                       excellence  and  high  professional  competency  which  can  be  recognized
                       internationally.

                       Section 3. Objectives

                              3.1.   regularly implement comprehensive guidance programs with a full
                                     range of activities such as assessment, information, consultation,
                                     counselling, referral, placement, follow-up and follow-through;
                              3.2.   implement  effective  information  and  orientation  strategies  in
                                     promoting awareness on student rights and obligations
                              3.3.   provide  financial  assistance  to the  needy  and deserving  students
                                     through scholarship grants, service and job experience programs,
                                     student  loans  and  mutual  aid  funds,  giving  priority  to  those
                                     belonging to the vulnerable and marginalized sector
                              3.4.   provide leadership trainings to enhance leadership effectiveness of
                                     students both at  personal and organizational levels
                              3.5.    strictly  implement  institutional  rules  and  regulations  governing
                                     student  behaviour  and  conduct  to  be  able  to  produce  morally
                                     upright professionals
                              3.6.    provide avenues to hone students’ talents and interest to ensure
                                     social and cultural growth;
                              3.7.    implement  relevant  sports  development  programs  to  provide
                                     opportunities  for  athletic  competition,  physical  fitness  and  well-
                                     being of students





               Excerpts from the Univeristy Manual of Operations]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                       TANZA CAMPUS


                      OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES


                              STUDENT



                               SERVICES



                            PROGRAMS]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 TANZA CAMPUS


 OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES


 STUDENT



 SERVICES



 PROGRAMS]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES                           UNIVERSITY VISION

                       As  an  institution  of  higher  learning,  the  Cavite  State           The  premier  University  in  historic  Cavite  recognized
               University  caters  to  the  needs  of  the  students,  not  only  in  the   for excellence in the development of globally competitive and
               acquisition of education but also in their personality development.       morally upright individuals.
               To  ensure  that  the  students’  potential  for  advancement  are
               maximized,  the  Student  Welfare  Services  was  established.  The       UNIVERSITY MISSION
               Student  Welfare  Services  had  been  renamed  Office  of  Student
               Affairs  (OSAS).  It  is  major  project  uner  the  Office  of  the  Vice       The  Cavite  State  University  shall  provide  excellent,
               President for Academic Affairs.                                           equitable and relevant educational opportunities in the arts,
                                                                                         sciences  and  technology  though  quality  instruction  and
               HISTORY
                                                                                         responsive  research  and  development  activities.  It  shall
               The Office of Student Affairs started as one of the functional units      produce professional, skilled and morally upright individuals
               of  the  then  Don  Severino  Agricultural  College  (DSAC)  in  1980.    for global competitiveness.
               Through the years the name of the office was changed to Student
               Services  Project  in  1986,  Student  Services  in  1989,  Student       OSAS GOALS
               Welfare  Services  in  1991  and  renamed again  to  Office  of  Student
               Affairs  in  1998  when  DSAC  was  elevated  into  a  university,  the          The  goals  of  the  Student  Affairs  are  the  following:  to
               Cavite State University. In December 2004, the OSA was renamed            look after the educational, vocational, as well as the personal
               to  Office  of  Student  Affairs  and  Services  by  virtue  of  BOR      development needs of the students; to assist the students to
               resolution no. 77 s. 2004. Since then, the office has been providing      maximize  their  potential  by  helping  them  understand
               different  student  services  to  its  clients  such  as  guidance  and   themselves  and  their  environment  and  to  enhance  their
               counselling,  admission  and  testing,  and  student  development         psychological growth towards socialized maturity.
               services  like  student  organization  and  socio  cultural  affairs,
               student publication and placement of students and graduates. The
               mandated  National  Service  Training  Program  (NSTP)  subject  was
               also offered by the office in 2002.The office will continue and shall
               remain  committed  to  provide  student  welfare  and  development
               activities to the CvSU academic community and the public.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES   UNIVERSITY VISION

 As  an  institution  of  higher  learning,  the  Cavite  State   The  premier  University  in  historic  Cavite  recognized
 University  caters  to  the  needs  of  the  students,  not  only  in  the   for excellence in the development of globally competitive and
 acquisition of education but also in their personality development.   morally upright individuals.
 To  ensure  that  the  students’  potential  for  advancement  are
 maximized,  the  Student  Welfare  Services  was  established.  The   UNIVERSITY MISSION
 Student  Welfare  Services  had  been  renamed  Office  of  Student
 Affairs  (OSAS).  It  is  major  project  uner  the  Office  of  the  Vice   The  Cavite  State  University  shall  provide  excellent,
 President for Academic Affairs.   equitable and relevant educational opportunities in the arts,
     sciences  and  technology  though  quality  instruction  and
 HISTORY
     responsive  research  and  development  activities.  It  shall
 The Office of Student Affairs started as one of the functional units   produce professional, skilled and morally upright individuals
 of  the  then  Don  Severino  Agricultural  College  (DSAC)  in  1980.   for global competitiveness.
 Through the years the name of the office was changed to Student
 Services  Project  in  1986,  Student  Services  in  1989,  Student   OSAS GOALS
 Welfare  Services  in  1991  and  renamed again  to  Office  of  Student
 Affairs  in  1998  when  DSAC  was  elevated  into  a  university,  the      The  goals  of  the  Student  Affairs  are  the  following:  to
 Cavite State University. In December 2004, the OSA was renamed   look after the educational, vocational, as well as the personal
 to  Office  of  Student  Affairs  and  Services  by  virtue  of  BOR   development needs of the students; to assist the students to
 resolution no. 77 s. 2004. Since then, the office has been providing   maximize  their  potential  by  helping  them  understand
 different  student  services  to  its  clients  such  as  guidance  and   themselves  and  their  environment  and  to  enhance  their
 counselling,  admission  and  testing,  and  student  development   psychological growth towards socialized maturity.
 services  like  student  organization  and  socio  cultural  affairs,
 student publication and placement of students and graduates. The
 mandated  National  Service  Training  Program  (NSTP)  subject  was
 also offered by the office in 2002.The office will continue and shall
 remain  committed  to  provide  student  welfare  and  development
 activities to the CvSU academic community and the public.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES                                                     1.     regularly     implement      comprehensive

                                                                                                              guidance  programs  with  a  full  range  of
                                                                                                              activities     such      as     assessment,
                      The  student  services  unit  of  Cavite  State  University                             information,  consultation,  counselling,
              shall be known as the Office of Student Affairs and Services                                    referral, placement, follow-up and follow-
              (OSAS).    It  shall  provide  relevant  programs  for  student-                                through;
              centered  activities  and  mandated  services  in  support  of                           2.     implement  effective  information  and
                                                                                                                                                promoting
                                                                                                                             strategies
              academic  instruction  intended  to  facilitate  well-rounded                                   orientation    on   student  in  rights   and
                                                                                                              awareness
              student development.                                                                            obligations
                                                                                                       3.     provide financial assistance to the needy
               Vision, Mission and Objectives                                                                 and      deserving     students     through
                                                                                                              scholarship  grants,  service  and  job
                      Vision                                                                                  experience  programs,  student  loans  and
                                                                                                              mutual aid funds, giving priority to those
                             The  OSAS  shall  be  a  resource  of  high  quality                             belonging     to    the   vulnerable     and
                      student  welfare  and  development  programs,  efficient                                marginalized sector
                      services and relevant opportunities geared towards the                           4.     provide  leadership  trainings  to  enhance
                                                                                                              leadership effectiveness of students both
                      development      of   morally    upright    and    globally                             at  personal and organizational levels
                      competitive professionals.                                                       5.      strictly  implement  institutional  rules
                                                                                                              and     regulations    governing     student
                      Mission                                                                                 behaviour  and  conduct  to  be  able  to
                                                                                                              produce morally upright professionals
                             The  OSAS  shall  provide  an  atmosphere  where                          6.      provide  avenues  to  hone  students’
                      students’ talents,  interests,  and values  are  developed                              talents and interest to ensure social and
                      to  the  fullest,  and  shall  deliver  efficient  student                              cultural growth;
                      services  which  can  contribute  to  the  achievement  of                       7.      implement  relevant  sports  development
                      academic      excellence     and     high     professional                              programs  to  provide  opportunities  for
                      competency which can be recognized internationally.                                     athletic competition, physical fitness and
                                                                                                              well-being of students
                      Section 3. Objectives
                                                                                                       8.     develop  skills  and  potentials  of  student
                                                                                                              writers]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES  1.    regularly   implement   comprehensive

                          guidance  programs  with  a  full  range  of
                          activities    such      as      assessment,
 The  student  services  unit  of  Cavite  State  University   information,  consultation,  counselling,
 shall be known as the Office of Student Affairs and Services   referral, placement, follow-up and follow-
 (OSAS).    It  shall  provide  relevant  programs  for  student-  through;
 centered  activities  and  mandated  services  in  support  of   2.    implement  effective  information  and
                                                            promoting
                                         strategies
 academic  instruction  intended  to  facilitate  well-rounded   orientation   on   student  in  rights   and
                          awareness
 student development.     obligations
                   3.     provide financial assistance to the needy
 Vision, Mission and Objectives     and   deserving   students   through
                          scholarship  grants,  service  and  job
 Vision                   experience  programs,  student  loans  and
                          mutual aid funds, giving priority to those
 The  OSAS  shall  be  a  resource  of  high  quality   belonging   to   the   vulnerable   and
 student  welfare  and  development  programs,  efficient   marginalized sector
 services and relevant opportunities geared towards the   4.    provide  leadership  trainings  to  enhance
                          leadership effectiveness of students both
 development   of   morally   upright   and   globally   at  personal and organizational levels
 competitive professionals.   5.     strictly  implement  institutional  rules
                          and     regulations    governing     student
 Mission                  behaviour  and  conduct  to  be  able  to
                          produce morally upright professionals
 The  OSAS  shall  provide  an  atmosphere  where   6.     provide  avenues  to  hone  students’
 students’ talents,  interests,  and values  are  developed   talents and interest to ensure social and
 to  the  fullest,  and  shall  deliver  efficient  student   cultural growth;
 services  which  can  contribute  to  the  achievement  of   7.     implement  relevant  sports  development
 academic   excellence   and   high   professional   programs  to  provide  opportunities  for
 competency which can be recognized internationally.   athletic competition, physical fitness and
                          well-being of students
 Section 3. Objectives
                   8.     develop  skills  and  potentials  of  student
                          writers]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[9.     promote      student     involvement      in              The Student Welfare Services Unit
                                     community development programs
                              10.   provide an environment conducive to free                          The  Student  Welfare  Services  Unit  shall  deliver
                                     expression  of  one’s  religious  orientation             student services and programs needed to ensure and
                                     in    accordance       with    institutional
                                     principles                                                promote the well-being of students. This shall include
                                                                                               information  and  orientation  services,  guidance  and
                                                                                               counselling  services,  career  and  job  placement
               Organizational Structure of OSAS                                                services,    and      student     economic      enterprise
                                                                                               development services.
                       The  OSAS  shall  be  headed  by  a  dean  who  shall  be
               under  the  direct  supervision  of  the  Vice-President  for                   The Student Development Services Unit
               Academic Affairs. The OSAS shall have four service units, the
               Student  Welfare  Services  (SWS)  Unit,  the  Student                                 The  Student  Development  Services  Unit   shall
               Development  Services  (SDS)  Unit,  the  Institutional  Student                provide  services  and  programs  designed  for  the
               Programs  and  Services  (ISPS)  Unit  and  the  Research,                      exploration,  enhancement  and  development  of  the
               Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Student  Services  (RMESS)                     students’  full  potential  for  personal  development,
               Unit.  Each  unit  shall  be  headed  by  an  over-all  coordinator             leadership  and  social  responsibility  through  various
               who shall report directly to the OSAS dean.                                     institutional    student     activities.   The     student
                                                                                               development  services  include  student  organization
               Student Services and Programs                                                   and activities, student government, student discipline,
                                                                                               and student publication.
                       The OSAS shall deliver three basic academic support
               services  to  students:  student  welfare  services,  student
               development  services  and  those  that  relate  to  institutional
               programs and services. In addition, there shall be a separate
               support  service  for  research,  monitoring  and  evaluation  of
               student  services.  These  services  shall  be  delivered  by  the
               following units:]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[9.    promote   student   involvement   in   The Student Welfare Services Unit
 community development programs
 10.   provide an environment conducive to free   The  Student  Welfare  Services  Unit  shall  deliver
 expression  of  one’s  religious  orientation   student services and programs needed to ensure and
 in   accordance   with   institutional
 principles   promote the well-being of students. This shall include
           information  and  orientation  services,  guidance  and
           counselling  services,  career  and  job  placement
 Organizational Structure of OSAS      services,   and   student   economic   enterprise
           development services.
 The  OSAS  shall  be  headed  by  a  dean  who  shall  be
 under  the  direct  supervision  of  the  Vice-President  for    The Student Development Services Unit
 Academic Affairs. The OSAS shall have four service units, the
 Student  Welfare  Services  (SWS)  Unit,  the  Student   The  Student  Development  Services  Unit   shall
 Development  Services  (SDS)  Unit,  the  Institutional  Student   provide  services  and  programs  designed  for  the
 Programs  and  Services  (ISPS)  Unit  and  the  Research,   exploration,  enhancement  and  development  of  the
 Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Student  Services  (RMESS)   students’  full  potential  for  personal  development,
 Unit.  Each  unit  shall  be  headed  by  an  over-all  coordinator   leadership  and  social  responsibility  through  various
 who shall report directly to the OSAS dean.    institutional   student   activities.   The   student
           development  services  include  student  organization
 Student Services and Programs       and activities, student government, student discipline,
           and student publication.
 The OSAS shall deliver three basic academic support
 services  to  students:  student  welfare  services,  student
 development  services  and  those  that  relate  to  institutional
 programs and services. In addition, there shall be a separate
 support  service  for  research,  monitoring  and  evaluation  of
 student  services.  These  services  shall  be  delivered  by  the
 following units:]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[The Student Affairs Services (SAS)



          is aligned to the College/Program




                              Goals and Objectives]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[VPAA-QF-10


                         CvSU Vision                                   Republic of the Philippines                        CvSU Mission
                     The  premier  university  in                  CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY                          Cavite  State  University  shall  provide
                   historic  Cavite  recognized  for                                                            excellent,  equitable  and  relevant  educational
                   excellence  in  the development                               Tanza Campus                   opportunities  in  the  arts,  science  and
                   of  globally  competitive  and                        Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite                  technology  through  quality  instruction  and
                   morally upright individuals.                              (046) 414-3979                    relevant research and development activities.
                                                                            www.cvsu.edu.ph                         It  shall  produce professional,  skilled and
                                                                                                                morally   upright   individuals   for   global
                                                                                                                competitiveness.
                                                                  TEACHER EDUCATION DEPARTMENT
                                                                          COURSE SYLLABUS
                                                                     First Semester, AY 2022-2023
               Course Code              EDUC 75      Course Title   Assessment in Learning 1  Type                  Lecture      Credit Units        3
                                      This  course  focuses  on  the  principles,  development  and  utilization  of  conventional  assessment  tools  to  improve  the  teaching-
                                      learning process. It emphasizes on the use of assessment of, as and for, in measuring knowledge, comprehension and thinking
               Course Description
                                      skills in the cognitive, psychomotor or affective domains. It allows students to go through the standard steps in test construction
                                      and development and the application in grading systems.
                                                                                             Monday, 10:30 AM – 12:00 NN; 2:00 – 3:30 PM; 5:30 – 7:00 PM
               Pre-requisites         None                    Course Schedule                Tuesday, 9:00 – 10:30 AM; 5:00 – 6:30 PM
                                                                                             Wednesday, 1:00 – 2:30 PM; 2:30 – 4:00 PM; 5:00 – 6:30 PM
                                      Students are expected to live by and stand for the following University tenets:
                                      TRUTH is demonstrated by the student’s objectivity and honesty during examinations, class activities and in the development of
                                      projects.
                                      EXCELLENCE is exhibited by the students’ self-confidence, punctuality, diligence and commitment in the assigned tasks, class
               Core Values
                                      performance and other course requirements.
                                      SERVICE is manifested by the students’ respect, rapport, fairness and cooperation in dealing with their peers and members of the
                                      community.
                                      In addition, they should exhibit love and respect for nature and support for the cause of humanity.
                                      The campus shall endeavor to:
               Goals of the              1.  Provide high quality instruction in order to produce skilled, morally upright, and globally competitive graduates;
               College/Campus            2.  Develop and pursue advance research activities through arts, sciences, and technology to support instruction; and
                                         3.  Develop and conduct extension activities that will empower people and communities.
                                      The Teacher Education Department (TED) intends to accomplish the following objectives:
               Objectives of the
               Department               1.  Provide relevant and quality course offering for pre-service teachers to improve their performance;
                                        2.  Conduct relevant researches in the teacher education and allied courses to produce good leaders and professionals; and


                                                                                                                                              V02-2020-06-01]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[VPAA-QF-10


 CvSU Vision   Republic of the Philippines   CvSU Mission
 The  premier  university  in   CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY   Cavite  State  University  shall  provide
 historic  Cavite  recognized  for   excellent,  equitable  and  relevant  educational
 excellence  in  the development         Tanza Campus   opportunities  in  the  arts,  science  and
 of  globally  competitive  and   Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite   technology  through  quality  instruction  and
 morally upright individuals.    (046) 414-3979   relevant research and development activities.
    www.cvsu.edu.ph             It  shall  produce professional,  skilled and
                            morally   upright   individuals   for   global
                            competitiveness.
 TEACHER EDUCATION DEPARTMENT
 COURSE SYLLABUS
 First Semester, AY 2022-2023
 Course Code   EDUC 75   Course Title   Assessment in Learning 1  Type   Lecture   Credit Units   3
 This  course  focuses  on  the  principles,  development  and  utilization  of  conventional  assessment  tools  to  improve  the  teaching-
 learning process. It emphasizes on the use of assessment of, as and for, in measuring knowledge, comprehension and thinking
 Course Description
 skills in the cognitive, psychomotor or affective domains. It allows students to go through the standard steps in test construction
 and development and the application in grading systems.
         Monday, 10:30 AM – 12:00 NN; 2:00 – 3:30 PM; 5:30 – 7:00 PM
 Pre-requisites   None   Course Schedule   Tuesday, 9:00 – 10:30 AM; 5:00 – 6:30 PM
         Wednesday, 1:00 – 2:30 PM; 2:30 – 4:00 PM; 5:00 – 6:30 PM
 Students are expected to live by and stand for the following University tenets:
 TRUTH is demonstrated by the student’s objectivity and honesty during examinations, class activities and in the development of
 projects.
 EXCELLENCE is exhibited by the students’ self-confidence, punctuality, diligence and commitment in the assigned tasks, class
 Core Values
 performance and other course requirements.
 SERVICE is manifested by the students’ respect, rapport, fairness and cooperation in dealing with their peers and members of the
 community.
 In addition, they should exhibit love and respect for nature and support for the cause of humanity.
 The campus shall endeavor to:
 Goals of the   1.  Provide high quality instruction in order to produce skilled, morally upright, and globally competitive graduates;
 College/Campus   2.  Develop and pursue advance research activities through arts, sciences, and technology to support instruction; and
 3.  Develop and conduct extension activities that will empower people and communities.
 The Teacher Education Department (TED) intends to accomplish the following objectives:
 Objectives of the
 Department   1.  Provide relevant and quality course offering for pre-service teachers to improve their performance;
 2.  Conduct relevant researches in the teacher education and allied courses to produce good leaders and professionals; and


                                                          V02-2020-06-01]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[3.  Conduct relevant community services to disseminate information and technologies to target clienteles to improve their well-
                                           being.
                                                       Program Educational Objectives (Based on the Program CMO)

                   1.  Articulate the rootedness of education in philosophical, socio-cultural, historical, psychological, and political contexts;
                   2.  Demonstrate mastery of subject matter/discipline;
                   3.  Facilitate learning using a wide range of teaching methodologies and delivery modes appropriate to specific learners and their environment;
                   4.  Develop innovative curricula, instructional plans, teaching approaches, and resources for diverse learners;
                   5.  Apply skills in the development and utilization of ICT to promote quality, relevant and sustainable educational practices;
                   6.  Demonstrate a variety of thinking skills in planning, monitoring, assessing, and reporting learning processes and outcomes;
                   7.  Practice professional and ethical teaching standards sensitive to the local, national, and global realities; and
                   8.  Pursue lifelong learning for personal and professional growth through varied experiential and field-based opportunities.

                                                  Student Outcomes and Relationship to Program Educational Objectives
                                                                                                Program Educational Objectives Code (Based on the
                       Program/Student Outcomes (Based on the Program CMO)                                          Program CMO)
                                                                                               1       2      3       4       5       6       7       8
                The BEE students should:
                        demonstrate in-depth understanding of the diversity of learners in various
                  a.                                                                                                                           
                        learning areas;
                        manifest meaningful and comprehensive pedagogical content knowledge
                  b.                                                                                                                           
                        (PCK) of the different subject areas;
                        utilize appropriate assessment and evaluation tools to measure learning
                  c.                                                                                                                           
                        outcomes;
                        manifest skills in communication, higher order thinking and use of tools
                  d.                                                                                                                           
                        and technology to accelerate learning and teaching;
                        demonstrate positive attributes of a model teacher, both as an individual
                  e.                                                                                                                           
                        and as a professional; and
                        manifest a desire to continuously pursue personal and professional,
                  f.    development.                                                                                                           

                The BSE Mathematics students should:
                  a.    exhibit competence in mathematical concepts and procedures;                                                            
                  b.    exhibit proficiency in relating mathematics to other curricular areas;                                                 
                        manifest meaningful and comprehensive pedagogical content knowledge
                  c.                                                                                                                           
                        (PCK) of mathematics;
                  d.    demonstrate competence in designing, constructing and utilizing different                                              ]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[3.  Conduct relevant community services to disseminate information and technologies to target clienteles to improve their well-
 being.
 Program Educational Objectives (Based on the Program CMO)

 1.  Articulate the rootedness of education in philosophical, socio-cultural, historical, psychological, and political contexts;
 2.  Demonstrate mastery of subject matter/discipline;
 3.  Facilitate learning using a wide range of teaching methodologies and delivery modes appropriate to specific learners and their environment;
 4.  Develop innovative curricula, instructional plans, teaching approaches, and resources for diverse learners;
 5.  Apply skills in the development and utilization of ICT to promote quality, relevant and sustainable educational practices;
 6.  Demonstrate a variety of thinking skills in planning, monitoring, assessing, and reporting learning processes and outcomes;
 7.  Practice professional and ethical teaching standards sensitive to the local, national, and global realities; and
 8.  Pursue lifelong learning for personal and professional growth through varied experiential and field-based opportunities.

 Student Outcomes and Relationship to Program Educational Objectives
           Program Educational Objectives Code (Based on the
 Program/Student Outcomes (Based on the Program CMO)   Program CMO)
           1       2      3       4       5       6       7       8
 The BEE students should:
 demonstrate in-depth understanding of the diversity of learners in various
 a.                                                        
 learning areas;
 manifest meaningful and comprehensive pedagogical content knowledge
 b.                                                        
 (PCK) of the different subject areas;
 utilize appropriate assessment and evaluation tools to measure learning
 c.                                                        
 outcomes;
 manifest skills in communication, higher order thinking and use of tools
 d.                                                        
 and technology to accelerate learning and teaching;
 demonstrate positive attributes of a model teacher, both as an individual
 e.                                                        
 and as a professional; and
 manifest a desire to continuously pursue personal and professional,
 f.    development.                                        

 The BSE Mathematics students should:
 a.    exhibit competence in mathematical concepts and procedures;                        
 b.    exhibit proficiency in relating mathematics to other curricular areas;                        
 manifest meaningful and comprehensive pedagogical content knowledge
 c.                                                        
 (PCK) of mathematics;
 d.    demonstrate competence in designing, constructing and utilizing different                        ]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[forms of assessment in mathematics;
                        demonstrate proficiency in problem-solving by solving and creating routine
                  e.                                                                                                                           
                        and non-routine problems with different levels of complexity;
                        use effectively appropriate approaches, methods, and techniques in
                  f.                                                                                                                           
                        teaching mathematics including technological tools; and
                        appreciate mathematics as an opportunity for creative work, moments of
                  g.                                                                                                                           
                        enlightenment, discovery and gaining insights of the world.
                The BSE English students should:
                  a.    possess broad knowledge of language and literature for effective learning;                                             

                  b.    use English as a global language in a multilingual context as it applies to                                            
                        the teaching of language and literature;
                  c.    acquire extensive reading background in language, literature, and allied
                        fields;                                                                                                                
                  d.    demonstrate proficiency in oral and written communication;                                                             
                  e.    shows competence in employing innovative language and literature
                        teaching approaches, methodologies, and strategies;                                                                    
                  f.    use technology in facilitating language learning and teaching;                                                         
                  g.    inspire students and colleagues to lead relevant and transformative
                        changes to improve learning and teaching language and literature; and                                                  
                  h.    display skills and abilities to be a reflective and research-oriented                                                  
                        language and literature teacher.
                                                       Course Outcomes and Relationship to Student Outcomes
                Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course                                                        Program/Student Outcomes Code
                After completing this course, BEE students must be able to:                             A        B        C        D        E        F
                1.  explain the basic concepts and principles of assessing student learning;            E        E        I        I        D        D
                2.  identify  the  different  learning  targets  and  their  appropriate  assessment  technique/test   E   E   E   E        D        E
                   formats;
                3.  design an examination with Table of Test Specification on specific field of specialization;   E   E   E        E        E        E
                4.  evaluate given test items based on the principles and guidelines in test construction; and   E   E    D        D        D        D
                5.  compute  and  explain  for  the  values  of  mean,  median,  mode,  range,  and  standard   D   D     D        D        D        D
                   deviation and interpret the meaning of such values.
                Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course                                                        Program/Student Outcomes Code
                After completing this course, BSEM students must be able to:                           A       B       C      D       E       F       G
                1.  explain the basic concepts and principles of assessing student learning;           E       E       I       I      D       D       E
                2.  identify  the  different  learning  targets  and  their  appropriate  assessment  technique/test
                   formats;                                                                            E       E       E      E       D       E       E]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[forms of assessment in mathematics;
 demonstrate proficiency in problem-solving by solving and creating routine
 e.                                                        
 and non-routine problems with different levels of complexity;
 use effectively appropriate approaches, methods, and techniques in
 f.                                                        
 teaching mathematics including technological tools; and
 appreciate mathematics as an opportunity for creative work, moments of
 g.                                                        
 enlightenment, discovery and gaining insights of the world.
 The BSE English students should:
 a.   possess broad knowledge of language and literature for effective learning;                        

 b.   use English as a global language in a multilingual context as it applies to                        
 the teaching of language and literature;
 c.   acquire extensive reading background in language, literature, and allied
 fields;                                                   
 d.   demonstrate proficiency in oral and written communication;                        
 e.   shows competence in employing innovative language and literature
 teaching approaches, methodologies, and strategies;                        
 f.   use technology in facilitating language learning and teaching;                        
 g.   inspire students and colleagues to lead relevant and transformative
 changes to improve learning and teaching language and literature; and                         
 h.   display skills and abilities to be a reflective and research-oriented                        
 language and literature teacher.
 Course Outcomes and Relationship to Student Outcomes
 Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course   Program/Student Outcomes Code
 After completing this course, BEE students must be able to:   A   B   C   D   E   F
 1.  explain the basic concepts and principles of assessing student learning;   E   E   I   I   D   D
 2.  identify  the  different  learning  targets  and  their  appropriate  assessment  technique/test   E   E   E   E   D   E
 formats;
 3.  design an examination with Table of Test Specification on specific field of specialization;   E   E   E   E   E   E
 4.  evaluate given test items based on the principles and guidelines in test construction; and   E   E   D   D   D   D
 5.  compute  and  explain  for  the  values  of  mean,  median,  mode,  range,  and  standard   D   D   D   D   D   D
 deviation and interpret the meaning of such values.
 Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course   Program/Student Outcomes Code
 After completing this course, BSEM students must be able to:   A   B   C   D   E   F   G
 1.  explain the basic concepts and principles of assessing student learning;   E   E   I   I   D   D   E
 2.  identify  the  different  learning  targets  and  their  appropriate  assessment  technique/test
 formats;          E       E      E       E       D       E       E]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[3.  design an examination with Table of Test Specification on specific field of specialization;   E   E   E   E       E       E       E
                4.  evaluate given test items based on the principles and guidelines in test construction; and   D   D   D    D       D       D       D
                5.  compute  and  explain  for  the  values  of  mean,  median,  mode,  range,  and  standard   D   D   D     D       D       D       D
                   deviation and interpret the meaning of such values.
                Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course                                                        Program/Student Outcomes Code
                After completing this course, BSEE students must be able to:                           A      B     C      D      E      F     G      H
                1.  explain the basic concepts and principles of assessing student learning;           E      E      I     I      D      D     E      E
                2.  identify  the  different  learning  targets  and  their  appropriate  assessment  technique/test
                   formats;                                                                            E      E     E      E      D      E     E      E
                3.  design an examination with Table of Test Specification on specific field of specialization;   E   E   E   E   E      E     E      E
                4.  evaluate given test items based on the principles and guidelines in test construction; and   D   D   D   D    D      D     D      D
                5.  compute  and  explain  for  the  values  of  mean,  median,  mode,  range,  and  standard   D   D   D   D     D      D     D      D
                   deviation and interpret the meaning of such values.
                *Level :          I-Introductory         E- Enabling           D-Demonstrative
                                                                          COURSE COVERAGE
                                                                                                                               Outcomes-
                Week        Intended Learning              Topic            Teaching and        Mode of       Resources          based        Due Date of
                                                                               Learning
                                                                                                                                              Submission
                 No.         Outcomes (ILO)                                                     Delivery        Needed        Assessment
                                                                            Activities (TLA)                                                   of Output
                                                                                                                                 (OBA)
                           After the completion of   Class Orientation       Lecture         Online:        Online:          Concept map       Week 2
                           the orientation, the                              Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     regarding
                           students will be able to:   CvSU Mission and      Discussion      online         recorded         assessment in
                                                     Vision                  Setting up the   discussion via   synchronous   learning.
                           1.  Inculcate in their                            LMS             Google Meet    class via
                               minds and hearts the   Course overview                        Consultation   Google Meet.
                               mission and vision of                                         via email or
                               the university.       Course requirements                     social media   Offline:
                 1
                           2.  Know the course                                               platform.      Uploaded
                               overview.             Grade computation                                      Modules
                           3.  Understand the                                                Offline:       Uploaded PPT
                               proper classroom      Classroom rules /                       Learning       Uploaded
                               decorum.              netiquette                              modules        lesson
                                                                                             Uploaded PPT  Forum
                                                                                                            discussion via
                                                                                                            LMS]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[3.  design an examination with Table of Test Specification on specific field of specialization;   E   E   E   E   E   E   E
 4.  evaluate given test items based on the principles and guidelines in test construction; and   D   D   D   D   D   D   D
 5.  compute  and  explain  for  the  values  of  mean,  median,  mode,  range,  and  standard   D   D   D   D   D   D   D
 deviation and interpret the meaning of such values.
 Program Outcomes Addressed by the Course   Program/Student Outcomes Code
 After completing this course, BSEE students must be able to:   A   B   C   D   E   F   G   H
 1.  explain the basic concepts and principles of assessing student learning;   E   E   I   I   D   D   E   E
 2.  identify  the  different  learning  targets  and  their  appropriate  assessment  technique/test
 formats;          E     E      E      E      D     E      E      E
 3.  design an examination with Table of Test Specification on specific field of specialization;   E   E   E   E   E   E   E   E
 4.  evaluate given test items based on the principles and guidelines in test construction; and   D   D   D   D   D   D   D   D
 5.  compute  and  explain  for  the  values  of  mean,  median,  mode,  range,  and  standard   D   D   D   D   D   D   D   D
 deviation and interpret the meaning of such values.
 *Level :          I-Introductory         E- Enabling           D-Demonstrative
 COURSE COVERAGE
                                          Outcomes-
 Week   Intended Learning   Topic   Teaching and   Mode of   Resources   based   Due Date of
 Learning
                                                          Submission
 No.   Outcomes (ILO)   Delivery   Needed   Assessment
 Activities (TLA)                                          of Output
                                             (OBA)
 After the completion of   Class Orientation   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Concept map   Week 2
 the orientation, the   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   regarding
 students will be able to:   CvSU Mission and   Discussion   online   recorded   assessment in
 Vision   Setting up the   discussion via   synchronous   learning.
 1.  Inculcate in their   LMS    Google Meet   class via
 minds and hearts the   Course overview   Consultation   Google Meet.
 mission and vision of   via email or
 the university.   Course requirements   social media   Offline:
 1
 2.  Know the course   platform.   Uploaded
 overview.   Grade computation      Modules
 3.  Understand the   Offline:   Uploaded PPT
 proper classroom   Classroom rules /   Learning   Uploaded
 decorum.   netiquette   modules   lesson
         Uploaded PPT  Forum
                        discussion via
                        LMS]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[After the completion of   CHAPTER I.              Lecture         Online:        Online:          Multiple choice   Week 3
                           the topic, the students   INTRODUCTION TO         Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     quiz
                           will be able to:          ASSESSMENT IN           Discussion      online         recorded
                                                     LEARNING                Class Forum     discussion via   synchronous    Accomplished
                           1.  differentiate                                                 Google Meet    class via        worksheet
                               measurement,          Lesson 1                                Consultation   Google Meet.     about the basic
                               assessment, and                                               via email or                    concepts and
                               evaluation;           Basic Concepts and                      social media   Offline:         principles in
                           2.  explain the various   Principles in                           platform.      Uploaded         assessing
                               types of              Assessing Learning                                     Modules          learning.
                 2             assessment;                                                   Offline:       Uploaded PPT
                           3.  identify the different     Assessment in                     Learning       Uploaded         Proposed plan
                               kinds of test; and      learning                              modules        lesson           for assessing
                           4.  demonstrate             Measurement                          Uploaded PPT  Forum             student
                               understanding of the    frameworks in                                        discussion via   learning based
                               different principles in   assessment                                         LMS              on the core
                               assessing learning      Types of                                                             principles in
                               through the             assessment in                                                         assessing
                               preparation of an       learning                                                              learning.
                               assessment plan.        Principles in
                                                       assessing learning



                           After the completion of   Lesson 2                Lecture         Online:        Online:          Multiple choice   Week 4
                           the topic, the students                           Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     quiz
                           will be able to:          Assessment              Discussion      online         recorded
                                                     Purposes, Learning      Class Forum     discussion via   synchronous    Accomplished
                           1.  differentiate the     Targets, and                            Google Meet    class via        worksheet
                               different types of    Appropriate Methods                     Consultation   Google Meet.     about the
                               assessment;                                                   via email or                    general
                 3-4
                           2.  discuss the role of     Purpose of                           social media   Offline:         purpose of
                               assessment in           classroom                             platform.      Uploaded         classroom
                               making instructional    assessment                                           Modules          assessment.
                               decisions to improve     Bloom’s Taxonomy                    Offline:       Uploaded PPT
                               teaching and            of Educational                        Learning       Uploaded         Formulate
                               learning; and           Objectives                            modules        lesson           learning targets
                           3.  formulate learning      Revised Bloom’s                      Uploaded PPT  Forum             and match an
                               targets that match      Taxonomy of                                          discussion via   appropriate]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[After the completion of   CHAPTER I.   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Multiple choice   Week 3
 the topic, the students   INTRODUCTION TO   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   quiz
 will be able to:   ASSESSMENT IN   Discussion   online   recorded
 LEARNING   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous   Accomplished
 1.  differentiate   Google Meet   class via   worksheet
 measurement,   Lesson 1   Consultation   Google Meet.   about the basic
 assessment, and   via email or          concepts and
 evaluation;   Basic Concepts and   social media   Offline:   principles in
 2.  explain the various   Principles in   platform.   Uploaded   assessing
 types of   Assessing Learning      Modules   learning.
 2   assessment;   Offline:   Uploaded PPT
 3.  identify the different     Assessment in   Learning   Uploaded   Proposed plan
 kinds of test; and   learning   modules   lesson   for assessing
 4.  demonstrate     Measurement   Uploaded PPT  Forum   student
 understanding of the   frameworks in   discussion via   learning based
 different principles in   assessment   LMS   on the core
 assessing learning     Types of        principles in
 through the   assessment in             assessing
 preparation of an   learning            learning.
 assessment plan.     Principles in
 assessing learning



 After the completion of   Lesson 2   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Multiple choice   Week 4
 the topic, the students   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   quiz
 will be able to:   Assessment   Discussion   online   recorded
 Purposes, Learning   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous   Accomplished
 1.  differentiate the   Targets, and   Google Meet   class via   worksheet
 different types of   Appropriate Methods   Consultation   Google Meet.   about the
 assessment;   via email or              general
 3-4
 2.  discuss the role of     Purpose of   social media   Offline:   purpose of
 assessment in   classroom   platform.   Uploaded   classroom
 making instructional   assessment      Modules   assessment.
 decisions to improve     Bloom’s Taxonomy   Offline:   Uploaded PPT
 teaching and   of Educational   Learning   Uploaded   Formulate
 learning; and   Objectives   modules   lesson   learning targets
 3.  formulate learning     Revised Bloom’s   Uploaded PPT  Forum   and match an
 targets that match   Taxonomy of   discussion via   appropriate]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[appropriate             Educational                                          LMS              assessment
                               assessment              Objectives                                                            method for a
                               methods.                Types of learning                                                    specific lesson.
                                                       targets
                                                       Appropriate
                                                       methods of
                                                       assessment

                           After the completion of   Lesson 3                Lecture         Online:        Online:          Multiple choice   Week 6
                           the topic, the students                           Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     quiz
                           will be able to:          Different               Discussion      online         recorded
                                                     Classifications of      Class Forum     discussion via   synchronous    Accomplished
                           1.  illustrate scenarios in   Assessment                          Google Meet    class via        worksheet on
                               the use of different                                          Consultation   Google Meet.     using a
                               classifications of      Classifications of                   via email or                    particular kind
                               assessment;             assessment                            social media   Offline:         of assessment.
                 5-6       2.  rationalize the         Educational and                      platform.      Uploaded
                               purpose of different    psychological                                        Modules
                               forms of                assessment                            Offline:       Uploaded PPT
                               assessment; and                                               Learning       Uploaded
                           3.  formulate                                                     modules        lesson
                               appropriate learning                                          Uploaded PPT  Forum
                               objectives that are                                                          discussion via
                               aligned with national                                                        LMS
                               standards.


                           After the completion of   CHAPTER II              Lecture         Online:        Online:          Multiple choice   Week 8
                           the topic, the students                           Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     quiz
                           will be able to:          DEVELOPMENT             Discussion      online         recorded
                                                     AND                     Class Forum     discussion via   synchronous    Accomplished
                           1.  set appropriate       ADMINISTRATION                          Google Meet    class via        worksheet on
                 7-8           instructional         OF TESTS                                Consultation   Google Meet.     selecting the
                               objectives for a                                              via email or                    right
                               written test; and     Lesson 4                                social media   Offline:         assessment
                           2.  prepare a table of                                            platform.      Uploaded         objectives for a
                               specifications for a   Planning a Written                                    Modules          written test.
                               written test.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[appropriate   Educational   LMS         assessment
 assessment   Objectives                 method for a
 methods.     Types of learning         specific lesson.
 targets
   Appropriate
 methods of
 assessment

 After the completion of   Lesson 3   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Multiple choice   Week 6
 the topic, the students   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   quiz
 will be able to:   Different   Discussion   online   recorded
 Classifications of   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous   Accomplished
 1.  illustrate scenarios in   Assessment   Google Meet   class via   worksheet on
 the use of different   Consultation   Google Meet.   using a
 classifications of     Classifications of   via email or      particular kind
 assessment;   assessment   social media   Offline:   of assessment.
 5-6   2.  rationalize the     Educational and   platform.   Uploaded
 purpose of different   psychological      Modules
 forms of   assessment   Offline:   Uploaded PPT
 assessment; and   Learning   Uploaded
 3.  formulate   modules   lesson
 appropriate learning   Uploaded PPT  Forum
 objectives that are    discussion via
 aligned with national   LMS
 standards.


 After the completion of   CHAPTER II   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Multiple choice   Week 8
 the topic, the students   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   quiz
 will be able to:   DEVELOPMENT   Discussion   online   recorded
 AND   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous   Accomplished
 1.  set appropriate   ADMINISTRATION   Google Meet   class via   worksheet on
 7-8   instructional   OF TESTS   Consultation   Google Meet.   selecting the
 objectives for a   via email or         right
 written test; and   Lesson 4   social media   Offline:   assessment
 2.  prepare a table of   platform.   Uploaded   objectives for a
 specifications for a   Planning a Written      Modules   written test.
 written test.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Test                                                                    Designing a
                                                                                             Offline:       Uploaded PPT     table of
                                                       Test objectives                      Learning       Uploaded         specifications
                                                       Objectives for                       modules        lesson           for a written
                                                       testing                               Uploaded PPT  Forum             test.
                                                       Table of                                            discussion via
                                                       Specifications                                       LMS
                                                       (TOS)
                                                       Different formats of
                                                       a test table of
                                                       specifications

                 9                                                             Midterm Examination
                 10                                                               Academic break

                           After the completion of   Lesson 5                Lecture         Online:        Online:          Multiple choice   Week 12
                           the topic, the students                           Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     quiz
                           will be able to:          Construction of         Discussion      online         recorded
                                                     Written Tests           Class Forum     discussion via   synchronous    Accomplished
                           1.  identify the                                                  Google Meet    class via        worksheet on
                               appropriate test        Guidelines in                        Consultation   Google Meet.     constructing
                               format to measure       choosing the                          via email or                    and evaluating
                 11-           learning outcomes;                                            social media   Offline:         a test.
                 12                                    appropriate test
                               and                     format                                platform.      Uploaded
                           2.  apply the general       Major categories                                    Modules
                               guidelines in           and formats of                        Offline:       Uploaded PPT
                               constructing test       traditional tests                     Learning       Uploaded
                               items for different                                           modules        lesson
                               test formats.                                                 Uploaded PPT  Forum
                                                                                                            discussion via
                                                                                                            LMS

                           After the completion of   Lesson 6                Lecture         Online:        Online:          Multiple choice   Week 13
                           the topic, the students                           Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     quiz
                 13        will be able to:          Establishing Test       Discussion      online         recorded
                                                     Validity and Reliability   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous   Accomplished
                           1.  use procedures and                                            Google Meet    class via        worksheet on
                               statistical analysis to     Test reliability                 Consultation   Google Meet.     determining]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Test                                    Designing a
         Offline:       Uploaded PPT     table of
   Test objectives   Learning   Uploaded   specifications
   Objectives for   modules   lesson    for a written
 testing   Uploaded PPT  Forum           test.
   Table of            discussion via
 Specifications         LMS
 (TOS)
   Different formats of
 a test table of
 specifications

 9   Midterm Examination
 10   Academic break

 After the completion of   Lesson 5   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Multiple choice   Week 12
 the topic, the students   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   quiz
 will be able to:   Construction of   Discussion   online   recorded
 Written Tests   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous   Accomplished
 1.  identify the   Google Meet   class via   worksheet on
 appropriate test     Guidelines in   Consultation   Google Meet.   constructing
 format to measure   choosing the   via email or      and evaluating
 11-  learning outcomes;   social media   Offline:   a test.
 12   appropriate test
 and    format   platform.   Uploaded
 2.  apply the general     Major categories      Modules
 guidelines in   and formats of   Offline:   Uploaded PPT
 constructing test   traditional tests   Learning   Uploaded
 items for different   modules   lesson
 test formats.   Uploaded PPT  Forum
                        discussion via
                        LMS

 After the completion of   Lesson 6   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Multiple choice   Week 13
 the topic, the students   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   quiz
 13   will be able to:   Establishing Test   Discussion   online   recorded
 Validity and Reliability   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous   Accomplished
 1.  use procedures and   Google Meet   class via   worksheet on
 statistical analysis to     Test reliability    Consultation   Google Meet.   determining]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[establish test validity     Test validity                    via email or                    and
                               and reliability;                                              social media   Offline:         establishing
                           2.  decide whether a                                              platform.      Uploaded         test validity and
                               test is valid or                                                             Modules          reliability.
                               reliable; and                                                 Offline:       Uploaded PPT
                           3.  decide which test                                             Learning       Uploaded
                               items are easy and                                            modules        lesson
                               difficult.                                                    Uploaded PPT  Forum
                                                                                                            discussion via
                                                                                                            LMS


                           After the completion of   CHAPTER III             Lecture         Online:        Online:          Trying out their   Week 15
                           the topic, the students                           Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     designed
                           will be able to:          ORGANIZATION,           Discussion      online         recorded         written test.
                                                     UTILIZATION, AND        Class Forum     discussion via   synchronous
                           1.  organize test data    COMMUNICATION                           Google Meet    class via        Organizing test
                               using tables and      OF TEST RESULTS                                        Google Meet.     data and
                               graphs; and                                                   Consultation                    interpreting the
                           2.  interpret frequency   Lesson 7                                via email or                    frequency
                               distribution of test                                          social media   Offline:         distribution of
                               data.                 Organization of Test                    platform.      Uploaded         the test data.
                                                     Data using Table and                                   Modules
                 14-                                 Graphs                                  Offline:       Uploaded PPT
                 15                                                                          Learning       Uploaded
                                                       Organizing and                       modules        lesson
                                                       presenting                            Uploaded PPT  Forum
                                                       ungrouped data                                       discussion via
                                                       through tables                                       LMS
                                                       Presenting test
                                                       data graphically
                                                       Shapes of
                                                       frequency
                                                       distributions]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[establish test validity     Test validity    via email or      and
 and reliability;   social media   Offline:   establishing
 2.  decide whether a   platform.   Uploaded   test validity and
 test is valid or       Modules          reliability.
 reliable; and   Offline:   Uploaded PPT
 3.  decide which test   Learning   Uploaded
 items are easy and   modules   lesson
 difficult.   Uploaded PPT  Forum
                        discussion via
                        LMS


 After the completion of   CHAPTER III   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Trying out their   Week 15
 the topic, the students   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   designed
 will be able to:   ORGANIZATION,   Discussion   online   recorded   written test.
 UTILIZATION, AND   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous
 1.  organize test data   COMMUNICATION   Google Meet   class via   Organizing test
 using tables and   OF TEST RESULTS   Google Meet.   data and
 graphs; and   Consultation              interpreting the
 2.  interpret frequency   Lesson 7   via email or   frequency
 distribution of test   social media   Offline:   distribution of
 data.   Organization of Test   platform.   Uploaded   the test data.
 Data using Table and      Modules
 14-  Graphs   Offline:   Uploaded PPT
 15      Learning       Uploaded
   Organizing and   modules   lesson
 presenting   Uploaded PPT  Forum
 ungrouped data         discussion via
 through tables         LMS
   Presenting test
 data graphically
   Shapes of
 frequency
 distributions]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[After the completion of   Lesson 8                Lecture         Online:        Online:          Use of MS         Week 16
                           the topic, the students                           Online Class    Synchronous    Video of the     Excel to
                           will be able to:          Analysis,               Discussion      online         recorded         analyze,
                                                     Interpretation, and     Class Forum     discussion via   synchronous    interpret, and
                           1.  Analyze, interpret,   Use of Test Data                        Google Meet    class via        compute for the
                               and use data                                                  Consultation   Google Meet.     measures of
                               applying (a)            Measures of central                  via email or                    central
                 16            measures of central     tendency                              social media   Offline:         tendency,
                               tendency, (b)           Measures of                          platform.      Uploaded         variability,
                               measures of             dispersion                                           Modules          position, and
                               variability, (c)        Measures of                          Offline:       Uploaded PPT     covariability of
                               measures of             position                              Learning       Uploaded         a test data.
                               position, and (d)       Standard scores                      modules        lesson
                               measures of             Measures of                          Uploaded PPT  Forum
                               covariability.          covariability                                        discussion via
                                                                                                            LMS


                           After the completion of   Lesson 9                Lecture         Online:        Online:          Accomplished      Week 17
                           the topic, the students                           Online Class                                    worksheet on
                           will be able to:          Grading and             Discussion      Synchronous    Video of the     assigning
                                                     Reporting of Test       Class Forum     online         recorded         grades and
                           1.  assess and            Results                                 discussion via   synchronous    reporting level
                               communicate                                                   Google Meet    class via        of performance
                               learners’ level of      Different types of                   Consultation   Google Meet.     and
                               achievement and         test scores                           via email or                    achievement.
                 17
                               performance through     Grading system of                    social media   Offline:
                               fair, accurate, and     the Philippine K-12                   platform.      Uploaded
                               meaningful grading      Program                                              Modules
                               and reporting                                                 Offline:       Uploaded PPT
                               methods.                                                      Learning       Uploaded
                                                                                             modules        lesson
                                                                                             Uploaded PPT  Forum
                                                                                                            discussion via
                                                                                                            LMS

                 18                                                               Final Examination]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[After the completion of   Lesson 8   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Use of MS   Week 16
 the topic, the students   Online Class   Synchronous   Video of the   Excel to
 will be able to:   Analysis,   Discussion   online   recorded   analyze,
 Interpretation, and   Class Forum   discussion via   synchronous   interpret, and
 1.  Analyze, interpret,   Use of Test Data   Google Meet   class via   compute for the
 and use data   Consultation   Google Meet.   measures of
 applying (a)     Measures of central   via email or      central
 16   measures of central    tendency    social media   Offline:   tendency,
 tendency, (b)     Measures of   platform.   Uploaded   variability,
 measures of   dispersion      Modules   position, and
 variability, (c)     Measures of   Offline:   Uploaded PPT   covariability of
 measures of   position   Learning   Uploaded   a test data.
 position, and (d)     Standard scores   modules   lesson
 measures of     Measures of   Uploaded PPT  Forum
 covariability.   covariability   discussion via
                        LMS


 After the completion of   Lesson 9   Lecture   Online:   Online:   Accomplished   Week 17
 the topic, the students   Online Class   worksheet on
 will be able to:   Grading and   Discussion   Synchronous   Video of the   assigning
 Reporting of Test   Class Forum   online   recorded   grades and
 1.  assess and   Results   discussion via   synchronous   reporting level
 communicate   Google Meet   class via   of performance
 learners’ level of     Different types of   Consultation   Google Meet.   and
 achievement and   test scores   via email or      achievement.
 17
 performance through     Grading system of   social media   Offline:
 fair, accurate, and   the Philippine K-12   platform.   Uploaded
 meaningful grading   Program      Modules
 and reporting   Offline:   Uploaded PPT
 methods.   Learning    Uploaded
         modules        lesson
         Uploaded PPT  Forum
                        discussion via
                        LMS

 18   Final Examination]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[COURSE REQUIREMENTS
               Lecture Requirements:
                   1.  Worksheets/Activities
                   2.  Midterm Exam
                   3.  Final Exam
                   4.  Recitation
                   5.  MS Excel Demo (Hands on)

               *All exams must follow a Table of Specifications (TOS) and Rubrics for evaluation of student’ performance or projects.
                                                                           GRADING SYSTEM

                    Examination
                         Worksheets                                      30%
                         Midterm Exam                                  20%
                         Final Exam                                       20%
                    Other Requirements
                         Attendance                                      10%
                         Recitation                                        10%
                         MS Excel Demo                              10%

                    TOTAL:                                                100%

                    STANDARD TRANSMUTATION TABLE FOR ALL COURSES

                       96.7 – 100.0            1.00
                       93.4 – 96.6              1.25
                       90.1 – 93.30            1.50
                       86.7 – 90.0              1.75
                       83.4 – 86.6              2.00
                       80.1 – 83.3              2.25
                       76.7 – 80.0              2.50
                       73.4 – 76.6              2.75
                       70.0 – 73.3              3.00
                       50.0 – 69.9              4.00
                       Below 50                 5.00
                       INC                          Passed the course but lack some requirements.
                       Dropped                  If unexcused absence is at least 20% of the Total Class Hours.
                                                            Total Class Hours/Semester: 54 hours Lecture]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[COURSE REQUIREMENTS
 Lecture Requirements:
 1.  Worksheets/Activities
 2.  Midterm Exam
 3.  Final Exam
 4.  Recitation
 5.  MS Excel Demo (Hands on)

 *All exams must follow a Table of Specifications (TOS) and Rubrics for evaluation of student’ performance or projects.
 GRADING SYSTEM

 Examination
      Worksheets                                      30%
      Midterm Exam                                  20%
      Final Exam                                       20%
 Other Requirements
      Attendance                                      10%
      Recitation                                        10%
      MS Excel Demo                              10%

 TOTAL:                                                100%

 STANDARD TRANSMUTATION TABLE FOR ALL COURSES

 96.7 – 100.0            1.00
 93.4 – 96.6              1.25
 90.1 – 93.30            1.50
 86.7 – 90.0              1.75
 83.4 – 86.6              2.00
 80.1 – 83.3              2.25
 76.7 – 80.0              2.50
 73.4 – 76.6              2.75
 70.0 – 73.3              3.00
 50.0 – 69.9              4.00
 Below 50                 5.00
 INC                          Passed the course but lack some requirements.
 Dropped                  If unexcused absence is at least 20% of the Total Class Hours.
                                              Total Class Hours/Semester: 54 hours Lecture]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[CLASS POLICIES
               A.  Attendance
                   Students are not allowed to have 20% or more unexcused absences of the total face to face class hours; otherwise, they will be graded as “DROPPED”.

               B.  Classroom Decorum
                   During face to face mode
                        Students are required to:
                        1.  wear identification cards at all times;
                        2.  wear face mask at all times
                        3.  observe physical/social distancing at all times
                        4.  clean the classroom before and after classes;
                        5.  avoid unnecessary noise that might disturb other classes;
                        6.  practice good manners and right conduct at all times;
                        7.  practice gender sensitivity and awareness inside the classroom; and
                        8.  come to class on time.

                   During distance mode
                        Students are required to:
                        1.  sign an honor system pledge;
                        2.  avoid giving or receiving unauthorized aid of any kind on their examinations, papers, projects and assignments,
                        3.  observe proper netiquette during on-line activities, and
                        4.  submit take home assignments on time.

               C.  Examination/ Evaluation
                        1.  Quizzes may be announced or unannounced.
                        2.  Mid-term and Final Examinations are scheduled.
                        3.  Cheating is strictly prohibited. A student who is caught cheating will be given a score of “0” for the first offense. For the second offense, the
                           student will be automatically given a failing grade in the subject.
                        4.  Students who will miss a mid-term or final examination, a laboratory exercise or a class project may be excused and allowed to take a special
                           exam, conduct a laboratory exercise or pass a class project for any of the following reasons:
                                a.  participation in a University/College-approved field trip or activity;
                                b.  due to illness or death in the family; and
                                c.  due to force majeure or natural calamities.
                                                            REFERENCES & SUPPLEMENTARY READINGS
                 References:

                        Balagtas, M., et al. (2020). Assessment in Learning 1. Manila: REX Book Store
                        Calmorin, L.P. (2011). Assessment of Student Learning 1. Manila: REX Book Store, Inc.]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[CLASS POLICIES
 A.  Attendance
 Students are not allowed to have 20% or more unexcused absences of the total face to face class hours; otherwise, they will be graded as “DROPPED”.

 B.  Classroom Decorum
 During face to face mode
      Students are required to:
 1.  wear identification cards at all times;
 2.  wear face mask at all times
 3.  observe physical/social distancing at all times
 4.  clean the classroom before and after classes;
 5.  avoid unnecessary noise that might disturb other classes;
 6.  practice good manners and right conduct at all times;
 7.  practice gender sensitivity and awareness inside the classroom; and
 8.  come to class on time.

 During distance mode
      Students are required to:
 1.  sign an honor system pledge;
 2.  avoid giving or receiving unauthorized aid of any kind on their examinations, papers, projects and assignments,
 3.  observe proper netiquette during on-line activities, and
 4.  submit take home assignments on time.

 C.  Examination/ Evaluation
 1.  Quizzes may be announced or unannounced.
 2.  Mid-term and Final Examinations are scheduled.
 3.  Cheating is strictly prohibited. A student who is caught cheating will be given a score of “0” for the first offense. For the second offense, the
 student will be automatically given a failing grade in the subject.
 4.  Students who will miss a mid-term or final examination, a laboratory exercise or a class project may be excused and allowed to take a special
 exam, conduct a laboratory exercise or pass a class project for any of the following reasons:
 a.  participation in a University/College-approved field trip or activity;
 b.  due to illness or death in the family; and
 c.  due to force majeure or natural calamities.
 REFERENCES & SUPPLEMENTARY READINGS
 References:

    Balagtas, M., et al. (2020). Assessment in Learning 1. Manila: REX Book Store
    Calmorin, L.P. (2011). Assessment of Student Learning 1. Manila: REX Book Store, Inc.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[   Navarro, R.L., et al. (2019). Assessment of Learning. Quezon City: Lorimar Publishing Inc
                        National Academy Press Washington DC (2001). Knowing what Students Know: The Science and Design of Educational Assessment
                        Nitko, Brookhart (2013) Educational Assessment of Students: Pearson
                        Mcmillan, J. (2018) Classroom Assessment: Pearson
                 Online References:
                        Department Order No. 73, series of 2012 – Guidelines on the Assessment and Rating of Learning Outcomes Under the K to 12 Basic Education
                        Curriculum. (http://www.deped.gov.ph/wpcontent/uploads/2018/07/DO_s2012_73.pdf)
                        Department Order No. 8, series of 2015 – Policy Guidelines on Classroom Assessment for K to 12 Basic Education Program.
                        (http://www.deped.gov.ph/wpcontent/uploads/2015/04/DO_s2015_08.pdf)

                                                                   REVISION HISTORY
                 Revision Number                Date of Revision                    Date of Implementation                   Highlights of Revision

                          1                       August 2019                       1  semester AY 2019 -2020                Outcome-Based Education
                                                                                     st
                                                                                     st
                          2                        June 2020                        1  semester AY 2020-2021                     Revised Syllabus
                          3                      September 2021                     1  semester AY 2021-2022                 Revised Mode of Delivery
                                                                                     st
                                                                                                                                 Revised Content
               Prepared by:                                   Evaluated by:                                 Approved:



               SHARMAINE M. BANATE                            MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                          GIL D. RAMOS,  MAHisto
               Instructor I                                   Department Chairperson                        Campus Administrator
               sharmaine.banate@cvsu.edu.ph                   Teacher Education Department                  Tanza Campus
                                                              CvSU – Tanza Campus                           Date Approved: September 13, 2022
                                                              mildred.sebastian@cvsu.edu.ph
               GERRY MAE T. SILVERO                           Date Evaluated: September 13, 2022
               Instructor I
               09092263177
               gerry.silvero@cvsu.edu.ph


               MARIA CRISTINA C. TAGLE, PABE
               Instructor I
               09068727389
               maria.tagle@cvsu.edu.ph
               Date Prepared: September 12, 2022]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[   Navarro, R.L., et al. (2019). Assessment of Learning. Quezon City: Lorimar Publishing Inc
    National Academy Press Washington DC (2001). Knowing what Students Know: The Science and Design of Educational Assessment
    Nitko, Brookhart (2013) Educational Assessment of Students: Pearson
    Mcmillan, J. (2018) Classroom Assessment: Pearson
 Online References:
    Department Order No. 73, series of 2012 – Guidelines on the Assessment and Rating of Learning Outcomes Under the K to 12 Basic Education
 Curriculum. (http://www.deped.gov.ph/wpcontent/uploads/2018/07/DO_s2012_73.pdf)
    Department Order No. 8, series of 2015 – Policy Guidelines on Classroom Assessment for K to 12 Basic Education Program.
 (http://www.deped.gov.ph/wpcontent/uploads/2015/04/DO_s2015_08.pdf)

 REVISION HISTORY
 Revision Number   Date of Revision   Date of Implementation   Highlights of Revision

 1   August 2019   1  semester AY 2019 -2020   Outcome-Based Education
 st
 st
 2   June 2020   1  semester AY 2020-2021    Revised Syllabus
 3   September 2021   1  semester AY 2021-2022   Revised Mode of Delivery
 st
                                             Revised Content
 Prepared by:   Evaluated by:   Approved:



 SHARMAINE M. BANATE   MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN   GIL D. RAMOS,  MAHisto
 Instructor I   Department Chairperson   Campus Administrator
 sharmaine.banate@cvsu.edu.ph   Teacher Education Department   Tanza Campus
    CvSU – Tanza Campus   Date Approved: September 13, 2022
    mildred.sebastian@cvsu.edu.ph
 GERRY MAE T. SILVERO   Date Evaluated: September 13, 2022
 Instructor I
 09092263177
 gerry.silvero@cvsu.edu.ph


 MARIA CRISTINA C. TAGLE, PABE
 Instructor I
 09068727389
 maria.tagle@cvsu.edu.ph
 Date Prepared: September 12, 2022]]></page></pages></Search>