<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="61"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.8.  The faculty conduct extension and


                    outreach activities.]]></page><page Index="2"/><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Summary of Extension Activities]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                                Tanza Campus
                                                                      Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                (046) 414 – 3979
                                                                                www.cvsu.edu.ph
                                                                         SUMMARY OF EXTENSION ACTIVITIES
                                                                           Second Semester, AY 2021-2022
                                                                   03/11 &                      03/2022-                                 03/2022-  05/2022-
                                           01/12/2022  01/25/2022            03/24/2022  03/18/2022     04/8/2022  4/29/2022   5/6/2022
                                                                  03/18/2022                    04/2022                                  05/2022  06/2022
                                                                             Webinar on   Fire Safety   Webinar on   Webinar on
                                           Consultative           Mentoring                                                Webinar on Disaster
                                           Meeting with   Meeting for   Session of   Business Pitching   and   Preparation  How to Start  Green the Bottle   Preparedness: Basic  Community   Revision of   TOTAL
               Faculty        Designation  DepEd ALS -   Planning of   Balikabayanihan   of   Prevention   of Extension  a Business in   + Save the   Life Support and   Needs   Extension
                                             Tanza     Extension   Micro-Business   Balikabayanihan   Webinar   Project   2022   Mother Earth   First Aid including its  Assessment  Project
                                           Implementers  Activities 2022  Training  Micro-Business   including its   Proposal  including its   including its   preparation  Proposal
                                                                              Training  preparation     preparation  preparation
                                            3 Hours     3 Hours    8 Hours    4 Hours   8 Hours  16 Hours  8 Hours  8 Hours    8 Hours   16 Hours  8 Hours  90 Hours
         1 Mildred A. Sebastian  Project Leader  ü        ü                               ü       ü        ü         ü           ü          ü       ü      78 Hours
         2 Ritch M. Banate  Project Coordinator  ü        ü          ü          ü         ü                ü         ü           ü          ü       ü      74 Hours
         3 Joyce Erika S. Senaris  Project Coordinator  ü  ü                              ü                ü         ü           ü          ü       ü      62 Hours
         4 Estelita A. Villa  Project Coordinator  ü      ü                     ü         ü       ü        ü         ü           ü          ü       ü      82 Hours
         5 Debbie Rose B. Fabian  Project Facilitator  ü  ü          ü          ü         ü                ü         ü           ü          ü              66 Hours
         6 Melona O. Igmasine  Project Facilitator  ü     ü          ü          ü         ü                ü         ü           ü          ü              66 Hours
         7 Charmaine T. Banag  Project Facilitator  ü     ü                               ü                ü         ü           ü          ü              54 Hours
         8 Mary Rose E. Elamparo  Project Facilitator  ü  ü          ü          ü         ü                ü         ü           ü          ü              66 Hours


           Prepared and Approved by:
                                                                                      Noted

                    ESTELITA A. VILLA                                                            PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
                   Extension Coordinator                                                          Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza Campus
 Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 (046) 414 – 3979
 www.cvsu.edu.ph
 SUMMARY OF EXTENSION ACTIVITIES
 Second Semester, AY 2021-2022
 03/11 &    03/2022-                                 03/2022-  05/2022-
 01/12/2022  01/25/2022  03/24/2022  03/18/2022  04/8/2022  4/29/2022  5/6/2022
 03/18/2022  04/2022                                 05/2022  06/2022
 Webinar on   Fire Safety   Webinar on   Webinar on
 Consultative   Meeting for   Mentoring   Business Pitching   and   Preparation  How to Start  Green the Bottle   Webinar on Disaster   Revision of
 Meeting with   Session of             Preparedness: Basic  Community   TOTAL
 Faculty  Designation  DepEd ALS -   Planning of   Balikabayanihan   of   Prevention   of Extension  a Business in   + Save the   Life Support and   Needs   Extension
 Tanza   Extension   Micro-Business   Balikabayanihan   Webinar   Project   2022   Mother Earth   First Aid including its  Assessment  Project
 Implementers  Activities 2022  Training  Micro-Business   including its   Proposal  including its   including its   preparation  Proposal
 Training  preparation  preparation  preparation
 3 Hours  3 Hours  8 Hours  4 Hours  8 Hours  16 Hours  8 Hours  8 Hours  8 Hours  16 Hours  8 Hours  90 Hours
 1 Mildred A. Sebastian  Project Leader  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü     78 Hours
 2 Ritch M. Banate  Project Coordinator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  74 Hours
 3 Joyce Erika S. Senaris  Project Coordinator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  62 Hours
 4 Estelita A. Villa  Project Coordinator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  82 Hours
 5 Debbie Rose B. Fabian  Project Facilitator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  66 Hours
 6 Melona O. Igmasine  Project Facilitator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  66 Hours
 7 Charmaine T. Banag  Project Facilitator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü        54 Hours
 8 Mary Rose E. Elamparo  Project Facilitator  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  ü  66 Hours


 Prepared and Approved by:
  Noted

 ESTELITA A. VILLA  PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
 Extension Coordinator  Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 235 – 7997
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                 EXTENSION SERVICES

                           SUMMARY OF EXTENSION ACTIVITIES BASED ON THE RESULTS OF THE
                                                 COMMUNITY NEEDS ASSESSMENT


                                Date                     Title of Activity            Needs Assessment
                                                                                             Result
                         December 3, 2021            Adapting, Evolving, and         Need for a webinar on
                                                        Thriving in Remote             Remote Learning
                                                             Learning
                         December 2, 2021            The Role of Teachers in         Need for a webinar on
                                                      Promoting Multilingual         Multilingual Education
                                                     Education: Preparing the
                                                     Pre-Service Teachers in
                                                      Multilingual Classroom
                                                              Setting
                          June 2 – 4, 2021           Managing Teaching and           Need for a webinar on
                                                       Learning in the New         teaching and learning on
                                                       Normal and Special             the New Normal and
                                                            Education                  special Education
                         February 28, 2020           Life and Career Skills for     Need for training on life
                                                       Alternative Learning             and career skills
                                                     System (ALS) Students
                        February – April 2019         Writing/Reading Literacy         Need for non-formal
                                                                                     education and remedial
                                                                                             classes
                      September – November            Writing/Reading Literacy         Need for non-formal
                                2018                                                 education and remedial
                                                                                             classes
                          April 6 and 8, 2018        Remedial Classes to High          Need for non-formal
                                                       School 4P’s Members           education and remedial
                                                                                             classes
                       March 3, 10, 17, 24, 2018     Remedial Classes to High          Need for non-formal
                                                       School 4P’s Members           education and remedial
                                                                                             classes
                       February 9 and 23, 2018       Remedial Classes to High          Need for non-formal
                                                       School 4P’s Members           education and remedial
                                                                                             classes
                              April 2019                Writing and Reading            Need for non-formal
                                                    Numeracy for Out-of-School       education and remedial
                                                              Children                       classes]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[March 2019                 Writing and Reading            Need for non-formal
                                                    Numeracy for Out-of-School       education and remedial
                                                              Children                       classes
                            February 2019               Writing and Reading            Need for non-formal
                                                    Numeracy for Out-of-School       education and remedial
                                                              Children                       classes
                           November 2018            Writing and Reading Literacy       Need for non-formal
                                                     for Out-of-School Children      education and remedial
                                                                                             classes
                            October 2018            Writing and Reading Literacy       Need for non-formal
                                                     for Out-of-School Children      education and remedial
                                                                                             classes
                          September 2018                Writing and Reading            Need for non-formal
                                                    Numeracy for Out-of-School       education and remedial
                                                              Children                       classes
                           November 2017            Writing and Reading Literacy       Need for non-formal
                                                     for Out-of-School Children      education and remedial
                                                                                             classes
                            October 2017                Writing and Reading            Need for non-formal
                                                    Numeracy for Out-of-School       education and remedial
                                                              Children                       classes
                          September 2017            Writing and Reading Literacy       Need for non-formal
                                                     for Out-of-School Children      education and remedial
                                                                                             classes



                    Prepared by:


                    RITCH M. BANATE
                    Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[COMMUNITY NEEDS ASSESSMENT


                                                       2015]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES

                                RESULTS OF COMMUNITY NEEDS ASSESSMENT
                                     IN BARANGAY BAGTAS, TANZA, CAVITE


                       The population explosion in Brgy. Bagtas has led to an initiative to alleviate
               poverty  in  the  barangay.  Brgy.  Bagtas,  having  the  most  number  of  populations  in

               Tanza  (20,370  out  of  188,755),  has  been  the  site  for  relocation  and  reclamation.
               However, people, who were displaced out of their previous addresses, were relocated

               in the said barangay without having a regular source of living. Some of them could not

               find a decent job because they lack the educational and other requirements for the job
               that they were applying for. Others could not start any business because they lack the

               skills in preparing innovative products that could help them earn additional income for
               their families.

                       Thus,  Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus  shall  launch  a  full-blown
               extension program through the Research and Extension Office. The campus extension

               program shall be called as “BAGTAS with CvSU – Tanza (Bagtas ay Aasenso at

               Giginhawa kung Tayo Ay Sama-sama with CvSU – Tanza)”. The main goal of the
               program is to increase the quality of life of the citizens in the said barangay.

                       For  this  reason,  it  is  essential  to  conduct  a  Community  Needs  Assessment

               (CNA) aiming to identify the needs in order to provide appropriate services to those
               needs.  CNA  will  provide  database  information  on  the  current  status  of  each

               community.  The  study  will  also  be  able  to  provide  a  framework  for  identifying
               appropriate  community,  profiling  of  their  needs,  and  provide  sustainable  extension

               program to meet specific needs.
                       Cavite State University – Tanza Campus is located in Tanza, Cavite so, the

               extension  unit  has  chosen  one  of  the  barangays  in  Tanza  to  be  adopted  for  its

               extension activities. It adopted barangay Bagtas since this is the barangay that has
               the most number of populations in the Municipality of Tanza.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Results and Quantitative Summary of Community Needs Assessment
                       A committee was formed to study and gather benchmark information on the

               status, needs, and conditions of selected communities in Tanza, Cavite during the
               second  semester,  AY  2014  –  2015.  The  committee  was  headed  by  the  Extension

               Coordinator. Two faculty members from the different departments of the campus were

               selected as members of the committee to ensure that the programs will conform to the
               mandate of the university. The committee used the following benchmark information,

               provided by Tanza Municipal Planning and Development Office (TMPDO), in order to
               assess which group of individuals will be the target beneficiaries of the proposal.



               Table 1. Data of Brgy. Bagtas population 2010 by sex, age, and employment
                                                 Male               Female                  Total
                 Brgy. Bagtas                   12,316               8,054                 20,370
                 Population
                 Age Bracket
                           5-9                  1,453                 951                  2,404
                          10-14                 1,299                 849                  2,148
                        OTHERS                  9,564                6,254                 15,818
                 Enrolment Data
                    Pre-School (3-6)            1,213                 878                  2,091
                   Elementary (7-12)            1,176                 823                  1,999
                 Employment Data
                        Employed                6,908                4,517                 11,425
                      Unemployed                 600                  393                   993
                 Not in the labor force         4,808                3,144                 7,952
               Source: Philippine Statistics Authority and Tanza Municipal Planning and Development Office
               The committee used the descriptive design of a study. Data utilized in the study mainly

               came  from  the  responses  on  the  self-administered  survey  questions  that  were
               distributed to the residents of Brgy. Bagtas. Residents were selected using simple

               random sampling.
                       Results revealed that:

                          •  87.14% of the residents perceived that they lack regular sources of living
                              in the barangay because most (48.15%) of them lack the educational
                              requirements and some (38.99%) lack the technical skills to either start
                              a small business or to apply for a regular job;]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[•  47.06% of the residents believed that these problems and issues may
                              be addressed through conduct of free seminars/trainings on livelihood
                              programs;
                          •  18.33% of the residents suggested to conduct free seminar on candle
                              making; 17.33% suggested soap making; 15.33% suggested delicacy
                              preparation such as yema, ube, leche flan, puto, and others; 13.67%
                              suggested dishwashing liquid making; 13.00% suggested recycling of
                              plastic  products  and  water  lily  bags;  while  the  remaining  8.67%
                              suggested perfume-making;

                          •  46.50% of the residents said that they have baking and cooking skills
                              and they are willing to undergo trainings for delicacy preparation; also
                              22.50% reiterated that they have the skills in the arts and trades and that
                              they  are  willing  to  undergo  trainings  on  preparation  of  innovative
                              products such as candle, soap, and dishwashing liquid;


               Table 1. Main Source of Income
                Main Source of Income                       FREQUENCY                  PERCENT
                   Employment in government or                   123                     87.86
                            private sector
                               Farming                             6                      4.29
                Self-Employment/Entrepreneurship                   8                      5.71
                    Overseas Contract Workers                      3                      2.14


               Table 2. Monthly Family Income
                Monthly Family Income (Php)                FREQUENCY                  PERCENT
                           5000 & below                         101                      72.14
                           5001 – 10,000                         32                      22.86
                          10,001 – 15,000                         7                        5

               Table 3. Most Common Type/Kind of Dwelling Units
                   Most Common Type/Kind of                FREQUENCY                  PERCENT
                          Dwelling units
                              Concrete                            5                       3.57
                        Nipa/bamboo/wood                          2                       1.43
                             Row house                          133                        95

               Table 4. Most common source of drinking water
                      Most Common Source                   FREQUENCY                  PERCENT
                         of Drinking Water
                       Artesian wells (poso)                      7                        5
                        Water works system                      131                      93.57
                         Deep wells (balon)                       2                       1.43]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Table 5. Presence of school in the barangay
                             SCHOOL                       GOVERNMENT                   PRIVATE
                             Day Care                             5                        5
                             Pre-school                           1                        5
                            Elementary                            1                        5
                            High School                           1                        5
                              College                             1

               Table 6. Health facilities
                          HEALTH FACILITIES                                 FREQUENCY
                Government
                     Barangay Health Station                                   1
                      Health/Nutrition Center                                  0
                    Community Hospital Clinic                                  0
                Private
                           Dental Clinic                                       0
                         Medical Hospital                                      0
                              Hospital                                         0

               Table 7. Most Common Transport Facilities
                           TRANSPORTATION                                   FREQUENCY
                                Jeep                                         140
                              Tricycle                                       140

               Table 8. Predominant Religion
                             RELIGION                      FREQUENCY                PERCENTAGE
                          Roman Catholic                         68                      48.57
                             Born Again                          17                      12.14
                                INC                              30                      21.43
                         Jehovah’s Witness                        4                       2.86
                               Aglipay                            6                       4.29
                               UCCP                               8                       5.71
                                Islam                             3                       2.14
                  Church of the Latter-Day Saints                 4                       2.86

               Table 9. Problems/issues encountered on living in barangay
                 PROBLEMS/ISSUES ENCOUNTERED                                FREQUENCY
                        Peace and Security                                     2
                           Overcrowding                                       12
                Lack of Regular Sources of Living                             122
                         Lack of Education                                    68
                      Lack of Technical Skills                                54
                      Lack of Job Experience                                  14
                           Health Issues                                      22
                              Abuses                                          13

               Table 10. Suggested ways to address problem
                SUGGESTED WAYS TO ADDRESS PROBLEMS                               FREQUENCY
                    Free tutorials on computer literacy                           31]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Free seminars/trainings on livelihood                          66
                           Non-formal education                                   54

               Table 11. Suggested livelihood program
                 PROBLEMS/ISSUES ENCOUNTERED                                  FREQUENCY
                             Water Lily Bags                                      18
                                 Perfume                                          12
                              Candle Making                                       25
                               Soap Making                                        24
                        Recycling Plastic Products                                18
                 Dishwashing Liquid/Fabric Conditioner                            19
                           Delicacy preparation                                   22
                           Baking and Pastries                                    10
                             Eco-bag making                                       8
                           Flower Arrangement                                     8
                Meat/Food Processing and Preservation                             15

               Table 12. Skills
                                       SKILLS                                    FREQUENCY
                                 Computer                                          5
                                  Sewing                                           9
                              Arts and Crafts                                     23
                                   Baking                                         47
                                  Cooking                                         47



               Problems to be addressed:
                   1.  Seminars/trainings on livelihood education/program

                   2.  Non-formal education and remedial classes
                   3.  Tutorials/trainings on computer literacy

                   4.  Health and wellness


               Prepared by:



               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
               Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                       Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                      (046)  235  –  7997
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES

                         NARRATIVE REPORT ON COMMUNITY NEEDS ASSESSMENT


                       Cavite  State  University  –  Tanza  Campus  conducted  a  community  needs

               assessment in Barangay Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite on January 30-31 and February 7,
               2015. The activity was headed by the campus extension coordinator, Ms. Mildred A.

               Sebastian. The officers and members of different student organization such as CSG,

               FAME, COPE and CSS, assisted in conducting interviews among the residents of the
               community. The event was also participated by the other faculty members and key

               officials of the campus.


                       The needs assessment was done to address the needs, problems or gaps

               between current conditions and desired conditions of the community. This also helps
               to identify the strengths and resources available in the community to meet the needs

               of the children, youth and families. This assessment pays particular attention to the
               capabilities of the community, including its citizens, agencies, and local organizations.



                       Prior  to  the  needs  assessment,  the  extension  coordinator  talked  to  the
               barangay captain over the phone, to offer an extension project that can cater the

               needs of the community. The barangay captain was overwhelmed to hear that the
               campus will help them to alleviate poverty in the barangay through this extension

               project. He also said that he is really willing to provide any assistance for the success

               of the project.


                       As the interview and needs assessment started, one of the barangay staff also
               accompanied  the  group  in  going  to  the  houses  of  the  residents.  Prepared

               questionnaires were used during the interview. The assessment went well because

               the interviewees were very cooperative. It was indeed a productive day for the group.]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Certificate of appearance which was duly signed by the barangay captain was

               issued to the interviewers.


               Prepared by:





               MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN

               Extension Coordinator


               Noted:






               CRISTINA M. SIGNO
               Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Approved Campus Extension Project]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[ACCOMPLISHMENT REPORT/


                                         TRAINING REPORT


                                                       2017 -2021]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                            Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                      Indang, Cavite
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                   TRAINING REPORT



               Campus/College/Unit:         Tanza
               Title of Training:         Adapting, Evolving and Thriving in Remote Learning and Coping
                                          with  the  New  Normal:  Addressing  the  Emotional  and  Mental
                                          Needs of the Students
               Related Degree/Program:  Bachelor of Secondary Education
               No. of days:                 1 day
               Date conducted:            December 03, 2021
               Place:                       Via Cisco Webex
               Partner Agency/ies:          N/A
               Part of a project:                   /        Yes                           No

               Category of training:               Technical, vocational,         Agricultural and
                                                  livelihood                       environmental trainings
                                                  Continuing education for        Basic education
                                                  professionals
                                                    Gender and Development              /   Others




               I.  Objectives of the Training

                   The  webinar  served  as  a  platform  to  provide  knowledge  to  the  pre-service  teachers
                   regarding remote learning and help them cope with the new normal of education.

               II.  Mode and Method of Training

                   Webinar (Cisco Webex)

               III.  Number of Participants

                   1.  By Sex

                       a.  Male                                                         68
                       b.  Female                                                       233
                          TOTAL                                                         301

                   2.  By Category

                       a.  Student                                                      294
                       b.  Farmer]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[c.  Fisherfolk
                       d.  Agricultural Technician
                       e.  Government Employee                                          6



                       f.  Private Employee
                       g.  Other Agency                                                  1

                          TOTAL                                                         301
                   3.  For technical, vocational, and livelihood trainings only

                       a.  No. of participants who are solo parents                    N/A
                       b.  No. of participants with disabilities

                       c.  Type of disability

               IV.  Evaluation

                    1.  No. of participants surveyed                                    210
                    2. Client’s rating on the training in terms of
                       relevance
                       a.  5                                                            168
                       b.  4                                                            33
                       c.  3                                                             8
                       d.  2                                                             1

                       e.  1
                    3.  Client’s rating on the training in terms of quality
                       a.  5                                                            169
                       b.  4                                                            30
                       c.  3                                                             9
                       d.  2                                                             2
                       e.  1
                    4. Client’s rating on the training in terms of
                       timeliness
                       a.  5                                                            162
                       b.  4                                                            34
                       c.  3                                                            12
                       d.  2                                                             2

                       e.  1

               V.  Budget

                   1.  Amount charged to CvSU (campus/college/unit)                 Php 3,000
                   2. Amount charged to partner agency (PhP) (if there
                       is no cash involve, include estimates/value)

               VI. Problem/s encountered, action/s taken, and recommendations
                   Internet connectivity of the participants]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[VII. Photos]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[The resource speakers during her talk about emotional and mental needs of the students]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Faculty members, resource speaker and participants during the
                                                         webinar


               Attachments:

               1.  Program
               2.  Attendance Sheet

               Prepared by:

                                                                                     December 13, 2021
                    MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN
                      Training Coordinator                                               Date


               Verified by:

                                                                                     December 13, 2021
                    ESTELITA A. VILLA
                     Extension Coordinator                                               Date]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                            Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                      Indang, Cavite
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                   TRAINING REPORT


                Campus/College/Unit:       Tanza
                    Title of Training:         The  Role  of  Teachers  in  Promoting  Multilingual  Education:
                                              Preparing the Pre-Service Teachers in Multilingual Classroom
                                          Setting
               Related Degree/Program:  Bachelor of Secondary Education and Elementary Education
               No. of days:                  0.5
               Date conducted:            December 02, 2021

               Place:                       Via Cisco Webex
               Partner Agency/ies:          N/A

               Part of a project:                 /       Yes                             No
               Category of training:              Technical, vocational,          Agricultural and
                                                  livelihood                      environmental trainings


                                                  Continuing education for        Basic education
                                             /    professionals


                                                  Gender and Development          Others



               I.  Objectives of the Training

                   The  webinar  served  as  a  platform  to  provide  meaningful  activities  to  the  pre-service
                   teachers  relative  to  the  work  of  in-service  teachers  and  prepare  them  in  multilingual
                   education.

               II.  Mode and Method of Training

                   Webinar (Cisco Webex)

               III.  Number of Participants

                   1.  By Sex

                       a.  Male                                                         68
                       b.  Female                                                       233
                          TOTAL                                                         301

                   2.  By Category

                       a.  Student                                                      294]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[b.  Farmer
                       c.  Fisherfolk
                       d.  Agricultural Technician

                       e.  Government Employee                                          6


                       f.  Private Employee
                       g.  Other Agency                                                  1
                          TOTAL                                                         301
                   3.  For technical, vocational, and livelihood trainings only

                       a.  No. of participants who are solo parents                    N/A

                       b.  No. of participants with disabilities
                       c.  Type of disability


               IV.  Evaluation


                    1.  No. of participants surveyed                                    258
                    2. Client’s rating on the training in terms of
                       relevance
                       a.  5                                                            192
                       b.  4                                                            47
                       c.  3                                                            17
                       d.  2                                                             2
                       e. 1
                    3.  Client’s rating on the training in terms of quality
                       a.  5                                                            183
                       b.  4                                                            52
                       c.  3                                                            19

                       d.  2                                                             4
                       e. 1

                    4. Client’s rating on the training in terms of
                       timeliness
                       a.  5                                                            158
                       b.  4                                                            74
                       c.  3                                                            21
                       d.  2                                                             4
                       e. 1

               V.  Budget

                   1.  Amount charged to CvSU (campus/college/unit)                  Php 1,500

                   2. Amount charged to partner agency (PhP) (if there
                       is no cash involved, include estimates/value)


               VI. Problem/s encountered, action/s taken, and recommendations

                          Internet connectivity of the participants]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[VII. Photos]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[The resource speakers during his talk about the roles of teachers in promoting multilingual education




































                            Faculty members, resource speaker and participants during the webinar]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Attachments:

               1.  Program
               2.  Attendance Sheet

               Prepared by:

                                                                                 December 13, 2021
                     DRED  A. SEBASTAIN
                      Training Coordinator                                               Date


               Verified by:


                     ELITA A. VILLA                                              December 13, 2021

                     Extension Coordinator                                               Date]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                            Don Severino de las Alas Campus
                                                      Indang, Cavite
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                   TRAINING REPORT


               Campus/College/Unit:        Tanza
               Title of Training:          Managing Teaching and Learning in the New Normal and
                                           Special Education
               Related Degree/Program:  Bachelor of Secondary Education and Elementary Education
               No. of days:                3 days
               Date conducted:             June 2-4, 2021
               Place:                      Via Facebook Live and Zoom
               Partner Agency/ies:         N/A
               Part of a project:                     /     Yes                           No
               Category of training:              Technical, vocational,          Agricultural and
                                                  livelihood                      environmental trainings
                                            /     Continuing education for        Basic education
                                                  professionals
                                                  Gender and Development          Others


               I.  Objectives of the Training

                   The  webinar  series  served  as  a  platform  to  develop  problem  solving  skills,  embrace
                   uniqueness, uplift mental health and strategies to teach literature amidst adversity during
                   this new normal of education.

               II.  Mode and Method of Training

                   Webinar (Facebook Live and Zoom)

               III.  Number of Participants

                   1.  By Sex

                       a.  Male                                                         73
                       b.  Female                                                      178
                          TOTAL                                                        251

                   2.  By Category

                       a.  Student                                                     208
                       b.  Farmer
                       c.  Fisherfolk
                       d.  Agricultural Technician
                       e.  Government Employee                                          43


                                                                                                         1]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[f.  Private Employee
                       g.  Others: Business Owners
                          TOTAL                                                        251
                   3.  For technical, vocational, and livelihood trainings only

                       a.  No. of participants who are solo parents                    N/A
                       b.  No. of participants with disabilities
                       c.  Type of disability

               IV.  Evaluation

                    1.  No. of participants surveyed                                   141
                    2.  Client’s rating on the training in terms of
                       relevance
                       a.  5                                                           138
                       b.  4                                                             3
                       c.  3
                       d.  2
                       e.  1
                    3.  Client’s rating on the training in terms of quality
                       a.  5                                                           137
                       b.  4                                                             4
                       c.  3
                       d.  2
                       e.  1
                    4.  Client’s rating on the training in terms of
                       timeliness
                       a.  5                                                           138
                       b.  4                                                             3
                       c.  3
                       d.  2
                       e.  1

               V.  Budget

                   1.  Amount charged to CvSU (campus/college/unit)                 Php 7,500
                   2.  Amount charged to partner agency (PhP) (if there
                       is no cash involve, include estimates/value)

               VI. Problem/s encountered, action/s taken, and recommendations
                   Internet connectivity of the participants








                                                                                                         2]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[VII. Photos

















































































                                                                                                         3]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[The resource speakers










                                                                                                         4]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[The resource speakers




                                                                                                         5]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Faculty members, resource speaker and participants during the webinar



















                                                                                                         6]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Faculty members, resource speaker and participants during the webinar
















                                                                                                         7]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Attachments:

               1.  Program
               2.  Attendance Sheet

               Prepared by:


                           MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                                      June 9, 2021
                      Training Coordinator                                               Date


               Verified by:


                       RITCH M. BANATE                                                June 9, 2021
                     Extension Coordinator                                               Date


























































                                                                                                         8]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414 - 3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                  EXTENSION SERVICES

                                                   NARRATIVE REPORT


                    OPLAN KARUNUNGAN for ALTERNATIVE LEARNING SYSTEM STUDENTS
                                                    February 29, 2020


               Topic 1: Life and Career Skills

                       Cavite State University-Tanza Campus conducted another extension activity as
               part of its extension program, Bagtas ay Aasenso at Giginhawa kung Tayo Ay Sama-

               Sama (BAGTAS) with CvSU – Tanza on February 29, 2020.

                       In  partnership  with  Alternative  Learning  System,  Cavite  State  University  Tanza
               Campus’ Oplan Karunungan program aims to help the out-of-school youth and adults in

               the barangay finished their secondary education.
                       On  February  29,  2020,  the  extension  services  unit  of  CvSU  –  Tanza  Campus

               conducted a life and career skills seminar to ALS students. Ms. Mary Rose E. Elamparo

               served as the resource person for the session. During the session, Ms. Elamparo talked
               about some of the most important life and career skills that the students should have such

               as how to develop their personalities, interpersonal communication, work habits, right and
               responsibilities  and  exploring  entrepreneurship.  During  her  talk,  she  asked  about  the

               dream of each participants and most of them were dreaming to become a teacher, nurse

               and etc. Then a follow-up question why they opted to stop studying and choose to work
               for their family. They answered that they need to stop studying as their parents cannot

               support their education anymore as some of their parents earn below minimal wage and
               sufficient only to their basic needs. This really implies the need to help these students

               finished their secondary education in order for them to achieve their dreams in life.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[During the seminar, they were also taught on how to acquire the attitude, skills and
               knowledge necessary for earning a living and promoting a sustainable lifestyle. They were

               also  encourage  to  attend  the  trainings  provided  by  the  extension  services  unit  of  the

               campus  for  them  to  be  able  to  have  extra  income.  Before  the  session  ends,  the
               participants were asked about their commitments on how they will achieve their dreams,

               most of them answered that they were really committed and will do everything just to

               finish their studies.
                       A total of 45 participants attended the training. The breakdown of the attendees is


               as follows:


                               PARTICIPANTS                                    HEAD COUNT



                               Faculty Members                                       9


                            Campus Administrator                                     1



                                   Trainees                                          9


                                    TOTAL                                            19]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[PHOTO DOCUMENTATION

                    OPLAN KARUNUNGAN for ALTERNATIVE LEARNING SYSTEM STUDENTS
                                                 (Life and Career Skills)
                                                     February 28, 2020

















































                           ALS students during their life and career skills session with Ms. Elamparo]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                            (Writing and Reading Numeracy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                       April 2019


                       During the month of April 2019, the Teacher Education Department headed by Ms.
               Mildred A. Sebastian, together by the Circle of Potential Educators together with selected

               faculty members of the said department spearheaded the teaching of Writing Numbers in the

               youngsters of Barangay Bagtas, Tanza Cavite. The pre-service teachers took turns in assisting
               the  learners  as  the  instructors  supervise  the  teaching  process.  Some  Education  students

               participated in doing the other necessary task such as cooking and preserving the cleanliness
               of the venue. The learners were very much eager to learn as they scribble their pencils on their

               worksheet. The guardians were delighted as the foods and refreshments were served as they
               wait for their young ones. It was indeed a remarkable and a truly successful month.

                       A total of 58 participants attended the training during this month. The breakdown of

               the attendees are as follows:
                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                30
                              Faculty Members                                      3
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     24
                                    Total                                         58


               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:


               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                            (Writing and Reading Numeracy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                       March 2019


                       During  the  second  month  of  Oplan  Karunungan  together  with  Circle  of  Potential

               Educators (COPE), and Ms. Mildread A. Sebastian, adviser and Department Head of the
               Teacher Education Department participated in teaching less fortunate young individuals in

               reading numbers. The Mathematics Majors facilitated the learners in familiarizing in symbols
               and numbers. The learners enjoyed the activity as they participate in motivational activities

               and learning tasks. Some education students were assigned as food committee and aide to the

               teachers to make the activity more productive. The guardians patiently waited on the lounge
               area as their youngsters enjoyed that day of learning. The CoPE members generously shared

               their information and efforts to make the day a success.
                       A total of 58 participants attended the training. The breakdown of the attendees are as

               follows:

                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                30
                              Faculty Members                                      3
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     24
                                    Total                                         58


               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:


               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                            (Writing and Reading Numeracy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                    February 2019


                       During  the  Month  of  February  2019,  the  Extension  Services  Unit  and  Teacher

               Education Department of CvSU- Tanza Campus conducted a teaching session and feeding
               program  as  part  of  the  Oplan  Karunungan.  This  program  aims  to  give  the  out of  school

               children a chance to learn and experience the usual classroom settings. There were many
               youngsters who attended the first month of the class. The Education students together with

               Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian, Adviser, served as the teachers for them who cheerfully shared

               their knowledge. All of the participants were proactive in the activities, especially in writing
               numbers. Many chose to do board work while others enjoyed the activities in their happy

               places. The kids were assisted by the Education students. Some of the students cooked food
               for the feeding program. They made soup for the participants and other guardians who are

               waiting outside the venue. The event ended as a fruitful one. The learning activity achieved

               the objectives of teaching how to write numbers and practiced their knowledge about it.
                       A total of 58 participants attended the training. The breakdown of the attendees are as

               follows:
                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                30
                              Faculty Members                                      3
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     24
                                    Total                                         58


               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:


               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                             (Writing and Reading Literacy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                     November 2018


                       During  this  month,  Ms.  Mildred  A.  Sebastian,  Adviser  of  the  Circe  of  Potential
               Educators (COPE), Department Head of the Teacher Education Department and Education

               together with participating instructors and students both Mathematics and English majors

               started the Reading of Letters for the participants of Oplan Karunungan in CUSU – T3, Tanza
               Campus. This activity aims to teach the participants how to read letters as one of the major

               objectives of the program is to increase literacy of the participants through having the ability
               to read letters.

                       At first, the students were timid in participating but as soon as they get comfortable
               with each other, it became smooth and free flowing. The tasks of everyone were distributed

               evenly and the event was indeed a success.

                       A total of 49 participants attended the training during this month. The breakdown of
               the attendees are as follows


                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                25
                              Faculty Members                                      3
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     20
                                    Total                                         49

               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:


               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                             (Writing and Reading Literacy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                      October 2018


                       During October 2018, the Teacher Education Department headed by Ms. Mildred A.
               Sebastian together with the Circle of Potential Educators and faculty members of the said

               department conducted another Oplan Karunugan activity which is the teaching of Writing

               Letters  in  the  out-of-school  children  of  Barangay  Bagtas,  Tanza  Cavite.  The  pre-service
               teachers as well as the instructors supervise the teaching process during this month. Some

               Education students participated in doing the other necessary tasks such as cooking food for
               the participants, cleaning the venue, distributing learning materials to the participants. The

               learners were very much eager to write as they hold their pencils with so much excitement.
               During the sessions, it was observed that most of the participants are still grasping on how to

               write letters but with the patience and assistance of the facilitators, they were able to write

               letters. The guardians were delighted as the food and refreshments were served as they wait
               for their young ones. It was indeed a remarkable and a truly successful month for  Oplan

               Karunungan team.

                       A total of 50 participants attended the training. The breakdown of the attendees are as
               follows:

                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                25
                              Faculty Members                                      4
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     20
                                    Total                                         50

               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:


               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                            (Writing and Reading Numeracy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                    September 2018


                       During the month of September, the Extension Services Unit and Teacher Education
               Department of CvSU – Tanza campus conducted a teaching session and feeding program as

               part of the Oplan Karunungan. This program aims to give change to the out-of-school children

               to  learn  and  experience  the  usual  classroom  settings.  There  were  many  youngsters  who
               attended the first month of the class. The Education students together with Ms. Mildred A.

               Sebastian,  Adviser,  Ms.  Gerry  Mae  T.  Silvero,  Mary  Joy  Angelique  Mojica,  and  Maria
               Cristina C. Tagle, faculty members, served as the teachers for them who cheerfully shared

               their knowledge. All of the students really enjoyed it as it was incorporated with games so
               that  students  may  not  get  bored  during  the  session.  The  children  were  assisted  by  the

               Education students and participated through preparing the snacks for the participants. They

               made snacks for the participants and other guardians who are waiting outside the venue. To
               sum up the sessions for this month, the learning activity achieved the objectives of teaching

               how to write numbers and practiced their knowledge about it.

                       A total of 50 participants attended the training. The breakdown of the attendees are as
               follows:

                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                25
                              Faculty Members                                      4
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     24
                                    Total                                         54

               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:


               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                                   (Remedial Classes to High School 4P’s Members)
                                                February 6 and 8, 2018


                       During the month of April 2018, the Extension Services Unit and Teacher Education

               Department of CvSU Tanza Campus continued the remedial program to high school 4P's
               members as part of the Oplan Karunungan. This program aims to help the high school 4P's

               members to excel in their subjects such as Mathematics, English, Science and other subjects.
                       For this month, 18 students attended the remedial classes who are members of 4P's.

               These students are known to have difficulty in their subjects. During the remedial classes for

               this month, they were taught subjects such as Mathematics, Science and English. The students
               really enjoyed the remedial classes as each of them had given a chance to express themselves

               during their English and Communication remedial classes.
                       To test if the remedial classes somewhat improve their knowledge on the subjects,

               they were given some exams similar to the structure of their exams in school. The results of

               their exam are quite impressive as their verbal and numerical skills really improved.
                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                12
                              Faculty Members                                      4
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     18
                                    Total                                         35

               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:



               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                                   (Remedial Classes to High School 4P’s Members)
                                               March 3, 10, 17, 24, 2018


                       During the month of March 2018, the Extension Services Unit and Teacher Education

               Department of CvSU- Tanza Campus continued the remedial program to high school 4P's
               members as part of the Oplan Karunungan. This program aims to help the high school 4P's

               members to excel in their subjects such as Mathematics, English, Science and other subjects.
                       For  this  month,  15  students  attended  the  program  as  recommended  by  the  Tanza

               National Trade School - Annex officer-in-charge and who are 4P's members. These students

               are certified to having difficulty in their subjects. During the remedial classes for this month,
               they were taught subjects such as Mathematics, Science and English. Through interactive

               activities and other methods that encourage learning without boredom, students are observed
               to have improvements compared from the start of the remedial classes. Some of them got

               higher scores in their examinations which is a good manifestation that the remedial program

               helped them to improve their academic standings.
                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                12
                              Faculty Members                                      4
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     15
                                    Total                                         32

               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:



               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                            (Writing and Reading Numeracy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                     November 2017


               During  November  2017,  the  Teacher  Education  Department  headed  by  Ms.  Mildred  A.
               Sebastian together with the Circle of Potential Educators and faculty members of the said

               department conducted another Oplan Karunungan sessions which is the teaching of writing

               and reading numbers to out-of-school children of Barangay Bagtas, Tanza Cavite. The pre-
               service teachers as well as the instructors supervised the teaching process during this month.

               Some Education students participated in doing the other necessary tasks such as cooking food
               for the participants, cleaning the venue, distributing learning materials to the participants. The

               learning were very much eagers to write as they hold their pencils with so much excitement.
               During the sessions, it was observed that most of the participants are still grasping on how to

               write numbers but with the patience and assistance of the facilitators, they were able to write

               and  read  numbers.  It  was  indeed  a  remarkable  and a  truly  success  month  for  the  Oplan
               Karunungan team.


                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                25
                              Faculty Members                                      4
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     20
                                    Total                                         50

               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:


               DEBBIE ROSE T. BANAG                        LYNN G. RENALES, PhD

               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                             (Writing and Reading Literacy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                      October 2017

                       During  this  month,  Ms.  Mildred  A.  Sebastian,  Adviser  of  the  Circle  of  Potential

               Educators (CoPE), Department Head of the Teacher Education Department and Education
               together with participating  instructors and students both Mathematics and English majors

               started  the  Reading  session  for  the  participants  of  Oplan  Karunungan  in  CvSU  –  Tanza
               Campus. This activity aims to teach the participants how to read as it is one of the major

               objectives of the program which is to increase the literacy of the participants through having

               the ability to read.


                       The children were eager to learn how to read letters as they attentively listened to their
               teachers. As an observation, some of the students are having a hard time but through the

               patience of their teachers they were able to read some words.


                       A total of 49 participants attended the training during this month. The breakdown of

               the attendees are as follows:

                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                15
                              Faculty Members                                      3
                            Campus Coordinator                                     1
                                 Participants                                     20
                                    Total                                         47


               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:



               DEBBIE ROSE T. BANAG                        LYNN G. RENALES, PhD

               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                             (Writing and Reading Literacy for Out-of-School Children)
                                                    September 2017

                       During the month of September, the Extension Services Unit and Teacher Education

               Department of CvSU – Tanza conducted the first teaching session of Oplan Karunungan as
               part of their extension program which is BAGTAS with CvSU– Tanza. This program aims

               to give chance to the out-of-school children to learn and experience the usual classroom
               settings. There were many children who attended the first month of the class. The Education

               students together with Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian, Adviser, Ms. Maria Cristina C. Tagle, Ms.

               Glenifer Tamio, and Ms. Purelyn A. Umpay, faculty members, served as the teachers for the
               whole sessions for this month. All of the participants were active in the activities especially

               in writing letters. These activities were really interactive and the students really enjoyed it as
               it was incorporated with enjoyable activities so that students may not get bored during the

               sessions. The children were assisted by Education students who also participated in preparing

               the snacks for the participants. Overall, the objectives of teaching how to write letters was
               achieved during this month.


                       A total of 50 participants attended the training this month. The breakdown of the

               attendees are as follows:

                                  PARTICIPANTS                                   HEADCOUNT
                           BSE Students / Officers                                10
                              Faculty Members                                      4
                                 Participants                                     28
                                    Total                                         42

               Prepared by:                                              Reviewed by:


               DEBBIE ROSE T. BANAG                                      LYNN G. RENALES, PhD

               Extension Coordinator                                     Campus Dean]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                            CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                     Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                   ☏ (046) 235 – 7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                               EXTENSION SERVICES


                                               NARRATIVE REPORT

                                               OPLAN KARUNUNGAN
                                  (ALS Classes to Out-of-School Youths and Adults)



                       Cavite State University - Tanza Campus is now an ALS provider after the chairperson

               of the Sangguniang Kabataan sought help to the Extension Services of the campus. Ms. Ma,
               Kathleena Rose J. Arca, the SK Chairperson of Barangay Bagtas asked the campus to become

               one of the ALS providers in Bagtas through its program Oplan Karunungan. She believed
               that  the  campus  is  really  suitable  on  providing  quality  instruction  to  ALS  students.  The

               campus is very glad to provide help to the barangay particularly in increasing numeracy and

               literacy in the adopted community. The campus immediately coordinated to the representative
               of  Dep-Ed  ALS  in  Bagtas  about  the  MOA  and  schedules  of  classes.  The  Campus  and

               representative of Dep-Ed ALS agreed to each terms and conditions and set the date when to
               start the classes for the new ALS students.

                       Before the start of the classes, the campus also posted announcements on its Facebook

               page to increase the number of ALS enrollees. During the orientation, 29 ALS enrollees
               attended the orientation. These 29 enrollees are composed of out-of-school youths and adults

               who wished to finish their secondary education. The ALS orientation was attended by the
               faculty members of the campus, Dep-Ed ALS representative and the barangay chairperson

               and his staff.
                       During the first class of ALS students, Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian, chairperson of TED,

               served as the lecturer for Mathematics lesson and digital literacy at the same time. Other faculty

               members served as the lecturers in the succeeding days of ALS classes. Ms. Charmaine T.
               Banag served as the lecturer for Digital Literacy. Dr. Noel B. Manarpiis served as the lecturer

               for English and Communication subjects. Mr. Melandro F. Soriano, pre-service teacher, served
               as the Science teacher.



                       During the two weeks of ALS classes, it was observed that the ALS students really]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[enjoyed the classes based on the feedback evaluation given to them after every class. According

               to  one  of  the  students,  he  was  amazed  on  how  the  teachers  teach  the  lessons  and  their
               approaches to them. He had stopped because his high school teachers reprimanded him inside

               the class that led him to traumatic experience. Because of that, he refused to go to school and
               worked in a construction firm instead. But now, his perspective in life had changed because of

               the treatment of the faculty members they received. It is good to know that his program really

               changes the perspective of these former out-of-school youths.


                       The ALS students also experienced how to use computer through their digital literacy
               subject. They were also taught how to express themselves as some of them have very low self-

               esteem due to their level of education. Dr. Manarpiis taught them some tips on how to become
               a confident English language speaker.


                       The Extension Services Unit of the campus will ensure that they will provide the needs

               of the students in order for them to receive the quality of education they deserve.





               Prepared by:                                       Reviewed by:






               RITCH M. BANATE                                    PROF. NOEL A. SEDIGO
               Extension Coordinator                              Campus Administrator]]></page></pages></Search>
