<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="6"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[O.2.           The Extension Program has



                         contributed to the improvement on the


                         quality of life of the target


                         clientele/beneficiaries.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                         CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                       Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                    (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                EXTENSION SERVICES

                         CLIENTELE SATISFACTION REPORT/FEEDBACK EVALUATION


                                                            FEEDBACK EVALUATION FROM THE
                 EXTENSION ACTIVITY
                                                                          CLIENTELE
           Training on Food Preservation and            The  seminar  was  participated  by  19  residents
                    Gourmet Products                   who  willingly  give  their  evaluation  after  its
                   (November 8, 2019)                  conduct.  The  result  of  the  evaluation  showed
                                                       that as regards to the topic of the seminar, 64%
                                                       rated it excellent and 22% rated it as very good
                                                       and 14% rated it as good. In terms of materials
                                                       used, 58 rated it excellent, 42% rated it as very
                                                       good. With respect to the trainor, 94% rated it as
                                                       excellent and 6% rated it as very good. For the
                                                       over-all rating, 74% rated it as excellent and 26%
                                                       rated it as very good.
              Training on Embutido Making              The  Department  of  Management  conducted  a
                   (September 6, 2019)                 training  about  Embutido  making  and  after  the
                                                       seminar,  an  evaluation  form  was  given  to  the
                                                       clientele. In terms procedure and materials used,
                                                       the 93 percent of the participants rated it as highly
                                                       satisfied  and  3  percent  rated  it  as  moderately
                                                       satisfied.  In  terms  of  timeliness  of  the  training,
                                                       80% of the participants were highly satisfied. With
                                                       respect to the trainor, 93% were highly satisfied
                                                       and 7% were moderately satisfied. As an over-all
                                                       ratings  of  the  training,  93%  rated  it  as  highly
                                                       satisfied and 3% were moderately satisfied.

         Training on Dishwashing Liquid Making         Series of trainings about dishwashing liquid and
                  (August 23-30, 2019)                 fabric  conditioner  are  conducted  were  50
       Training on Dishwashing Liquid and Fabric  participants attended the series of trainings. Out
                   Conditioner Making                  of 50 participants, 52% of the participants rated it
                    (March 8-15, 2019)                 as “lubhang sapat” and 48% rated is as “sapat”.

                                                       Interview was done few weeks after the conduct
                                                       of the training, it was revealed that some of the
                                                       participants   started    to   make     their   own
                                                       dishwashing  liquid  and  earning  additional
                                                       income.  We  are  happy  to  know  that  they  are
                                                       applying  what  they  had  learned  during  the
                                                       training.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Training on Skinless Longganisa            The  Extension  Services  Unit  and  Department  of
                   (December 1, 2018)                  Management of CvSU-Tanza Campus together with
                                                       the  Future  Managers, Administrators  and  Executive
                                                       (FAME)  Society  conducted  a  training  on  skinless
                                                       longganisa  as  part  of  their  Livelihood  Training
                                                       Program. The training was attended by 20 trainees. In
                                                       terms  of  (pamamaraan  at  nilalaman)  60%  of  the
                                                       participants  rated  it  as  “lubhang  sapat”,  while  35%
                                                       rated it “sapat” and 5% rated it as “bahagyang sapat”.
                                                       In terms of (kaangkupan sa kasalukuyang panahon)
                                                       65% of the participants rated it as “lubhang sapat”,
                                                       while  20%  rated  it  “sapat”  and  15%  rated  it  as
                                                       “bahagyang  sapat”.  In  terms  of  (tagapagturo  at
                                                       tagasanay)  70%  of  the  participants  rated  it  as
                                                       “lubhang sapat”, while 15% rated it “sapat” and 15%
                                                       rated  it  as  “bahagyang  sapat”.  In  terms  of  over-all
                                                       rating, 80% rated the training as “lubhang sapat” and
                                                       20% rated it as “sapat”.


                                                       After  the  training,  the  extension  services  offices
                                                       conducted some monitoring and they found out that
                                                       some  of  the  participants  started  to  sell  their  own
                                                       skinless Longganisa and now have earning additional
                                                       income.


          Food Processing and Siomai Making            On  November  10,  2018,  Saturday,  the  Extension
                  (November 10, 2018)                  Services  Unit  and  Department  of  Management  of
                                                       CvSU-Tanza Campus  conducted  a  training  on  food
                                                       processing  and  Siomai  Making  as  part  of  their
                                                       Livelihood  Training  Program.  The  training  was
                                                       attended by 20 trainees. In terms of (pamamaraan at
                                                       nilalaman) 75% of the participants rated it as “lubhang
                                                       sapat”, while 15% rated it “sapat” and 5% rated it as
                                                       “bahagyang  sapat”.  In  terms  of  (kaangkupan  sa
                                                       kasalukuyang panahon) 60% of the participants rated
                                                       it as “lubhang sapat”, while 20% rated it “sapat” and
                                                       20%  rated  it  as  “bahagyang  sapat”.  In  terms  of
                                                       (tagapagturo  at  tagasanay)  80%  of  the  participants
                                                       rated it as “lubhang sapat”, while 10% rated it “sapat”
                                                       and 10% rated it as “bahagyang sapat”. In terms of
                                                       over-all  rating,  85%  rated  the  training  as  “lubhang
                                                       sapat” and 15% rated it as “sapat”.

                                                       After  the  training,  the  extension  services  offices
                                                       conducted some monitoring and they found out that
                                                       some  of  the  participants  started  to  sell  their  own
                                                       skinless Longganisa and now have earning additional
                                                       income.



     Prepared by:


     RITCH M. BANATE
     Extension Coordinator]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                         CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                       Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                    (046) 414 – 3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                EXTENSION SERVICES

        MANIFESTATIONS THAT EXTENSION PROGRAMS/PROJECTS HAVE CONTRIBUTED TO THE
                  IMPROVEMENT OF THE QUALITY OF LIFE OF THE CLIENT/BENEFICIARIES


         EXTENSION ACTIVITY                    OBJECTIVES                       IMPLICATIONS
             Training on Food           Help    the    residents     of  Start-up activity for additional
        Preservation and Gourmet        barangay  particularly  the  source  of  income  for  the
                 Products               4P’s  members  and  non- residents  of  the  adopted
                                        working  women  to  have  barangay.
                                        additional  source  of  income
                                        and  to  improve  their  socio-
                                        economic status.
           Training on Embutido         Help    the    residents     of  Start-up activity for additional
                  Making                barangay  particularly  the  source  of  income  for  the
                                        4P’s  members  and  non- residents  of  the  adopted
                                        working  women  to  have  barangay.
                                        additional  source  of  income
                                        and  to  improve  their  socio-
                                        economic status.
         Training on Dishwashing        Help    the    residents     of  Start-up activity for additional
             Liquid and Fabric          barangay  particularly  the  source  of  income  for  the
            Conditioner Making          4P’s  members  and  non- residents  of  the  adopted
                                        working  women  to  have  barangay.
                                        additional  source  of  income
                                        and  to  improve  their  socio-
                                        economic status.
           Training on Skinless         Help    the    residents     of  Start-up activity for additional
                Longganisa              barangay  particularly  the  source  of  income  for  the
                                        4P’s  members  and  non- residents  of  the  adopted
                                        working  women  to  have  barangay.
                                        additional  source  of  income
                                        and  to  improve  their  socio-
                                        economic status.
       Food Processing and Siomai  Help         the    residents     of  Start-up activity for additional
                  Making                barangay  particularly  the  source  of  income  for  the
                                        4P’s  members  and  non- residents  of  the  adopted
                                        working  women  to  have  barangay.
                                        additional  source  of  income
                                        and  to  improve  their  socio-
                                        economic status.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Prepared by:


     RITCH M. BANATE
     Extension Coordinato

                                                 MS. CARLA A. MOLINA
                       (ONE OF THE BENEFICIARIES WHO STARTED SELLING DISHWASHING LIQUID)

























                             Ms. Molinas while selling her dishwashing liquid products












                              The production area of her dishwashing liquid business]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>