<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="19"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.12.           The institution provides opportunities


                        for promotion and appreciation of


                        culture and arts.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Manual of Operations]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[21


                              2.2.9.  CvSU  Scholarship  Privilege.  This  scholarship  is  awarded  to
                                       employees of the University and their dependents provided that
                                       such  employees  have  rendered  at  least  one  year  of  continuous
                                       service to the University, irrespective of their employment status.
                       2.3.   In  general,  the  criteria  in  the  selection  of  financial  awardees  include:
                              good  moral  character;  economic  background  of  parents  or  guardians;
                              willingness  to  work;  and  academic  performance.  The  University  shall
                              promulgate  the  details  of  selection  criteria  and  the  mechanics  of
                              implementation and revise the same accordingly, as the need arises.
                       2.4.    The  benefits  to  the  awardees  of  the  financial  assistance  program
                              include:
                              2.4.1.  either free tuition or discounts in tuition;
                              2.4.2.  monthly stipend; allowance per semester;
                              2.4.3.  book allowance and others.
                              2.4.4.  In  addition,  some  types  of  financial  assistance  include  priority
                                       booking in the University Dormitory.
                       2.5.   The responsibilities of the recipients include maintaining high academic
                              standards;  and  also  rendering  some  types  of  service  work  to  the
                              University.  The  University  shall  issue  from  time  to  time,  update
                              guidelines on these aspects of the program.
                       2.6.   The  financial  assistance  is  automatically  terminated  if  a  student
                              recipient  is  involved  in  any  misdemeanor  in  contravention  of  the
                              University  Student’s  Norm  of  Conduct  or  any  other  University  policies,
                              rules  and  regulations.  In  addition,  student  recipients  whose  grades  fall
                              below  the  required  academic  requirements  by  the  type  of  financial
                              assistance shall also forfeit the benefits and/or allowances.

                       Section 3. Culture and Arts Program
                       3.1.   The Office of Student Affairs and Services shall implement a culture and
                              arts  program  geared  towards  the  development,  enhancement  and
                              promotion  of  CvSU  talents  through  their  artistic  expression  and
                              creativity  with  enriched  appreciation  and  conservation  of  national
                              culture.
                       3.2.   Specifically,  the  culture  and  arts  program  shall  have  the  following
                              objectives:
                              3.2.1.  develop  students’  talents  and  interest  to  ensure  social  and
                                       cultural growth
                              3.2.2.  create  meaningful  opportunities  for  students  to  show  off  and
                                       share their artistic talents
                              3.2.3.  promote appreciation of culture and arts in the University
                       3.3.   In  order  to  achieve  the  above-mentioned  objectives,  the  following
                              functions must be performed:
                              3.1.1.  organize arts groups with qualified trainers and staff
                              3.1.2.  implement regular cultural activities
                              3.1.3.  collaborate cultural activities with various university offices
                              3.1.4.  create avenues for showcase of talents
                              3.1.5.  organize cultural activities for community involvement


                 Excerpts from the OSAS Manual pp. 21-23]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[22


                              3.1.6.  engage in cultural and arts competitions
                              3.1.7.  solicit support of administrators, local and corporate partners in
                                       the enhancement of students’ talents

                       3.4.   The culture and arts program shall have the following components:
                              3.4.1.  artistic  talent  enhancement  program  –  artistic  training  through
                                       non-formal curriculum
                                       3.4.1.1.    summer workshops
                                       3.4.1.2.    week-end tutorials
                                       3.4.1.3.    recitals
                                       3.4.1.4.    seminars and workshops
                              3.4.2.  artistic talent development program
                                       3.4.2.1.    audition
                                       3.4.2.2.    regular rehearsals and trainings and upgrading
                                       3.4.2.3.    in-house performances
                                       3.4.2.4.    performance requests
                                       3.4.2.5.    concerts
                              3.4.2.6. competitions
                              3.4.2.7. supplementary cultural education program
                              3.4.2.8. live demonstration of some forms of performing arts
                              3.4.2.9. attendance to national and international culture and arts
                                       workshops

                       Section 4. Performing Arts Group
                              The University shall recognize one official organization for each of the
                       following performing arts group:

                              4.1.   Dance
                                     4.1.1.  Folk
                                     4.1.2.  contemporary
                                     4.1.3.  hip hop
                              4.2.   Chorale
                              4.3.   Theatre
                              4.4.   Band

                              All members of performing groups shall enjoy service scholarship in
                       accordance to existing guidelines.


                       Section 5. Culture and Arts Staff

                       5.1.   The CA Program shall be supervised by a Culture and Arts Coordinator
                              who shall be designated by the University President as recommended by
                              the  OSAS  Dean  and  the  VPAA.  The  CACoord  shall  have  the  following
                              functions:]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[23


                              5.1.1.  Plans, implements, attends and evaluates cultural programs and
                                       activities
                              5.1.2.  Develops non-formal cultural education programs
                              5.1.3.  Supervises the operation and activities of all cultural groups and
                                       organizations
                              5.1.4.  Acts  as  overall  adviser  to  the  different  artistic  and  cultural
                                       groups
                              5.1.5.  Acts as property custodian for culture and arts
                              5.1.6.  Evaluates seminars and workshops conducted
                              5.1.7.  Prepares financial plans and fund utilization reports
                              5.1.8.  Evaluates  and  recommends  hiring  of  coaches  and  trainers  of
                                       performing arts group
                       5.2.   The CA Coordinator shall be assisted by a Council of Advisers for Culture
                              and  Arts  which  shall  be  composed  of  advisers,  trainors/coaches  and
                              events coordinators.
                       5.3.   Source of Funds
                                     All budgetary and financial requirements of the Culture and Arts
                              Program shall be coming from  Student Funds collected by the Central
                              Student Government and specifically allotted to Culture and Arts
                              Program according to its approved financial plan.


               Section  6. NSTP and Community Involvement
                       6.1.   Organization.
                              6.1.1.  The  CvSU  NSTP  shall  be  implemented by  the  Office  of  Student
                                       Affairs (OSA) Main Campus in coordination with the University,
                                       College,  and  Campus  Registrars.  While  the  Dean  for  Student
                                       Affairs  is  the  over  all  Program  Coordinator,  all  NSTP  student
                                       records shall be handled by the University Registrar’s Office for
                                       the  main  campus    and  the  campus  registrars,  in  the  case  of
                                       students in the branch campuses.
                              6.1.2.  College  Registrar’s  in  the  main  campus  shall  assist  the
                                       University  registrar  in  keeping  track  of  records  of  students
                                       taking the CvSU NSTP in their respective colleges.
                              6.1.3.  College and campus registrars shall submit the list of students
                                       in  CvSU  NSTP  to  the  Dean  for  Student  Affairs  for  purposes  of
                                       monitoring and evaluation.
                              6.1.4.  The  NSTP  to  be  conducted  in  branch  campuses  shall  be
                                       coordinated  with  the  OSA.  They  may  designate  their  own
                                       respective NSTP component coordinators.
                              6.1.5.  The  conduct  of  the  ROTC  component  shall  be  taken  care  of  by
                                       the  DND  under  their  own  guidelines.  In  addition  to  the  ROTC,
                                       the  University  main  campus  shall  also  offer  the  Civic  Welfare
                                       Training  Services.(CWTS)  and  Literacy  Training  Services  (LTS)
                                       components. The branch campuses may opt for any of the three
                                       components. In cases where the component selected by students
                                       is  not  being  offered,  he/she  may  cross  register  in  other]]></page><page Index="6"/><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Student Handbook]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Approved Plan of Activities]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines                                                                CvSU Mission
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus                                                                  Cavite State University shall provide
                                                                                                                                     excellent, equitable and relevant
                                          Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite                                                 educational opportunities in the arts,
                                                       (046) 414-3979                                                            sciences and technology through quality
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph                                                            instruction and responsive research and
                                                                                                                                        developmental activities.
                                         OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES                                                   It shall produce professional, skilled and
                                                                                                                                   morally upright individuals for global
                                                    PLAN OF ACTIVITIES                                                                     competitiveness.
                                                 First Semester AY, 2022-2023
                                                             TIME AND
                       DATE               ACTIVITY                            PARTICIPANTS
                                                              VENUE                               MODALITY
                                         Parents’ and
                                       Students’ Virtual   1:00-4:00 PM via   Students, Parents,
                 September 16, 2022
                                         Orientation       Facebook Live      Faculty, and Staff     Online

                                       Local Search for
                 September 26, 2022    Culture and Arts     7:00-3:00 PM          Students           Online
                                        Festival 2022
                                           Student          8:00 AM- 4:00
                                        Organizations’                      Old and new student
                  October 1-4, 2022                        PM via Google
                                        Application for         Link            organizations     Online/Offline
                                         Accreditation
                                                            7:00-3:00 PM
                                       Culture and Arts
                  October 5, 2022                            CvSU-Main            Students        Face-to-face
                                        Festival 2022
                                                              Campus
                                     Recognition Program     10:00 AM-
                                      and Oath-taking of                    Old and new student   Face-to-face
                  October 20, 2022                            12:00NN
                                      Accredited student     BM DOME            organizations
                                        Organizations
                  November 7-12,                                   Midterm Exam
                       2022
                 November 21, 2022   Leadership Seminar         TBA          All student leaders   Face-to-face
                  November 22-24,      Pre-employment        CvSU-Main       Mid-year graduating
                       2022                Webinar            Campus              students        Face-to-face
                                        Environmental      Central Student    Students, Faculty
                 November 19, 2021    Awareness Month        Government           and Staff          Online
                                         Celebration       Facebook page
                                     187- Day Campaign     Central Student
                 November 24, 2022   to End VAW Against      Government       Students, Faculty      Online
                                                                                  and Staff
                                           Women           Facebook page
                                          Year-End
                 December 16, 2022       Celebration            TBA           Students, Faculty   Face-to-face
                                                                                  and Staff
                                       (Per Department)
                   January 23-28,
                       2023                                       Final Examination
                  January 30, 2023                                Semestral Break

               Prepared by:                                                     Noted:


               MELONA I. SAQUIN                                                      GIL D. RAMOS
               OSAS Coordinator                                                 Campus Administrator
               Date prepared: September 12, 2022]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY                                                                           CvSU Mission
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                          Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite                                                     Cavite State University shall provide
                                                       (046) 414-3979                                                                 excellent, equitable and relevant
                                                       www.cvsu.edu.ph                                                               educational opportunities in the arts,
                                                                                                                                    sciences and technology through quality
                                                                                                                                    instruction and responsive research and
                                      OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES                                                              developmental activities.
                                                                                                                                    It shall produce professional, skilled and
                                                   PLAN OF ACTIVITIES                                                                morally upright individuals for global
                                              Second Semester AY, 2020-2021                                                                   competitiveness.


                     DATE               ACTIVITY          TIME AND VENUE        PARTICIPANTS
                                                                                                    MODALITY
                                     Start of admission                             Guidance
                  March 1, 2021      for incoming first    CvSU Admission       Coordinator/OSAS  Online/Offline
                                     year (1st Sem S.Y         System              Coordinator
                                       2021-2022)
                April 12-17, 2021                               Midterm Examination
                                       Virtual Pre-
                                       employment         CvSU-Main Campus      Students, Faculty     Online
                  April 28, 2021
                                     Webinar and Job        Facebook Page           and Staff
                                           Fair
                                    Virtual Culture and    1:00-4:00 PM via       Students and
                April 28-29, 2021
                                       Arts Festival        Facebook Live           Faculty           Online
                                       Webinar on          1:00-4:00 PM via       Students and
                April 29-30, 2021
                                     Entrepreneurship       Facebook Live           Faculty           Online
                                      Mental Health        1:00-4:00 PM via     Students, Faculty
                  May 21, 2021
                                         Webinar            Facebook Live           and Staff
                                      Orientation on
                                     Scholarship and      CvSU-Main Campus                            Online
                  May 22, 2021                                                      Students
                                        Financial           Facebook Page
                                        Assistance
                                       Webinar on
                  June 3, 2021      Managing Students      1:00-4:00 PM via        Faculty and        Online
                                                            Facebook Live
                                                                                    Students
                                    with Special Needs
                                     Webinar on Risk                                                  Online
                  June 9, 2021          Reduction          1:00-4:00 PM via     Faculty, Students
                                                            Facebook Live
                                                                                    and Staff
                                      Management
                June 14-19, 2021                                 Final Examination

               Prepared by:                                                     Noted:


               MELONA I. SAQUIN                                                       NOEL A. SEDIGO
               OSAS Coordinator                                                 Campus Administrator
               Date prepared: September 19, 2020]]></page></pages></Search>
