<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="10"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.            The institution has an approved printed


                        Student Handbook/Manual containing


                        policies and guidelines on the following

                        aspects of student life:


                        S.1.11.   attendance; and]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10.4 The Accounting Office shall post the names of students who have not been cleared of
                       accountabilities before the start of the succeeding registration period.

                       10.5 The students should present their clearance before they can enroll in the succeeding
                       semester.


                       b) Academic Load. No student shall be allowed to take more than a maximum credit unit per
                       semester. A graduating student may be allowed to enroll more than the maximum allowable
                       credits units not to exceed 26 units during the last two semester of his course provided that he
                       has a GPA of 2.50 or better in the previous two semester as certified by the University Registrar.
                       A graduating student petitioning for registering up to maximum allowable academic load must
                       secure a certification from the University Registrar that he is a graduating student.

                              During summer program, a student may be allowed a maximum of three (3) lecture
                       courses or one with laboratory and one lecture course. No student will be allowed to register
                       with two (2) laboratory courses except when one is a co-prerequisite of the other.

                       c) Class Attendance. A student who has been absent from classes for at least two (2)
                       consecutive meeting must obtain an excuse slip form the Office of Student Affairs and present
                       this to the instructor concerned on the day he returns to class.

                              Excuses are for time missed only. Work covered by the class during the absence shall be
                       made up within reasonable time to the satisfaction of the instructor.


                              If a student has been absent in 20 percent of the time schedule devoted to the class
                       without justifiable reasons, he/she shall e dropped from the rolls. If the majority of these
                       absences are not excused and the student’s performance is poor, he/she will receive a grade of
                       “5.00”.

                       d) Changing/Adding/Dropping of Course/s. Transfer to other section must be made for valid
                       reasons only such as conflict in schedule


                              No change in matriculation will be allowed after three (3) weeks of regular classes.
                       Change in subject can be accomplished by filling up a changing/dropping from duly noted by the
                       registration adviser and the instructor concerned and approved by the College Dean concerned.

                              A student, with the consent of the instructor concerned and the Den of the college
                       where he is enrolled, may drop a subject by filling a prescribed form for the purpose. No
                       dropping of subject is allowed after the midterm examination ha elapse except due to illness
                       and other justifiable reasons.


                              Dropping of courses/subjects shall only be made for valid reasons, only such cases as
                       the course is not needed, ill-advised, conflict in schedule, registered higher course without
                       passing the prerequisite course(s) and registered major course without passing all the required]]></page></pages></Search>