<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="15"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.17.           The institution establishes programs


                        for the students to help in crime


                        prevention, cleanliness and

                        orderliness, observance of a clean and


                        green environment, safety and security


                        of the school premises.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Documentation of Programs/ Activities


         related to Crime Prevention, Cleanliness


                          and Orderliness etc.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[FOGGING AND MISTING OPERATION IN THE CAMPUS

                                                       September 12, 2022]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[DISINFECTION CONDUCTED BY DOH IN THE CAMPUS
                                                  September 20, 2022]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[PHOTO DOCUMENTATION
                                       NSTP 2 – National Service Training Program
                                            Second Semester, AY 2019 – 2020]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                          CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                      Tanza Campus
                                                            235-7997
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                 Green the Bottle + Save the Mother Earth Webinar was held at Cavite State University -

                                   Tanza Campus, April 29, 2022 through online Webex






                       The  program  started  with  the  opening  remarks  by  the  host  speaker,  Ms.  Gerry  Mae

               Silvero. As she greeted and welcome all the participants of the webinar, she introduced NSTP

               Facilitator, Ms. Estie Viela, who hope that all the participants will inspires to save the Mother Earth

               by planting and using recyclable materials and she also introduced the resource speaker, a, Ms.

               Honey Joy N. Mojares.


                       The speaker started to discuss the bottle gardening. She discussed the different types of


               usage of plastic bottles such as Plastic Bottles Bertcal Garden Ideas, Plastic Bottles on Walls,

               Tower Garden, Vertical Herb Garden, Hang Bottles with Strings, Bottle Ladder, Upside Down

               Bottle Tower, on the Shelf, and more.


                       She also explains that not all plastic bottles are safe to use in planning. Because some

               are  harmful  and  release  toxins  into  the  soil,  especially  when  heated,  exposed  to  sunlight  or

               exposed for extended periods of time.



                       Moreover,  she  talked  about  applying  fertilizers  and  different  examples  of  it,  such  as

               compost, manure, carbonized rice hull, and vermicast. Lastly, the speaker clarifies the benefits of

               bottle gardening.


                       Ended discussion, with the cohost, Ms. Gerry Mae Silverio, moderated the question and

               answer portion. Many students were asked for their queries, as Ms. Mojares answered each.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Announcement /Invitation]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>