<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="21"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.3.            The institution conducts leadership


                        training.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Pictures]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[ESTABLISHMENT OF LOCAL YOUTH DEVELOPMENT COUNCIL
                                   Local Youth Development Office, Tanza Cavite
                                                  September 16, 2022

               On September 16, 2022, President of the SK Federation Hon. Rhon Jay Perdito invited Local
               Youth Development Council (LYDC) members at Tanza Command Center for a Establishment
               Seminar  led  by  THK  head  Mr.  Justin  Celeste.  Student  leaders  from  academic  and  non-
               academic  organizations  from  Cavite  State  University-Tanza  Cavite  such  as  The  Oracle
               Publication,  Circle  of  Potential  Educators,  Radicals,  Association  of  Compasionate  Work
               Athlete,  Anglicists  Guild,  Theatro  Tanza  of  Phenomenal  Students,  and  Central  Student
               Government - Tanza Campus participated the aforementioned event.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[The students leaders of CvSU-Tanza Campus with the SK Federation
                                            President, Hon. Rhon Jay Perdito.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[LINGGO NG KABATAAN 2022
                                     Governance and Active Citizenship Seminar
                                     Provincial Capitol, Trece Martires City Cavite
                                                    August 31, 2022

               In  observance  of  Linggo  ng  Kabataan,  the  Provincial  Government  of  Cavite  through  the
               Provincial Youth and Sports Development Office and in collaboration with College of Arts and
               Sciences  Student  Council  -  Cavite  State  University-Main  and  UTOPIA  -  CvSU  Political
               Science Society conducted a seminar about Active Citizenship with the theme "The Role of
               Filipino Youth in Pursuing Accountability and Transparency Towards Good Governance" and
               Goverance  with  the  theme  "New  Models  in  Politics:  Empowering  Youth  Leaders
               Competencies Towards Civic Engagement Promoting Good Governance" for Caviteño Youth
               at the Cavite Collaboration Center for Public Health Auditorium, Trece Martires City, Cavite.
               Student leaders from CvSU-Tanza Campus joined the said activity.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Mr. Vincent Bae, Chairperson of
                                                                             the Cavite Provincial Youth and
                                                                            Sports Development Office giving
                                                                              his welcoming remarks to the
                                                                                      participants.






































                       Ms. Jan Angela L. Catindig, CSG President of CvSU-Tanza, during the seminar
                                                          session]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Student leaders of CvSU-Tanza Campus with other participants from different
                                               universities and colleges in Cavite]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[YOUTH SUMMIT LEADERSHIP TRAINING
                                    Provincial Gymnasium, Trece Martires City Cavite
                                                     August 19, 2022


                       The  Provincial  Government  of  Cavite  through  the  Provincial  Youth  and  Sports
               Development  Office  conducted  leadership  training  and  team  building  activities  for  the
               registered  youth  and  youth-serving  organizations  of  Cavite  at  the  Cavite  Provincial
               Gymnasium, Trece Martires City, Cavite including all the registered student organizations
               of CvSU-Tanza Campus. The training proper began with a profound discussion of the
               topic,  "Collaborative  Leadership"  by  Ms.  Nikki  R.  Jerusalem  from  the  National  Youth
               Commission. The training aims to develop the leadership skills of the participants and to
               build their camaraderie and friendship. Several organizations from Cavite State University
               including  Central  Student  Government  -  Tanza  Campus,  Anglicists  Guild  ,  Radicals  ,
               Theatro  Tanza  of  Phenomenal  Students  ,Circle  of  Potential  Educators  ,  Alliance  of
               Bachelor of Elementary Education Students, and The Oracle - Cavite State University -
               Tanza Campus Publication attended the Cavite Youth and Youth - Serving Organization.
               Ms. Jan Angela Catindig, the CSG Vice President and Ms. Lorraine Victoria Encarnacion
               of The Oracle Publication was part of the core team and helped in facilitating the event.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Ms. Jan Angela Catindig (third from the left), CSG President of CvSU-Tanza Campus, and
                  Ms. Lorraine Victoria Encarnacion, The Oracle President, (Third from the right), with the
                                                     event core team






















                 Student leaders from CvSU-Tanza Campus with other participants from different colleges
                                 and universities in Cavite during the teambuilding activity]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Team building activities during the leadership seminar]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[LEADERSHIP TRAINING AND TEAM BUILDING
                                     Local Youth Development Office, Tanza Cavite
                                                      July 2, 2022


                       SK Federation President Hon. Rhon Jay Perdito invited Local Youth Development
               Council (LYDC) members at Tanza Command Center for a Leadership Training and Team
               Building lead by Sir Justin Celeste. The Oracle  Publication , Circle of Potential Educators,
               Radicals, Association of Compasionate Work Athlete, Anglicists Guild , Theatro Tanza of
               Phenomenal Students and to Central Student Government - Tanza Campus and CSG
               Vice President, Ms. Jan Angela Catindig, CSG Treasurer Ms. Kayla Rose Magpantay, and
               CSG  Public  Relations  Officer,  Ms.  Jennelyn  M.  Valderama  attended  the  leadership
               seminar.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[CSG Officers with Mr. Justin Celeste from Tanza Command Center




























                                                     Seminar lecture]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[CvSU-Tanza student leaders during the teambuilding activities





               Prepared by:

               FATIMA M. DIAZ
               SDS Coordinator





               Noted:


               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, OSAS]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Certificates]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[CERTIFICATES OF LEADERSHIP SEMINARS ATTENDED BY THE STUDENT
                                              LEADERS OF CvSU-TANZA





























                  Certificates from leadership seminars participated by Ms. Angela Catindig, the CSG
                                                 President of CvSU-Tanza]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[CERTIFICATES OF LEADERSHIP SEMINARS ATTENDED BY THE STUDENT
                                              LEADERS OF CvSU-TANZA





























                  Certificates from leadership seminars participated by Ms. Angela Catindig, the CSG
                                                 President of CvSU-Tanza]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[CERTIFICATES OF LEADERSHIP SEMINARS ATTENDED BY THE STUDENT
                                              LEADERS OF CvSU-TANZA





























                Certificates from leadership seminars participated by Ms. Lorraine Victoria Encarnacion,
                                 the President of The Oracle Publication of CvSU-Tanza]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[CERTIFICATES OF LEADERSHIP SEMINARS ATTENDED BY THE STUDENT
                                              LEADERS OF CvSU-TANZA





























                Certificates from leadership seminars participated by Ms. Lorraine Victoria Encarnacion,
                                 the President of The Oracle Publication of CvSU-Tanza]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[CERTIFICATES OF LEADERSHIP SEMINARS ATTENDED BY THE STUDENT
                                              LEADERS OF CvSU-TANZA



























                Certificates from leadership seminars participated by Ms. Lorraine Victoria Encarnacion,
                                 the President of The Oracle Publication of CvSU-Tanza]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[CERTIFICATES OF LEADERSHIP SEMINARS ATTENDED BY THE STUDENT
                                              LEADERS OF CvSU-TANZA





























                Certificates from leadership seminars participated by Ms. Lorraine Victoria Encarnacion,
                                 the President of The Oracle Publication of CvSU-Tanza]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[CERTIFICATES OF LEADERSHIP SEMINARS ATTENDED BY THE STUDENT
                                              LEADERS OF CvSU-TANZA]]></page></pages></Search>