<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="97"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.            The institution has policies on:


                        S.1.3.  supervision, monitoring and


                                       evaluation of faculty

                                       performance.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[REVISED PROGRAM ON AWARDS



                               AND INCENTIVES FOR


                              SERVICE EXCELLENCE]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[REVISED PROGRAM ON



                                       AWARDS AND



                    INCENTIVES FOR SERVICE



                                         EXCELLENCE



                                     (CvSU- PRAISE)













                            Cavite State University




                                        Indang, Cavite]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                           REVISED  PROGRAM ON AWARDS AND INCENTIVES FOR SERVICE
                                              EXCELLENCE (CvSU- PRAISE)

                   In line with the Revised Policies on Employee Suggestions and Incentives Awards System
                   (ESIAS) provided under CSC Resolution No. 01-0112 and CSC MC No. 01, s. 2001, CSC
                   MC 6, s. 2002, CSC MC 18, s. 2012, EO 201, s. 2016, and CSC MC No. 01, s. 2019,  the
                   University  adopts  the  herein  Revised  Program  on  Awards  and  Incentives  for  Service
                   Excellence (PRAISE) to be referred to as CvSU PRAISE.


                   I.  BASIC POLICIES

                   1.  The  University shall establish its own employee suggestions and incentive awards
                       system.

                   2.  The   System shall  be designed  to  encourage creativity,  innovativeness,  efficiency,
                       integrity and productivity in the public service by recognizing and rewarding officials
                       and employees, individually or in groups for their suggestions, inventions, superior
                       accomplishments  and  other  personal  efforts  which  contribute  to  the  efficiency,
                       economy or other improvement in government operations, or for other extraordinary
                       acts or services in the public interest.

                   3.  The  CvSU PRAISE shall adhere to the principle of providing incentives and awards
                       based on performance, innovative ideas, and exemplary behavior.

                   4.  The  CvSU  PRAISE  shall  give  emphasis  on  the  timeliness  of  giving  award  or
                       recognition.  Aside  from  conferment  of  awards  during  the  traditional  or  planned
                       awarding  ceremonies,  the  spirit  of  on-the-spot  grant  of  recognition  shall  be
                       institutionalized.

                   5.  The  CvSU  PRAISE  shall  provide  both  monetary  and  non-monetary  awards  and
                       incentives to recognized, acknowledge and reward productive, creative,  innovative,
                       and ethical behavior of employees through formal and informal mode.

                          For this purpose, the CvSU PRAISE shall encourage the grant of non-monetary
                          awards. Monetary awards shall be granted only when the suggestions, inventions,
                          superior accomplishments, and other personal efforts result in monetary savings
                          which shall not exceed 20% of the savings generated.

                   6.  The PRAISE shall be institutionalized through the creation of a PRAISE Committee.


                   7.  The PRAISE Committee shall ensure that productivity, innovative ideas, suggestions,
                       and exemplary behavior can be identified, considered, managed, and implemented on
                       a continuing basis to cover employees at all levels.


                   8.  The  PRAISE  Committee shall  establish its  own  internal  procedures  and strategies
                       which may  be  independent  from  but not  contrary  to  CSC established  rules  as  the
                       committee deems applicable. Membership in the Committee shall be considered part
                       of the member’s regular duties and functions.

                   9.  The University shall submit this CvSU PRAISE and its subsequent amendments to the
                       CSCRO IV. The Civil Service Commission Regional Office No. IV and/or CSC Cavite
                       Field Office shall provide technical assistance, if deemed necessary, to ensure proper
                       implementation
                                                                                                  Page 1 of 23]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE


                   10. The CSC- approved  PRAISE shall be the basis of the grant of the bonuses, other
                       awards, and incentives. The Annual PRAISE Report shall be submitted to the CSC
                       Region IV on or before the thirtieth (30 ) day of January and shall be due for evaluation
                                                           th
                       of the CSC Regional Office No.  IV anytime to enable the employees to qualify for
                       nomination to the CSC-sponsored national awards.

                   11. Issues relative to awards and incentives shall be brought before the CvSU PRAISE
                       Committee which shall address the same within fifteen (15) days from the date of
                       submission.


                   12.  The University shall adopt the following Equal Opportunity Policy  (EOP_ Guidelines
                       in the implementation of CvSU- PRAISE.

                       a.  The  University  shall  not  discriminate  against  a  qualified  person  by  reason  of
                          physical disability  regarding grant of rewards and recognition, and other terms,
                          conditions, and privileges of employment.

                       b.  The    PRAISE  Committee  shall  observe  the  applicable  guidelines  herein  when
                          screening  and  evaluating  nominees  who  may  belong  to  one  of  the  following
                          categories: visually impaired, hearing impaired, with speech/vocal impediment and
                          with physical disability.

                       c.  The following shall be considered acts of discrimination:

                          •  Utilizing  standards,  criteria,  or  methods of  selecting  candidates  for  grant  of
                              rewards  and  recognition  that  have  the  effect  of  discrimination  based  on
                              disability or perpetuate the discrimination of others who are subject to common
                              administrative control
                          •  Excluding  a  disabled  employee  as  nominee  or  candidate  for  the  grant  of
                              rewards and recognition by reason of disability.
                          •  Disqualifying a disabled employee by reason of his disability in the roster of
                              candidates to the grant of rewards and recognition
                          •  Favoring a  non-disabled employee  over  a  qualified disabled employee with
                              respect to rewards and recognition solely on account of the latter’s disability.

                       d.  The University shall ensure that all similarly qualified employees shall have equal
                          access and opportunity to the grant of rewards and recognition regardless of sex,
                          gender, age or disability

                       e.  No employee shall be overlooked for the grant of reward, recognition, or promotion
                          because of any protected characteristics.

                       f.  The PRAISE Committee shall encourage nominations of employees with disability,
                          special needs, and members of indigenous group to various awards by providing
                          and accessing them to opportunities to excel within their field of expertise.


                       g.  Nominations forms, tools and selection criteria shall not discriminatory.

                       h.  Working environment for employees with special needs must be conducive and
                          inclusive such as provision of accessibility ramp, use of wheelchair, use of braille




                                                                                                  Page 2 of 23]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                          1 for deaf and mute, provision of prayer room for other religious groups, provision
                          of breastfeeding area for lactating mother and other facilities that promote diversity
                          and inclusion.


                       i.  During  CvSU PRAISE Program assessment, interview for employees with special
                          needs  shall  be  done  in  a  venue  conducive  to  them,  so  as  during  awarding
                          ceremonies.

                       j.  Availment  of  solo  parent  leave  shall  not  be  ground  for  disqualification  in  the
                          deliberation of awardees of Perfect Attendance Award.

                       k.  In crafting criteria for giving awards and incentives, conditions of those employees
                          with disability or special needs shall always be given preferential attention.


                   II.   OBJECTIVES


                       a.  General Objective

                          To encourage, recognize and reward employees, individually and in groups, for
                          their  suggestions,  innovative  ideas,  inventions,  discoveries,  superior
                          accomplishments,  heroic  deeds,  exemplary  behavior,  extraordinary  acts  or
                          services to the public interest and other personal efforts which contribute to the
                          efficiency, economy and improvement in government operations, which lead to
                          organizational productivity.

                       b.  Specific
                          1.  To establish a mechanism for identifying, selecting, rewarding, and providing
                              incentives to deserving employees at the start of each year.

                          2.  To identify outstanding accomplishments and best practices of employees on
                              a continuing basis.

                          3.  To recognize and reward accomplishments and innovations periodically or as
                              the need arises.

                          4.  To  provide  incentives  and  interventions  to  motivate  employees  who  have
                              contributed   ideas,   suggestions,    inventions,   discoveries,   superior
                              accomplishments, and other personal efforts.

                   III.   SCOPE

                         The CvSU PRAISE shall apply to all employees in the career and non-career service
                         of the  University.


                   IV.   DEFINITION OF TERMS

                         For the purpose of this guidelines, the following terms are defined:



                                                                                                  Page 3 of 23]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                         Award  –  recognition  which  may  be  monetary  or  non-monetary  conferred  on
                         individual  or  group  of  individuals  for  ideas,  suggestions,  inventions,  discoveries,
                         superior accomplishments, exemplary behavior, heroic deeds, extraordinary acts or
                         service  in  the  public  interest  which  contribute  to  the  efficiency,  economy,  and
                         improvement in the  University’s operations which lead to organizational productivity.

                         Career – positions in the civil service characterized by (1) entrance based on merit
                         and fitness to be determined as far as practicable by competitive examination, or
                         based on highly technical qualifications; (2) opportunity for advancement to higher
                         career positions; and (3) security of tenure.

                         Committee –  refers to the designated CvSU PRAISE Committee.

                         Contribution  –  any  input  which  can  be  in  the  form  of  an  idea,  invention,  or
                         performance. (See also Idea type and Performance type contribution)

                         Discovery – is the uncovering of something previously existing but found or learned
                         for the first time which will improve public service delivery.

                         Equal  Opportunity  Principles  (EOP)  -  arises  from  the  similar  treatment  of  all
                         people, unhampered by artificial barriers or prejudices or preferences, except when
                         particular distinctions can be explicitly justified (Jonsen, et.al 2015); an ideal state in
                         which everyone has the same chance to participate and succeed in any aspect of
                         their work and lives (Westen, 1985).

                         Gender  Equality  -  also  known as sexual  equality,  is  the state  of  equal  ease  of
                         access  to  resources and opportunities  regardless  of  gender,  including  economic
                         participation  and  decision-making;  and  the  state  of  valuing  different  behaviors,
                         aspirations and needs equally, regardless of gender. (ILO, 2000)

                         Gender Identity - is a person's internal feelings of being a woman, man, both, or
                         neither. Most people have a gender identity and/or gender expression (how a person
                         shows their gender through their appearance or behavior) that matches their sex
                         assigned  at  birth.  However,  some  people  have  a  gender  identity  or  gender
                         expression that is different from their sex assigned at birth; these people might use
                         the term "transgender" or "gender non-conforming" to describe their gender identity.
                         (Young Mens Health, n.d.)

                         Idea  Type  Contribution  –  refers  to  an  idea,  a  suggestion,  or  discovery  for
                         improvement to effect economy in operation, to increase production and improve
                         working conditions.

                         Incentive – monetary or non-monetary motivation or privilege given to an official or
                         employee  for  contributions,  suggestions,  inventions,  ideas,  satisfactory
                         accomplishment,  or  demonstration  of  exemplary  behavior  based  on  agreed
                         performance standards and norms of behavior.

                         Invention – the creation of something previously non-existent which will benefit the
                         government.

                         Non-Career – positions expressly declared by law to be in the non-career service,
                         or those whose entrance in the service is characterized by (1) entrance on bases
                         other than those of the usual tests of merit and fitness for the career service and (2)
                         tenure which is limited to the duration of a particular project for which purpose of
                         employment was made.

                                                                                                  Page 4 of 23]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE


                         Performance Based Incentive (PBI) – a PBI system consisting of the Productivity
                         Enhancement Incentive (PEI) and the Performance-Based Bonus (PBB). (EO 80, s.
                         2012)

                         Performance Type Contribution – refers to performance of an extraordinary act or
                         service  in  the  public  interest  in  connection  with,  or  related  to  one’s  official
                         employment; or outstanding community service or heroic acts in the public interest;
                         or sustained work performance for a minimum period of one (1) year which is over
                         and above the normal position requirement of the individual or group.

                         PRAISE – refers to Program on Awards and Incentives for Service Excellence.

                         Sexual Orientation - refers to sexual and romantic feelings for people of the same
                         gender, a different gender, or more than one gender. People who identify their sexual
                         orientation  as  "straight"  or  "heterosexual"  feel  attracted  to  people  of  a  different
                         gender than themselves. (Young Mens Health, n.d.)

                         Suggestion – idea or proposal which improves work performance, systems and
                         procedures and economy in operations that will benefit the government.

                         System – the  University’s Awards and Incentives Program for Employees.


                   V.    TYPES OF AWARDS

                         A.  National Awards

                         The University  shall participate in the search for deserving employees who may be
                         in  the  screening  of  candidates  for  awards  given  by  other  government  agencies,
                         private entities, NGO’s and other award giving bodies such as the:

                         1.  Presidential or Lingkod Bayan (PLB) Award –  conferred on an individual or
                            group comprised of five members for exceptional or extraordinary contributions
                            resulting  from  an  idea  or  performance  that  had  nationwide  impact  on  public
                            interest,  security,  and  patrimony.  The  contribution  may  be  a  suggestion,
                            innovation, invention, or superior accomplishment.

                              Forms of Rewards and Incentives:
                              •  The awardee shall receive a gold-gilded medallion.
                              •  A  plaque  containing  the  citation  and  signature  of  the  President  of  the
                                 Philippines.
                              •  P200,000.00 cash reward
                              •  Pursuant to Section 5 of EO No. 508 entitled “Instituting the Lingkod Bayan
                                 Award  as  the  Presidential  Award  for  Outstanding  Public  Service”  dated
                                 March 2, 1992, they are entitled to “an automatic promotion to the next
                                 higher  position  suitable  to  their  qualifications  and  with  commensurate
                                 salary; provided that if there is no next higher position or it is not vacant,
                                 said position shall be included in the next budget of the office, except when
                                 the creation of a new position would result in distortion in the organizational
                                 structure of the department, office or agency. Where there is no next higher
                                 positions immediately available, a salary increase equivalent to the next


                                                                                                  Page 5 of 23]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                                 higher position shall be given and incorporated in the basic pay. When a
                                 new position is created, that which is vacated shall be deemed abolished”

                         2.  Civil  Service  Commission  or  the  PAGASA  AWARD  –  is  conferred  to  an
                            individual  or  group  comprised  of  five  members  for  outstanding  contribution/s
                            resulting  from  an  idea  of  performance  that  directly  benefit  more  than  one
                            department of the government.

                              Forms of Rewards and Incentives:
                              •  The awardee shall receive a gold-gilded medallion.
                              •  A plaque containing the citation and signature of the Chairperson of the
                                 Civil Service Commission as provided under Section 6 (b) of the Omnibus
                                 Rules Implementing Book V of Executive Order No. 292 and CSC MC No.
                                 03, s. 1992.
                              •  The Commission in various Resolutions (CSC Resolution Nos. 1101501-A,
                                 s.  2011;  1201147,  s.  2012;  1301973,  s.  2013;  and  1401195,  s.  2014)
                                 increased the cash award of the recipients of the CSC PAGASA Award to
                                 P100,000.00 each beginning 2011. The cash reward as well as the non-
                                 monetary incentives stipulated in said resolutions shall, unless otherwise
                                 amended, be applicable for CSC PAGASA awardees in succeeding years.
                                 Thus, the PAGASA awardees after 2011, both individual and group/team
                                 awardees, shall also receive a cash reward of P100,000.00 each.

                         3.  Outstanding Public Officials and Employees or the Dangal ng Bayan (DnB)
                            Award is conferred to an individual for performance of an extraordinary act or
                            public service and consistent demonstration of exemplary ethical behavior on the
                            basis of observance of the eight norms provided under Republic Act No. 6713,
                            otherwise known as the Code of Conduct and Ethical Standards for Commitment
                            to Public Interest, Professionalism, Justness and Sincerity, Political Neutrality,
                            Responsiveness  to  the  Public,  Nationalism  and  Patriotism,  Commitment  to
                            Democracy and Simple Living.

                          Forms of Rewards and Incentives:
                           •  The awardee shall receive a trophy designed and executed by National Artist
                              for Sculpture Napoleon V. Abueva.
                           •  P200,000.00 cash reward.
                           •  Pursuant to Section 6, paragraph 3 of RA 6713, otherwise known as the Code
                              of  Conduct  and  Ethical  Standards  for  Public  Officials  and  Employees,
                              incentives and rewards to government officials and employees of the year to
                              be  announced  in  public  ceremonies  honoring  them  may  take  the  form  of
                              bonuses,  citations,  directorships  in  government-owned  or  controlled
                              corporations, local and foreign scholarship grants, paid vacations, and the like.
                              They shall likewise be automatically promoted to the next higher positions with
                              the commensurate salary suitable to their qualifications. In case there is no
                              next higher position, or it is not vacant, said position shall be included in the
                              budget of the office in the next General Appropriations Act.








                                                                                                  Page 6 of 23]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                         4.   Other Awards – given by other government agencies, private institutions, or
                            NGO’s to an individual or team for contributions of an idea or performance that
                            directly benefited the government.

                         B.  University Level Awards

                              The University shall develop and initiate the search for deserving employees
                       who may be included in the screening of candidates for awards to be given such as:

                       1.  TANGLAW NG MAG –AARAL AWARD

                                 This shall be conferred on to one (1) distinguished faculty member who
                          excel in the tasks of promoting instruction activities expected of the academic staff.
                          Eligibility:

                              The qualification requirements of nominees are as follows:
                              1.  served the University for at least five (5) continuous teaching years.
                              2.  has not incurred leave without pay during the period under review
                              3.  full-time faculty members  with plantilla  position regardless of academic
                                 rank
                              4.  obtained  at  least  Very  Satisfactory  performance  for  the  last  two  rating
                                 periods.
                              5.  has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                                 action during the period under review
                          Criteria:

                                 The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of awardee.

                           A. Instruction                                                                     80%
                              •  Teaching Philosophy                                                        15%
                                     o  Submit a 500 -word essay about philosophy of teaching
                                         (Font: Arial, size 11, A4 bond paper)
                              •  Instructional Materials:                                            30%
                                     •  Syllabi, lesson plan, instructional design and creative materials
                                            o  Appropriateness of content
                                            o  Consistency with teaching philosophy
                                            o  Appropriateness of teaching strategies to content
                                            o  Appropriateness of evaluation scheme to objectives
                                     •  Student Evaluation for Teachers                              15%
                                            o  Not lower than Very Satisfactory
                                     •  Teaching Innovation                                           20%
                                            o  Manner of teaching done in the University
                                            o  New Evaluation and teaching material
                                            o  Use of technology

                            B. Professional Growth                                  _____           20%
                                     •  Enrollment in graduate studies
                                            o  Certification from registrar’s office of units for the last 5 years
                                     •  Certificates of attendance to trainings, seminars, etc.
                                     •  Articles (books or chapters/module that are for revision)
                          TOTAL                                                                   100%



                                                                                                  Page 7 of 23]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                          Nomination Procedure:
                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the  PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation  detailing  why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.


                          Required documents to be submitted:

                              1.  Nomination Form
                              2.  Justification  for  nomination  prepared/  signed  by  the  College/Campus
                                 Faculty  Search  Committee  and  endorsed  by  the  Dean.  Only  one
                                 nomination should be submitted by each College/Campus.
                              3.  Curriculum Vitae of the nominee
                              4.  A  one-  page  resume  of  the  highlights  of  teaching  performance  and
                                 innovations
                              5.  Portfolio  of  best  works  e.g.  syllabi,  module,  sample  learning  materials,
                                 sample exams, sample lectures/visual aids
                              6.  Reports of student evaluation (SET) for the last three years.
                              7.  Proof of attendance to training, seminars, awards and recognition received,
                                 academic studies and publication
                              8.  Administrative  clearance  (Certificate  of  No  pending  administrative  case
                                 issued by the HRDO)
                          Awards:

                                 A plaque of recognition and the amount of P25,000 will be given to the
                          Awardee during Foundation Day Celebration.



                   2.  KABALIKAT AWARD

                                 This  shall  be  given  annually  to  one  (1)  non-teaching  employees  who
                          excellently performed the tasks of providing support or auxiliary services for the
                          cause of education.

                          Eligibility:

                                 The qualification requirements of nominees are as follows:
                              1.  at least three (3) years of continuous service to the university
                              2.  has not incurred leave without pay during the period under review
                              3.  non- teaching staff with plantilla position
                              4.  obtained  at  least  very  satisfactory  performance  for  the  last  two  rating
                                 periods.
                              5.  has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                                 action during the period under review


                          Criteria:

                                 The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of awardee

                                 Significant Contribution                                            40%
                                      •  Problems addressed, savings generated,
                                          people/ office benefited and transactions facilitated
                                 Consistency of Performance                                       20%
                                     ▪  Responsive delivery of work outputs based on the
                                                                                                  Page 8 of 23]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                                         set standards per job category
                                 Work Attitude and Interpersonal Relations                        20%
                                     ▪  Commendatory work behavior
                                     ▪  Harmonious working relationship with colleagues
                                 Professional Growth                                                 15%
                                     ▪  Enrollment in graduate studies
                                     ▪  Certificates of attendance to trainings, seminars, etc

                                 Loyalty to the University                                              5 %
                                 TOTAL                                                                                     100%


                          Nomination Procedure:

                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the    PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation detailing why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.


                          Required documents to be submitted:

                              1.  Nomination form
                              2.  Justification for the nomination (description of the nominee’s performance,
                                 accomplishments, work attitude and interpersonal relation) to be submitted
                                 by the College/ Campus/ Unit and endorsed by the College/Campus /Unit
                                 Head. Only one should be nominated by the College/Campus/Unit.
                              3.  Personal Data Sheet (PDS)
                              4.  Certified Copies of proofs of:
                                     •  Academic  Degrees  or  subjects  earned/taken/enrolled  within  the
                                         rating period
                                     •  Seminars/trainings/workshops attended within the rating period
                              5.  Administrative  clearance  (Certificate  of  No  pending  administrative  case
                            issued by the  HRDO)


                          Awards:

                                A  plaque  of  recognition  and  the  amount  of  P25,000  will  be  given  to  the
                         Awardee during Foundation Day Celebration.


                   3.  DANGAL NG CvSU AWARD (Exemplary Behavior Award)

                              This award shall be given to one (1) University employee who had exhibited
                       exemplary dedication to work based on the eight norms of conduct as provided under
                       RA 6713- Code of Conduct and Ethical Standards.

                              The  Awardee  will  be  automatically  nominated  by  the  University  PRAISE
                       Committee to the Dangal ng Bayan Award of the Civil Service Commission.


                          Eligibility:

                          The qualification requirements of nominees are as follows:


                                                                                                  Page 9 of 23]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                              1.  at least five (5) years of continuous service to the university
                              2.  has not incurred leave without pay during the period under review
                              3.  faculty member or non-teaching employee with plantilla position
                              4.  obtained at least very satisfactory performance for the last two rating
                                    periods.
                              5.  has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                                    action during the period under review


                         Criteria:

                                 The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of awardee:

                            Exemplary Behavior/Conduct Displayed within the last 3 years          40%
                                 •  Adherence to one or more norms of ethical standards
                                                i.e. circumstances, risk involved and problems encountered
                            Impact of Accomplishment
                          40%
                                 •   Problems addressed, savings generated, people office
                                        benefited and transactions facilitated
                                 •   Circumstances why the accomplishments are considered
                                         exemplary or extraordinary
                          Professional Improvement                                                20%
                                      •  Major awards/Citations Received and memberships
                                          In professional organizations
                                                                                                  ____
                          TOTAL                                                                                       100%


                          Nomination Procedure:
                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the  PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation  detailing  why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.


                          Required documents to be submitted:

                          1.  Nomination form
                          2.   Justification  for  the  nomination  (description  of  the  nominee’s  exemplary
                              behavior,  impact  of  accomplishment  and  professional  improvement)  to  be
                              submitted by the College/ Campus/ Unit and endorsed by the College/Campus
                              Unit Head. Only one should be nominated by the College/Campus/Unit.
                          3.  Personal Data Sheet (PDS)
                          4.  Certified Copies of proofs of:
                                 ▪  Major Awards/ Citations Received
                                 ▪  Certificate of Membership in Professional Organizations
                          5.  Supporting including photos, recorded and/or written narration of exemplary
                              behavior.
                          6.  Has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                              action during the period under review




                                                                                                 Page 10 of 23]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                          Awards:
                                A  plaque  of  recognition  and  the  amount  of  P25,000  will  be  given  to  the
                         Awardee during Foundation Day Celebration.


                   4.   HUSAY NG CvSU AWARD  (Best Organizational Unit Award)

                                 This award shall be granted to one (1) organizational unit, which may be a
                        College,  Campus  or  office  on  the  basis  of  meeting  the  University’s  performance
                        targets and other pre-determined criteria.
                          Criteria:

                                 The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of Office awardee.

                          Office Performance                                                      40%
                                 •  Attainment of Office Targets within the prescribed period
                                 •  Problems addressed, savings generated, people office
                                      benefited and transactions facilitated
                           Quality and Consistency of Performance                                 20%
                                 •  Increased Office productivity
                                 •  Zero-complain transactions
                           Cost efficiency                                                                  20%
                                 •  Cost saving mechanisms employed to reduce waste, minimal
                                                usage of resources without sacrificing the quality of Office
                                                outputs
                           Team Spirit                                                                       20%
                           Total                                                                                 100%


                         Nomination Procedure:

                                Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  a  Vice  President  can  submit
                         nominations to the  PRAISE Committee with the explanation detailing why the office
                         nominee is deserving of the award.


                         Required documents to be submitted:

                         1.  Nomination form
                         2.  Justification  for  the  nomination  (description  of  the  office-  nominee’s
                             performance, to be submitted by the College/ Campus/ Unit and endorsed by
                             the  College/Campus  Unit  Head.  Only  one  should  be  nominated  by  the
                             College/Campus/Unit.
                         3.  Annual Accomplishment Report



                         Awards:

                                A  plaque  of  recognition  and  the  amount  of  P25,000  will  be  given  to  the
                         Awardee during  Foundation Day Celebration.



                                                                                                 Page 11 of 23]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE


                   5.  SIKAP NG CvSU AWARD (Career and Self-Development Award)


                              This award shall be granted in recognition of a faculty member or non-teaching
                       employee who has satisfactory completed a course or degree within or outside the
                       country at one’s own expense.


                          Eligibility:

                              The qualification requirements of nominees are as follows:

                              1.  at least five (5) years of continuous service to the university
                              2.  full time faculty member and staff  with plantilla position
                              3.  obtained  at  least  very  satisfactory  performance  for  the  last  two  rating
                                 periods.
                              4.  has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                                 action
                                  during the period under review
                              5.  the completed course or degree within or outside of the country is obtained
                                 from top 1000 universities in the world or from higher educational institution
                                 with level iii accredited graduate program by AACCUP. The degree should
                                 be aligned with the academic thrust of the university.

                          Nomination Procedure:

                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the    PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation detailing why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.


                          Required documents to be submitted:

                          1.  Nomination form
                          2.  Justification for the nomination to be submitted by the College/ Campus/ Unit
                              and endorsed by the College/Campus/ Unit Head. Only one candidate should
                              be nominated by the College/Campus/Unit
                          3.  IPCR for two rating periods
                          4.  Diploma and Transcript of Records


                          Awards:
                                 A  certificate  of  recognition  shall  be  given  to  the  awardee  during  the
                          University Foundation Day celebration. In addition, the awardee will also receive a
                          P 20,000 monetary incentive.


                   6.  LINGKOD NG CvSU AWARD (Service Award )

                                 This  award  shall  be  conferred  to  retirees  whether  under  optional  or
                          compulsory retirement schemes held during the University Foundation Day.


                                                                                                 Page 12 of 23]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE



                         Awards
                                A retiree will receive of a plaque of appreciation, a ring and cash award in the
                          amount of P1,000.00 for every year of service with the University but not more than
                          P30,000.00.



                   7.  GABAY NG CvSU AWARD (Administrator of the Year Award)

                          This award shall be granted to one (1) administrator who excels in the tasks of
                   strategically  leading  and  managing  the  assigned  organizational  unit  which  may  be  a
                   college/campus,  section,  division  or  office  that  created  a  value  added  products  and
                   services.


                          Eligibility:

                              1.  This award is open to all designated administrators in the University who is
                                 supervising at least three employees. Designations include vice-presidents,
                                 college deans, campus administrators, department chairs and unit heads.
                              2.  The nominee should be designated for at least two (2) years
                              3.  Obtained  at  least  Very  Satisfactory  performance  for  the  last  two  rating
                                 periods.
                              4.  Has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                                 action  during the period under review

                          Criteria

                          The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of awardee:

                          Impact and Relevance of Accomplishment                                  40%
                                      •  Attainment of Office Targets within the prescribed period
                                      •  Problems addressed, savings generated, people office
                                          benefited and transactions facilitated
                          Leadership Performance                                                  30%
                                     ▪  Innovation and creativity towards improvement
                                         of existing policies, procedures and practices
                                     ▪  Problem solving  and decision making capabilities
                                     ▪  Resource generation, linkages with partner individuals/
                                         agencies
                          Exemplary Behavior/Conduct Displayed within the last 3 years            20%
                                      •  Adherence to norms of ethical standards
                                          i.e. circumstances, risk involved and problems encountered
                          Professional Improvement                                                10%
                                      •  Major awards/Citations Received and memberships
                                          In professional organizations                                                          _____
                                 TOTAL                                                                    100%







                                                                                                 Page 13 of 23]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                          Nomination Procedure

                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the  PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation  detailing  why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.

                          Required documents to be submitted:

                              1.  Nomination form
                              2.  Justification for the nomination to be submitted by the College/ Campus/
                                 Unit and endorsed by the College/Campus Unit Head.
                              3.  IPCR for two rating periods
                              4.  Administrative Clearance
                              5.  Annual Accomplishment Report of the Office


                          Awards
                                 The Awardee will be given a plaque of recognition and a cash award in the
                          amount of P25,000.00


                   8.  MANANALIKSIK NG CvSU AWARD (Researcher of the Year Award)

                          This  award  shall  be  granted  to  one  (1)  outstanding  researcher  who  has  made
                          significant contributions on research in terms of attainment  of the research targets
                          of  the  University  particularly  on  having  the  research  outputs  disseminated  in
                          recognized fora; publication in refereed , ISI, Scopus  –Indexed journals and /or
                          intellectual  property rights application such as patents, utility model, copyrights
                          and others.

                          This  award  is  open  to  all  faculty  members  and  employees  who  are  actively
                          engaged in research undertakings.

                          Eligibility:

                          The qualification requirements of the nominee are as follows:

                            1.  at least five (5) years of continuous service to the university
                            2.  full time faculty members and staff with plantilla position
                            3.  obtained at least very satisfactory performance for the last two rating periods.
                            4.  has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                              action
                              during the period under review
                            6.  must have been a principal investigator for at least one project completed
                              within the last 5 years.


                          Criteria:
                                 The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of the awardee:

                             Research Work
                               Significance of Research Work                                      20%
                                  How the research contributed in the discipline, development of
                                   New principle, theory, concept, methodology or technology


                                                                                                 Page 14 of 23]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                               Impact of research work(s)                                         20%
                                 Contribution to science, technology generation, national development
                                 policies and programs or to the culture and well-being of the Philippine
                                 society; contribution to the university (e.g. promotion/enhancement of
                                 academic programs, provision of new or upgraded facilities/equipment
                                 for instruction and further research

                          Track Record
                            Publication Record                                                    50%
                                 Number of researches published in the last 5 to 10 years ( listed in the
                                 following order: refereed journals, non-refereed journals, articles like
                                 books, monographs, etc,)

                          Recognition
                                 Citations, awards and other forms of recognition from academic
                                 institutions and scientific societies’ recognition for the University
                                          as  result of impact of the research.                   10%
                          TOTAL                                                                      100%


                          Nomination Procedure:

                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the  PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation  detailing  why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.

                          Selection Process:

                                 1.  Each  College/unit  can  nominate  at  most  three  (3)    nominees.
                                     Nomination should be coursed through the Dean or Director
                                 2.  The members of the Search Committee will review and rate each of the
                                     nominee based on the above criteria and will deliberate  en banc to
                                     choose the recipient of the award. Ties will be resolved by a majority
                                     vote.

                          Documents to be submitted:
                                 1.  Nomination Form
                                 2.  One-page resume of the nominee
                                 3.  Copies of three (3) most important research projects for the last 5 years
                                 4.  List of published works with bibliographical citations
                                 5.  Abstracts of all publications
                                 6.  Documentation of citations, awards and other forms of recognition from
                                     academic institution and scientific societies.

                          Awards:

                                 The Awardee will be given a plaque of recognition and a cash award in the
                          amount of P25,000.00


                   9.  TAGAPAG-UGNAY NG CvSU AWARD ( Extensionist of the Year Award)

                          This award shall be granted to one (1) outstanding extensionist who excels in the
                          tasks of providing/ sharing mature technologies and/or developing strong linkages



                                                                                                 Page 15 of 23]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                          to stakeholders and other interested parties that help improve the lives of people
                          in the community.

                          This award is open to all University teaching and non- teaching employees  who
                          are actively engaged in extension activities.

                          Eligibility:

                            The qualification requirements of the nominees are as follows:
                            1.  at least five (5) years of continuous service to the university
                            2.  full time faculty members and staff with plantilla position
                            3.  obtained at least very satisfactory performance for the last two rating periods.
                            4.  has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                              action  during the period under review
                            5.  must  have  been a  principal  investigator  for  at  least  one  project  completed
                              withinthe last 5 years.
                            6.  the  extent  of  community  work  performed  by  the  nominee    must  be  as
                              widespread as possible e.g. entire university or outside communities. Example
                              of  extension  services  are  non  -degree  training,  seminars,  workshops,
                              conferences, review classes, advisory/technical/information services, exhibits,
                              performance,  consultancy,  networking,  advocacy  and  volunteer  community
                              work.


                          Criteria
                                 The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of the awardee:

                          Potential expected outcome/impact of extension work in the              40%
                               University, community or country

                          Extension work aligned with the vision and mission of CvSU              25%

                               Commitment of employee in extension work (without compromising
                          Official duties in the University)                                      20%

                               Advocacy for the University through involvement of other members
                          of the institution                                                      15%
                                 TOTAL                                                               100%


                          Nomination Procedure:

                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the  PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation  detailing  why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.


                          Documents to be submitted:
                                 1.  Nomination form
                                 2.  Duly accomplished Information Sheet and Justification for Nomination
                                 3.  Approved Extension Program
                                 4.  Accomplishment Reports of significant extension works for the last 3
                                     years
                                 5.  Written Feedback from the Community
                                 6.  Administrative Clearance from the HRDO

                                                                                                 Page 16 of 23]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE


                    10. GAWAD NG PANGULO AWARD (President’s Award)

                              This award shall be granted in recognition of an “extra-ordinary achievement
                       i.e successfully implemented an idea that contributed to the efficiency and economy of
                       individual,  College/Campus/Unit  or  University’s  productivity  or  improvement  in
                       operations or in the welfare of co- employees.

                              Two awards will be granted annually for Level 1  and Level 2 employees . Level
                       1 positions shall include clerical, trades and crafts, and custodial service positions
                       which  involve  non-  professional  or  sub-professional  work  in  a  non-supervisory  or
                       supervisory capacity requiring less than four (four) years of collegiate studies. Level 2
                       positions shall involve professional, technical and scientific work in a supervisory or
                       non-supervisory capacity up to Division Chief Level or its equivalent.


                          Eligibility:

                          The qualification requirements of the nominee are as follows:
                            1.  served the University for at least 5 years
                            2.  faculty member or non teaching staff with plantilla positions
                            3.  obtained at least very satisfactory performance for the last two rating periods.
                            4.  has not incurred any leave of absence without pay
                            5.  has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                              action  during the period under review


                          Criteria

                          The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of awardee:

                          Impact  and Relevance of Accomplishment                                  40%
                              • Problems addressed, savings generated, people /office
                                benefited and transactions facilitated
                          Reliability and Effectiveness                                            30%
                               •  Demonstrated outstanding competence, teamwork
                                             and cooperation, which resulted to achievement of goals
                                             and great improvement in the delivery of services
                          Exemplary Performance                                                    20%
                                ▪ Consistent, dedicated performance and achievements
                                          or demonstrated exemplary ethical behavior , in order to
                                          inspire other employees to improve their quality of performance
                          Professional Improvement                                                10%
                                •  Demonstrated professional growth in the exercise
                                            of  profession/work assignment i.e. Professional and
                                           academic preparation and Training/continuing education
                                            for the last five years                               _____
                          TOTAL                                                                                100%


                         Nomination Procedure

                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the  PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation  detailing  why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.

                                                                                                 Page 17 of 23]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE


                          Required documents to be submitted:

                          1.  Nomination form
                          2.  Justification for the nomination to be submitted by the College/ Campus/ Unit
                              and endorsed by the College/Campus Unit Head.
                          3.  IPCR for two rating periods
                          4.  Supporting documents including diploma, certificates of trainings, seminars,
                              conferences
                          5.  Administrative Clearance


                          Awards

                          Each Awardee will be given a plaque of recognition and a cash award in the amount
                          of P50,000.00



                   11. PINAKAMAAYOS NA YUNIT NG CvSU AWARD ( Most Organized Unit Award)

                              This  award  shall  be  given  to  one  (1)  Office  which  the  physical  areas  of
                       responsibility are well maintained and follow good office keeping practices as defined
                       by the principles of “5s” of good house-keeping, i.e, Sort, Sytematize, Sweep,
                       Sanitize and Sustain.

                         Criteria
                                This award is open to all Colleges/Campuses/ Office of the University that
                         have most consistently exhibited the following criteria:

                             •  Work/Floor Space Utilization improvement                          20%
                             •  Minimized Use of Consumables and less wastage of resources        20%
                             •  Systematic Workflow and error-free products and services          20%
                             •  Clean, safe and well-organized working environment                20%
                             •  Team Spirit/ Team work                                            20%

                             TOTAL                                                                   100%
                          Nomination Procedure

                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations to the PRAISE Committee with the explanation detailing why the office
                          nominee is deserving of the award.


                          Required documents to be submitted:

                             1.  Nomination form
                             2.  Justification for the nomination to be submitted by the College/ Campus/
                                   Unit and endorsed by the College/Campus Unit Head.
                             3.  Supporting document such as photos, procedures used in 5S of Good
                                   Housekeeping. .




                                                                                                 Page 18 of 23]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                          Awards

                                A plaque  of Recognition and a cash award amounting to P25,000 will be
                         given to the Office Awardee during the Foundation Day.


                   12.  GALING NG CvSU AWARD (Model Employee of the Year)

                         This  award  shall  be  given  to  one  (1)  University  employee  who  had  exhibited
                         exemplary dedication to their work, outstanding performance in technical duties and
                         responsibilities  and  behavioral  dimensions,  compliance  to  office  rules  and
                         regulations.

                         Eligibility

                          The qualification requirements of nominees are as follows:
                            1.  at least five (5) years of continuous service to the university
                            2.  has not incurred leave without pay during the period under review
                            3.  faculty member /non teaching employee with plantilla position
                            4.  obtained at least very satisfactory performance for the last two rating periods.
                            5.  has no pending administrative case or has not been given any disciplinary
                          action
                                 during the period under review


                          Criteria:

                              The following are the criteria to be used in the selection of awardee

                                 Outstanding Work Performance                        40%
                                 Dedication to work                                  20 %
                                 Work Attitude and Interpersonal Relations           20%
                                 Adherence to Office Rules and Regulations           20%
                                 TOTAL                                                                       100%

                          Nomination Procedure:

                                 Nominations  are  open  each  year  wherein  any  employee  can  submit
                          nominations  to  the    PRAISE  Committee  with  the  explanation detailing why  the
                          nominee is deserving of the award.


                          Required documents to be submitted:

                          1.  Nomination form
                          2.  Justification for the nomination to be submitted by the College/ Campus/ Unit
                              and endorsed by the College/Campus Unit Head. The College/Campus/Unit
                              should nominate only one employee.
                          3.  Personal Data Sheet (PDS)
                          4.  Administrative clearance (Certificate of No pending administrative case issued
                              by the
                               HRDO)
                          5.  IPCR for two rating periods
                          6.  HRDO Records
                          7.  Written Commendation/Feedback from Stakeholders

                                                                                                 Page 19 of 23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE


                          Awards:

                                A  plaque  of  recognition  and  the  amount  of  P25,000  will  be  given  to  the
                         Awardee during Foundation Day Celebration.


                   VI.   INCENTIVES

                       1.  TYPES OF INCENTIVES

                          The agency shall continuously search, screen, and reward deserving officials and
                          employees to motivate them to improve the quality of their performance and instill
                          excellence in public service. As such, the following types of incentives shall be
                          regularly awarded:

                          a)  Loyalty Incentive – granted to all officials and employees who rendered ten (10)
                              years of continuous and satisfactory service in the government. MC 6, s. 2002
                              Criteria:
                              The official or employee who incurred an aggregate of not more than 50 days
                              authorized  vacation  leave  without  pay  within  the  10-year  period  shall  be
                              considered as having rendered continuous service. In the same way, an official
                              or employee who incurred an aggregate of not more than twenty-five (25) days
                              authorized vacation leave without pay within the 5-year period may qualify for
                              the 5-year milestone loyalty award. Services rendered in other agencies prior
                              to January 1, 2002 shall not be considered for purposes of granting the loyalty
                              award.

                              Forms of Incentives:
                              1.  Memorabilia / souvenir
                                 10 and 15 years              - bronze service pin
                                 20 and 25 years              - silver service ring
                                 30, 35, and 40 years         - gold service rings with CvSU Logo
                                 or other memorabilia / souvenir as may be provided in the agency PRAISE.

                              2.  Cash  gift  which  shall  not  be  less  than  P500.00  but  not  more  than  Php
                                 1,000.00 for every year of service.

                          b)  Length of Service Incentive – given to an employee who has rendered at least
                              three (3) years of continuous satisfactory service in the same position. (MC 1,
                              s. 2001)

                              Criteria:
                              The cash award shall be incorporated in the salary adjustments following the
                              CSC-DBM joint circular no. 1, s. 1990 and CSC-DBM joint circular no. 1, s.
                              2012, provided, the grant of step increment shall not exceed the maximum.

                              Forms of Incentives:
                              Grant of step increment

                          c)  Productivity Enhancement Incentive (PEI) – shall be given to all employees
                              who have performed satisfactorily for the year covered in accordance with the
                                                                                                 Page 20 of 23]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                              agency’s CSC approved SPMS. This incentive shall follow relevant existing
                              guidelines (EO 201, s. 2016)

                              Criteria and Forms of Incentives:
                              See: DBM 2017-4 (Guidelines on the Grant of the Productivity Enhancement
                              Incentive  (PEI)  to  Government  Employees  for  fiscal  year  (FY)  2017  and
                              thereafter.


                          d)  Other incentives which the CvSU PRAISE Committee may recommend on
                              the  basis  of  special  achievements,  innovative  approaches  to  assignments,
                              exemplary  service  to  the  public  and  recognition  by  an  outside  group  of  a
                              particular achievement.


                   VII.FORMS OF AWARDS AND INCENTIVES
                       1.  Compensatory Time-Off – granted to an employee who has worked beyond his
                          regular office hours on a project without overtime pay.

                       2.  Flexiplace  –  work  arrangement  allowed  for  qualified  employee/s  who  has
                          demonstrated responsibility, initiative, and capacity to produce output/result and
                          accomplishment outside of the workplace subject to established guidelines.

                       3.  “Salu-salo” Together – meal hosted by superiors or supervisors foremployees
                          who have made significant contributions.

                       4.  Personal  Growth  Opportunities  –  incentives  which  maybe  in  the  form  of
                          attendance  in  conferences  on  official  business,  membership  in  professional
                          organizations,  books,  journals,  tapes,  travel  packages  and  other  learning
                          opportunities.

                       5.  Trophies, Plaques and Certificates
                       6.  Monetary Award

                       7.  Travel Packages

                       8.  Other Incentives – incentives in kind which may be in the form of merchandise,
                          computers, wristwatch, cellular phones, recognition posted at the Wall of Fame,
                          feature in University publication  or in any social media account, and others (as
                          may be suggested by PRAISE COMMITTEE).

                   VII.  FUNCTIONS AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE PRAISE COMMITTEE

                      The  PRAISE  Committee  shall  be  responsible  for  the  development,  administration,
                      monitoring and evaluation of the awards and incentives system of the Agency. As such,
                      the committee shall meet periodically to perform the following tasks:

                            a.  establish  a  system  of  ncentives  and  awards  to  recognize  and  motivate
                               employees for their performance and conduct;
                            b.  formulate, adopt, and amend internal rules, policies and procedures to govern
                               the conduct of its activities which shall include the guidelines in evaluating the
                               nominees and the mechanism for recognizing the awardees;
                                                                                                 Page 21 of 23]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                            c.  Determine the forms of awards and incentives to be granted;
                            d.  monitor  implementation  of  approved  suggestions  and  ideas  through
                               feedbacks and reports.
                            e.  prepare plans, identify resources, and propose budget for the system on an
                               annual basis;
                            f.  develop,  produce,  distribute  a  System  Policy  Manual,  and  orient  the
                               employees on the same;
                            g.  document  best  practices,  innovative  ideas  and  success  stories  which  will
                               serve as promotional materials to sustain interest and enthusiasm;
                            h.  Submit an annual report on the awards and incentives systems to the CSC
                               RO No. IV on or before the thirtieth (30 ) day of January;
                                                                     th
                            i.  Monitor  and  evaluate  the  System’s  implementation  every  year  and  make
                               essential improvements to ensure its suitability to the agency;
                            j.  Address issues relative to awards and incentives within fifteen (15) days from
                               the date of submission.

                          To  implement  the  System  effectively,  the  PRAISE  Committee  members  are
                          expected to possess positive attitude, be capable of implementing submitted ideas,
                          open-minded, decisive, have high tolerance for stress or pressure, and actively
                          participate in all committee meetings.

                          The  University  President  or  authorized  representative  shall  be  responsible  in
                          overseeing the System’s operations and the Human Resource Development Office
                          Unit shall serve as the System’s Secretariat

                          The University may, however, employ an external or independent body to assist
                          the  PRAISE  Committee  to  implement  the  system  of  incentives  and  awards
                          judiciously and objectively.

                   VIII.  COMPOSITION OF THE PRAISE COMMITTEE
                                The PRAISE committee in the agency without prejudice to future changes in
                         its composition shall be comprised of the following:


                           Chairperson        :  Vice President for Administrative and Support Services

                         Members              :  Vice President for Academic Affairs
                                                 Vice President for Research and Extension
                                                 Vice President for Planning and Development
                                                 Director for Human Resource Development Office
                                                 Director for Finance and Management
                                                 President of the Faculty Association
                                                 President for Non-Academic Employees

                           Secretariat           :  Head of the Rewards and Recognition Unit of HRDO


                   IX.   FUNDING

                   The    University  shall  allocate  at  least  5%  of  the  HRD  Funds  for  the  PRAISE  and
                   incorporate the same in the Annual Work and Financial Plan and Budget. (MC 1, s. 2001)


                                                                                                 Page 22 of 23]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY REVISED PRAISE

                   X.    EFFECTIVITY

                   This    CvSU  PRAISE  shall  become  effective  after  final  evaluation  by  the  CSC  RO  IV.
                   Subsequent amendments shall likewise be submitted to CSC ROIV for evaluation and
                   shall take effect immediately.



                   XI.   COMMITMENT
                   I hereby commit to implement and abide by the provisions of this CvSU- PRAISE which
                   shall  be  the  basis  for  the  grant  of  awards  and  incentives  including  Productivity
                   Enhancement Incentive (PEI).
                   The annual PRAISE Report shall be submitted to the CSC Regional Office concerned on
                   or before the thirtieth day of January to enable our employees to qualify for nomination to
                   the CSC-sponsored national awards.




                                                                   DR. HERNANDO D. ROBLES, CEO VI
                                                                              University President

                                                                     ______May 20, 2021 ____________
                                                                                    Date
                   CSC Action:

                   I have evaluated the herein  CvSU PRAISE and found it to be in accordance with the
                   provision of CSC MC No. 1, 2001, CSC MC 6, s. 2002, CSC MC 18, s. 2012, EO 201, s.
                   2016, and CSC MC No. 01, s. 2019 and may now be implemented.






                   KARIN LITZ P. ZERNA
                              Director IV
                   CSC Regional Director

                   ___________________
                          Date




















                                                                                                 Page 23 of 23]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PERFORMANCE



                               MANAGEMENT SYSTEM]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[4.1.]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>