<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="82"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.1.            Students are provided opportunities to


                        participate in the planning and


                        implementation of activities concerning

                        their welfare.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY

                                                     Tanza Campus

                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979



                                          CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT
               December 13, 2021



               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS

               Campus Administrator
               Tanza



               Dear Prof. Ramos,
               Good day Sir! We, the Central Student Government of Cavite State University- Tanza Campus
               are humbly asking for your approval to conduct a “Virtual Winter Wonderland Year End 2021”
               Theme: Engaged in New Beginnings to Remarkable Possibilities. This is a Christmas
               tradition that our campus has every year in December. The virtual year-end celebration is an
               occasion for students and teachers to reflect on the previous year, set new goals, and make
               plans for the coming year. This is also an occasion for them to send each other good wishes
               and express gratitude to all who have contributed in the previous year. All activities for this
               event will be virtual and will promote solidarity to the community.



               Attached are the proposed events; program of activities; and working committees for the said
               activity



               Hoping for your positive response. Thank you and God bless!


               Respectfully yours,



               CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS
               President, CSG]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Noted by:


               MARK JOEL C. SIBULO                                                              AUDREYSON H. BORILLA
               Senior Adviser, CSG                                                                          Junior Adviser, CSG




               Recommending Approval:

               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, OSAS

                                                       Approved:



                                               GIL D. RAMOS, MaHisto
                                                   Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979



                                         CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT


                                                ACTIVITY PROPOSAL




               I.  Title of Activity: Virtual Winter Wonderland Year End 2021
                                               Theme: Engaged in New Beginnings to Remarkable Possibilities


               II. Proponents: All bonafied students of Cavite State University-Tanza Campus

               II.  Rationale:

                                   For  the  students  and  teachers  of  Tanza  Campus,  the  Central  Student
                   Government officers and advisers plan a "Virtual Winter Wonderland Year End 2021." The
                   theme, Engaged in New Beginnings to Remarkable Possibilities, is about adjusting to

                   new beginnings, mending, giving, and sharing the possibilities that will arise in the future
                   year. Virtual Year End is one of the events that College students look forward to, as the

                   semester of learning requires a reward. The CSG and adviser are planning a variety of
                   activities, including surprise raffle presents, contests, and performances, to give Tanza
                   Campus students a great Year-end in 2021.

               III.  Objective/s of Project:
                       This virtual event aims to foster a sense of community, solidarity, and gratitude among
                   all participants. It's a great chance to show our appreciation for students, teachers, and

                   school staff in order to make our community a better place. Students and teachers can
                   reflect on the previous year, set new goals, and make preparations for the current year at
                   the virtual year-end celebration. This is also an opportunity for them to give each other

                   greetings and express gratitude to everyone who helped out the previous year.
               IV. Mechanics and Implementations

                       A.  List of Participants
                          All bonafide students of Cavite State University –Tanza Campus.
                       B.  Date and Venue]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[The Virtual Year End will be on December 20, 2021, Monday from 3:00 P.M to 5:00
                          P.M. The registration for the event will be start on December 18,2021 to December

                          20,2021 until 2:00 P.M. There will be also live caroling and live bazaar in this day.
                          This event will be virtual via Facebook.
                       C.  Strategies/Mechanics

                          1.  The students who can register to this event will be from CVSU –Tanza Campus
                              and official enrolled students of First Semester A.Y. 2021-2022 only. The CSG

                              officers will launch a short video and posters about the event. There will be a
                              raffle ticket and that is 20.00php and Message Booth is 5.00 Php. The raffle
                              ticket is not mandatory for the students.


                          2. The event will be virtual, the CSG Officers will be preparing a program and the

                          students will be watching virtually all throughout of the day. The CSG officers will
                          have different committees for the said event. The program will be the guide of the
                          host. We will also be asking some help of other organizations.


                          3. There are lots of different contest that the students to join and they need to
                          contact Ms. Catindig for the contest of Talentadong Tanza Knights. They need to

                          register and send their recorded videos before the event. This is open for group
                          performances only. The other contest also needs to register before to participate
                          in the day of the event. After the event there will be a live Caroling of the CSG

                          Officers  and  live  BAZAAR  of  products  from  the  virtual  shop  of  CSG.  All  the
                          payments will have received by the CSG Treasurer. After of the whole event the

                          CSG will have an awarding and recognition for the best virtual outfit and many
                          more. The judges will be the CSG advisers.



                          D. Safety and Security Measures

                          1.  This virtual event will be live via Facebook. The distribution of raffle gifts and
                              contest prizes will be sent by trusted delivery personnel.

                          E.  Budgetary Estimate

                                                   Raffle Ticket (20.00)

                                               Virtual Message Booth – 5.00]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[this is not required and for the students who will avail the tickets this will be using for the

                                            future activities of the CSG in 2022.





                   VI. Contact Person

                   CSG President: Ms. Christine Jewel R. Gallos- christinejewel.gallos@cvsu.edu.ph
                   CSG Vice President: Jan Angela L. Catindig- janangela.catindig@cvsu.edu.ph
                   CSG Secretary: Mary Rose S. Morana- maryrose.morana@cvsu.edu.ph

                   CSG Treasurer: Ms. Kayla Rose I. Magpantay- kaylarose.magpantay@cvsu.edu.ph
                   CSG Senior Adviser: Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo- markjoel.sibulo@cvsu.edu.ph
                     CSG Junior Adviser: Mx. Audreyson Borilla – audreyson.borilla@cvsu.edu.ph


                                                 Program of the Event
                                        “Virtual Winter Wonderland Year End 2021”
                           Theme: Engaged in New Beginnings to Remarkable Possibilities.

                                         December 20, 2021- 3:00 P.M. - 06:00P.M.
                                                        Via FB Live
                    Program Flow                  In Charge

                 I. Prayer                        Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                                  CSG Senior Adviser
                 II. Opening Remarks              Mr. Gil D. Ramos, MAHisto
                                                  Campus Administrator
                 III. Video Greetings             CvSU Tanza Faculty and Staff
                                                  CSG Advisers
                 IV. CSG Accomplishment
                 Video Presentation
                                                  Audio Visual Presentation

                                                  Kap. Boyet Mintu
                 V.     Greetings from            Gov. Jonvic Remulla
                        Sponsors                  Mayor Yuri Pacumio- Tanza
                                                  Mayor Gemma Lubigan- Trece
                                                  Tanza Councilors
                                                  Trece Councilors
                                                  Audio Visual Presentation

                                                  Bytes – Mr. Raymond Potenciando
                                                  Fame Society- Angel Tabua
                 VI.    Greetings    from    the
                        Organization Presidents   Themes- Cherika Valdezco
                                                  Cope- Woodelyn Reyes
                                                  Anglicists Guild- Rose Ann Volante
                                                  Abees- Brian Emanciando
                                                  Radicals- Maria Angela Capuz]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[ApCon- Angelika Garcia
                                                  Theatro Tanza- John Mark Mirambel
                                                  Acwa- Elmer Ynopia
                 VII.   BE AMONG THE              Ms. Jan Angela Catindig & Hyram Salinas
                        STARS TALENT SHOW  CSG Officer & TTOPS Officer

                 VII.  Ice Breaker & Special      Audio Visual Presentation
                 Performances                     CSG Officers
                 VIII. RAFFLE                     Ms. Christine Jewel Gallos, Regie Anne Arabia
                                                  and Romulo Zabala Jr.

                                                  CSG Officers

                                              CSG VIDEO GREETINGS

                 IX.    Musical Concert           Audio Visual Presentation

                                                  TTOPS Officers

                 X. Closing Remarks               Ms. Christine Jewel R. Gallos

                                                  CSG President

                 XI. CvSU Hymn                    Audio Visual Presentation

                 XII. Awarding for the winners   Ms. Jan Angela Catindig & Hyram Salinas
                                                  CSG Officer & TTOPS Officer



                 XIII. BAZAAR LIVE                Ms. Geanne Gacu, Mr. Archie Carlos, Ms. Kayla
                                                  Rose Magpantay, Ms. Julie Claire Andres and Mr.
                                                  Luis Ansalmo
                                                  CSG Officers & TTOPS Officer




              I.       WORKING COMMITTEES

                 Technical Committee           TTOPS and Bytes Officers
                                               Mr. Raymond Potenciando
                                               Mr. Marson Mapile
                 Program and Documentation  CSG Officers

                                               Christine Jewel R. Gallos
                                               Jan Angela Catindig
                                               Mary Rose Morana
                                               Kayla Rose Magpantay
                                               Geanne Gacu
                                               Jennelyn Valderama
                                               Regie Anne Arabia
                                               Julie Claire Andres
                                               Archie Carlos
                                               Romulo Zabala Jr.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[TTOPS Officers

                                               Hyram Salinas
                                               Johnthel Jalbuena
                                               Marson Mapile
                                               John Mark Mirambel

                                               CSG Officers
                 Certificates and Evaluation   Jennelyn Valderama
                                               Mary Rose Morana
                                               Jennelyn Valderama
                 Social Media Committee        Regie Anne Arabia
                                               Julie Claire Andres
                                               CSG Officers
                 Registration and Monitoring   Jan Angela Catindig
                                               Mary Rose Morana
                                               Kayla Rose Magpantay
                 In-charge of the Ceremony     Jan Angela Catindig
                                               Hyram Salinas
                 Ice Breakers & Performances  CSG Officers, TTOPS Officers and other organizations]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[OSAS-QF-23

                                               Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979



               December 13, 2021


               To whom it may concern,

               Good day!

               We, the Altruistic Psych Confederate would like to request for your approval to carry out our
               activity. The said activity is entitled: “Online Caroling”.  The activity aims to raise a fund for
               our other pending activities. This activity will encourage the students to represent their talents
               and to have a chance to join games prepared by APCon Officers and Section Officers of each
               section.

               The proposed activity happens through Facebook Live on the organization’s Facebook Page.
               Psychology majors from BSP 2-1, BSP 2-2, BSP 3-1 will be having a performance which is a
               pre-recorded  video  performance  that  will  be  shown  on  the  day  of  the  said  event  on  the
               organization’s  Facebook  page. Psychology  majors  may  join  games  prepared  by  APCon
               Officers and Section Officers of each section.

               We are hoping for your positive response. Thank you and God bless you!


               Respectfully yours,


               ANGELICA R. GARCIA
               Altruistic Psych Confederate, President

               Noted:



                   MICAH SANCHEZ                                                                           ERWIN REGIO
                       Senior Adviser                                                                                Junior Adviser
               Recommending Approval:

               MARK JOEL C. SIBULO                                                                 MELONA I. SAQUIN
                      Chairperson                                                                                      Head, OSAS
                                                        Approved:



                                                GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Campus Administrator

                                               Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979



                                                 ACTIVITY PROPOSAL

                    I.     Title of Activity                               Online Caroling
                    II.    Proponents                             Altruistic Psych Confederate(APCon)
                    III.   Rationale
                                                                   It  aims  to  raise  fund  for  the
                                                                    organization’s other pending activities.
                    IV.    Objective of Activity                    The  said  pending  activities  will  be
                                                                    helpful for the students of Cavite State
                                                                    University-Tanza Campus.

                                                               1.  Online  Caroling  happens  through
                                                                   Facebook  Live  on  the  organization’s
                                                                   Facebook Page.
                                                               2.  Psychology     majors    from    BSP
                                                                   2-1, BSP 2-2, BSP 3-1 will be having a
                                                                   performance  which  is  a  pre-recorded
                                                                   video performance that will be shown
                                                                   on  the  day  of  the  said  event  on  the
                                                                   organization’s Facebook page.
                                                               3.  Psychology  majors  may  join  games
                                                                   prepared  by  APCon  Officers  and
                                                                   Section Officers of each section.
                                                                   Kantanong (host  in  the  Facebook
                                                                     live will play a minus one Christmas
                                                                     song  then  viewers  will  be  given  10
                                                                     seconds to guess what’s the title of
                 Mechanics and Implementations
                                                                     the song)
                                                                   What’s  in  a  box (viewers  will  be
                                                                     given  10  seconds  to  guess  what's
                                                                     inside the box. Win a point for every
                                                                     object they guess correctly.)
                                                                   Guess the Word (player will have to
                                                                     read the definition or clues that will be
                                                                     shown on the screen and guess what
                                                                     the word is. The player will be given
                                                                     10 seconds to answer.)
                                                                   Name it to Win it (a player will look
                                                                     at the two pictures then guess an
                                                                     answer by combining the given
                                                                     objects shown on the screen. The
                                                                     player will be given 10 seconds to
                                                                     answer)
                                                              Organization President:
                    V.     Contact Person                     Angelica R. Garcia
                                                              Contact Number:]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[09951019261
                                                              Organization Adviser:
                                                              Ms. Micah M. Sanchez
                                                              Contact Number:
                                                              09175913225
                                                              Organization Adviser:
                                                              Mr. Erwin Regio
                                                              Contact Number:
                                                              09104398974]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[February 14, 2022

                   PROF GIL D. RAMOS
                   Campus Administrator
                   This Campus


                    Dear Sir:

                   Good day!

                   The Future Administrators, Managers, and Executives (FAME) Society is planning to
                   conduct an activity called, “FAME-UNO”: Fame Top Students of the First Semester.
                   On  February  21,  2022,  the  organization  is  planning  to  conduct  an  activity  that  will
                   reward the top Business Management students of CvSU- Tanza Campus, who has the
                   highest GPA for the First Semester.

                   This activity aims to encourage all the FAME Society members and/or the Business
                   Management students to balance life and study, to motivate the students to appreciate
                   their efforts academically and congratulate themselves for surviving the first semester,
                   and to inspire the students to continue studying because all their efforts will pay off in
                   time.

                   We are hoping for your support on this matter. Thank you very much and take care.
                   President, FAME Society


                    Respectfully yours,





                   FAME, President

                   Noted by:



                                                                     JOHNNY RICK S. APELLANES
                     Adviser                                                                      Adviser

                   Recommending Approval:


                   MELONA I. SAQUIN                                  RITCH M. BANATE
                   Coordinator, OSAS                                 Department Chairperson


                                                                 Approved:





                                           GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Campus Administrator








                  I.      Title: “FAME-UNO”: Fame Top Students of the First Semester

                 II.      Proponent: Future Administrators, Managers and Executives Society

                 III.     Rationale:
                                 The  Future  Administrators,  Managers,  and  Executives  Society  have
                          come  up  with  the  proposal  to  reward  the  most  hardworking  Business
                          Management students of CVSU - Tanza for doing their very best academically
                          this First Semester, A.Y. 2021-2022.
                                 On  February  21,  2022,  the  organization  is  planning  to  conduct  an
                          activity that will reward the top business management students of CvSU- Tanza
                          Campus, who have the highest GPA for the first semester. The top student who
                          has the highest GPA among all the business management students will receive
                          a one-month subscription to an entertainment streaming application, and the
                          top student per year level will also receive a token from the organization.

                 IV.      Objectives:
                                 This activity aims to:
                              ●   Encourage all the FAME Society members and/or the Business
                                 Management students to balance life and study.
                              ●   To motivate the students to appreciate their efforts academically and
                                 congratulate themselves for surviving the 1  semester.
                                                                           st
                              ●   To inspire the students to continue studying because all of their efforts
                                 will pay off in time.

                  V.      Mechanics of Implementation:
                               1. This activity is for Business Management of CvSU - Tanza Campus.
                               2. The organization will coordinate with the campus registrar for the list of
                                 Business Management students GPA.
                               a.  The organization will ensure the confidentiality of all  the documents
                                 connected to this activity.
                               b.  Only  the  President  of  the  organization  will  check  the  documents
                                 connected to this activity.
                               3. Upon  checking  the  GPA  list  for  1   semester  of  the  Business
                                                                        st
                                 Management students, the organization will pick the student with the
                                 highest GPA overall, and the top student with the highest GPA per year.
                               4. All the top students picked will receive rewards and certificate from the
                                 organization.
                               a.  The  sole top  student for  overall  Business  Management  students  will
                                 receive  one  monthly  subscription  of  an  entertainment  streaming
                                 application and a certificate.
                               b.  The  top  student  per  year  will  receive  100  pesos  worth  of  e-load and
                                 certificate.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[VI.     Participants
                                 All the members of FAME Society and/or all Business Management
                          students in CVSU-Tanza.

                  VI.     Date and Venue
                               Announcing the “FAME-UNO” will be on the 21st of February 2022 via
                          Google Meet.

                   VII.   Budgetary Estimates
                                            Particulars              Amount in Peso

                                              E-load                      500.00
                                       (Prize of the Winner)



                                  Total                                  500.00







                   ANGEL T. TABUA
                   President, FAME Society



                   Noted by:




                                                                       JOHNNY RICK S. APELLANES
                   Adviser                                           Junior Adviser


                   Recommending Approval:


                   MELONA I. SAQUIN                                  RITCH M. BANATE
                   Coordinator, OSAS                                 Department Chairperson


                                                                 Approved:


                                                            GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979

                                          CENTRAL STUDENT GOVERNMENT

               February 15, 2022

               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Campus Administrator
               Tanza


               Dear Prof. Ramos,
               Good day Sir! We, the Central Student Government of Cavite State University- Tanza Campus
               are writing to humbly ask for your approval allowing us in organizing a donation drive for the
               students who are affected by the recent fire outbreak in Cavite City. We are deeply moved by
               this recent calamity and we want to extend help to the students of Cavite State University-
               Cavite  City  Campus.  Students  from  our  campus  can  extend  help  by  donating  water  pail,
               dipper,  toiletries,  facemask,  alcohol,  diaper  and  milk  for  babies.  Students  can  drop  their
               donations at Cavite State University- Tanza Campus located at Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite until
               February 17, 2022 from 8:00 am to 12 noon. For cash donations, anyone can send through
               the  gcash  account  of  CSG  President  Ms.  Christine  Jewel  Gallos  with  account  number
               09569920133.
               Hoping for your positive response. Thank you and God bless!



               Respectfully yours,


               CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS
               CSG, President



               Noted by:

               MARK JOEL C. SIBULO                                                    AUDREYSON H. BORILLA

               CSG, Senior Adviser                                                                  CSG, Junior Adviser


               Recommending Approval:

               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               OSAS Coordinator

                                                       Approved:



                                                GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                                                  Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979


                                         ANGLICISTS GUILD ORGANIZATION


               January 28, 2022

               PROF. GIL D. RAMOS
               Campus Administrator
               Tanza

               Dear Prof. Ramos,


                       Good day Sir! We, the Anglicists Guild Organization of Cavite State University- Tanza
               Campus are writing to humbly request your approval to allow us to conduct a monthly podcast
               as we want to build a bond with officers and with the students. This upcoming podcast is a
               celebration of Valentine's Day. This activity is entitled "Love on Air: Stories from the Heart" in
               which we are going to read stories, poems, or letters on air to spread love and appreciation of
               students for their family, friends, teachers, and to anyone else who holds a special place in
               their hearts.

                                                                                                     th
                                                                                          th
                       The collection of letters through google form will run from February 4  to the 11 day
               of February and the podcast will air on February 14, 2022.
               Hoping for your positive response. Thank you and God bless!


               Respectfully yours,



               ROSE ANN G. VOLANTE
               ANGLICISTS GUILD, President


               Noted by:

               AUDREYSON H. BORILLA                                            REIN R. ORTIGOSA

               ANGLICISTS GUILD, Senior Adviser                             ANGLICISTS GUILD, Junior Adviser

               Recommending Approval:


               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               OSAS Coordinator
                                                        Approved:




                                                GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
                                                  Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                    Tanza Campus
                                       Phase 2 Pabahay 2000 Bagtas Tanza Cavite
                                                      (046)414-3979



                                         ANGLICISTS GUILD ORGANIZATION

                                                 ACTIVITY PROPOSAL



                  I.   Title of Activity: Love on Air: Stories from the Heart

                 II.   Proponents: Anglicists Guild Organization

                 III.    Rationale

                       As part of the celebration of Valentine’s Day, we would like to give the students of


                   Cavite State University a chance to experience being broadcast on-air on how they are

                   loved and appreciated by their loved ones. This activity will enlighten their hearts on how

                   important it is to express your appreciation to make other people feel loved and important.

             IV.   Objective/s of Activity:



                       The  main  objective  of  this  activity  is  to  give  students  a  new  experience  of  the

               Valentine’s Day celebration. In this activity, the students will learn to express the love that is

               not only for a romantic partner but also for friends, family, teachers, and other people that they

               love.  This  event  will  promote  a feeling  of  well-being,  confidence,  and great  connection  or

               relationship with their loved ones. This will also encourage and allow them to use their creative

               writing skills and ideas to present their stories in an engaging and entertaining manner.



             V.    Mechanics and Implementations

                       A.  List of Participants


                          All Bonafide Students of Cavite State University-Tanza Campus.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[B.  Date and Venue


                          The answering of google form will start on February 4, 2022 (8:00 A.M-7:00 P.M).
                          This will be open on Friday-Friday only (February 4-11). The venue will be through

                          Virtual Platform

                       C.  Strategies/Mechanics


                   1.  The students who will join in this activity will need to answer the google form link that
                       they will see on the official Facebook page of Anglicists Guild.

                   2.  The  Anglicists  Guild  officers  will  launch  a  poster  about  this  activity  on  our  official
                       Facebook page (Anglicists Guild).

                   3.  The Anglicists Guild Officers is the one who will assist the students who will join this
                       Podcast. The said activity does not have any program but it is a simple appreciation of
                       the student’s loved ones.

                   4.  After the event, the officers will manifest the importance for students on sharing their
                       hearts  out  and  build  a  great  connection  to  their  favorite  person  in  the  world.



                       D.  Safety and Security Measures
                              1.  This  activity  will  be  virtual  and  the  Anglicists  Guild  officers  will  do  a

                                 Recorded  Love-On  Air  broadcasting  on  their  Facebook  Page.



                       E.  Budgetary Estimate
                       This is free for all the students of CVSU Tanza Campus. There will be NO money used

                       in this virtual activity.



             VI.   Contact Person



               Anglicists Guild Vice President: Ms. Crestel Cylah Estur – crestelcylah.estur@cvsu.edu.ph
               Anglicists Guild Secretary: Ms. Julie Claire C. Andres- julieclaire.andres@cvsu.edu.ph

               Anglicists    Guild    Documentation      Councilor:    Sir   Johnthel     R.    Jalbuena-
               johnthel.jalbuena@cvsu.edu.ph

               Anglicists Guild Senior Adviser: Mx. Audreyson H. Borilla – audreyson.borilla@cvsu.edu.ph
               Anglicists Guild Junior Adviser: Ms. Rein R. Ortigosa – rein.ortigosa@cvsu.edu.ph]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Sample Poster:]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[MANAGEMENT TRAINING AND STRATEGIC
                                            PLANNING WORKSHOP


                                               January 24-27, 2017



                                                  PROCEEDINGS



               A  Management  Training  and  Strategic  Planning  Workshop  was  conducted  on
               January 24, 2017 at the International House II.  CvSU: Global University 2020 was the
               theme of the annual planning exercise participated by deans, directors, alumni, students,
               and other stakeholders.

               This academic exercise was conducted in support of the new programs of the government
               in relation to the 0+10 agenda of the new president of the Philippines, President Rodrigo
               Duterte.

               The exercise was specifically done to formulate the Medium-Term Strategic Plan that will
               set direction for CvSU to become a Global University by 2020 and to position CvSU
               among the top universities in the ASEAN Region.

               Adopting  the  Vision  for  Public  Higher  Education  of  the  Roadmap  for  Public  Higher
               Reform,  Cavite  State  University,  a  publicly-funded  higher  education  institution,  is
               instrumental in developing high-level professions to meet the manpower needs of the
               industry,  public  service  and  society.    Through  its  triad  of  functions,  e.g.  instruction,
               research  and  extension,  it  significantly  contributes  to  the  urgent  tasks  of  alleviating
               poverty, hastening the pace of innovations, creating new knowledge and functional skills;
               and increasing the productivity of the workplace and the dynamism of communities.

               The  Management  Training  and  Strategic  Planning  Workshop  aimed  at  revisiting  the
               overall  directions,  vision  and  mission    for  advancing  development,  excellence  and
               competitiveness.    The  plans  developed    shall  layout  the  initiatives  and  performance
               measures to be achieved towards the realization of the needed reforms.











               1 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[DAY 1 – JANUARY 24, 2017


               Registration
               CvSU International House II


               The Management Training and Strategic Planning Workshop was conducted at the CvSU
               International House II.  Registration started at 8:00 in the morning.  This was attended by
               the President, Vice-Presidents, deans, directors, unit heads, alumni, industry partners,
               students, and other planning stakeholders.




















                        Participants registering for the Management Training and Strategic Planning Workshop


               OPENING REMARKS
               Dr. Hernando D. Robles
               University President

               The  opening  remarks  was  delivered  by  Dr.  Hernando  D.  Robles.    He  explained  the
               purpose of the workshop and said that the management training was conducted to equip
               the new set of oflficials on leadership and management.









               2 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Dr. Hernando D. Robles, CvSU President delivering his opening remarks


               The President acknowledged the presence  and attendance of the stakeholders in the
               workshop and recognized their participation and roles in drafting the strategic plans.  He
               likewise  explained  the  need  for  management  and  strategic  workshop  including  the
               benchmarking activities to be done in some selected universities.  Lastly, he explained
               the importance of the planning exercise and its relationship with the new leadership of the
               country and the University.

               Specifically, the planning exercise was conducted to address some of the reports required
               by the government such as:

                      New programs under the vertical, horizontal articulation
                      Typology of SUCs under the Outcomes-based Education Framework
                      Regional University (Amalgamation)
                      Strategic Performance Management System
                      the key results under the Organizational Performance Indicator Framework (OPIF)
                      New Higher Education Reform Agenda (NHERA)

               He presented the Strategic Planning Model and emphasized the relevance of vision and
               mission of the University to the challenges of the times and the current situation of the
               University in terms of:

                     Academics
                     Research
                     Extension
                     Governance and Leadership


               3 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[  Student Achievements
                     Faculty

               Emphasizing the vision and mission of the University, the President enjoined everyone to
               revisit:

                     Where do we want to be in the next five (5) years
                     What will be our stakeholders’ needs
                     What does our University look like

               Addressing all these challenges were the strategic priorities to be backed up by stringent
               monitoring and evaluation such as the conduct of:
                     Yearly action plans
                     Financial plan
                     Program/ project budgets
                     Periodic accomplishments
                     Performance Evaluations


               LEVELING OF EXPECTATIONS
               Dr. Leyma L. Cero
               Director Planning and Development


               For leveling of expectations, Dr. Leyma L. Cero presented the objectives as:

                     Train the new set of designated officials about leadership and management
                     Review / revise the University vision and mission
                     Realign the existing strategic plans in response to the challenges / priority thrusts
                       / development agenda
                     Revisit the University Manual of Operations
                     Conduct benchmarking in selected SUCs

               Emphasis  was  given  to  Revisiting  the  Past  by  addressing  the  Major  Final  Outputs
               (MFOs)

                     MFO 1 – Higher Education Services
                     MFO 2 – Advanced Education Services
                     MFO 3 – Research Services
                     MFO 4 – Extension Services
                     General Administration and Support Services and Support to Operations








               4 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Dr. Leyma L. Cero, Director for Planning and Development



               Looking  forward,  Mapping  Up  the  Future  was  likewise  presented  which  can  be
               addressed  through  the  development  of  CvSU  Development  Agenda  2017-2022,  with
               careful consideration of:

                     Ambisyon Natin 2040
                     Higher Education Reform Agenda
                     ASEAN and Philippine Qualifications Network
                     National Higher Education Research Agenda


               STATUS OF ACADEMIC AFFAIRS: MAJOR ACCOMPLISHMENTS (2012-2016)
               Dr. Camilo A. Polinga
               Vice President for Academic Affairs


               Dr. Polinga presented the status of the Academic Affairs. He   presented the following:

                     Enrolment trend
                     Graduates
                     Number of students who graduated on time
                     Faculty profile
                     Performance in the Licensure Examination
                     Topnotchers
                     Total number of programs offered
                     Status of program accreditation
                     Status of government recognition
                     Center of Excellence and Center of Development

               5 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[  Student recognitions and Awards
                     Faculty recognition and awards
                     Accreditation recognition and awards
                     Institutional recognition and awards





























                                                       Dr. Camilo A. Polinga, VP for Academic Affairs


                       Challenges: Where do we go from here?

                     Rationalization of program offerings – adoption of flagship programs, conduct of
                       cutting-edge R and D, closure of sub-standard and non-performing programs

                     Upgrading  of  Quality  –  strengthening  of  quality  assurance,  upgrading  of
                       qualifications  of  faculty,  modernization  of  facilities,  accreditation  of  programs,
                       International Accords

                     Rationalization  of  resource  generation  and  utilization  –  effective  fund
                       management, impact projects, efficient asset and property management

                     Good governance – improvement of efficiency

                     Rationalization of campus operations – clustering

                     Towards Research-based Academic Programs






               6 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[STATUS  OF  GRADUATE  SCHOOL:  REVISITING  THE  CVSU  ADVANCED
               EDUCATION SERVICES (SY 2011-2012 TO SY 2015-2016)
               Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro
               Dean, Graduate School and Open Learning College



























                                  Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro, Dean, Graduate School and Open learning College


               Dr. Nuestro presented the status of the Graduate School and Open Learning College:

                     Quality and  Relevance – accreditation of Programs

                     Best and Brightest – enrolment, awards

                     Internationalization – recognitions and awards

                     Research Capability

                     Relations with and Services to the Community


















               7 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[STATUS OF RESEARCH AND EXTENSION
               Dr. Alejandro DC. Mojica Sr., Vice President for Research, Extension, Continuing
               Education and Training Services



























                              Dr. Alejandro C. Mojica Sr., VP for Research, Extension, Continuing
                                                                                 Education and Training Services


               Dr. Mojica presented the following:

                       Highlights of Accomplishments - Research (2011-2016)

                     Number of research projects
                     List of researchers
                     RECETS manpower
                     Number of CvSU-funded Research projects
                     Number of Externally-funded research projects
                     Number of Publications
                     Number of ISI publications
                     Presentations in Conferences
                     Research grants generated from external funding
                     Number of patents

                       Highlights of Accomplishments - Extension Services (2011-2016)

                     Number of persons trained
                     Number of persons provided with technical assistance
                     Quality and timeliness of training provided



               8 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Dr. Hosea L. Matel, Director for Research, presented the following:

                       Identified Research Issues, Problems and Concerns

                     Leadership and Management
                     Organizational structure
                     Facilities
                     Funding / grants and donations
                     Information system
                     RDE Program and Agenda
                     Monitoring and Evaluation Program
                     Research and Publication
                     Technology to Demand-driven Extension
                     Mismatch
                     Faculty workload


























                                                   Dr. Hosea L. Matel, Director for Research


                       Goals for Improvement

                     Technology generation
                     Foster excellence and improve research performance
                     R and D results utilization
                     Strengthen and establish linkages and strategic alliances
                     Capability and Governance





               9 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[STATUS OF ADMINISTRATION AND SUPPORT SERVICES
               Dr. Henry O. Garcia
               Vice President for Administration and Support Services































                                  Dr. Henry O. Garcia, VP for Administrative and Support Services


                       Highlights of Accomplishments

                            Administration – Supply and Property office, Records Office and Internal
                              Audit
                            Financial Management Services Office
                            Human Resource Development Office
                            Health Services Unit
                            Physical Plant Services Unit
                            Civil Security Services Unit


                       Challenges of OVPASS

                            Manpower requirement
                            Mobility requirement
                            Service facilities
                            Administrative / managerial efficiency for ISO 9001 certification
                            Budget utilization Rate Allotment and Disbursement
                            Online collection and enrollment system tied-up with Registrar’s office



               10 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[  Automation of financial Management Services in line with Government
                              Management Information System
                            Promotion and implementation of health and wellness programs for the
                              University Personnel and Students
                            PRIME-HRM Certification
                            Enhancement of HR Capabilities


                       Future Directions

                              The future directions of OVPASS are focused on serving its clientele well
                       since it strives to become Very Proud Advocates of Service with a Smile.



               SETTING THE OVERALL DIRECTION: CvSU 2020
               Dr. Hernando D. Robles
               University President



























                                                       Dr. Hernando D. Robles, University President


               Moving Forward in One Direction

                       2016 – Transition
                       2017 – Transformation
                       2018 – Institutionalization
                       2019 – Recognition
                       2020 –Global University
                       2021 – Sustainability
                       2022 – Research University


               11 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[  2016 – Transition

                         From output-based to Outcomes-based Quality Assurance
                         This stage is backed up by adherence to the ASEAN Qualifications Reference
                          Framework, Performance Based Budgeting and Incentive-based of the Major
                          Final Outputs (MFOs) and Performance Indicators (PIs).  Likewise, the issues
                          of the K-12 issues and concerns shall be addressed.


                 2017 – Transformation

                         From Reactive to Pro-active
                         This  shall  be  characterized  by  seriously  achieving  the  targets  for  research,
                          development and innovation (with full funding support).  The merit and fitness-
                          based  recruitment  and  massive  infrastructure  development  shall  be  in  the
                          priority list.

                 2018 – Institutionalization

                         It  is  desired  that  the  QMS/ISO  Certification  be  formally  awarded  to  the
                          University.      The  University  shall  work  very  hard  to  create  Research  and
                          Innovation Centers including the patenting of innovations and technologies.

                 2019 – Recognition

                     After  serious  work,  it  is  hoped  that  the  University  will  be  gaining  international
                       recognition.  Quality shall be a way of life.  Faculty members and staff shall be
                       known  and  recognized  through  their  scholarly  works  having  published  their
                       researches in ISI and other accredited journals.

                     The University is likewise expected to become part of internationally renowned
                       Universities  in  the  ASEAN  Region.    Its  membership  with  the  Washington
                       International  Accord  and  other  international  accrediting  bodies  for  academic
                       programs shall be done.

                 2020 – Global University

                     International  collaborative  researches  in  Science,  Technology,  Engineering,
                       Agriculture  and  Mathematics  (STEAM)  with  international  universities  shall  be
                       established.    Visiting  and  affiliate  professors  from  leading  universities  shall  be
                       regularly invited to become part of the University’s active teaching force.









               12 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[  2021 – Sustainability

                     Having established the good practices and achieved the accolades, this year is
                       marked by sustaining all the initiatives in instruction, research, and extension and
                       resource generation.  The University shall be recognized as an active employment
                       generator for graduates.

                 2022 – Research University

                     The university shall be hailed as one of the research universities in the country and
                       in  Asia.    Obtaining  advanced  degrees  through  research  shall  be  part  of  the
                       instructional initiatives.  Likewise, it is hoped that the University be included in the
                       world rankings.


                               The covenant:

                               We will affirm beginning today and in the next years to

                               come that in achieving our vision and mission we will

                               be…….fast …and….serious.


               ROADMAP FOR HIGHER PUBLIC HIGHER EDUCATION REFORM
               Dr. Camilo A. Polinga
               Vice President for Academic Affairs


               Dr. Polinga presented the Roadmap for Higher Public Education Reform.  This can be
               used as bases for formulating workable and responsive plans, programs and activities
               related to the Academic Affairs.

               The presentation tackled on the thrusts, objectives, strategies and state of the higher
               education in the next coming years.   The roadmap was guided by the:

                         Education 2030 framework for action (of which CHED is a signatory)
                         AmBisyon 2040
                         10-point agenda of Duterte Administration
                         HERA 2 Strategic Plan for Internationalization of Philippine Higher Education

               The guiding principles of the roadmap include:

                         Demographic governance
                         Higher education as both a private and public good



               13 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Dr. Camilo A. Polinga, VP for Academic Affairs


               Among the strategic thrust and objectives:

                       1.  To improve access to and success in  quality higher education among the poor
                          and disadvantage but college-ready students
                       2.  To capacitate student to become high level professionals and specialists with
                          competencies  that  match  the  requirements  of  industry  and  national
                          development
                       3.  To  enable  public  higher  education  institutions  to  become  knowledge,
                          technology and innovation centers,  and
                       4.  To institutionalize ethical and innovative governance


               The initiatives to be done are the following:

                       1.  Expand financial support for the  poor and disadvantaged but college-ready
                          students
                       2.  Broaden  access  to  higher  education  through  non-conventional  delivery
                          schemes and learning pathways
                       3.  Enhance provisions for student support and development
                       4.  Enrich the curricula of program offerings through world or work
                       5.  Intensify  program-level  and  institutional-level  quality  assurance  and
                          improvement
                       6.  Strengthen research development and extension functions
                       7.  Promote development of academic and non-academic personnel
                       8.  Undertake  internationalization initiatives
                       9.  Upgrade  graduate education programs
                       10. Establish / sustain COEs and CODs



               14 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[11. Develop capacity and provide the enabling policy environments for conduct of
                          high-end R and D
                       12. Amalgamation: promote and undertake regional unification / complementation
                          initiatives
                       13. Professionalize  institutional  management  through  capability  building  and
                          professional enhancement
                       14. Cross-cutting initiatives: strengthen multi-sectoral partnerships for education,
                          research, innovation and governance.


               The policy priorities:

                            Progressive  free  tuition  and  other  fees  for  students  from  the  lowest  two
                              quintiles
                            ROTC Bill
                            Magna Carta for students
                            Revision / replacement of NBC 461
                            Regional unification / amalgamation bills
                            Adoption of revised organizational standards for SUCs
                            Professionalization  of  SUCs/LUCs  Management  –  Institutionalization  of
                              PhilHECS


               ENHANCING THE MOBILITY OF FILIPINOS IN THE ASEAN AND THE WORLD
               Dr. Adolfo C. Manuel, Jr.
               Director, Quality Assurance and Accreditation Center


               Dr. Adolfo C. Manuel, Director for Quality Assurance and Accreditation Center presented
               the ASEAN and Philippine Qualifications Framework.   He started his talk by presenting
               the  overall  conceptual  framework  and  the  ASEAN  Mutual  Recognition  Agreements
               (MRAs).

               The objectives of the MRAs:

                       1.  Facilitate mobility of practitioners within the ASEAN
                       2.  Exchange  information  and  enhance  cooperation  in  respect  of  mutual
                          recognition of practitioners
                       3.  Promote adoption of best practices on standards and qualifications
                       4.  Provide opportunities for capacity building and training of practitioners

               The ASEAN Mutual agreements have been entered into the following academic
               offerings:

                         Engineering
                         Nursing


               15 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[  Surveying
                         Architecture
                         Dentistry
                         Medicine
                         Accountancy

















                              Dr. Adolfo C. Manuel Jr., Director for Quality Assurance and Accreditation Center


               Dr. Manuel presented the issues and challenges in complying with the qualification
               networks as:

                   1.  Quality assurance

                            compliance with accreditation system with globally accepted students
                            Re-engineering of ACCREDITATION MINDSET

                   2.  Comparability of our programs with the world standards

                         How do we make our higher education programs comparable with
                          international standards?
                         How do we fully implement our internationalization policies?
                         How do we encourage student mobility with ASEAN?
                         For the professors, are there concrete exchange programs?
                         How do we make our University flexible, open and innovative?

                   3.  Infrastructure and Facilities Development

                         Compliance of University’s leaning resources and environment to global
                          standards
                         Establishment of state of the art facilities

               16 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[NATIONAL HIGHER EDUCATION RESEARCH AGENDA (NHERA 2)
               DR. RUEL M. MOJICA
               Director National Coffee Research Development and Extension Center

               Dr. Ruel Mojica, Director of the National Coffee Research Development and Extension
               Center, presented the NHERA.  The agenda explain the frontiers of knowledge across all
               HEIs.  These  likewise  explain  the  policies,  disciplines,  priorities  and  thrusts  of  the
               Philippine HEI research in medium to long term.















                              Dr. Ruel M. Mojica, Director of the National Coffee, Research, Development
                                                   and Extension Center


               The principles of NHERA were discussed as follows:

                       1.  Ensure that the academic environment nurtures and supports Filipino talents
                       2.  Enhance the institution’s and the individuals’ capacity to conduct independent,
                          collaborative and productive research
                       3.  Lead in the conduct of discipline-based, policy-oriented, technology-directed
                          and innovative and creative researchers that are locally responsive and globally
                          competitive.

               The objectives of NHERA were the following:

                            Improve research capability of HEIs, particularly the Philippine universities
                              whose  main  business  is  to  generate  knowledge  towards  international
                              competiveness
                            Enhance research productivity in distinctive areas of competence
                            Promote and facilitate dissemination and utilization of research outputs
                            Generate knowledge and technologies needed  for:
                                 o  International, national and regional higher education development
                                 o  Policy / plan formulation particularly in higher education


               17 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[o  Developing  innovative  programs  in  cutting  edge  higher  education
                                     fields    (nanotechnology,      biotechnology,      information     and
                                     communications technology and materials science)
                                 o  Advancing the frontiers of knowledge in the disciplines

               The research agenda were the following:

                       1.  Improving research capability of HEIs towards international competitiveness
                       2.  Enhancing research productivity of HEIs
                       3.  Generating new knowledge needed for the advancement of higher education
                          as well as for national development.
                       4.  Promoting and facilitating dissemination and utilization of research outputs

               The research priorities were:

                            Basic research to generate new knowledge and advance the frontiers in the
                              various disciplines
                            Research to aid policy / plan formulation and implementation particularly in
                              education
                            Research  aimed  at  producing  /  adapting  education  technologies  and
                              developing education programs in cutting edge fields
                            R and D in aid of national / regional development

               The priority discipline clusters were the following:

                            Science and Mathematics
                            Education and Teacher Training
                            Health and health profession
                            Information and Communications Technology
                            Engineering, Maritime and Architecture
                            Agriculture
                            Environmental Science
                            Humanities
                            Social Sciences
                            Other disciplines identified by the Commission

               The following are the priority areas in education and education management:

                            Program / curricular studies on higher education
                            Policy oriented studies
                            Research quality and standards
                            Technology and education
                            Model building studies
                            Institutional development studies



               18 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[  Manpower demand and supply studies
                            Graduate tracer studies
                            Other  research  topics  considered  by  the  Commission  in  response  to
                              emerging needs of the country

               In closing, Dr. Mojica emphasized the need to serve and satisfy our stakeholders and to
               give the services they deserve to get.


               OPEN FORUM

               After all the presentations, an open forum followed.  Issues and concerns were raised
               from the participants including the stakeholders and industry partners:




























                               The President and the Vice-Presidents while listening to the suggestion of
                                Dr. Sotero L. Lasap, Jr., retired VP for Academic Affairs of CvSU



               On the serious bid of the University to become a Global University by 2020, the following
               shall be considered in the development plans:

                         Infrastructure development shall consider global standards
                         Benchmarking with the ASEAN universities
                         Transnational education
                         Graduate and undergraduate offerings
                         Mutual Recognition Agreement
                         Improving linkages for generation of research grants
                         Comprehensive program for orientation


               19 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[  Facility improvement for international settings such as conferences and fora
                         Fund utilization – internet, computer, undersubscribed programs, etc.
                         Development of graduates for self-employment
                         Patenting of innovations, technologies and discoveries
                         On-line registration
                         Techno-preneurship
                         Development of research culture in the University


               In so doing, the industry partners and stakeholders suggested the following strategies:

                         Formulation of sound and workable  action plans to address the development
                          agenda
                         Provision of enabling mechanisms conducive to the conduct of relevant and
                          responsive researches
                         Monitoring and evaluation of  the plans  and their alignment to the national and
                          regional agenda
                         Development  and  provision  of  impacts  of  the  programs  and  projects  to  the
                          clientele the University serves
                         Integration of diversity and cultural identity in the curriculum























                                   Prof. Noel Sedigo, Ms. Rosalia Guevarra and Dr. Edna A. Vida during the open forum











               20 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Miss Lovely Mores shares her views on the plans while Dr. Hernando Robles responds


               REVISITING THE UNIVERSITY’S VISION AND MISSION:
               Dr. Leyma L. Cero
               Director for Planning and Development


               Dr. Leyma L. Cero, Director for Planning and Development, presented the existing Vision
               and Mission of the University:

















                                             Dr. Leyma L. Cero, Director for Planning and Development



               21 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Vision:

                                            The premier University in historic Cavite recognized
                                      for excellence in the development of morally upright and
                                      globally competitive individuals.


                                      Mission:

                                               Cavite  State  University  shall  provide  excellent,
                                      equitable and relevant educational opportunities in the arts,
                                      science  and  technology  though  quality  instruction  and
                                      relevant  research  and  development  activities.    It  shall
                                      produce  professional,  skilled  and  morally  upright
                                      individuals for global competitiveness:



               During the presentation and deliberation of the existing vision and mission, the following
               issues were raised:

                          a.  Relevance of the existing vision and mission to the need of times
                          b.  Timeliness of revision
                          c.  Conformance to the Higher Education Reform Agenda
                          d.  The metrics to be used to measure the accomplishment of the vision and
                              mission






















               22 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[DAY 2 – JANUARY 25, 2017, Hotel Veniz, Baguio City



               A group of 63 officials composed of the President, Vice Presidents, Deans, Directors and
               other staff of the University headed to Hotel Veniz, Baguio City.  This was the continuation
               of the two-phased planning and benchmarking workshop of the University.

               The opening program was started at 9:00 am with an invocation led by Dr. Analita M.
               Magsino, Dean of the College of Agriculture, Food, Environment, and Natural Resources.



















                                     Dr. Analita dM. Magsino, Dean of the College of Agriculture, Food, Environment
                                                      and Natural Resources


               It was followed by a recap of Day 1 activities which was delivered by Prof. Roderick M.
               Rupido.
















                                          Prof. Roderick M. Rupido delivering the session recap

               23 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Pres. Hernando D. Robles gave his opening remarks and words of encouragement.  He
               enjoined the participation of everyone to carefully make the strategic plans in order to
               achieve the University’s serious bid to become a Global University by 2020.


















                                          Dr. Hernando D. Robles, University President


               To set the mood for the workshop and presentation, an energizer followed:


























                                               Participants doing a zumba dance before the session



               Dr. Camilo Polinga explained the mechanics for presentation. Each of the presenting unit
               was given 15 minutes for the presentation and 15 minutes for questions and suggestions.
               The order of presentation was:

               24 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[1.  College of Arts and Sciences

                       Dean Bettina Joyce Ilagan presented the strategic plans of the College of Arts and
                       Sciences.  Accordingly, they are not only one in CAS, but they are also TRUE,
                       which stands for Train, Research, Utilize and Extend.















                                                     Dr. Bettina Joyce Ilagan, CAS


                       The body suggested to focus on strategies to address the internationalization of
                       the  University.      It  was  likewise  suggested  to  focus  on  areas  of  research  and
                       extension that are related to Arts and Sciences and to concentrate on the thematic
                       areas of the University.

                       Prof. Sedigo suggested the following:

                       a.  To connect the researches of the College to the extension to be conducted.
                       b.  Strengthen the existing offering and concentrate on improving the performance
                          in the licensure examination of the BS Psychology
                       c.  Prioritize  the  establishment  of  Centers  of  Development  or  Excellence  since
                          some of the program offerings are Level III re-accredited already.

                       Dr.  Robles  likewise  suggested  to  strengthen  instruction  and  concentrate  on
                       producing outcomes since CAS is a service college. Dr. A. Mojica on the other
                       hand, suggested on improving researches and extension works since they have
                       conducted some already.

                       Dr. Vida commented that external funding for researches are possible since the
                       College can venture into social and anthropological researches. Dr. Alava on the


               25 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[other hand, said that the College can continue the accomplishments of its previous
                       professors like the development of e-books.


                   2.  College of Engineering and Information Technology

                       Mr.  Marlon  Pereña,  Chairman  of  the  Department  of  Information  Technology
                       presented CEIT’s strategic plans.  The highlights of his presentation focused on
                       the use of technology and automation to be used mainly in instruction, research
                       and extension.  Furthermore, infrastructure are mostly for the development of IT
                       facilities.




















                                                     Prof. Marlon P. Pereña, CEIT

                       Dr. Robles suggested to concentrate on the production of the best and brightest
                       students, faculty and staff rather than attracting them.

                       Dr.  Vida  said  that  CEIT  has  the  most  number  of  patentable  products  and
                       innovation. She advised CEIT focal personnel to coordinate with Dr. Teddy Tepora
                       for possible patenting of fabricated products.

                       Prof.  Sedigo  advised  to  focus  on  specific  research  and  to  collaborate  all  its
                       research  undertakings.    Dr.  Sanchez,  asked  the  help  of  CEIT  personnel  and
                       students to develop a medical database for the students.

                       On  harmonization  of  programs,  Dr.  Polinga  suggested  to  harmonize  CEIT’s
                       programs and activities with the Management Information System (MIS).  Likewise,
                       Dr.  Manuel  noted  the  need  for  streamlining  of  programs  and  revisiting  of  the
                       organizational structure to reflect the BS Office Administration.




               26 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[3.  College of Education

                       Dr. Editha G. Reyes, Dean College of Education presented the strategic plans of
                       the College.  Prof. Sedigo suggested to revisit the performances of the College’s
                       graduates  in  the  licensure  examinations  and  to  strategize  to  improve  their
                       performances.

























                                                      Dr. Editha G. Reyes, CEd


                       Among the issues and suggestions raised in the discussions were:

                            Possible splitting of the College to make clear-cut distinction of the
                              offerings, like the Child Development Center and Science Laboratory High
                              School.
                            Strict implementation of the retention policies
                            Inclusion of the competency appraisal for the BSE and BEE students prior
                              to graduation
                            Strict implementation of the comprehensive examinations
                            Patenting of the HRM and Science High School innovations
                            Preparation o for the COD and COE application by reviewing the
                              provisions in the CMO and preparing for them


                   4.  Naic Campus

                       The  strategic  plans  of  Naic  Campus  were  presented  by  Prof.  John  Xavier
                       Nepomuceno. During the discussion, Dr. Vida suggested to look into the possibility


               27 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[of creating a Technology Business Incubator (TBI) in the campus.  Through this,
                       technologies to be developed can easily be commercialized.

                       Prof. Sedigo advised the dean to collaborate with some agencies most especially
                       on marine technologies.  These areas may include the operationalization of coastal
                       water resources, capacity building and aggressive recruitment of graduates.





















                                             Prof. John Xavier Nepomuceno, Naic Campus


                       Dr. Robles said that Naic Campus can conduct fishery resources research since it
                       was identified as NUCAF.  As such, it can concentrate on developing the pawikan
                       sanctuary  and  can  work  on  international  linkages  such  as  JICA,  JOCB,  and
                       PEMSEA. It can also work on the establishment of Marine Biological Research
                       center.

                       Likewise, Dr. Vida, suggested to concentrate on fishery (inland fishery) and coastal
                       services management.


                   5.  Rosario Campus

                       Dr. Ariel Santos presented the strategic plan of the Rosario Campus.  What was
                       surprising was the downtrend enrolment.













               28 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Dr. Ariel Santos, Rosario Campus


                       The body suggested to:

                                   concentrate on resource generation
                                   research  collaboration  in  its  areas  of  expertise  such  as  prototype
                                     and design fabrication
                                   strengthen the banner programs – Industrial Technology
                                   publish  its  research  findings  in  refereed  journals  and  own  journal
                                     once accredited


                   6.  Carmona Campus

                       Prof. Cristina M. Signo presented the strategic plans.  She said that the campus is
                       so fortunate for the active support of the LGU and some of the infrastructure will
                       soon rise.


                       The following were the suggestions raised:


                                   Due to decreasing enrolment, the campus can benchmark some of
                                     its programs to strengthen the offerings
                                   Strengthen the Academe-Industry linkage
                                   Review the possibility of offering some courses which can become
                                     its flagship programs
                                   Take the opportunity of its presence in the industrial hub of the
                                     town


               29 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Prof. Cristina Signo, Carmona Campus


                   7.  College of Agriculture, Food, Environment and Natural Resources

                       Dr. Analita M. Magsino, College Dean, presented the strategic plans of CAFENR.
























                                                    Dr. Analita Magsino, CAFENR

                       Recognizing  some  of  the  College’s  excellent  programs  especially  its  Level  IV
                       program, Dr.  Robles suggested to still improve its linkages in terms of the number
                       of MOAs and MOUs signed, approved and secured. Other suggestions were:

                            Work on collaboration  with international research and funding agencies
                            Study the possibility of tie-up with ASEAN universities


               30 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[  Conduct policy researches in Agriculture
                            Include commodity-based researches and extension works.


                   8.  Graduate School

                       Dr.  Maria Agnes P. Nuestro presented the strategic plans of the Graduate School
                       and Open Learning College.




















                                   Dr. Ma. Agnes Nuestro, Graduate School and Open Learning College


                       Prof. Sedigo suggested that the Graduate School should have separate extension
                       activities.  Dr. Nuestro said that each college has its own extension work and the
                       graduate students are involved.  Dr. Polinga said the graduate students can be
                       tapped as speakers according to their expertise.

                       Dr. Robles suggested that the Graduate School can offer courses to support the
                       Department  of  Education  through  strengthening  of  the  learning  centers  in  the
                       campuses.  Along with this is the possible membership to the International Council
                       of  Distance  Education  and  involvement  in  the  transnational  education.
                       Involvement and participation of graduate in research can likewise be enhanced
                       through the Faculty and Students Research Capability Program of the University
                       (FSRCEP).

                       Other suggestions for consideration in the Graduate School were the following:

                            Offering of the graduate programs during weekdays and weeknights
                            Training of the graduate faculty to make them technology savvy
                            Observance of the intellectual property rights in the innovations and
                              discoveries of the graduate students
                            Sponsorship of conferences of the graduate students


               31 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[9.  Office of Student Affairs and Services

                       Ms. Sharon M. Isip, Officer-in-Charge presented the strategic plans of the Office
                       of Student Affairs and Services.



























                                                    Ms. Sharon Isip, OSAS



                       Issues and concerns regarding student services were raised.

                            Conduct of the orientation program shall be done to provide the students
                              and their parents the warmest welcome from the University.
                            Careful utilization of student publication fund
                            Conduct of the psychological assessment of the students
                            Careful issuance of certificates of recognition to the student organizations

                        The following suggestions were given:
                            Strengthen the guidance center
                            Outsource  the services of a psychometrician
                            Train faculty members as guidance counselor
                            Development of OSAS Help Desk  to include the International Affairs who
                              will oversee the student services operations such as visa application and
                              extension
                            Observance of a stricter security measures in the University
                            Careful accreditation of organizations including religious organizations
                            Careful review of the organizational set-up and possible centralization of
                              student activities



               32 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[  Improvement  in  the  communication  within  and  among  the  University
                              officials and the students



               Day 2 Session ended at 5:00 pm with a closing remarks delivered by Dr. Julio G. Alava,
               Vice President for External and Business Affairs.


























                                        Dr. Julio Alava, VP for External and Business Affairs





































               33 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[DAY 3 – JANUARY 26, 2017, Hotel Veniz, Baguio City



               The third day of the strategic planning workshop was started at 8:00 am with an opening
               prayer led by Dr. Romeo Sanchez, Director for Health Services.



































                              Dr. Romeo M. Sanchez, Director for Health Services, leads the participants in prayer


               It was followed by a recap of Day 2’s activities presented by Prof. Roderick M. Rupido.























                                     Prof. Roderick M. Rupido delivers the recapitulation of Day 2 session

               34 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[An energizer followed through a Zumba dance.

























                                   The participants start the productive day with an energizer dance



               Dr.  Alejandro  Mojica  gave  words  of  encouragement.  He  shared  a  biblical  verse  in
               Proverbs  29:18  which  says  “without  a  vision,  the  people  will  perish”.  He  likewise
               shared  the  formula  for  success:    respect,  sacrifice,  commitment,  unity  and
               innovation.























                            Dr. Alejandro dC. Mojica, VP for RECETS, gives his words of encouragement







               35 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[1.  Research Center


                       Prof. Agnes Alimboyuguen presented the strategic plans of the Research Center.































                                            Prof. Agnes Alimboyuguen, Research Center


                    She emphasized that performance in research can be measured in terms of:

                            Publications
                            Number of patents
                            Number of citations

                   Dr. Vida commented that the University can concentrate of the commodity thrusts of
                   the University.  Through this, more research centers can be developed.  Dr. Alava
                   assured the support coming from the administration. He also suggested to revisit the
                   staffing pattern and practice multi-tasking.

                   Dr. Robles advised everyone to document all researches.



                   2.  Extension Services

                       Prof. Mariel Lising presented the strategic plans of the Extension Services Unit.




               36 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[Prof. Mariel L. Lising, Director for Extension Services


                       Among the suggestions given were the following:

                       a.  Reactivation of the different sub-units of the Extension Service Unit  such as
                          the Training Unit, Techno-demo Unit, Communications and Monitoring
                       b.  Publication of the extension handbook which is also needed for accreditation
                       c.  Rehabilitation of the techno-demonstration farms  for replication and
                          commercialization
                       d.  Developing a sense of ownership to all the programs implemented


                   3.  Human Resources Management Office

                       Miss Eileen Cubillo presented the strategic plans of the Human Resources
                       Office.  She emphasized the strength of the organization through its work force.

                       The suggestions given were the following:

                       a.  Complementation of HR activities with those of the Faculty Association like
                          trainings, and seminars
                       b.  Streamlining of the structure and careful review of the redundant positions
                       c.  Observance of flexible time in and time out to satisfy the required number of
                          hours of work
                       d.  Utilization of biometrics for the contractual and part time employees
                       e.  Provision of enabling mechanism for building a stronger workforce
                       f.  Adoption of effective Human Resource Information System (HRIS)
                       g.  Stringent monitoring and evaluation of employees

               37 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[h.  Continuing retraining of personnel for globalization
                       i.  Development of interventions for faculty and employees to increase
                          productivity and efficiency
                       j.  Provision of a workable health and wellness program
                       k.  Continuing orientation for employees (leave privileges, retirement, etc)




























                              Ms. Eileen I. Cubillo, Director for Human Resources Management Office


                   4.  Financial Management Services

                       The strategic plans were presented by Ms. Lolita Herrera.























                              Ms. Lolita G. Herrera, Director for Financial Management Services  Office



               38 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[The following suggestions were given:

                       a.  Automation of the finance office for a much effective monitoring of fund
                          utilization
                       b.  Adoption of a networking system such as inter-campus connectivity
                       c.  Closer monitoring of financial reports like those of externally funded
                          researches


                   5.  Administration

                       Dr. Mary Jane  D. Tepora presented the strategic plans.































                                            Dr. Mary Jane D. Tepora, Director for Administration


                       The suggestions given for improvement were:

                          a.  Clear-cut definition of the services rendered and given
                          b.  Constant monitoring and maintenance of system to avoid breakdown
                          c.  Identification of the missing link to facilitate the services
                          d.  Improve  the efficiency, productivity and effectiveness of the services






               39 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[6.  Physical Plant Services

                       Dr. Cero presented the strategic plans.  One of the highlights of the plans was
                       the construction of multi-level parking.


























                                            Dr. David L. Cero, Director for Physical Plant Services


                       The unit will work hard to become FREE (fast, reliable, efficient and effective).


                   7.  Health Services Unit

                       Dr. Romeo Sanchez presented the strategic plans of the unit. Among the issues
                       raised were the following:

                       a.  Use of ambulance and other medical tools and equipment
                       b.  Development of a doable health and wellness program for faculty and
                          employees
                       c.  Development of Management Information Systems for health data base
                       d.  Continuing health training















               40 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[Dr. Romeo M. Sanchez, Director for Health Services


                   8.  Security Services

                       Mr. Deo Marca presented the plans of the Security Services Unit.



























                                            Mr. Dionisio Marca, Director for Civil Security Services



               41 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[The following issues were raised:

                       a.  Presence of stray dogs and cats of the university
                       b.  Illegal assembly of some students
                       c.  Utilization of stickers and IDs
                       d.  Traffic management



                   9.  Business Affairs

                       Mr. Guillermo  Desenganio presented the plans and targets of the Business
                       Affairs.  A net income of at least PhP 16 million shall be generated per year.



























                                        Prof. Guillermo Desenganio, Director for Business Affairs


                       The following areas of concern were raised:

                       a.  Adoption of a more effective data system
                       b.  Rehabilitation of the existing income generating projects
                       c.  Improvement and refurbishment of old structures used for business
                       d.  Consideration for more business ventures such as tricycle operation and bank
                          rentals and gasoline station






               42 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[10. Public Information and Community relations Office

                       Prof. Robert Solis presented the plans of PICRO.
































                                               Prof. Alan Robert Solis, Director for PICRO


                       The following issues were tackled on the restructuring of PICRO to include :

                                News and Information
                                Communications and Media Relations
                                Events Management
                                Reception and Accommodation


                   11. Alumni Affairs


                          Dr. Amie F. Peñalba, Director for Alumni Affairs presented the strategic plans of
                       the office.  She shared the strengths and weaknesses of the office. Among the
                       strategies considered were:

                                Leverage the power of the alumni network to help students secure jobs
                                 and internships
                                Utilize  the  social  media  to  create  excitement  and  communicate  with
                                 alumni


               43 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[  Strengthen connections and increase the involvement of alumni abroad
                                 in all activities of the University
                                Increase opportunities for alumni to return to campus to interact with the
                                 students and each other
                                Conduct of researches and related activities for the alumni
                                 o  Alumni data base
                                 o  Tracer studies
                                 o  Job fairs


























                                            Dr. Ammie F. Penalba, Director for Alumni Affairs































               44 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[DAY 4– JANUARY 27, 2017, Tarlac Agricultural University



               The  officials,  led  by  Dr.  Hernando  D.  Robles  visited  the Tarlac  Agricultural  University
               TAU) in Camiling, Tarlac.  They headed to the administration building and was met by
               TAU’s president, Dr. Max Guillermo.  He was installed as TAU’s first university president
               in December 2016.






























                       A warm welcome was accorded to the members of CvSU delegation.


























               Members  of  TAU’s  academic  council  were  introduced.  After  which,  an  open  forum
               followed.  TAU’s leaders shared the healthy practices and initiatives:

               45 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[The members of Tarlac Agricultural University during the orientation for CvSU delegates






































                       Dr. Max Guillermo, president of Tarlac Agricultural University welcomes Dr. Hernando D. Robles





               46 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[Among these were the following:

                     Provision of PhP10,000 per faculty per year to do research
                     Provision of at most PhP30,000 per faculty per year to present paper abroad
                     Monetary incentive for every publication in journal
                     Reduction  of teaching load to a maximum of 21 units to do research and
                       extension
                     Constant retooling of faculty members
                     Intensive review for programs with licensure exams
                     Constant updating of course syllabi
                     Monitoring of faculty
                     Regular performance review
                     Development of master[ plan for 2016-2025
                     Subjecting of the University to ISO and institutional accreditation







































                The members of CVSU delegation pose with Dr. Max Guillermo, President of Tarlac Agricultural
               University










               47 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[CvSU Delegation with the Administrative Council of Tarlac Agricultural University





               DAY 4– JANUARY 27, 2017, Tarlac State University

                     The group headed to Tarlac State University (TSU).  The group was welcomed by
                       TSUs officials :
























                                     Dr. Hernado D. Robles with the Vice-Presidents of Tarlac State University


                          o  Dr. Armi Rocel, Vice President for Academic Affairs,
                          o  Dr. Glennard Madriaga, Vice President for Research and Extension
                          o  Dr. Lorna Dimatulac, Vice President for Institutional Linkages and External
                              Affairs

               48 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[An  orientation  through  audio-visual  presentation  about  the  University  followed.
                       Likewise, CvSU President Dr. Robles responded and said that TSU and CvSU
                       have commonalities as higher education institutions.   He likewise said that one of
                       the reasons of the benchmarking was to renew friendships.





















                       The Administrative Council of Tarlac State University share their healthy practices to the CvSU
                       delegation



                       Tarlac University is one of the universities that has been awarded with ISO 9001:
                       2015, ISO 14001 and OHSAS 18001:2007.  They shared their good practices that
                       were awarded with the certifications:

                          o  Changing the  culture of the people towards observance of quality
                          o  Consistency of operations and services
                          o  Adoption of common forms to facilitate services




               DAY 4– JANUARY 27, 2017, Don Honorio Ventura Technological State University


               The CvSU group did benchmarking at the Don Honorio Ventura State Technological
               State University in Pampanga.  They were able to meet some university personnel at
               their hostel.












               49 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[Marker of Don Honorio Ventura Technological State University
































                            Administration Building of Don Honorio Ventura Technological State University

               50 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[51 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[2017 MANAGEMENT TRAINING, STRATEGIC PLANNING WORKSHOP
                                       AND REGIONAL BENCHMARKING

                                                 January 24-27, 2017




                                                     ATTENDANCE



               Dr. Hernando D. Robles                      President
               Dr. Camilo A. Polinga                       VP for Academic Affairs
               Dr. Alejandro dc. Mojica                    VP for RECETS
               Dr. Henry O. Garcia                         VP Administration and Support Services
               Dr. Julio A. Alava                          VP External and Business Affairs
               Dr. Analita dM. Magsino                     Dean, CAFENR
               Dr. Bettina Joyce P. Ilagan                 Dean, CAS
               Dr. Editha G. Reyes                         Dean, CED
               Dr. Florindo C. Ilagan                      Dean, CEMDS
               Dr. Marilyn Escobar                         Dean, CEIT
               Dr. Evelyn M. del Mundo                     Dean, CON
               Dr. Almon R. Oquendo                        Dean, CSPEAR
               Dr. Allan William A. Alvarez                Dean, CVMBS
               Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro                    Dean, GS-OLC
               Dr. Famela Iza C. Matic                     Dean, CCJ
               Dr. John Xavier B. Nepomuceno               Administrator, Naic Campus
               Prof. Jose P. Lisama                        Administrator, Rosario Campus
               Prof. Cristina M. Signo                     Dean, Carmona Campus
               Dr. Lynn G. Penales                         Dean, Trece, Tanza and Gen Trias Campuses
               Dr. Gilchor P. Cubillo                      Dean, Silang Campus
               Prof. Ma. Cristina J. Baesa                 OIC, Cavite City Campus
               Mrs, Sharon M. Isip                         OIC, Office of Student Affairs and Services
               Prof. Ronan M. Cajigal                      OIC, Bacoor Campus
               Dr. Ammie P. Ferrer                         Dean, Maragondon Campus
               Dr. Liza C. Costa                           Dean, Imus Campus
               Dr. Evelyn O. Singson                       Director, Professional Review Center
               Prof. Analiza R. Mojica                     Director, Sports
               Mrs. Leonita C. Costa                       In-charge, University Library
               Mrs. Edwina O. Roderos                      In-charge, University Registrar
               Prof. daisy M. Marca                        Manager, Hostel Tropicana
               Dr. Hosea DL. Matel                         Director, Research
               Prof. Ma. Soledad M. Lising                 Director, Extension Services
               Dr. Ruel M.Mojica                           Director, NCRDEC


               52 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[Ms. Almira Macawas                          Director CETS
               Dr. Edna A. Vida                            STAARDEC
               Ms. Bernadeth Morelos                       RECETS
               Prof. Guillermo P. Desenganio               Director, Business Affairs
               Prof. Allan Robert C. Solis                 Director, PICRO
               Dr. Ammie P. Ferrer                         OIC, Alumni Affairs
               Dr. Mary Jane D. Tepora                     Director, Administrative Services
               Dr. David L. Cero                           Director, Physical Plant Services
               Mr. Dionisio F. Marca                       Director, Civil Security
               Mrs. Eileen I. Cubillo                      Director, Human Resource Development Office
               Dr. Romeo M. Sanchez                        Director, Health Services
               Dr. Leyma L. Cero                           Director, Planning and Development Office
               Dr. Adolfo C. Manuel                        Director, Quality Assurance & Accreditation
               Mrs. Lorna C. Matel                         Director, Special projects
               Prof. Analyn A. Mojica                      Director, FSDO
               Dr. Nelia C. Cresino                        Director, Gender and Development
               Prof. Noel A. Sedigo                        President, faculty Association
               Mr. Rodel Vincent Bae                       President, Central Student Government
               Prof. Noelle Legaspi                        President (ad Interim) Alumni Association
               Dr. Elizabeth E. Polinga                    Secretariat
               Ms. Catherine Quinones                      Secretariat
               Ms. Aileen A. Ardina                        Secretariat
               Prof. Antonio V. Cinto                      Secretariat
               Prof. Roderick M. Rupido                    Secretariat
               Mr. Jefferson G.  Rodriguez                 Secretariat
               Mr. Harold M. Rodil                         Secretariat
               Ms. Rosa R. Hernandez                       Chairman, DLMC
               Ms. Marcelina Masicap                       OIC, Internal Audit
               Ms. Edna L. Mojica                          Administrative Officer V
               Ms. Rosalie A. Pelle                        Administrative Officer V
               Prof. Gil D. Ramos                          Chair, Social Sciences
               Dr. Edna A. Vida                            Consortium Director, STARRDEC
               Ms. Bernadette Morelos                      STARRDEC
               Prof. Elsa T. Arcon                         Director, for Instruction, Rosario
               Prof. Deanna C. Parcon                      OIC, Office of Student Affairs and Services
               Prof. Carnia S. Merced                      Director for RECET Rosario
               Prof. Noelle T. Legaspi                     Alumni Regent
               Prof. Nestor M. Alvarez                     Director, AFS Rosario Campus
               Dr. Arnel G. Santos                         Director, PPSS – Rosario Campus
               Prof, Carmen A. Batiles                     Department Chair
               Dr. Lumine R. Crisostomo                    Department Chair
               Mr. Herson John H. Robles                   Security Officer
               Ms. Rowena V. Penalba                       Cashier


               53 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[Ms. Corazon Rodrin                          Budget officer
               Ms. Louziella Masana                        Department Chair, Gen. Trias Campus
               Ms. Gemma S. Legaspi                        Chair, Physical Sciences
               Mr. Bryan Ayos                              Staff, PICRO
               Mr. Vernon C. Costa                         Staff, EBA
               Ms. Rhea A. Blaquera                        Staff, Alumni Affairs
               Ms. Crisel Romen                            Staff
               Prof. Tessie Samonte                        Principal, Secondary High School
               Prof. Willie Buclatin                       Chair
               Prof. Marlon Perana                         Chair
               Prof. Michael Costa                         Chair
               Engr. Cene Bago                             Chair
               Mr. Ferry Pabalate                          Chair
               Ms. Michelle C. Taneja                      Director, OSAS
               Mr. Mat M. Nuestro                          Director for ODCI – Naic Campus
               Ms. Karen Krista                            OIC
               Ms. Jane A. Romea                           OIC Principal
               Ms. Jocelyn Dimayuga                        Clinical Coordinator
               Prof. Susan Tan                             Chair, BSISA – CCJ
               Mr. Edgar Dello                             Staff,Supply Office
               Mr. Jessie Anne T. Demetillo                Campus Secretary


























               54 | P a g e]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[55 | P a g e]]></page></pages></Search>