<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="11"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.3.            The objectives of the SAS are clearly


                        defined.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[1


                                                         RULE VII

                                          STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES

               Article 1. Office of Student Affairs and Services.

                       The student services unit of Cavite State University shall be known as the Office
               of Student Affairs and Services (OSAS).  It shall provide relevant programs for student-
               centered activities and mandated services in support of academic instruction intended
               to facilitate well-rounded student development.

               Article 2. Vision, Mission and Objectives

                       Section 1. Vision

                              The  OSAS  shall  be  a  resource  of  high  quality  student  welfare  and
                       development  programs,  efficient  services  and  relevant  opportunities  geared
                       towards  the  development  of  morally  upright  and  globally  competitive
                       professionals.

                       Section 2. Mission

                              The  OSAS  shall  provide  an  atmosphere  where  students’  talents,
                       interests,  and  values  are  developed  to  the  fullest,  and  shall  deliver  efficient
                       student  services  which  can  contribute  to  the  achievement  of  academic
                       excellence  and  high  professional  competency  which  can  be  recognized
                       internationally.

                       Section 3. Objectives

                              3.1.   regularly implement comprehensive guidance programs with a full
                                     range of activities such as assessment, information, consultation,
                                     counselling, referral, placement, follow-up and follow-through;
                              3.2.   implement  effective  information  and  orientation  strategies  in
                                     promoting awareness on student rights and obligations
                              3.3.   provide  financial  assistance  to the  needy  and deserving  students
                                     through scholarship grants, service and job experience programs,
                                     student  loans  and  mutual  aid  funds,  giving  priority  to  those
                                     belonging to the vulnerable and marginalized sector
                              3.4.   provide leadership trainings to enhance leadership effectiveness of
                                     students both at  personal and organizational levels
                              3.5.    strictly  implement  institutional  rules  and  regulations  governing
                                     student  behaviour  and  conduct  to  be  able  to  produce  morally
                                     upright professionals
                              3.6.    provide avenues to hone students’ talents and interest to ensure
                                     social and cultural growth;
                              3.7.    implement  relevant  sports  development  programs  to  provide
                                     opportunities  for  athletic  competition,  physical  fitness  and  well-
                                     being of students





               Excerpts from the Univeristy Manual of Operations]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                       TANZA CAMPUS


                      OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES


                              STUDENT



                               SERVICES



                            PROGRAMS]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 TANZA CAMPUS


 OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES


 STUDENT



 SERVICES



 PROGRAMS]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES                           UNIVERSITY VISION

                       As  an  institution  of  higher  learning,  the  Cavite  State           The  premier  University  in  historic  Cavite  recognized
               University  caters  to  the  needs  of  the  students,  not  only  in  the   for excellence in the development of globally competitive and
               acquisition of education but also in their personality development.       morally upright individuals.
               To  ensure  that  the  students’  potential  for  advancement  are
               maximized,  the  Student  Welfare  Services  was  established.  The       UNIVERSITY MISSION
               Student  Welfare  Services  had  been  renamed  Office  of  Student
               Affairs  (OSAS).  It  is  major  project  uner  the  Office  of  the  Vice       The  Cavite  State  University  shall  provide  excellent,
               President for Academic Affairs.                                           equitable and relevant educational opportunities in the arts,
                                                                                         sciences  and  technology  though  quality  instruction  and
               HISTORY
                                                                                         responsive  research  and  development  activities.  It  shall
               The Office of Student Affairs started as one of the functional units      produce professional, skilled and morally upright individuals
               of  the  then  Don  Severino  Agricultural  College  (DSAC)  in  1980.    for global competitiveness.
               Through the years the name of the office was changed to Student
               Services  Project  in  1986,  Student  Services  in  1989,  Student       OSAS GOALS
               Welfare  Services  in  1991  and  renamed again  to  Office  of  Student
               Affairs  in  1998  when  DSAC  was  elevated  into  a  university,  the          The  goals  of  the  Student  Affairs  are  the  following:  to
               Cavite State University. In December 2004, the OSA was renamed            look after the educational, vocational, as well as the personal
               to  Office  of  Student  Affairs  and  Services  by  virtue  of  BOR      development needs of the students; to assist the students to
               resolution no. 77 s. 2004. Since then, the office has been providing      maximize  their  potential  by  helping  them  understand
               different  student  services  to  its  clients  such  as  guidance  and   themselves  and  their  environment  and  to  enhance  their
               counselling,  admission  and  testing,  and  student  development         psychological growth towards socialized maturity.
               services  like  student  organization  and  socio  cultural  affairs,
               student publication and placement of students and graduates. The
               mandated  National  Service  Training  Program  (NSTP)  subject  was
               also offered by the office in 2002.The office will continue and shall
               remain  committed  to  provide  student  welfare  and  development
               activities to the CvSU academic community and the public.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[OFFICE OF STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES   UNIVERSITY VISION

 As  an  institution  of  higher  learning,  the  Cavite  State   The  premier  University  in  historic  Cavite  recognized
 University  caters  to  the  needs  of  the  students,  not  only  in  the   for excellence in the development of globally competitive and
 acquisition of education but also in their personality development.   morally upright individuals.
 To  ensure  that  the  students’  potential  for  advancement  are
 maximized,  the  Student  Welfare  Services  was  established.  The   UNIVERSITY MISSION
 Student  Welfare  Services  had  been  renamed  Office  of  Student
 Affairs  (OSAS).  It  is  major  project  uner  the  Office  of  the  Vice   The  Cavite  State  University  shall  provide  excellent,
 President for Academic Affairs.   equitable and relevant educational opportunities in the arts,
     sciences  and  technology  though  quality  instruction  and
 HISTORY
     responsive  research  and  development  activities.  It  shall
 The Office of Student Affairs started as one of the functional units   produce professional, skilled and morally upright individuals
 of  the  then  Don  Severino  Agricultural  College  (DSAC)  in  1980.   for global competitiveness.
 Through the years the name of the office was changed to Student
 Services  Project  in  1986,  Student  Services  in  1989,  Student   OSAS GOALS
 Welfare  Services  in  1991  and  renamed again  to  Office  of  Student
 Affairs  in  1998  when  DSAC  was  elevated  into  a  university,  the      The  goals  of  the  Student  Affairs  are  the  following:  to
 Cavite State University. In December 2004, the OSA was renamed   look after the educational, vocational, as well as the personal
 to  Office  of  Student  Affairs  and  Services  by  virtue  of  BOR   development needs of the students; to assist the students to
 resolution no. 77 s. 2004. Since then, the office has been providing   maximize  their  potential  by  helping  them  understand
 different  student  services  to  its  clients  such  as  guidance  and   themselves  and  their  environment  and  to  enhance  their
 counselling,  admission  and  testing,  and  student  development   psychological growth towards socialized maturity.
 services  like  student  organization  and  socio  cultural  affairs,
 student publication and placement of students and graduates. The
 mandated  National  Service  Training  Program  (NSTP)  subject  was
 also offered by the office in 2002.The office will continue and shall
 remain  committed  to  provide  student  welfare  and  development
 activities to the CvSU academic community and the public.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES                                                     1.     regularly     implement      comprehensive

                                                                                                              guidance  programs  with  a  full  range  of
                                                                                                              activities     such      as     assessment,
                      The  student  services  unit  of  Cavite  State  University                             information,  consultation,  counselling,
              shall be known as the Office of Student Affairs and Services                                    referral, placement, follow-up and follow-
              (OSAS).    It  shall  provide  relevant  programs  for  student-                                through;
              centered  activities  and  mandated  services  in  support  of                           2.     implement  effective  information  and
                                                                                                                                                promoting
                                                                                                                             strategies
              academic  instruction  intended  to  facilitate  well-rounded                                   orientation    on   student  in  rights   and
                                                                                                              awareness
              student development.                                                                            obligations
                                                                                                       3.     provide financial assistance to the needy
               Vision, Mission and Objectives                                                                 and      deserving     students     through
                                                                                                              scholarship  grants,  service  and  job
                      Vision                                                                                  experience  programs,  student  loans  and
                                                                                                              mutual aid funds, giving priority to those
                             The  OSAS  shall  be  a  resource  of  high  quality                             belonging     to    the   vulnerable     and
                      student  welfare  and  development  programs,  efficient                                marginalized sector
                      services and relevant opportunities geared towards the                           4.     provide  leadership  trainings  to  enhance
                                                                                                              leadership effectiveness of students both
                      development      of   morally    upright    and    globally                             at  personal and organizational levels
                      competitive professionals.                                                       5.      strictly  implement  institutional  rules
                                                                                                              and     regulations    governing     student
                      Mission                                                                                 behaviour  and  conduct  to  be  able  to
                                                                                                              produce morally upright professionals
                             The  OSAS  shall  provide  an  atmosphere  where                          6.      provide  avenues  to  hone  students’
                      students’ talents,  interests,  and values  are  developed                              talents and interest to ensure social and
                      to  the  fullest,  and  shall  deliver  efficient  student                              cultural growth;
                      services  which  can  contribute  to  the  achievement  of                       7.      implement  relevant  sports  development
                      academic      excellence     and     high     professional                              programs  to  provide  opportunities  for
                      competency which can be recognized internationally.                                     athletic competition, physical fitness and
                                                                                                              well-being of students
                      Section 3. Objectives
                                                                                                       8.     develop  skills  and  potentials  of  student
                                                                                                              writers]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[STUDENT AFFAIRS AND SERVICES  1.    regularly   implement   comprehensive

                          guidance  programs  with  a  full  range  of
                          activities    such      as      assessment,
 The  student  services  unit  of  Cavite  State  University   information,  consultation,  counselling,
 shall be known as the Office of Student Affairs and Services   referral, placement, follow-up and follow-
 (OSAS).    It  shall  provide  relevant  programs  for  student-  through;
 centered  activities  and  mandated  services  in  support  of   2.    implement  effective  information  and
                                                            promoting
                                         strategies
 academic  instruction  intended  to  facilitate  well-rounded   orientation   on   student  in  rights   and
                          awareness
 student development.     obligations
                   3.     provide financial assistance to the needy
 Vision, Mission and Objectives     and   deserving   students   through
                          scholarship  grants,  service  and  job
 Vision                   experience  programs,  student  loans  and
                          mutual aid funds, giving priority to those
 The  OSAS  shall  be  a  resource  of  high  quality   belonging   to   the   vulnerable   and
 student  welfare  and  development  programs,  efficient   marginalized sector
 services and relevant opportunities geared towards the   4.    provide  leadership  trainings  to  enhance
                          leadership effectiveness of students both
 development   of   morally   upright   and   globally   at  personal and organizational levels
 competitive professionals.   5.     strictly  implement  institutional  rules
                          and     regulations    governing     student
 Mission                  behaviour  and  conduct  to  be  able  to
                          produce morally upright professionals
 The  OSAS  shall  provide  an  atmosphere  where   6.     provide  avenues  to  hone  students’
 students’ talents,  interests,  and values  are  developed   talents and interest to ensure social and
 to  the  fullest,  and  shall  deliver  efficient  student   cultural growth;
 services  which  can  contribute  to  the  achievement  of   7.     implement  relevant  sports  development
 academic   excellence   and   high   professional   programs  to  provide  opportunities  for
 competency which can be recognized internationally.   athletic competition, physical fitness and
                          well-being of students
 Section 3. Objectives
                   8.     develop  skills  and  potentials  of  student
                          writers]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[9.     promote      student     involvement      in              The Student Welfare Services Unit
                                     community development programs
                              10.   provide an environment conducive to free                          The  Student  Welfare  Services  Unit  shall  deliver
                                     expression  of  one’s  religious  orientation             student services and programs needed to ensure and
                                     in    accordance       with    institutional
                                     principles                                                promote the well-being of students. This shall include
                                                                                               information  and  orientation  services,  guidance  and
                                                                                               counselling  services,  career  and  job  placement
               Organizational Structure of OSAS                                                services,    and      student     economic      enterprise
                                                                                               development services.
                       The  OSAS  shall  be  headed  by  a  dean  who  shall  be
               under  the  direct  supervision  of  the  Vice-President  for                   The Student Development Services Unit
               Academic Affairs. The OSAS shall have four service units, the
               Student  Welfare  Services  (SWS)  Unit,  the  Student                                 The  Student  Development  Services  Unit   shall
               Development  Services  (SDS)  Unit,  the  Institutional  Student                provide  services  and  programs  designed  for  the
               Programs  and  Services  (ISPS)  Unit  and  the  Research,                      exploration,  enhancement  and  development  of  the
               Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Student  Services  (RMESS)                     students’  full  potential  for  personal  development,
               Unit.  Each  unit  shall  be  headed  by  an  over-all  coordinator             leadership  and  social  responsibility  through  various
               who shall report directly to the OSAS dean.                                     institutional    student     activities.   The     student
                                                                                               development  services  include  student  organization
               Student Services and Programs                                                   and activities, student government, student discipline,
                                                                                               and student publication.
                       The OSAS shall deliver three basic academic support
               services  to  students:  student  welfare  services,  student
               development  services  and  those  that  relate  to  institutional
               programs and services. In addition, there shall be a separate
               support  service  for  research,  monitoring  and  evaluation  of
               student  services.  These  services  shall  be  delivered  by  the
               following units:]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[9.    promote   student   involvement   in   The Student Welfare Services Unit
 community development programs
 10.   provide an environment conducive to free   The  Student  Welfare  Services  Unit  shall  deliver
 expression  of  one’s  religious  orientation   student services and programs needed to ensure and
 in   accordance   with   institutional
 principles   promote the well-being of students. This shall include
           information  and  orientation  services,  guidance  and
           counselling  services,  career  and  job  placement
 Organizational Structure of OSAS      services,   and   student   economic   enterprise
           development services.
 The  OSAS  shall  be  headed  by  a  dean  who  shall  be
 under  the  direct  supervision  of  the  Vice-President  for    The Student Development Services Unit
 Academic Affairs. The OSAS shall have four service units, the
 Student  Welfare  Services  (SWS)  Unit,  the  Student   The  Student  Development  Services  Unit   shall
 Development  Services  (SDS)  Unit,  the  Institutional  Student   provide  services  and  programs  designed  for  the
 Programs  and  Services  (ISPS)  Unit  and  the  Research,   exploration,  enhancement  and  development  of  the
 Monitoring  and  Evaluation  of  Student  Services  (RMESS)   students’  full  potential  for  personal  development,
 Unit.  Each  unit  shall  be  headed  by  an  over-all  coordinator   leadership  and  social  responsibility  through  various
 who shall report directly to the OSAS dean.    institutional   student   activities.   The   student
           development  services  include  student  organization
 Student Services and Programs       and activities, student government, student discipline,
           and student publication.
 The OSAS shall deliver three basic academic support
 services  to  students:  student  welfare  services,  student
 development  services  and  those  that  relate  to  institutional
 programs and services. In addition, there shall be a separate
 support  service  for  research,  monitoring  and  evaluation  of
 student  services.  These  services  shall  be  delivered  by  the
 following units:]]></page></pages></Search>