<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="39"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.10.           The institution ensures that:


                        I.10.1.  Research outputs are protected


                                       by IPR laws; and]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           319
                   APPENDIX 14

                              PROTECTING THE INTELLECTUAL PROPERTIES OF
                                             CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY


                   I. Rationale

                          Republic  Act  No.  8293,  otherwise  known  as  the  Intellectual
                   Property Code of the Philippines, states that:


                          “The  State  recognizes  that  an  effective  intellectual  and  industrial
                   property  system  is  vital  to  the  development  of  domestic  and  creative
                   activity,  facilitates  transfers  of  technology,  attracts  foreign  investments,
                   and ensures market access for our products.  It shall protect and secure
                   the  exclusive  rights  of  scientist,  inventors,  artists  and  other  gifted
                   citizens  to  their  intellectual  property  and  creations,  particularly  when
                   beneficial to the people.”


                          With  the  various  intellectual  properties  (IP’s)  developed  in  the
                   university  such  as  the  Aguinaldo  Blend  Coffee,  processed  products,
                   design  for  biogas  digester  and  innumerable  research  outputs  being
                   presented  for  public  consumption,  a  few  of  them  were  able  to  acquire
                   protection. The biogas digester was just recently granted a patent, while
                   research  outputs/publications  have  been  presented  without  copyright
                   protection,  except  for  some  that  were  able  to  acquire  ISBN  registration
                   from  the  National  Library.  Therefore,  the  University  must  develop  a
                   system  for  protecting  economically  viable  intellectual  properties  to
                   maximize gains that could finance more researches in the future.


                   II. Definition of Terms


                          “Copyright” is  the  protection  extended  to  expressions  and  not  to
                   ideas, procedures, and methods of operations or mathematical concepts
                   as  such.  Such  expressions  may  be  in  the  forms  of  literary,  scholarly,
                   scientific and artistic works.

                          “Intellectual Property or IP” is an asset that possesses commercial
                   value  which  can  be  exploited  to  generate  revenue.  IP  value  lies  in  its
                   utilization, not existence.

                          “Intellectual Property Rights” or “IPR” refers to the entitlement and
                   enjoyment of the attributes of ownership over intellectual properties. IPR
                   consists  of:  a)  Copyright  and  related  rights;  b)  Trademarks  and  Service
                   Marks;  c)  Geographic  Indications;  d)  Industrial  Designs;  e)  Patents;  f)
                   Layout-Designs (Topographies) of Integrated Circuits; and g) Protection of








                                                                                                      319]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           320
                   Undisclosed Information.  IPR shall likewise include plant varieties  and
                                                 1
                   animal breeds.

                          “Patent’       is a grant issued by the Philippine government giving
                   an  inventor  the  right  to  exclude others  from  making,  using,  setting,  or
                   importing the product of his invention within the Philippines in exchange
                   of his patentable information or disclosure.

                          “Patentable inventions”  means any technical solution of a problem
                   in  any  field  of  human  activity  which  is  new,  involves  an  inventive  step
                   and is industrially applicable, which may be, or may related to a product,
                   or process, or an improvement of any of the foregoing.
                                                                                  2

                          “Plant variety”       means a plant grouping within a single botanical
                   taxon of the lowest known rank which can be defined by the expression
                   of the characteristics resulting from a given genotype, or combination of
                   genotypes,  distinguished  from  any  other  plant  groupings  by  the
                   expression  of  at  least  one  characteristic  and  considered  as  a  unit  with
                   regard to the suitability for being propagated unchanged. A variety may
                   be  represented  by  seed,  transplants,  plants,  tubers,  and  tissue  culture
                   plantlets.


                          “Prior art”   Everything made available to the public by means of a
                   written or oral disclosure, by use, or in any other way, before the filing
                   date  or  the  priority  date  of  the  application  claiming  the  invention.
                   Prior use which is not present in the Philippines, even if widespread in a
                   foreign country, cannot form part of the prior art if such prior use is not
                   disclosed in printed documents or in any tangible form.


                   III. Objective


                          To establish a system protecting the intellectual properties (IP’s) or
                   results/products  generated  through  researches  conducted  in  the
                   university.

                   IV. Strategy


                          The  University  shall  establish  an  IPR  Office  that  covers  all
                   intellectual property protection activities and provide trainings/seminars
                   to  researchers  to  increase  awareness  on  IPR.  The  IPR  Office  will  be
                   divided in to two sections, each having IPR Assistants, one for patentable
                   IP’s and the other for publishable IP’s.


                          The IPR Officer will work under the Office of the Vice-President for
                   Research,  Extension,  Continuing  Education  and  Training  Services
                   (RECETS), and is tasked to identify, protect and exploit commercially on


                   1  Section 4, R.A. 8293 (1998); TRIPS.
                   2  Section 21, R.A. 8293 (1998).
                                                                                                      320]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           321
                   the  University’s  behalf  the  intellectual  property  rights  generated  by  the
                   University’s researchers.

                          The  IPR  Officer  will  be  involved  in  identifying  and  protecting  the
                   University’s  intellectual  property  rights,  and  in  conforming  to  existing
                   systems in managing, recording and tracking the progress of intellectual
                   property  applications  and  commercialization  of  the  property.  The  IPR
                   Officer will be required to work in close coordination with both research
                   and  academic  units  of  the  university  to  identify  research  results  and
                   intellectual property rights with commercial potential. In this capacity the
                   IPR  Assistants  will  be  responsible  for  applying  for  and  liquidating  cash
                   advances  accrued  during  the  applications  and  payment  of  other  fees
                   pertinent  to  the  application.  Where  necessary  the  IPR  Officer  will  work
                   with the University’s legal advisers.

                          The  IPR  Officer  and  IPR  Assistants  will  be  provided  with
                   appropriate external training to ensure that they can become competent
                   in all aspects of the role.

                   Other responsibilities include the following:


                          Formulate,  propose  and  implement  governing  guidelines  in
                   patenting/copyrighting research results in the University

                          Deal  with  agencies  requesting  for  commercialization  rights  for
                   patented/ copyrighted materials from the university, enter into licensing
                   agreements and manage the payment of royalties.

                          Monitor  violations  and  persecute  violators  for  patents/copyrights
                   issued to the university.


                   V. Implementation

                          The  CvSU-Intellectual  Property  Office  (CvSU-IPO)  shall  head  two
                   units,  Patentable  IP  Unit  and  Publishable  IP  Unit,  each  having  IPR
                   Assistants and will work in consultation with the legal authority of the
                   University;






















                                                                                                      321]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           322









































                          Figure 1:       Proposed Organizational set-up of the IPR Office











































                                                                                                      322]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           323
                   Intellectual properties generated through the university researches shall
                   be  jointly  owned  by  the  researcher  and  the  university.  Sharing  of  the
                   royalties will be at 70% for the researcher and 30% for the University


                          A 5% cut from the royalty share of the researcher shall be placed in
                   a  trust  fund  for  future  research  projects,  travels,  attendance  to
                   conferences of the respective researcher

                          Registration/processing  fees  for  patents/copyrights  shall  be
                   shouldered by the University.

                          All  research  outputs,  patentable/copyrightable  or  not,  shall  be
                   reported  to  the  CvSU-IPO  and  shall  only  be  presented/published  for
                   public consumption if, and only if, a written permit from the CvSU-IPO
                   has been granted to the researcher

                          Licensing agreements, before being entered into shall be reviewed
                   and approved by the University President and Board of Regents.

                   VI. IPR Application Process Flow (University Level)


                   A.  Patents  (filing  fee,  PhP  3,636.00,  until  4  years  after  publication  of
                   patent, annual fees on each subsequent anniversary) *validity: 20 years
                   from filing date


                          The  researcher  submits  the  terminal  report  to  the  University
                   Research Center.

                          The  IPR  Officer  and  the  Research  Center  Director  periodically
                   submit technologies for patentability evaluation to the Vice President for
                   RECETS.

                          If  approved,  the  researcher  is  asked  to  fill  up  Patent  Application
                   Form and submit necessary documents to the IPR Officer.

                          The  IPR  Officer  applies  for  Cash  Advance  that  would  cover
                   expenses  for  the  application  including,  but  not  limited  to,  filing  fee,
                   photocopying fee, transportation and travel allowances, etc.


                   As the cash advance is released, the application will be filed at the:

                                      INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY PHILIPPINES
                                                       IPO Building
                                         351 Sen. Gil Puyat Ave., Makati City

                   Other documents and fees, as the need arises, related to the application
                   will be accomplished, submitted and paid promptly by the IPR Officer.



                                                                                                      323]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           324
                   B. Copyrights (registration fee: PhP 150.00) * validity: lifetime + 50 years

                          Register and deposit two (2) copies each to:


                                 i. National Library Copyright Division


                                 ii. Supreme Court Library










































































                                                                                                      324]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   _____________________________________________________________________

                                                                                                           325
                   VII. Potential IP’s developed in the University


                                                   Classificat                                  Unit/College/
                   IP                                            Year       Author
                                                   ion                                          Campus
                   1.  Aguinaldo Blend             Patent        2002       Dr.  Alejandro  Coffee Center
                                                                            C. Mojica, Sr.
                   2.  Aguinaldo  Blend  in  Utility             2002       Dr.  Alejandro  Coffee Center
                   Filter Bags                     Model                    C. Mojica, Sr.
                   3.Chevon               Mara,   Patent         2000       Prof.    Fe    N.  CAFENR
                   Nuggets                                                  Dimero
                   4.  Native Chicken Mara,  Patent              2001       Prof.    Fe    N.  CAFENR
                   reformed  ham,  sausage,                                 Dimero
                   nuggets, franks
                   5.  Laya at Diwa                Copyright  2006
                   6.    Softwares,  computer  Copyright  ---               Students  and  CEIT
                   programs, etc.                                           faculty
                   7.    Research  results,  Copyright  ---                 Students  and  All
                   articles,          journals,                             faculty
                   theses,       presentation,
                   photographs, leaflets
                   8.       T-shirt     designs  Copyright  2007            Dr.  Tepora  /  Research
                   (dragonfruit             and                             Dr. Mojica          Center
                   Aguinaldo blend)
                   9.Processed  dragonfruit  Patent              2007       Dr.  Teddy  F.  Research
                   products                                                 Tepora              Center






































                                                                                                      325]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>