<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="14"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[S.1.            The institution has an approved printed


                        Student Handbook/Manual containing


                        policies and guidelines on the following

                        aspects of student life:


                        S.1.8.   scholarships/grants/


                                       assistantships;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[f)  Curricular classification shall be based on the actual number of academic units completed
                          as required for a particular curricular year. For this purpose, a student shall be classified as
                          Freshman, Sophomore, Junior, and Senior depending on the total required academic units
                          he has earned. The official curricular classification of students shall be responsibility of the
                          University Registrar.



               UNIVERSITY SCHOLARSHIP

                       Scholarship in the university shall be classified into: entrance scholarship, university or full
               scholarship, and college or partial scholarship. These scholarships are defined as follows:


                       a)  An entrance scholarship* shall consist of free tuition or, in units where no tuition is
                          charged; free laboratory fee shall be enjoyed for one semester only by the following
                          students upon admission to the University.

                                     Valedictorian, salutatorians and honor students from recognized public/private
                              high schools shall be awarded entrance scholarships. In order to avail this scholarship,
                              valedictorians, salutatorians and honor graduates should come from graduating classes
                              with at least 30 students to be certified by the head of the school concerned; provided
                              further that valedictorians and salutatorians from high school units of the University
                              shall be exempted from taking the university entrance examination and from payment
                              of regular University fees including tuition, except the miscellaneous fees.
                                     Entrance scholarship shall be for the first semester only. The renewal to full or
                              partial scholarship shall be subject to terms and conditions of Sections b and c below.

                       b)  A university or full scholarship which consist of free tuition and other school fees shall be
                          enjoyed by any undergraduate student who obtains at the end of the semester a GPA of
                          1.50 or better and attains a lowest grade of 2.50, or by any graduate student enrolled in
                          graduate school who obtains at the end of the semester a GPA of 1.25 or better; and
                       c)  A college or partial scholarship which consist of a 50 percent reduction in tuition and other
                          school fees shall be enjoyed by any undergraduate student who obtains at the end of the
                          semester a GPA of 1.75 or better and attains a lowest grade of 2.50, or by any graduate
                          student enrolled in the graduate program of the University who obtains at the end of the
                          semester a GPA of 1.5 or better.

                                     Provided, however, that full or partial scholarships are granted to those not
                              being supported by another agency or institution.
                                     A University (or full) and a college (or partial) scholarship shall be valid only for
                              one semester, but shall be renewable for the succeeding semester if the student meets
                              the conditions prescribed.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[student meets this requirement, a screening committee shall be created by the SHS
                          Principal for the purpose of determining the possibility and appropriateness of transfer.

                       d)  Types of Scholarships. Starting in the second year, students may be entitled to scholarships.
                          There shall be two types of scholarship:

                                            1.  Full Scholarship – GPA of 90% or better in all academic subjects at
                                                the end of the school year; and weighted average grade of 90% or
                                                better in Science, Mathematics and Scientific Research.
                                            2.  Partial scholarship -  GPA of 88% to 88.99 % in all academic subjects
                                                at the end of the school year; and GPA of 88% to 89.99% in Science,
                                                Mathematics and Scientific Research.

                                                   A scholar, whether full or partial must:

                                                     Not have a grade lower than 85% in any of the subjects
                                                       taken;

                                                     Abide by the provision of the University Norm of Conduct
                                                       for students. (The scholarship is forfeited if the student is
                                                       involved in any form of misdemeanor); and

                                                     Submit notice or any change of legal guardian and residence
                                                       while studying in the University SHS.

                       e)  Scholarship Privileges. The scholar shall receive the privileges listed below. These privileges
                          may be changed at any time as deemed necessary by the Board of Regents:

                                                1.  Full scholarship

                                                   1.1 P500.00 monthly stipend
                                                   1.2 P500.00 yearly book allowance

                                            2.  Partial scholarship

                                                   2.1 P300.00 monthly stipend
                                                   2.2 P500.00 yearly book allowance

                       f) Student Conduct and Discipline. Students of SHS shall be covered by the University Student’s
                       Code of Conduct as astipulated in Rule VIII of the CvSU Manual of Operation 2009 Vol. 1.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[The selection of the chief editor and other members of the staff of tertiary student publication
               shall  be  through  competitive  examinations  prepared,  conducted  and  supervised  by  the  selection
               committee composed of a representative of the school administration, one faculty member, one mass
               media practitioner who is acceptable to both (school administration and editorial board) and two past
               editors to be chosen by the outgoing board (adopted from campus journalism Act RA 7079).
               In the event of vacancy in the position of Editor-in-Chief by reasons of illness, transfer, removal from
               office, resignation and/or similar causes, the same shall be filled immediately according to the next-in-
               rank rule. The new Editor-in-Chief shall serve the remaining term within the school year.

                       The  student  writers  are  required  to  maintain  the  grade  of  2.25  or  better  with  no  dropped
               subjects or failing grades (BOR Res. No.  84, s. 2006)
                       The  members  of  the  editorial  board  and  staff  receive  honoraria  every  semester.  Senior  staff
               members are also given Service Scholarship.

               Section 22. Information Materials

                       The privilege of posting, exhibiting or distributing non-commercial literature within University
               premises is limited to University Students and registered student organizations. Any material posted or
               distributed shall clearly indicate the name of the person or student organization on whose behalf the
               announcement is posted and shall bear the approval of the Office of Student Affairs.

                       Anonymous materials or announcements are strictly prohibited and the University shall exercise
               sanctions on the author whether student or University employee, if positively identified.

                       Printed materials should be placed on vehicles parked on campus or inside the classrooms. They
               may be distributed only with the consent of the instructor or teacher of the class at the time. Literature
               materials may be distributed within the college premises only after prior authorization.

                       Materials in the form of protest, expressing certain views or espousing ideas not contrary to
               prudent taste may be posted on the structure or bulletin board provided by the University.

                       The college/department official bulletin boards are exclusively for announcements, notices or
               programs and activities sponsored by the said college/department. Their use by any student groups may
               be allowed upon previous approval by the college dean/department chairman concerned. Walls shall
               not be used for posting announcements.

               Section 23. Students’ Code of Conduct

                       The University, in the consultation of the students, shall promulgate and implement a student’s
               code of conduct as a general guide on the actions and activities of students while in campus. The rules
               and  guidelines  shall  include  wearing  of  identification  cards  and  uniforms;  abusive  language,  assault
               against others and persons in authority; smoking alcoholic drinks and prohibited drugs; and others that
               shall contribute a peaceful, harmonious and orderly academic atmosphere. The full text of Students’
               Code of Conducts is in Rule VIII of the CvSU Manual of Operations 2009 Vol 1, pages 212-239 and is
               contained in page 101 of this handbook.

               Section 24. Student Financial Assistance]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Reproduced  below  is  the  overall  student  financial  assistance  program  of  the  University.  Any
               revision thereof shall be approved by the Board of Regents.

                       The Financial Assistance Services Unit of the Office of Student Affairs shall be responsible for the
               implementation of the University Student Financial Assistance Program.

                       Listed below are the current types of financial assistance offered by the University. Other types
               of financial assistance may be implemented later upon approval by the Board of Regents.



                       a.  CvSU Sate Scholarship

                              This  scholarship  is  awarded  to  financially  deserving  students  who  excel  in  academic
                          performance. The grant is classified as full and partial. In order to avail the full and partial
                          grant, the students shall have the Grade Point Average (GPA) of 1.50 or better, and 1.51 to
                          2.00  respectively.  Also,  the  scholar  shall  obtain  a  lowest  grade  of  2.50  in  the  previous
                          semester.

                       b.  Honorific or Academic Scholarship

                              This scholarship is awarded to students whose Grade Point Average (GPA) is not lower
                          than  1.75  and  obtain  a  lowest  grade  of  2.50  in  the  preceding  semester.  The  grant  is
                          classified as full scholars with GPS of 1.50 or better and partial scholars with GPA of 1.75 to
                          1.51. valedictorians and salutatorians are considered entrance scholars and are entitled full
                          and partial scholarship, respectively.

                       c.  Private Scholarship

                              This is granted to students who are selected and sponsored by private individuals and
                          organizations.  The  continuance  or  the  default  of  scholarship  is  at  the  discretion  of  the
                          sponsor.

                       d.  Endowed Scholarship

                              This is a scholarship set up when donors provide grant money or raise a certain amount,
                          which will be the principal of a scholarship fund. The earnings of the endowment be utilized
                          to support scholarship grants. The fund is managed by the Office-In-Charge of the University
                          Development Fund/Office of Student Affairs.

                       e.  Job Experience Program (formerly known as Work for Tuition)

                              This is a form of student assistance extended to financially handicapped student so they
                          can  enroll  in  a  particular  course  and  pay  the  corresponding  school  fees  incurred  for  the
                          semester  through  work  services  rendered  to  the  University.  The  number  of  work  service
                          depends on the amount of fees discounted.

                       f.  Student Assistantship]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[This is a grant available to students who desire to render service to the University and
                          receive remuneration for services while studying. The allowable number of hours of work
                          service shall be maximum of 100.

                       g.  Government Scholarship

                              This  is  a  scholarship  given  to  any  student  under  the  AFP/Philippine  Veterans  Affairs
                          (PVAO).  R.  A.  7160,  PD  577  RA  7883,  DND/CHED/PASUC  and  other  similar  recognized
                          government  scholarship  honored  by  the  University  upon  presentation  of  the  necessary
                          credentials.

                       h.  CvSU Scholarship Privilege

                              This  scholarship  is  awarded  to  employees  of  the  University  and  their  dependents
                          provided that such employees have rendered at least one year of employment status.

                       i.  Service Scholarship

                              This is a program, which provides free tuition or tuition discount to students who have
                          rendered service to the University as members of the varsity teams, CvSU band and socio-
                          cultural, senior staff of student publication, officers of the University Student Council and
                          first class ROTC Cadet Officers.

                       In  general,  the  criteria  in  the  selection  of  financial  awardees  include:  good  moral  character;
               economic  background  of  parents  or  guardians;  willingness  to  work;  and  academic  performance.  The
               University shall promulgate the details of selection criteria and the mechanics of implementation and
               revise the same accordingly, as the need raise.

                       The benefits to the awardees of the financial assistance program include: either free tuition or
               discounts  in  tuition  fees;  monthly  stipend;  allowance  per  semester;  book  allowance  and  others.  In
               addition, some types of financial assistance include priority booking in the University Dormitory. The
               responsibilities of the recipients include maintaining high academic standards; and also rendering some
               types of service work to the University. The University shall issue from time to time, update guidelines
               on these aspects of the program.

                       The  financial  assistance  is  automatically  terminated  if  a  student  recipient  is  involved  in  any
               misconduct  in  contravention  of  the  University  Students’  Code  of  Conduct  or  any  other  University
               policies,  rules  and  regulations.  In  addition,  student  recipients  whose  grades  fall  below  the  required
               academic  requirements  by  the  type  of  financial  assistance  shall  also  forfeit  the  benefits  and/or
               allowances.

               Section 25.  Residence Halls/Dormitories

                       The  University  shall,  as  much  as  possible,  maintain  residence  halls/dormitories  for  students
               where  are  expected  to  reside.  Students  not  living  in  the  University  residence  halls/dormitories  shall
               reside in the homes or dormitories accredited by the Office of Student Affairs.]]></page></pages></Search>