<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="21"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[AREA IX












                    LABORATORIES]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[PARAMETER D












                                       SPECIAL





                            PROVISIONS]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[IMPLEMENTATION]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[I.1.            The institution implements the special


                        provisions as listed in the CMO.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Internship]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[26


                                                THE TRAINING EXPERIENCES



                              This consists of the tasks performed by the trainee, her observations during the

                       training, and her insights into work-from-home on-the-job training.


                       Task Performed

                              During the 600 hours of virtual on-the-job training in ROC.PH Digital Marketing

                       Services, the trainee was able to perform the following tasks;

                              Adding the leads. The trainee was tasked with creating a new profile for a

                       potential company client.

































                                            Figure 18. The trainee while adding leads




                              Sending  email  via  company  portal  or  client's  portal.  After  creating  the

                       profile lead, the trainee has experience sending proposal emails via the company or

                       client portal.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[27































                        Figure 19. The trainee while sending email via the company portal or client's portal.



                              Sending  SMS  via  the  company  portal.  After  sending  the  initial  email

                       proposal, the trainee sent an initial SMS saying they had submitted an email to the

                       client.
































                                Figure 20. The trainee while sending SMS via the company portal.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[28


                              Sending email follow-up via company portal or client's portal. When the

                       lead client did not answer within 48 hours, the trainee was instructed to send a follow-

                       up email proposal.
































                       Figure 21. The trainee while sending an email to follow up via the company or client's
                                                             portal.



                              Sending SMS follow-up via company portal. After submitting the follow-up

                       email proposal, the trainee was told to do so by her team leader. After delivering a

                       follow-up email proposal, it is vital to send follow-up messages regularly to achieve the

                       desired reaction.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[29































                          Figure 22. The trainee while sending SMS to follow up via the company portal.



                              Making a poster for Facebook Page. The trainee was assigned to create a

                       poster and caption by her team leader regarding the company's offerings, which will

                       be posted on the team's Facebook page.
































                                 Figure 23. The trainee while making a poster for Facebook Page]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[30


                              Attending a meeting. While on a meeting, the trainees are expected to attend

                       every scheduled or unplanned meeting. They have a meeting once in a while to provide

                       important corporate information that might affect all teams or specific departments.
































                                        Figure 24. The trainee while attending a meeting.




                              Clinic consultation. The trainee must go to the wellness hall every Friday for

                       a  clinic  consultation.  They  were  asked  to  do  the  exercise  on  the  share  screen

                       presentation and answer some riddles and the question of the day. Also, after the

                       consultation, they will answer a clinic form for the performance evaluation.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[31































                       Figure 25. The trainee was on clinic consultation and doing the torso twist exercise at
                                                        the wellness hall.


                       Observed Strength of the Training Area

                              The  trainee  observed  that  the  supervisors  and  team  leaders  were

                       approachable, friendly, and trustworthy. They made sure every team completed each

                       task appropriately. They were able to keep the trainees informed and provide support


                       with any task requirements. Also, in every meeting, the management  ensured that

                       everyone was heard and their questions were answered.

                       Problems Encountered

                              The trainee encountered some problems during the training period. Since the

                       on-the-job  training  is  work  from  home,  there  were  internet  connectivity  problems,

                       power interruption, the game lost connection at the virtual office when there were so


                       many people in one room, and the international SMS that causes the documents to be

                       on hold for the meantime.

                              The trainee suggested that the management provide much understanding and

                       consideration since most of the problems encountered are inevitable.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[32


                                                          SUMMARY



                              On-the-job training (OJT) is a type of skill development where a worker learns

                       how to do work through hands-on experience from home. It aims to teach, orient, and


                       enhance students' unique qualities as they relate to their work and future careers. The

                       main goal of the training is acquiring new competencies and skills needed for a job in

                       a real or close to the working environment.

                              The training at ROC.PH Digital Marketing Services started officially when the

                       trainee was enrolled in the program. The University approved her on-the-job training


                       on March 1, 2022, as client service. As a client service representative, her duties and

                       responsibilities are adding new leads, sending email proposals, sending initial SMS,

                       sending followed-up email proposals, making posters and captions for Facebook page,

                       and  attending  meetings.  Throughout  the  training  period,  the  trainee  continued  to

                       perform her daily tasks.

                              With the guidance and support of the management and teammates, she was

                       able to gain industry knowledge from the experts and expand her abilities in a relevant


                       office job. She also learned to cherish closeness and interaction with her co-trainees

                       and superiors.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Appendix 14. Photo documentation                                                 72































                                        Appendix figure 2. The trainee while adding leads.

































                         Appendix figure 3. The trainee while sending email via company or client's portal.]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[73































                            Appendix figure 4. The trainee while sending SMS via the company portal.
































                        Appendix figure 5. The trainee while sending email to follow up via the company or
                                                         client's portal.]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[74
































                        Appendix figure 6. The trainee while sending SMS follow-up via the company portal































                                 Appendix figure 7. The trainee while making a Facebook poster.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[14


                                                THE TRAINING EXPERIENCES



                                This consists of the trainee's tasks, observations, and insights of work-from-

                       home on-the-job training.


                       Task Performed

                              During  the  600  hours  of  on-the-job  training  ROC.PH  /Digital  Marketing

                       Services, the trainee was able to perform the following assignments:

                              Sending  email  proposal  to  the  prospective  client. The  trainee  sends  an

                       email proposal to the client, which offers the ROC.PH services.























                         Figure 5. The trainee follows up on her leads through email while sending email
                                                           proposals



                              Adding new leads using Bitrix. The trainee was putting new leads to Bitrix

                       so she could send proposals to clients.]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[15






















                                          Figure 6. The trainee while adding new leads



                              Assisting inters payment. The trainee inputted the interns' payment

                       information and copied and pasted the order number.

























                                         Figure 7. The trainee while assisting interns’ payment]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[16


                       Observed Strength of the Training Area

                                  The trainee observed that the management and staff treated each intern with

                       care. Every week the intern had to fill out a weekly form regarding their stress factors,

                       which an intern completed, and they had to do clinic wellness every Friday, provided


                       by the clinic department. They were able to keep the intern entertained while offering

                       support and guidance. The trainee noticed open internal communication, which made

                       them feel more at ease.

                       Problems Encountered

                                  During the training time, the trainee encountered some difficulties with the time


                       allocated to complete the task. There are times when technical difficulties prevent the

                       intern from completing her job.

                              The trainee suggested that management have enough quota so that sending

                       email  proposals  to  clients  through  Bitrix  (company  portal)  is  not  difficult,  and  the

                       process is efficient and reliable.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[17


                                                          SUMMARY



                              Internships  provide  a  wealth  of  early  career  opportunities  and  experiences.

                       Working as an intern allows you to put what you've learned into practice in a real-world


                       or virtual setting.

                              The training at ROC.PH Digital Marketing Services started officially when the

                       trainee was enrolled in the program. The University approved to convert her working

                       hours into on-the-job training hours as the trainee was already part of the company as

                       a sales member since March 1, 2022. Her task is to find prospecting clients and input


                       the leads in Bitrix (company portal) to send email proposals. Throughout the training,

                       the trainee continued to perform her daily tasks, such as adding new leads, sending

                       proposals, and sending follow-up emails to prospective clients. Before her exit day,

                       she was tasked with deducting compliance and assisting interns’ payments.

                              She gained knowledge and developed her skills by performing this virtually with

                       the help of her general manager, office staff, and her team. Even though she was

                       apprehensive  about  the  internship  mainly  because  it  was  virtual,  experiencing  this


                       opportunity has been integral for the intern to identify what future career she will take

                       through the experience in the workplace.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Appendix 14. Photo documentation                                                 56




















                                     Appendix figure 1. The trainee while attending a meeting
























                                     Appendix figure 2. The trainee while attending a briefing]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[57
























                               Appendix figure 3. The trainee while attending a startup conference























                                  Appendix figure 4. The trainee while adding leads using Bitrix]]></page></pages></Search>