<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="21"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.6.            The system of student evaluation and


                        grading is defined, understood and


                        disseminated to:

                        I.6.1.  students;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



                         PARENTS’ AND STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION AND
                                        RE-ORIENTATION PROGRAM 2022
                                                 September 16, 2022



                         The  Cavite  State  University-Tanza  Campus  conducted  the  virtual
               parents and student orientation and re-orientation last September 12, 2022,
               1:00pm-4:00pm via FB live. The implementing guidelines on the limited face-
               to-face  classes,  academic  policies  and  grading  system,  student  code  of
               conduct  and  other  student  services,  learning  delivery  modes,  orientation
               about  the  Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  of  the  University,  and
               orientation on the library system are some of the topics discussed during the
               program.

























                             Activity banner posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook page]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph






















                          Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro, Vice President for Academic Affairs, giving her
                                             welcome remarks to the participants
























                                           Introduction to the Campus’ key officials and support personnel]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                            Introduction to the faculty members of the Teacher Education Department
























                            Introduction to the faculty members of the Department of Management]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                                     The University academic calendar for S.Y 2022-2023, presented by the
                                                    Campus Registrar, Ms. Noemi A. Perida
























                              Discussion on the academic policies and grading system of the University]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph























                   Discussion on the student programs and service provided by the Office of Student
                         Affairs and Services, presented by Ms. Melona I. Saquin, OSAS Head




































                                        Discussion on the student code of conduct]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
























                Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and Children Act, Anti-
                  bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on Drug Abuse and Drug
                  Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442 vilification against Person with
                                                          Disability





























                 Presentation on the CvSU Learning Management System (LMS) and flexible learning delivery
                                modes, presented by the MIS officer, Ms. Charmaine T. Banag]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

























                         Library orientation presented by the Campus’ Librian, Ms. Roselyn C. Baltar
























                               Mr. Gerard Advincula, program host, facilitating the open forum]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



               Prepared by:                                                     Certified Correct:


               FATIMA M. DIAZ                                                   MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Facilitator, ISPS                                                Head, OSAS
               Date prepared: September 19, 2022


                                                                                Noted:


                                                                                GIL D. RAMOS
                                                                                Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                            PARENTS’ AND STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION AND

                                          RE-ORIENTATION PROGRAM 2021
                                                   September 10, 2021




                       The  academic  year  2021-2022  was  the  second  year  of  the
               implementation of flexible learning in universities and colleges. Cavite State
               University-Tanza Campus conducted the virtual parents and student virtual
               orientation  and  re-orientation  on  September  10,  2021  via  FB  live.  The

               academic policies and grading system, student code of conduct, Netiquette
               during flexible learning, learning delivery modes and orientation about the
               Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  of  the  University,  are  some  of  the
               topics discussed during the program.
























                             Activity banner posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook page


                       Registration announcement posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook Page]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

























                        The Vice President for Academic Affairs, Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro, giving her
                                             welcome remarks to the participants






















                          Prof. Gil D. Ramos, Campus Administrator, giving his inspiration message]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                                 to the students and parents.























                                Introduction to the Campus key officials and support personnel
























                   Discussion on the academic policies and grading system of the University, presented by the]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



































                                                    Campus Registrar, Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                  Discussion on the scholarships and student financial assistance program, presented by the
                                             OSAS Head, Ms. Melona I. Saquin]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                  Discussion on the netiquette during flexible learning, presented by Mr. Mark Joel C.
                                      Sibulo, the guidance facilitator of the Campus
























                Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and Children Act, Anti-
                  bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on Drug Abuse and Drug
                  Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442 vilification against Person with
                                                          Disability]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                 Orientation on the CvSU Learning Management System (LMS), presented by the MIS officer,
                                                  Ms. Charmaine T. Banag

































                               Prof. Gil D. Ramos and other participants during the open forum





               Prepared by:                                                     Certified Correct:


               JOYCE ERIKA S. SENARIS                                           MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Facilitator, ISPS                                                Head, OSAS
               Date prepared: September 16, 2021

                                                                                Noted:


                                                                                GIL D. RAMOS
                                                                                Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                     T3 STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION 2020
                                                  September 21, 2020

               Cavite State University – T3 Campuses held the Students’ Virtual Orientation on September
        21, 2020 thru Facebook live stream. The program started with the AVP of the T3 campuses, CvSU

        Tanza, Gen. Trias City, and Trece Martires City Campuses facilities and its development through
        the  years. It was followed  by the  introduction  of T3 key  officials, support  personnel, faculty per

        department and students class adviser per program.
               Meanwhile,  Ms.  Mary  Ann  L.  Anonas,  T3  Campus  Registrar,  discussed  the  academic

        policies  and  grading  system  followed  by  the  discussion  of  different  scholarship  offered  in  the

        University and other external agencies.
               Furthermore, Ms. Loran Camille Villarante oriented the students about the CvSU e-Library

        System Open Education Resources and Creative Commons.
               In addition, an open forum was conducted to answer the questions of the students and to

        enlighten them about the “new normal” academic set-up of T3 Campuses. During the open forum,
        various questions were raised by the students and were answered by Prof. Noel A. Sedigo, T3

        Campus Administrator, and other key officials.

               The virtual orientation ended with the closing statement of Prof. Sedigo with his emphasis
        that despite the pandemic, T3 Campuses will continue serving and providing quality education and

        ensuring that no students will be left behind.





        Prepared by:                                                             Certified Correct:


        JOYCE ERIKA S. SENARIS                                                   MELONA I. SAQUIN

        Facilitator, ISPS                                                        OSAS Head

        Date pr  epared: September 25, 2020



                                                                                Noted:

                                                                                NOEL A. SEDIGO
                                                                                Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>