<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="34"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.6.            The system of student evaluation and


                        grading is defined, understood and


                        disseminated to:

                        I.6.1.  students;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[A.Y. 2022 - 2023

                  Students' Virtual Orientation and



                                           Re-orientation]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


               02 September 2021


               DR. HERNANDO D. ROBLES
               President                                                            A-210907-2363
               This University                                                      ED
                                                                                    09-07-2021

               Dear Sir:

               The Cavite State University-Tanza will hold its Parents and Students Virtual Orientation and
               Re-orientation Program on September 10, 2021. This aims to inform parents and students
               about  academic  policies  and  grading  system,  student  code  of  conduct,  Netiquette  during
               flexible learning, learning delivery modes and orientation about the Learning Management
               System (LMS) of the University. This activity will be conducted via Cisco Webex and thru FB
               live.

               In this regard, we would like to seek your approval to allow us to conduct the said activity.
               Attached is the activity proposal for your reference.

               Thank you very much for your usual support.

               Respectfully yours,



               MELONA I. SAQUIN
               Head, OSAS


               Recommending Approval:


               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Dean, OSAS



               MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Vice President for Academic Affairs




                                                        Approved:


                                         HERNANDO D. ROBLES, EdD, CEO VI
                                               for:  University President


             O - 2067
             ED
             09-09-2021]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



               Title:              Parents and Students Virtual Orientation and Re-orientation Program 2021

               Proponent:    Cavite State University-Tanza Campus, Office of Student Affairs and Services

               Target Participants:   Parents and students of CvSU-Tanza


               Rationale:

                       This coming semester marks the second year of the implementation of flexible learning

               in universities and colleges. In this regard, the Cavite State University-Tanza Campus will

               conduct a virtual parents and student virtual orientation and re-orientation on September 10,

               2021. The academic policies and grading system, student code of conduct, Netiquette during

               flexible learning, learning delivery modes and orientation about the Learning Management


               System  (LMS)  of  the  University,  are  some  of  the  topics  that  will  be  discussed during  the

               program.

               Objectives:

                   1.  To formally introduce the key officials, old and new faculty members and employees;

                   2.  inform the parents and students about the calendar of activities for school year 2021-

                       2022;


                   3.  discuss the academic policies and grading system;

                   4.  conduct orientation about the Student Code of Conduct;

                   5.  present video presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and

                       Children Act, Anti-bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on

                       Drug Abuse and Drug Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442

                       vilification against Person with Disability;

                   6.  conduct orientation about Netiquette during flexible learning; and


                   7.  discuss the Learning Delivery Modes and Learning Management System (LMS) of the

                       University.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


               Implementation:


                   1.  All students must register by filling out the Google Form before the day of the activity.

                       Parents are also encourage to register.

                   2.  Campus key officials are required to join the virtual meeting room during the orientation

                       program.

                   3.  Cisco Webex Meet will be used as the platform for the orientation and the program will


                       be aired through FB Live.

                   4.  An activity evaluation form through Google Form will be sent to the participants after

                       the orientation program.

               Participants:

                       The participants of the proposed activity are students, parents and faculty members.



               Working Committee:


                Activity In-charge                            Melona I. Saquin
                                                              Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                                              Mildred A. Sebastian
                Program Lay-out and Posting                   Gerry Mae T. Silvero
                                                              Mary Joy Angelique R. Mojica
                Technical Requirements                        Joseph O. Sabaybay
                                                              Jeffrey M. Delgado
                Screening of Questions                        Debbie Rose T. Banag
                                                              JR Apellanes
                                                              Maria Kristina Galicha
                Registration/Evaluation                       Jed de Silva
                                                              Rein Ortigosa
                                                              Jessica Avon Quezada
                Certificates                                  Joyce Erika S. Senaris
                                                              Charles Pitagan
                Documentation                                 Ivory Mojica
                                                              Erwin Regio
                                                              John Daniel V. Cap-atan]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                     Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
               Programme:

                     “Parents and Students Virtual Orientation and Re-orientation Program 2021”
                                          September 10, 2021 (1:00-5:00 P.M)


                1:00 -1:05 P.M     Prayer                                     Mr. Crisostomo Sibulo
                                                                              Faculty, DAS

                1:06 -1:10 P.M     National Anthem                            AVP

                1:11 -1:15 P.M     CvSU-Tanza at a Glance                     AVP

                1:16-1:20 P.M      Introduction of Campus Key Officials and   AVP
                                   Faculty Members
                1:21 -1:35 P.M     Inspirational Message                      Prof. Gil D. Ramos
                                                                              Campus Administrator
                                   Presentation of Students per Program
                  1:36 -2:15 P.M  and their Registration Advisers and         Ms. Noemi A. Perida
                                   Academic Policies and Grading System       Campus Registrar

                  2:16 -2:40 P.M  Scholarships and Student Financial          Ms. Melona I. Saquin
                                   Assistance                                 Head, OSAS/ Scholarship
                                                                              Coordinator
                  2:41 -3:30 P.M  Student Code of Conduct and Netiquette      Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                   during Flexible Learning                   Department
                                                                              Chairperson/Guidance and
                                                                              Counselling
                  3:31 -3:50 P.M  Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the
                                   Anti-violence   Against   Women      and
                                   Children Act, Anti-bullying Act, R.A 7877 or
                                   Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on  AVP
                                   Drug  Abuse  and  Drug  Prevention  and
                                   Control,  HIV  Aids  Awareness  and  R.A
                                   9442  vilification  against  Person  with
                                   Disability;

                  3:51 -4:30 P.M  Flexible  Learning  Delivery  Modes  and  Ms. Charmaine T. Banag
                                   CvSU  Learning  Management  System  MIS Officer
                                   (LMS)
                  4:31-4:55 P.M    Open Forum                                 ---

                  4:56-5:00 P.M    Closing Remarks                            Prof. Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                                              Instruction and Curriculum
                                                                              Development
                                                                              Coordinator/Department
                                                                              Chairperson, TED

                                          CvSU Hymn                           AVP


                                          Mr. Audreyson H. Borilla
                                            Master of Ceremonies]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph



                          PARENTS’ AND STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION
                                   AND RE-ORIENTATION PROGRAM 2022
                                               September 16, 2022



                         The  Cavite  State  University-Tanza  Campus  conducted  the
               virtual parents and student orientation and re-orientation last September
               12, 2022, 1:00pm-4:00pm via FB live. The implementing guidelines on the
               limited  face- to-face  classes,  academic  policies  and  grading  system,
               student  code  of  conduct  and  other  student  services,  learning  delivery
               modes,  orientation  about  the  Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  of
               the  University,  and orientation  on  the  library  system  are  some  of  the

               topics discussed during the program.
































                           Activity banner posted in the CvSU-Tanza  Campus’ Facebook page



                                      You may watch here the CvSU Tanza
                                     Campus Parent’s and Student’s Virtual
                                       Orientation and Re-orientation 2022]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph





























                          Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro, Vice President for Academic Affairs, giving
                                             her welcome remarks to the participants


































                                     Introduction to the Campus’ key officials and support personnel]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

































                           Introduction to the faculty members of the Teacher Education Department

































                            Introduction to the faculty members of the Department of Management]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
































                                The University academic calendar for S.Y 2022-2023, presented by
                                               the Campus Registrar, Ms. Noemi A. Perida

































                          Discussion on the academic policies and grading system of the University]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
































                 Discussion on the student programs and service provided by the Office of Student
                       Affairs and Services, presented by Ms. Melona I. Saquin, OSAS Head



































                                      Discussion on the student code of conduct]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


































                 Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and Children Act,
                 Anti- bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on Drug Abuse and
                Drug Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442 vilification against Person
                                                      with Disability
































                   Presentation on the CvSU Learning Management System (LMS) and flexible learning
                          delivery modes, presented by the MIS officer, Ms. Charmaine T. Banag]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


































                           Library orientation presented by the Campus’ Librian, Ms. Roselyn C.
                                                          Baltar


































                              Mr. Gerard Advincula, program host, facilitating the open forum]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[A.Y. 2021 - 2022

                  Students' Virtual Orientation and



                                           Re-orientation]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

                              PARENTS’ AND STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION

                                      AND RE-ORIENTATION PROGRAM 2021
                                                 September 10, 2021


                       The  academic  year  2021-2022  was  the  second  year  of  the
               implementation  of  flexible  learning  in  universities  and  colleges.  Cavite
               State  University-Tanza  Campus  conducted  the  virtual  parents  and
               student virtual orientation and re-orientation on September 10, 2021 via

               FB  live.  The academic  policies  and  grading  system,  student  code  of
               conduct, Netiquette during flexible learning, learning delivery modes and
               orientation  about  the  Learning  Management  System  (LMS)  of  the
               University, are some of the topics discussed during the program.




















                             Activity banner posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook page


                       Registration announcement posted in the CvSU-Tanza Campus’ Facebook Page


                                    You may watch here the CvSU Tanza
                                   Campus Parent’s and Student’s Virtual

                                     Orientation and Re-orientation 2021]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

































                        The Vice President for Academic Affairs, Dr. Ma. Agnes P. Nuestro, giving
                                         her welcome remarks to the participants

































                             Prof. Gil D. Ramos, Campus Administrator, giving his inspiration
                                          message to the students and parents.]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
































                                   Introduction to the Campus key officials and support
                                                        personnel

































                  Discussion on the academic policies and grading system of the University, presented by
                  the
                                               Campus Registrar, Ms. Noemi A. Perida]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph

































                 Discussion on the scholarships and student financial assistance program, presented by the
                                            OSAS Head, Ms. Melona I. Saquin

































                 Discussion on the netiquette during flexible learning, presented by Mr. Mark Joel C.
                                    Sibulo, the guidance facilitator of the Campus]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph
































                 Video Presentation about R.A 9262 or the Anti-violence Against Women and Children Act,
                 Anti- bullying Act, R.A 7877 or Anti-sexual Harassment Act, Guideline on Drug Abuse and
                Drug Prevention and Control, HIV Aids Awareness and R.A 9442 vilification against Person
                                                      with Disability






























                   Orientation on the CvSU Learning Management System (LMS), presented by the MIS
                                             officer, Ms. Charmaine T. Banag]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                       Tanza Campus
                                        Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                       (046) 414-3979
                                                     www.cvsu.edu.ph


































                              Prof. Gil D. Ramos and other participants during the open forum

































                                  Ms. Joyce Erika S. Senaris giving her closing remarks]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[A.Y. 2020 - 2021

                  Students' Virtual Orientation and



                                           Re-orientation]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                         CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          235-7997 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                   www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                      T3 STUDENTS’ VIRTUAL ORIENTATION 2020
                                                   September 21, 2020

                       Cavite State University – T3 Campuses held the Students’ Virtual Orientation

               on September 21, 2020 thru Facebook live stream. The program started with the AVP
               of the T3 campuses, CvSU Tanza, Gen. Trias City, and Trece Martires City Campuses

               facilities and its development through the years. It was followed by the introduction of

               T3 key officials, support personnel, faculty per department and students class adviser
               per program.

                       Meanwhile,  Ms.  Mary  Ann  L.  Anonas,  T3  Campus  Registrar,  discussed  the
               academic  policies  and  grading  system  followed  by  the  discussion  of  different

               scholarship offered in the University and other external agencies.
                       Furthermore,  Ms.  Loran  Camille  Villarante  oriented  the  students  about  the

               CvSU e-Library System Open Education Resources and Creative Commons.

                       In  addition,  an  open  forum  was  conducted  to  answer  the  questions  of  the
               students  and  to  enlighten  them  about  the  “new  normal”  academic  set-up  of  T3

               Campuses. During the open forum, various questions were raised by the students and

               were  answered  by  Prof.  Noel  A.  Sedigo,  T3  Campus  Administrator,  and  other  key
               officials.

                       The virtual orientation ended with the closing statement of Prof. Sedigo with his
               emphasis  that  despite  the  pandemic,  T3  Campuses  will  continue  serving  and

               providing quality education and ensuring that no students will be left behind.


                                      You may watch here the

                                           T3 Students' Virtual
                                                   Orientation]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[21 September 2020
                                                        1:00 PM




        Prayer
        National Anthem

        Introduction of T3 Key Officials and Support Services

        Introduction of Faculty per Department
        Introduction of Students per Program and their          Lilian O. Sidamon (Trece)
        Registration Advisers                                   Shaine C. Hayag (Gen. Trias)
                                                                Mildred A. Sebastian (Tanza)
                                                                Campus Coordinators

        Academic Policies and Grading System                    Mary Ann L. Anonas (Trece)
                                                                Registrar I, T3 Campuses
        Student Norm and Conduct in the New Normal              Lilian O. Sidamon (Trece)
                                                                Office of Student Affairs and Services Head
        Scholarships                                            Melona I. Saquin (Tanza)
                                                                Office of Student Affairs and Services Head

        Orientation to CvSU e-Library System, Open              Lora Camille A. Villarante
        Education Resources and Creative Commons                Librarian I, T3 Campuses

        Open Forum                                              Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                                Mary Ann L. Anonas
                                                                Rogelyn P. Alarca
                                                                Noemi A. Perida
                                                                Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                                Shaine C. Hayag
                                                                Melona I. Saquin
                                                                Lora Camille A. Villarante
        Announcements

        CvSU Hymn



                                             Mr. John Daniel V. Cap-atan
                                               In-Charge of Ceremonies]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines

                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                       414-3979 ǀ  (0977)8033809 ǀ  509-4148
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                     PARENTS AND STUDENTS VIRTUAL ORIENTATION ON THE CvSU T3
                  CAMPUSES IMPLEMENTATION OF FLEXIBLE LEARNING DELIVERY MODE
                                            05 September 2020 at 1:30PM
                                                       via F LIVE

               Rationale
                       On 08 March 2020, through Proclamation No. 922 s, 2020, the country was declared
               in  a  state  of  public  health  emergency  because  of  the  outbreak  of  Corona  Virus  Disease
               (COVID-19).
                       Another Proclamation No. 929 on 16 March 2020 was released declaring a state of
               calamity throughout the Philippines because of COVID-19 pandemic.
                       With  these  and  the  Inter-agency  Task  Force  for  the  Management  of  Emerging
               Infectious Diseases (IATF) Resolutions, Commission on Higher Education released CHED
               COVID Advisory No. 7, providing guidelines on the HEIs operation and work arrangements.
               The use of flexible learning delivery mode was also provided for guidance.
                       Cavite  State  University  through  the  Academic  Affairs  Unit  continuously  provide
               webinars and trainings to prepare the faculty members with the flexible learning and other
               alternative modes of  delivery  for the  AY  2020-2021.  And  with the  series  of  webinars  and
               trainings, the CvSU T3 Campuses come up with different strategies on how flexible learning
               will be possible.
                       Together with the faculty members, students and parents should also be informed on
               how the flexible learning will be conducted in the First Semester, AY 2020-2021 through an
               orientation.

               Objectives
                       The activity aimed to provide a clearer understanding on how the flexible learning will
               be conducted in the T3 Campuses for the First Semester, AY 2020-2021 and at the same time
               come up with a united desire on how to provide quality education to students despite the
               pandemic.

               Program of Activities
                       The program started at 1:30PM by a prayer followed by the CvSU at a Glance video
               presentation.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[The CvSU Calendar of Activities for AY 2020-2021 was presented by Ms. Vienna Mi
               A. Ferail, T3 Curriculum Development and Instruction Head. She also discussed the CvSU T3
               Campuses Flexible Learning Delivery Modes.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[The  CvSU  eLearning  System  was  discussed  and  presented  by  Ms.  Charmaine  T.
               Banag and Mr. Jeffrey M. Delgado, IT Faculty Members of CvSU Tanza Campus.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Afterwards, Mr. Keno A. Villavicencio and Ms. Pamela Daphne R. Busog, IT Faculty

               Members of CvSU Trece Martires City Campus discussed GSuite for Education.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Then,  the  Open  Forum  proceeds  with  Mr.  Gideon  Luke  P.  Ty  (Admission  Officer-
               Trece),  as the Moderator.  The  panel  are composed  of  Prof.  Noel  A.  Sedigo  (T3  Campus
               Administrator), Ms. Mildred A. Sebastian (Campus Coordinator-Tanza), Ms. Lilian O. Sidamon
               (Campus Coordinator-Trece), Ms. Shaine C. Hayag (Campus Coordinator-Gen. Trias), Ms.
               Vienna  Mi  A.  Feranil  (T3  Curriculum  Development  and  Instruction  Head),  Mr.  Keno  A.
               Villavicencio  (IT  Department  Chairperson-Trece),  Ms.  Pamela  Daphne  R.  Busog  (MIS
               Coordinator-Trece),  Ms.  Charmaine  T.  Banag  (MIS  Coordinator-Tanza),  Mr.  Jeffrey  M.
               Delgado (IT Faculty Member-Tanza), Mr. Mark Joel C. Sibulo (Admission Officer-Tanza), Ms.
               Mary Ann L. Anonas (Registrar-Trece), Ms. Noemi A. Perida (Registrar Aide-Tanza), and Ms.
               Rogelyn P. Alarca (Admin Officer-Gen. Trias) to answer the questions.


































               Question and Answer

               Question (BSP 1-Trece): Do we need books in our subjects?
               Answer (Ms. Feranil): Books are not required, but there are books which are already reviewed,
               evaluated, and approved by the University Textbook Board especially in General Education
               subjects that may be used as references.

               Question (BSP 1-Trece): Do we need to pay any fees?
               Answer (Ms. Feranil): No fees will be collected because of the RA 10931 or the Free Tertiary
               Education.

               Question (Tanza Student): Who will decide on the type of platform to use in learning, whether
               CvSU eLearning o Google classroom, is it the student?
               Answer (Ms. Villavicencio): Faculty members will define the type of platform to use.

               Question  (First  Year-Trece):  What  will  happen  to  those  students  who  are  qualified  for
               admission but did not able to submit original admission requirements?
               Answer  (Ms.  Anonas):  Students  are  temporary  enrolled  unless  original  admission
               requirements are submitted.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Question (Tanza Student): Are you going to provide each student an account to access the
               eLearning System?
               Answer (Ms. Busog): Yes, but we are still waiting for the account from Main Campus.

               Question (BSP 1-Trece): How would be the distribution of modules and submission of activities
               for those who prefer modular mode of learning?
               Answer (Ms. Feranil): There are assigned day for each program, for the pickup of learning
               materials and submission of activities in the campus as stated in the virtual class schedule
               provided.

               Question  (BSBM-Trece):  What  will  happen  if  we  are  taking  online  quiz,  and  there  were
               technical interruptions, is the system capable of saving the status of our quiz?
               Answer (Ms. Banag): Yes, it may be saved. The Instructor will just set the time for the quiz.

               Question (BSIT Parent): Will the University provide the students with a copy of University
               Academic Calendar and the tutorial on how to use the system and take the examinations?
               Answer (Mr. Villavicencio): Yes, calendar will be provided to students through Facebook page
               the same with the tutorial which was presented earlier. Since this orientation is in FB Live,
               students may review or replay the tutorial anytime since this will not be deleted anymore. And
               at the same time, during the first week of class orientation, Instructors will discuss again the
               process of using the learning platform.

               Question (BSHRM-Trece): When will we have our OJT which are scheduled last Midterm?
               Answer (Ms. Sidamon): OJTs are allowed if it is online.

               Question (GenTri Student): I am a working student; can I still attend to online classes?
               Answer (Prof. Sedigo): Yes, you may. Because we discourage synchronous classes.

               Question (Trece Student): Are the learning materials downloadable?
               Answer  (Mr.  Ty):  Yes,  all  learning  materials  once  uploaded  to  the  platform  are  ready  for
               download anytime as long as you have your device.

               Question (First Year Student): Are we required to attend online class in uniform? Do we need
               to buy one?
               Answer (Ms. Feranil): No, just wear appropriate outfit that is appealing to the class.

               Question (Gen. Trias Student): How sure that the answers to online exams taken by students
               are authentic, since they could search the net while taking the exam?
               Answer (Mr. Villavicencio): College set up is different from high school or senior high school.
               Examinations are skill based and not knowledge based only. Questions can be reshuffled,
               have timer and other strategies, your instructors may set it.

               Question: Which is the best mode of learning?
               Answer (Prof. Sedigo): Modular mode of learning are very risky for everyone. Since, there are
               limited transportation and at the same time there is increasing number of COVID cases in the
               area. But if you really prefer the modular type, modules will be available in a designated area
               in the campus entrance where you can get your modules. But if you want it to be delivered to
               your doorsteps, yes, it is possible, but you will shoulder the cost of shipping. But we cannot
               give  you  the  whole  semester  module  because  that  is  so  many  pages.  That  is  why  we
               discourage the modular type of learning. Unlike online, materials will be uploaded to the LMS
               or Google classroom or could be send to you through fb messenger, chat groups, email or
               even text messages. Synchronous classes are discouraged, so meaning, if you will have the
               online, it is not necessary that you spend load for the data daily for zoom classes, no. We will
               have  the  asynchronous  type  of  teaching  and  learning.  Because  our  motto  is  NO  ONE
               SHOULD BE LEFT BEHIND.
               Online is more advantageous, cheaper, or safer rather than modular.
               Another thing, we should also invest on this. Especially IT students, not only connectivity but
               also having a laptop is necessary in your program.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Question (BSE Student): Do we have the qualifying examination schedule? If ever, will it be
               online?
               Answer (Mr. Ty): There are previous announcements that it will be scheduled in latter part.
               Answer (Prof. Sedigo): The qualifying exam is still face to face and is probably scheduled in
               January 2021.

               Question: Do we need to pay for the printing of modules?
               Answer (Mr. Ty): No payment. It is free for students because CHED paid for their tuition and
               school fees.

               Question (Gen. Trias Student): How about the academic scholars?
               Answer (Ms. Sidamon): Only Tulong Dulong and TES are active scholarship grant for this
               semester.

               Question (BSE Student): If we have 3-hour virtual class schedule, do we need to attend 3
               hours virtual class also?
               Answer (Ms. Feranil): No, we prepared the virtual class schedule for you to be aware of the
               available schedule for the teacher for consultation and possible queries or clarifications on the
               lesson. This flexible learning is a self-paced learning, so you can do the readings or studying
               in  your  convenient  time  not  necessarily  during  the  virtual  class  schedule.  In  addition,
               attendance is not part of the grading system for this semester.
               Answer  (Prof.  Sedigo):  In  addition,  during  virtual  class  schedule,  that  is  the  time  that  the
               teacher will post the lessons and made himself available to students’ consultations.

               Question (Parent): I am an OFW parent, can I monitor my child’s performance in the online
               learning platform?
               Answer (Ms. Busog): Yes, if the student will allow their parents to access his/her account,
               he/she will give the username and password of the student.

               Question (New Student): How can we meet our teachers? Are we going to look or contact
               them, or they are the one who will contact us?
               Answer  (Ms.  Feranil):  Each  section  has  assigned  Registration  Adviser.  They  are  the  one
               tasked to look for the students and create a group for the class. Then later, all subject teachers
               will be added to the group, so that there will be only one group for each class to elicit confusion
               on the part of the student on how to communicate and whom.

               Question  (Irregular  Student):  How  about  if  virtual  class  schedule  is  conflict  with  my  back
               subjects, do I need to drop the subject?
               Answer (Ms. Anonas): No, flexible learning is self-paced and can do the learning even not
               during the virtual class schedule.

               Question: How will the lesson be delivered? Is the lesson/module will be provided for the whole
               semester one at a time?
               Answer (Prof. Sedigo): Preparing a module is not the easy but almost all faculty have their
               modules for one month or until Midterm except for some that they really have prepared the
               whole module for one semester. So module delivery, is by lesson or chapter, so that you will
               not be overwhelmed by the lessons and the activities.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Program of Activities]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Evaluation Results

                            CRITERIA                   PARENTS           STUDENTS           OVERALL
                Meeting your expectation                  4.62               4.18              4.19
                Attainment of the objectives              4.54               4.32              4.33
                Topics discussed                          4.69               4.47              4.47
                Input presentation                        4.69               4.17              4.18
                Management team / Secretariat             4.62               4.29              4.30
                Virtual arrangement                       4.38               4.15              4.16
                Over-all assessment                       4.69               4.38              4.39
                          Overall Rating                  4.60               4.28              4.29

               Comments:
               1.  Every instructor is well-prepared to answer the questions. Even though comments' section was
                   getting "flooded" by questions, they managed to answer almost all of them on time with also the
                   help of Professor Noel.
               2.  Maayos naman yung naging virtual orientation at malinaw lahat ..
               3.  Nasagot naman po lahat ng tanong ko about sa new normal class maayos din po na naipahayag
                   ang bawat detalye.
               4.  Maganda naman po yung presentation about sa ibat ibang modes of learning. naipakita rin po ang
                   mga applications maaaring gamitin ng mga estudyante at naituro rin kung paano ito gamitin. naging
                   malinaw naman ang orientation para sa lahat at nasagot din ang mga katanungan ng mga parents
                   at students.
               5.  Wala pong sound at some point. un lang hehe
               6.  Very informative
               7.  Na deliver naman nila ng ayos ang online orientation suggestion kolang mag bigay sila ng warnings
                   sa mga students na nag comment lang ng hindi maganda para bang nag papansin lang or make it
                   private para hindi masali ang mga students na gusto lang mang bastos
               8.  Over-all po, okay naman po ang orientation na naganap. Maayos pong sinagot nang mga faculty
                   members ang mga katanungan namin at nalinawan po ako. Laking tulong po sa amin ang ganitong
                   orientation dahil natulungan po kaming mga estudyante at ang mga magulang na maintindihan ang
                   bagong sistema ng pag-aaral ngayong panahon ng pandemya.
               9.  Ok naman po yung presentation and marami po ako facts na nalaman regarding sa online class
                   and yung delivery po nung presentation maganda
               10. It went well although there's some problem but it was fixed quickly.
               11. naway sa susunod po ee medyo maayos yung live kasi nawalawala po kasi ee
               12. Ang galing po ng graphic organiser o yung nagmamanage po ng graphics, tapos malinaw rin pong
                   naipaliwanag ng maayos yung mga topic na kailangang malaman ng mga istudyante at magulang.
                   Salamat po
               13. Napaka maintindihin ng mga teachers. Thankyou.
               14. Very creative
               15. Overall the virtual presentation was good well explained but there's some technical problems.
               16. For me it was good, and because of this virtual orientation I realized that Online learning is not so
                   hard :) . God bless!
               17. The virtual presentation and orientation itself was very satisfactory, necessary information were
                   properly explained and elaborated as well.
               18. All of the speakers are good, but there's some interruptions when it comes on presentation.
               19. I'm so  grateful to have the people who  were trying their  best  to create  the education  be  more
                   effective. As a student, I'll pray for the faculty member of Cavsu. God Bless us.
               20. Ok  naman  maayos  at  magandang  nasagot  lahat  ng  tanong  ng  parents  at  ng  student  napaka
                   approachable po ng mga teachers.
               21. Not properly set the audio
               22. Thank  you  po  na  kahit  medyo  may  technical  problems  eh  nagawan  pa  din  po  ng  paraan  na
                   maipaliwanag  ng  maayos  ang  dapat  malaman  naming  mga  estudyante..  Good  job  po!  
                   Godbless..❤
               23. Well appreciated yung effort ng lahat ng bumuo at speaker ng virtual orientation.
               24. Good job! I gather all of the information a to make a decision, which benefits for me in incoming
                   new normal class.
               25. Napaka ganda ng mga sinabi ni Dean    at mga plano nya sarap sa pakinggan ❤]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Working Committee
                 Activity in Charge                           Vienna Mi A. Feranil
                 Program Layout and Posting                   Gideon Luke P. Ty
                                                              Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                              Shaine C. Hayag
                                                              Melona I. Saquin
                 Technical Requirements                       Keno A. Villavicencio
                                                              Jeffrey M. Delgado
                                                              Mikael Florenz P. Nuestro
                 Registration/ Attendance and Evaluation      Jeffrey M. Delgado
                                                              Pamela Daphne R. Busog
                                                              Diolito C. Gregorio Jr.
                 Screening of Questions                       Joyce Erika S. Senaris
                                                              Christian P. Langit
                                                              Diolito C. Gregorio Jr.
                 Panel Members                                Prof. Noel A. Sedigo
                                                              Vienna Mi A. Feranil
                                                              Lilian O. Sidamon
                                                              Shaine C. Hayag
                                                              Mildred A. Sebastian
                                                              Keno A. Villavicencio
                                                              Pamela Daphne R. Busog
                                                              Charmaine T. Banag
                                                              Jeffrey M. Delgado
                                                              Gideon Luke P. Ty
                                                              Mark Joel C. Sibulo
                                                              Mary Ann L. Anonas
                                                              Noemi A. Perida
                                                              Rogelyn P. Alarca
                 Documentation in Charge                      Vienna Mi A. Feranil
                 In Charge of Ceremonies                      Aljevin A. Comiso
                 Overall in Charge                            Prof. Noel A. Sedigo


               Prepared by:

               VIENNA MI A. FERANIL
               Assistant Professor III



               Noted:


               NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSc
               Campus Administrator]]></page></pages></Search>