<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="126"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.7.            Independent work and performance are


                        encouraged and monitored in the


                        following:

                        I.7.3.  practice teaching;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[CvSU-DepEd Division of Cavite


                          Field Studies and Student Teaching


                                       Internship Program]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Student Internship Endorsement Letters]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Pre-service Teachers during their

                                      Student Internship]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics student-teachers during their class.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English student-teachers during their class.]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Sample of Practice Teaching Portfolio]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[STUDENT TEACHING EXPERIENCES AT TRECE MARTIRES CITY NATIONAL
                              HIGH SCHOOL – SAN AGUSTIN, TRECE MARTIRES CITY, CAVITE













                                                   Student Teaching Portfolio
                                                 Submitted to the Faculty of the
                                                 Teacher Education Department
                                            Cavite State University – Tanza Campus
                                                         Tanza, Cavite














                                                       In partial fulfillment
                                                of the requirements for the degree
                                                Bachelor of Secondary Education
                                                        (major in English)















                                                CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS
                                                         January 2022]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[1


                                                      Republic of the Philippines
                                               CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                            Tanza Campus
                                             Ph. 2, Bahay Katuparan, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                             (046) 414 – 3979
                                                           www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                Teacher Education Department (TED)


                              Autho           :         CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS
                       r

                              Title           :           STUDENT TEACHING EXPERIENCES AT
                                                 TRECE MARTIRES CITY NATIONAL HIGHSCHOOL-
                                                                        CAVITE




                                                           A P P R O V E D:





                      MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN              06/06/22  ESTELITA A. VILLA                   06/07/22
                      Student Teaching Adviser            Date     Student Teaching Coordinator         Date





                      MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN              06/07/22  GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto               06/09/22
                      Department Chair                    Date     Campus Administrator                 Date


































                                                               ii]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[BIOGRAPHICAL DATA




                              I am Christine Jewel R. Gallos. I was born in Dasmarinas, Cavite, on December

                       22, 1995. I reside at Block 24 Lot 12 Alaska St. Sampaguita Village, Brgy. Inocencio,

                       Trece Martires City, Cavite. I am the eldest daughter of Aida R. Gallos and Richard S.

                       Gallos and the eldest sibling of Regine Faith R. Gallos and Rin-Bee R. Gallos.

                              I finished my grade school at Bagong Pook Elementary School in 2007 with a

                       special  award.  I  finished  high  school  at  Amore  International  School  in  2012  with


                       honorable mention and a leadership award. Aside from that, I am also a member of

                       our school ‘s drum and lyre band, and I served as the President of our Theatro de

                       Amore Organization for one year. I am one of the three representatives in our school

                       who became part of the Little Sangguniang Kabataan Trece Martires City Officials in

                       2012. I became the Little City Health Officer, and my school appreciation gave me the


                       opportunity to become one of the best leaders on our campus. They gave me my first

                       leadership award in 2012.

                              I am currently enrolled at Cavite State University-Tanza Campus, taking up a

                       Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English. I chose this program because of

                       my experiences engaging in teaching street children and being part of an outreach

                       program for adults who teach how to read and write. This is the greatest gift I can give

                       to the world. I’ve created an official organization in the Philippines, which is named


                       HATAG ESKWELA, and I have been awarded as a Young Educator Awardee in the

                       year  2019-2020.  Also,  I  have  been  awarded  as  the  Most  Outstanding  Youth

                       Community Ambassador from 2018 to 2021 by the Sampaguita Asiatic Youth United

                       Organization in Trece Martires City. Ms. Mary Rose Morana and I was awarded as the

                       Outstanding Volunteer of the Year 2019-2020 at The Liwayway Marketing Corporation


                       for the Outreach Program Project: Adult Literacy Program.






                                                            iii]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[LETTER TO THE READERS




                       Dear Readers,

                              This portfolio is a summary of my entire practice teaching experience at Trece

                       Martires City National High School.

                              This portfolio would not be possible without the help of my cooperating teacher,

                       my adviser, my students, TMCNHS, the school principal, English Department Head

                       Teacher, and Master Teacher. I will always be forever grateful for the opportunity and


                       help they offer to all student teachers.

                              With  this  portfolio,  you  will  be  able  to  see  all  my  insights,  my  over-all

                       realizations, problems that I have encountered, and their solutions. You will be able to

                       see  the  things  that  I  have  prepared,  from  my  observation,  discussion,  and  pre-

                       demonstration to my final demonstration. You will see my experiences that helped me


                       improve as a future educator. Also, with this, you can know the experience that I had

                       with my students, cooperating teacher, and cooperating school. Aside from those, you

                       will also see here the materials I used and some necessary documents that helped me

                       fulfill my days as an intern.

                              I  hope  that  with  this  portfolio,  you  will  see  how  pleasing,  beautiful,  and

                       sensational it is to become a future educator. I hope this portfolio will light your heart’s

                       and help you to love our profession. It will also give future educators the chance to love


                       their careers, discover themselves, love their unique styles of learning, and become

                       an encourager to others.



                                                                                                     CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS
                                                                                     Student Teacher












                                                             iv]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[ACKNOWLEDGMENT




                              I would like to extend my warmest and deepest gratitude and appreciation to

                       the following people behind the success of this Student Teaching program.

                              To our Almighty God, who never tires of providing me faith, patience, wisdom

                       and  strength  on  a  daily  basis  so  that  I  can  teach  and  share  information  with  my

                       students;

                              To my Family, who have been very supportive to me since day one and serves


                       as my inspiration for everything that I do;

                              To  my  best  friend  and  boyfriend,  Mr.  Bryan  Lee  Dacoy,  who  has  always

                       believed in me and has always supported me;

                              To our advisers, Miss Estelita Villa and Miss Mildred Sebastian, who always

                       guides us in this memorable and journey;


                              To my college buddies, BSEE 4-1, especially my very close friends Ms. Mary

                       Rose Morana, John Mark Mirambel, Mark Jhon Gadores, and Ms. Geraldine Quines,

                       who are my encouragers, supporters, and constant reminders that I can always do

                       better;

                              To my Cooperating teacher, Mrs. Kristina G. Soriano, who is a very who is very

                       patient, kind, generous, motivational, and enthusiastic in teaching and coaching me on

                       how to treat our cherished students, and also to Mrs. Cecilia Ferrer, Mrs. Lourdes


                       Panganiban, Mr. Magdaleno Lubigan, who believed in us and accepted us in their

                       honorable school;

                               To my students, Grade 8 MakaDiyos, Quisumbing, Alcala and Makatao, who

                       are very bright, cheerful, respectful, lovable and helped me to do better, helped me to

                       appreciate my own style of teaching and helped me to love my profession even more.


                              Without them, any of this will not be possible. I am forever grateful to each one

                       of them.

                                                                         CHRISTINE JEWEL R. GALLOS


                                                             v]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENTS




                                                                                                        Page

                       BIOGRAPHICAL DATA.........................................................................................   iii

                       LETTER TO THE READERS……………………………………………………….…                                      iv

                       ACKNOWLEDGMENT…………………………………………..……………………..                                         v

                       TABLE OF CONTENTS…………………………………………….………………….                                       viii

                       LIST OF APPENDICES………………………………………………………………..                                      ix

                       EXPECTATIONS FROM THE STUDENT TEACHING PROGRAM…...……….....                         1

                       REFLECTION ON CLASSROOM OBSERVATION……………………….………..                                 2

                       SELF ASSESSMENT ON READINESS IN ACTUAL TEACHING………………..                            7

                       DAILY JOURNAL……………………………………………………………….……...                                        8

                       COMMON CLASSROOM PROBLEMS………………………………………….…...                                    38

                       FINAL DEMONSTRATION TEACHING………………………………...……………                                  41

                       OVERALL REFLECTION AND SELF APPRAISAL…………………….………….                               46

                       REFERENCES……………..……………………………………………….…...……...                                     51

                       APPENDICES ………………………………………………………….……………….                                         52





























                                                            vi]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[LIST OF APPENDIX FIGURES





                       Appendix                                                                       Page


                        Figure

                           1       The pre-service teacher ………………………………………………..                         75

                           2       The pre-service teacher with his co-practice teachers ……………..        77

                           3       Trece Martires City National High school……………………………..                78

                           4       Christine Jewel Gallos and Ms. Kristina Soriano…………………….             79

                           5       Grade 8 Maka Diyos and Grade 8 Quisumbing………………………                   80

                           6       Grade 8 Alcala and Grade 8 Makatao……. ……………………….                     81


                           7       Jewel during her observation phase……. ………………                         82

                           8       Jewel during her actual teaching  phase…………………….                     83

                           9       Jewel during her final demonstration teaching ……………………...            85

                           10      PowerPoint presentation ………………………………………………                           86

                           11      The instructional materials used during the class discussion ………     86







































                                                             vii]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[LIST OF APPENDICES




                       Appendix                                                                    Page

                           1       Student information sheet ……………………………………….....                    53

                           2       Endorsement letter ………………………………………………….                           55

                           3       Lesson plan for the final demonstration teaching ………………..         56

                           4       Guide questions ……………………………………………….........                       64

                           5       Student teaching rating scale ……………………………………...                   66


                           6       Daily time record …………………………………………………….                           67

                           7       Case study sheet ……………………………………………………                             71

                           8       Clearance from cooperating school ……………………………….                   72

                           9       Form 138a ……………………………………………………….......                            73

                          10       Form 137 ……………………………………………………………..                                74


                          11       School                                                register    75

                                   ……………………………………………………….

                          12       The pre-service teacher …………………………………………….                        76

                          13       The cooperating school ……………………………………………..                        78

                          14       The cooperating teacher …………………………………………....                      79

                          15       The students …………………………………………………………                               80

                          16       The observation phase ……………………………………………..                         82


                          17       The actual teaching phase …………………………………………                        83

                          18       The final demonstration teaching ………………………………….                   85

                          19       The instructional materials ………………………………………….                     86

















                                                            viii]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[1


                                EXPECTATION ON THE STUDENT TEACHING PROGRAM




                          Ms.  Mary  Rose  Morana,  my  research  partner,  and  I  decided  to  complete  our

                   student teaching internship at a public school in Trece Martires City. Before the Virtual

                   Student Teaching Program, I expected that I’d be handling a lot of sections because I

                   decided to choose a public school. I also expect that I’ll experience different problems like

                   poor internet connection, distractions in my environment, loss of electricity, or technical

                   problems all of a sudden.


                          As  for  my  cooperating  teacher,  I  expect  my  CT  will  understand  my

                   situation because, for now, I have found a part-time job and I hope she can give me a lot

                   of patience in doing the tasks that I need to finish. I expect the Head and Master Teacher of

                   the English Department in Trece Martires City to be kind, teach us a lot, and treat us as

                   one of their new teachers, so we will understand the feeling the environment of future


                   teachers  could  have  in  public  school. I  expect my  students to  treat  me with

                   kindness and respect. I also expect them to enjoy and learn a lot from me that can help

                   them  in  real  life  situations.  I  expect  them  to  face  different  problems  in  our

                   virtual classes, and  I  want  them  to  know  that  I am  a very  considerate  person.  I  hope

                   they will love my motivational activities for them and remember our lesson by heart and

                   not  only  in their  minds.  Also,  expect  them  to  have  difficulties learning on this

                   virtual platform, and  I  will  do  my  best  to  help  all  of  them understand  our  lesson  in  a


                   productive and enjoyable way.

                          Aside  from  this,  I  expect  our  cooperating  school  will  provide  a  guide  or  an

                   orientation before we meet our cooperating teachers and our students. I expect them to

                   treat us well and give us experiences that we will cherish after our internship. I expect them

                   to help us understand the ways of public school teachers in teaching both modular and


                   virtual distance learning as our future reference.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[2



                                      REFLECTION ON CLASSROOM OBSERVATION




                          On  October  1st,  2021,  the  cooperating  school  and  the  head  teacher  of  Trece

                   Martires City sent as a meet link to have an orientation before joining the classes of our

                   cooperating teacher on October 4th, 2021, Monday. Ma’am Cecile discusses the things

                   we need to do before handling the classes on our own. Ma’am Cecile told us that we have

                   two weeks to observe our cooperating teacher in preparing their lesson plan. instructional

                   materials and ways they are used in teaching virtual classes. Observation is not that easy


                   as we think, but thankfully in our field study subject last semester we encountered how to

                   observe in a virtual classroom. It gave us knowledge and some experience in observing

                   different classrooms.

                          In my first week observing my cooperating teacher, she prepares a lot and she is

                   very strict with her class. I observe that Ma’am Kristina needs to prepare her lesson plan,


                   instructional materials, and motivational activities ahead of time, which is every Friday.

                   She needs to submit the said outputs for the approval of the master and head teacher of

                   the  English  Department.  They  have  a  DepEd  Module  for  their  guide  or  reference  in

                   teaching different lessons every week. My cooperating teacher is handling four sections in

                   ODL, or Online Distance Learning. Every Monday she meets the Grade 8 MakaDiyos. She

                   meets the Grade 8 Quisumbing every Tuesday, Grade 8 Alcala on Wednesday, and Grade

                   8 Makatao on Thursday. In my first week, I observed that every Monday she was preparing


                   a virtual flag ceremony before starting her Monday class. She always starts her classes

                   with  a  prayer  and  then  checks  the  attendance  of  her  students.  She  also  reminds  the

                   students the proper etiquette in online classes before her discussion starts. The students

                   are well behaved and arrive early.

                           As part of their participation, they must open their camera, and some students


                   have poor connection because I constantly see them joining and leaving the Google meet.

                   My  cooperating  teacher  has  an  intimidating  and  strict  voice  when  she  is  teaching  her

                   classes. I feel nervous when she is asking questions and when she explains her lesson,]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[3


                   even though I’m there for observation only. She always started on time and ended her

                   classes exactly on time. It is hard to have the patience needed in teaching virtual classes

                   of high school students because there are students who can’t afford to attend the classes

                   for a long period of time. My cooperating teacher never failed to remind the students of the


                   tasks that they needed to complete every week.

                          In my second week attending my cooperating teacher classes, I observed that the

                   students in every section are not responsive at all when straight English is used by my CT.

                   They are afraid and hesitant about participating in class. My cooperating teacher uses

                   other  methods  to  help  her  students  still  participate  in  the  discussion.  Ma’am  Kristina


                   sometimes uses Tagalog and gives her students time to speak in Tagalog words, but not

                   all the time. She is also careful in using words because she says that it will stay in the

                   student’s mind if we are not careful in the words that we use in teaching. She also reminded

                   me  that  our  classes  are  English  classes.  As  a teacher,  we  need  to  help  the  students

                   practice their English and use some words that will add to their vocabulary to improve

                   more.  I  also  observe  that  she  is  always  using  events  that  happened  recently  in  her

                   examples.  In  her  discussion,  she  always  takes  a  stop  to  see  if  her  students  are  still


                   listening.  Sometimes  she's  giving  a  warm  up  to  her  students  in  the  middle  of  her

                   discussion. She never smiles in her classes, but when she meets me, her voice is not

                   harsh, but sweet, and she smiles frequently. She says that she was not smiling at her

                   students because she didn’t want her students to treat her as a friend but treat her with

                   respect as their teacher.


                          The  only  application  my  cooperating  teacher  uses  is  Google  Classroom.  She

                   doesn’t use any application when she is giving quizzes or activities to the students. They

                   have a seminar regarding the other applications that can be helpful, but my cooperating

                   teacher is still focusing on what she can share using the things she knows and is easy to

                   use. Some of her uploaded videos in the Google Classroom are from DepEd YouTube

                   videos to support the topic of the students every week. I understand her because she is

                   still learning some of the applications that can be helpful in virtual classes. This is her first]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[4


                   year handling online distance learning and she is still managing to improve her knowledge

                   and skills in creating very productive interactions in her virtual classes. My cooperating

                   teacher used two motivational activities. The first is about the past lesson to evaluate if the

                   student remembers the lesson from last week. The second motivational activity is about


                   the topic that will be discussed for a day. Some of her activities are not in the module

                   because she wants to prepare another set of activities that will be new to the students.

                   Some  of  the  motivational  activities  include  creativity,  imagination,  and  not  only  critical

                   thinking. To get the students' attention, the activities must include physical movement,

                   watching educational videos or be related to some creative arts.


                          The synchronous activities have to be two to four activities. The lesson plan we

                   have submitted must contain a lot of activities. Because the primary goal of the public

                   teacher in Trece Martires City is for students in modular and online distance learning to

                   improve in all areas. The goal is to get the students’ interaction and attention to understand

                   a certain lesson. The motivational activities,  synchronous activities,  and asynchronous

                   activities play a big role in the students’ performance in the whole grade. In synchronous

                   activities, it can be applied not only after the lesson, but it can be added after discussing


                   a simple activity before proceeding to another topic. Synchronous activities are needed

                   because they are part of the grade of the students. If the students fail to attend the classes

                   and submit a synchronous activity, it will be a zero for all but the students who send an

                   excuse letter. The asynchronous activities are the assessment and performance activities

                   of the students. There is also an assignment uploaded in the classroom that needs to be


                   submitted by Friday. Asynchronous activities help us evaluate if the students are having a

                   hard time understanding the lesson.

                           I also observe when my cooperating teacher gives activities. She is very clear

                   regarding the instructions of the activities because the Grade 8 students have a problem

                   understanding the instruction if it is very complicated to understand. It is essential to create

                   simple instructions so that they can respond to the activities without difficulty or confusion.

                   Our  students  are  intelligent,  respectful,  cheerful,  and  well-behaved,  and  I  always]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[5


                   compliment them to my cooperating teacher because they never disrespect me. They try

                   their best to participate in our class discussion. Each section has 45 to 75 students, and

                   while not all of them are answering, they are all doing their best to participate and submit

                   their  work.  Regarding  their  Google  Classroom,  I  observe  that  they  are  using  DepEd


                   accounts and some of the students are still not familiar with how Google Classroom works.

                   My cooperating teacher and I still needed to walk the students through each section of

                   Google  Classroom.  Some  of  the  students  are  turning  in  their  activities  but  with  no

                   attachments. They always ask after our lesson about this problem. Observing how the

                   teachers in public schools teach in virtual classes is a good opportunity, but I feel tired of


                   the large number of outputs that they need to prepare and submit to the Master Teacher,

                   Head Teacher, and Principal.

                           I also observe that my cooperating teacher checks the student’s attendance before

                   starting the class and after the class for their outputs of the student’s participation on this

                   day. The students can’t lie to Ma’am Kristina, so they try their best to always attend to their

                   classes because some activities in synchronous are part of their grading system. Half of

                   the class are good at using English as their medium, and some are still learning. In my


                   sixty days of handling them, I never heard any of them laughing at their classmates when

                   they were not good at speaking English. That’s what I like about them; they are cheerful

                   but can also respect their classmates and their teachers too.

                          Furthermore,  my  cooperating  teacher  still  helps  the  students  with  constructing

                   sentences  if  they  are  having  a  hard  time.  She  is  always  there  for  her  students  and


                   continues  to  guide  them  even  if  they  think  Ma’am  Kristina  is  being  too  strict  in  their

                   perspective. She is always observing her students, and she never shouts or says mean

                   words to her students. She has her own strategy every day to get the attention of her

                   students. She knows her students very well because of the way she prepares her activities

                   and questions. You can see that for her students to learn a lot, this is the kind of activity

                   she should prepare so every student participates. She also helps me to improve my tone

                   of voice in teaching because I have a sweet voice and not an energetic one. She didn’t]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[6


                   say mean words when she was saying her comments to me after handling the classes

                   every day. Ma’am Kristina’s way of teaching is one of the great experiences I have had

                   that I will always cherish. Remember, she is so great at handling her students and I am

                   very  thankful.  Our  cooperating  school  has  a  public  school  teacher  who  is  excellent  at


                   teaching. They all know what they are teaching and inspire me a lot. The teachers are

                   prepared, and they give a lot of attention to their students. But the efforts of teachers are

                   still not enough to address all the problems that students encounter in virtual classes. But,

                   at the very least, I saw how my cooperating teacher was doing everything she could to

                   help the students enrolled in Online Distance Learning learn in the new normal.


                          In  observing  the  junior  high  school  from  day  one  to  day  sixty,  it  is  the  best

                   experience that God gave me because I have been part of the life journey of these students

                   in this short period of time. I reflect every day and bring back the memories from when I

                   was in high school too. They are still too young and there are lots of things they still need

                   to  learn  and  understand.  When  teaching  them  a  new  lesson,  all  the  reminders  of  my

                   cooperating  teacher  came  back  to  me.  I  applied  them  and  obeyed  them  because  the

                   students needed guidance. When I create an assessment and performance task, their


                   outputs make my day happy because of their goals and dreams. I also observe that my

                   students love my motivational quotes before and after my discussion, and I always ask

                   how they are before discussing our lesson. Paying attention and asking them how they

                   are also a sign of love that a student needs, because some of the students can afford to

                   enroll in online distance learning, but there are also students who can’t enroll, and it is sad


                   to see the differences. Some of the students’ parents enroll their children in online distance

                   learning even though they don’t have internet access or a gadget that they will provide just

                   to help their children study in this new normal.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[7


                            SELF-ASSESSMENT ON READINESS IN THE ACTUAL TEACHING




                                 The Virtual Student Teaching Internship Program allows future educators

                   to develop their skills and knowledge that can help them in the future. I have been involved

                   in our community a lot in teaching children how to read and write. Because of this, my skills

                   in discussing a certain lesson or topic improve every day, and it helps me be confident

                   when I am teaching in our community.

                          Aside from being part of an organization for education, I also prepare myself to


                   focus on the things I need to improve, like my English speaking skills. When I am teaching,

                   even if it is a young or old student, when it comes to teaching, my heart and mind are one.

                   Before this program came, I had been exposed to teaching different people in different

                   places and settings. The confidence and passion I have are not the result of practicing,

                   but I am always in love with teaching. I am preparing myself every day and the experience


                   I  have  helps  me  to  be  ready  for  actual  teaching.  I  have  been  involved  in  different

                   organizations  and  activities  that  also  help  me  to  improve  my  communication  and  my

                   methods of teaching.

                          Furthermore, I prepare myself by visiting different schools so I can see the different

                   teaching methods and strategies they use  when discussing their lessons. I take down

                   notes of the things I need to know and need to remember so I can apply them in actual

                   teaching. My cooperating teacher always says that I have potential in teaching and I can


                   use it as my strength in teaching. I observe each of my students so I can have the right

                   amount of knowledge when I teach. I loved my students, and I always helped them to learn

                   a lot in our lessons. I may not be good at using the English language, but I have a passion

                   for teaching students. I learned a lot from this virtual student teaching program, and I met

                   a fantastic cooperating teacher  who taught me a lot that I can apply in the field. I am


                   confident and ready to share the beauty of education.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[8



                   DAILY JOURNAL

                   Day 1: 04 October 2021

                          This is my first day of my teaching internship. My cooperating teacher and I meet

                   at  exactly  7:00  A.M  via  Google  Meet  in  the  morning  to  have  an  orientation.  First  my


                   cooperating  teacher  introduces  herself  and  I  follow.  My  CT’s  name  is  Ms.  Kristina  G.

                   Soriano. For short, I can call her Ma’am Kaye. Then Ma’am Kaye discussed the flow of the

                   online classes and asked me some questions regarding the flow of my internship. What

                   follows is the list of my tasks that I need to complete. After we discussed it, she asked me

                   about my field study observation and what I had learned. Then she asks me to have a


                   short demo discussion on the Subject Verb Agreement topic. I felt nervous and couldn’t

                   concentrate on speaking English at that time. But I still do my best to do the tasks that she

                   asks  me  to  do.  Then,  after  my  demo  discussion  She  asked  me  to  have  two  weeks’

                   observation in her online classes. She explains that in public schools, each English adviser

                   has four sections to handle under Online Distance Learning. The good part is, I just need

                   to prepare my LP and instructional material. I can use it for one week for four sections.

                   Then she also says that her classes are from Monday to Thursday and they are from


                   07:00am  to  09:00  AM  synchronous  classes.  The  rest  of  the  time  is  for  asynchronous

                   activities.

                   Day 2: 05 October 2021

                          My cooperating teacher introduced me as her co-teacher for the time being to her

                   students and to the parents. After the introduction, her classes started and I observed


                   carefully. While discussing, I also encoded the grades of the students and checked their

                   previous outputs because after the discussion, my cooperating teacher will be checking

                   them and I need to submit the grades before 7:00 P.M. After submitting the needed files,

                   my CT gave me the list of the students to prepare my own class record and take note of

                   the attendance while observing her classes.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[9


                   Day 3: 06 October 2021

                          My third observation day, I meet the Grade 8 Alcala while observing their classes

                   I have observe this day that this section has a lot of bright young students. The discussion

                   of my CT is great. I also observed this day the techniques of my CT in teaching activities


                   to the students. She has a lot of questions to know the students understanding about the

                   lessons. After the discussion she always checking the attendance of her students from the

                   start and end of her classes. After her classes she give me a task to read the different

                   sample of her DepEd sample lesson plans. Then she asks me to prepare a lesson plan

                   and  a  PowerPoint  presentation  in  the  topic  of  Adverb  and  Verb  that  need  to  submit


                   tomorrow. At 07:00P.M I submitted the needed documents and back in reading the sample

                   lesson plan that may cooperating tells me that I need to memorize.

                   Day 4: 07 October 2021

                          I prepared at 6:40 A.M. because my cooperating teacher was already prepared for

                   her last class for this week. I met Grade 8 Makatao, and this section has a lot of students.

                   I observed and took down notes from this day. I observed that this section also had well-

                   behaved students and they respected me as co-teacher of Ma’am Kristina. The students


                   are very active and always participate in the discussion. After the discussion, my CT gave

                   me another task to check the previous and latest outputs of the students. I need to finish

                   this task by tomorrow because my grades will fall into the second quarter. The students

                   need to submit their outputs even if it's late. This will be the basis for the meeting of my

                   CT with the parents of the students she’s handling in online distance learning.]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[10


                   Day 5: 08 October 2021

                          Every Friday, there will be a meeting of my cooperating teacher and the parents of

                   her students. This meeting is about  the updates of  the students’ performance, lack of

                   activities, and other concerns. I also observed this day just to have an idea about these


                   kinds of meetings. The parents ask Ma’am Kristina to help their children understand the

                   lesson and understand the English carefully. Ma’am Kristina also met the parents of the

                   Module Distance Learning students and they communicated about the students' lack of

                   activities and their improvements. Ma’am Kristina handles both ODL and MDL. But she

                   tells me that I just need to handle the ODL sections only.


                   Day 6: 11 October 2021

                          This is my second week observing the four sections of grade 8. I woke up 6:30 A.M

                   to take my breakfast because I need to remind myself that every Monday I need to conduct

                   a Flag ceremony virtually. I need to be prepared early every Monday, the students will be

                   entering the google meet link at exact 06:40 A.M and play the Lupang Hinirang Hymn and

                   Cavite Hymn. After this, my cooperating teacher started her classes at exact 07:00 A.M

                   every day. Then, she checked the attendance of Grade 8 MakaDiyos. The students are


                   not always complete in the class time. Ma’am Kristina always gave additional points to her

                   students  when  they  are  participating  to  the  discussion.  I  observed  that  this  section  is

                   respectful and very active. This section always passing their activities on time because I

                   always checking and monitoring their outputs every week and their section always on time

                   when submitting outputs. In discussion they also answering and Ma’am Kristina trained


                   them to use English policy to practice their English speaking skills.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[11


                   Day 7: 12 October 2021

                          Every Tuesday, I will be meeting Grade 8 Quisumbing. In this section, I observed

                   that they are very quiet. But there were a few students who were still answering when my

                   cooperating teacher discussed their new lesson for this week. I observed in this section


                   that they are not always prepared and their outputs are always late. After their lessons,

                   Ma’am Kristina reminds them again of their outputs from last month and that they need

                   them to be completed to release their grades in the second quarter. Quisumbing in Grade

                   8 is similar to a Science Section. They are not that active, but they are all respectful and

                   good at speaking English.


                   Day 8: 13 October 2021

                          Today is Wednesday, and I’m still observing the classes of Ma’am Kristina. This

                   day I will be meeting the Grade 8 Alcala. This section is also one of the Science Classes

                   in Grade 8. In this section, I observed that they are all good at speaking English as a

                   second language. It is because Ma’am Kristina disciplined her classes to practice their

                   English speaking skills every day. They are active and answer a lot. This section has a lot

                   of students who are bright and cheerful. I’ve enjoyed their classes and I’ve learned a lot


                   when  Ma’am  Kristina  presents  her  lesson  and  presentation  to  the  students.  My

                   cooperating teacher introduces and invites me to join the Google Classroom of each class

                   she manages via Gmail. Ma’am Kristina explained that I need to check the outputs of the

                   students in the Google Classroom directly and then create my own record file in Excel.

                   From  now  on,  I  will  be  checking  and  monitoring  each  student’s  output  in  the  Google


                   Classroom form. After this, I will be meeting the Grade 8 Makatao tomorrow.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[12


                   Day 9: 14 October 2021

                          It’s  Thursday  This  is  the  last  week  and  last  day  of  my  observation  in  Ma’am

                   Kristina's classes. Grade Makatao are also very respectful and there are a lot of students

                   in this section whose English speaking skills are not good. But they are still participating


                   in the discussion. All of their outputs have a lot of missing comments too. Ma’am Kristina

                   always  reminds  them  to  submit  their  outputs.  This  section  also  didn’t  complete  the

                   attendance of the class. Some students are also having trouble answering some questions

                   given to  them. But  this section  is  calm and  funny. After  their classes,  my  cooperating

                   teacher and I have a conversation regarding the format of lesson plans and instructional


                   materials that I need next week.

                   Day 10: 15 October 2021

                          This Friday, Ma’am Kristina informed me that I didn’t need to attend the meeting

                   with the parents; she  would be the one to talk to them every Friday. Then I focus on

                   checking and monitoring the students' outputs for this day. In two weeks, I observed that

                   every Monday my cooperating teacher was always preparing herself at 6:30 a.m. to open

                   the flag ceremony for her students. My cooperating teacher tells me that I need to prepare


                   my lesson plan and instructional materials ahead of time for the week coming and she

                   needs to approve it. She also says that I need to observe the Google classroom when she

                   uploads the lesson, activities, and updates in each class. There are lots of things I need

                   to do, and I need to adjust. I am not a morning person, but I still need to complete my task

                   and equip myself too. At 7:00 P.M., my cooperating teacher sent me a copy of the pivot


                   module  from  DepEd  for  the  Third  Quarter  referenced  in  preparing  my  lesson  plan,

                   instructional materials, and activities for the upcoming week. Ma’am Kristina also reminds

                   me that I will be handling her classes next week and she will be observing me for one

                   week. This day I feel pressured by the number of tasks that will be coming, but I understand

                   that I need this to mold my own development. Online classes are not easy.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[13


                   Day 11: 18 October 2021

                   Today is the day. This is my first day handling the first section of Grade 8. I prepared my

                   lesson plan and instructional materials for this coming week last Friday, and I just revised

                   some details, but my cooperating teacher approved it last Saturday. I prepared a lot, but


                   I’m still nervous. Ma’am Kristina reminds me that I need to remember that speaking English

                   is my main priority and the interaction of the students is very important too. I woke up at

                   exactly 06:00 A.M. and then prepared myself, wore my FS uniform, and ate my breakfast.

                   At 06:40 A.M., the students started entering the link, and my CT also entered the link. Then

                   Ma’am introduced me again to the class and asked me to lead the flag ceremony virtually.


                   Then after this, we started our class at 7:00 A.M. I still felt nervous and my stomach was

                   having  problems  while  presenting  the  lesson.  I  didn’t  have  any  technical  problems  or

                   internet problems this day. After my class in Grade 8 MakaDiyos, Ma’am Kristina and I

                   have  a  conversation  about  my  first  day.  She  didn’t  say  anything  negative;  she  only

                   reminded me that I need to improve my voice and practice my English more. Being nervous

                   is good because it means that I have really  prepared. After this, I need to upload the

                   asynchronous  activities  of  the  students  in  the  Google  Classroom  and  prepare  for


                   tomorrow's class.

                   Day 12: 19 October 2021

                          My routine for  this morning is still the same as yesterday. Our class started at

                   exactly 07:00 A.M. but for this day I will be meeting Grade 8 Quisumbing. My cooperating

                   teacher is also coming along on this day for the observation. I am still feeling nervous but


                   not like yesterday. My stomach is OK now and I have been practicing my English more. I

                   also prepare some notes for the right time to pronounce English words. Because Ma’am

                   Kristina tells me that I need to be careful in pronouncing words because the students will

                   be remembering what we teach them. I didn’t encounter any problems for this day, but my

                   CT tells me how to get the attendance of each student. I need to install Google Attendance

                   so I can easily generate who is absent and present at every meeting]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[14


                   Day 13: 20 October 2021

                          Today I will be meeting the Grade 8 Alcala and, like what I did on Monday, I will be

                   preparing the same things and discussing the same topic. I didn’t encounter any problems

                   this  day.  My  cooperating  teacher  is  also  here  for  the  observation.  This  morning  the


                   students from Grade 8 Alcala were all productive and cheerful. I develop and improve my

                   speaking voice to become louder. I also prepare different notes for the right pronunciation

                   of words. I will also have a nice day today because the students are actively participating

                   in our discussion. After our discussion, I uploaded their asynchronous activities to their

                   Google  Classroom.  After  an  hour,  I  have  another  conversation  with  my  CT  about  her


                   comment about my third day in practice teaching. Ma’am Kristina says that I have the

                   ability, and I obey and remember all of her advice, and she already sees my improvement.

                   Then, after our conversation, I need to prepare again for my last class tomorrow and need

                   to check the outputs of the students to prepare a report for the parents.

                   Day 14: 21 October 2021

                          My last class for this week is the Grade 8 Makatao. At exactly 07:00 A.M., our class

                   started, and this day I also didn’t encounter any problems. Grade 8 Makatao is not that


                   active when speaking English, but there are a few students still answering to give their

                   participation for this day. This section has a lot of very funny students. This day is also the

                   same  as  yesterday.  I  started to  check  their  attendance  and  ended  with  asynchronous

                   activities  and  checking  their  attendance  again.  After  our  classes,  I  go  to  their  Google

                   Classroom to upload their assessment and performance tasks and their homework. Then


                   there is also a group conversation in the messenger for an announcement. My CT sent

                   me a link to her comment for my presentation this afternoon. She says that this is her last

                   day this week to observe me and then I need to prepare myself to handle her classes

                   without her supervision for the upcoming weeks. This is a great opportunity for me because

                   it is one way to prepare for my final demonstration in January.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[15


                   Day 15: 22 October 2021

                   I  don’t  have  any  classes  every  Friday  because  this  is  a  day  for  the  consultation  and

                   meeting of my cooperating teacher with the parents. If there is a meeting, my CT is the

                   one who will update the parents and I will be there for the observation. The things that I


                   need to prepare are the updates of the activities and attendance of the students from

                   Monday to Thursday. I also need to prepare my lesson plan, instructional materials, and

                   activities for next week. I need to send the draft every Saturday for approval. Then I need

                   to  prepare  myself  and  have  some  reading  and  examples  prepared  for  my  discussion.

                   Every Friday I also need to finish checking the activities of each section because I need to


                   put them or encode them in my class record. This needs to be done every week because

                   the master and head teachers in the English Department will also monitor the students’

                   performance every week.

                   Day 16: 25 October 2021

                          I am on my first day without my cooperating teacher. I didn’t get enough sleep and

                   am very nervous. My cooperating teacher was already up at 06:30 A.M. to just give me

                   the link to the Google meet that she uses for the DepEd account of her students. I am very


                   nervous, but I still need to fulfill my task. At exactly 06:40 AM, the students are already

                   entering the meet, and I am preparing to facilitate the flag ceremony today. When the

                   majority of the class were present, I greeted them and gave them some guidelines for the

                   flag ceremony. After this, our class started at 07:00 AM. We prayed and then checked their

                   attendance, had two motivational activities, and then discussed our lesson. I only have two


                   hours to discuss, and synchronous activities are included in the given time. I don’t have

                   any problems with my internet connection. The ones who have a problem are my students,

                   because some of them are really having difficulty with their signals and their environment

                   because it is too noisy in their places. I am comfortable while being nervous because the

                   parents of the students are hearing me too. But overall, the Grade 8 MakaDiyos are all

                   respectful students, and even though my CT is not around, they are all listening to me and

                   participating in the discussion.]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[16


                   Day 17: 26 October 2021

                          Today, it was a great day and like what I did yesterday, it was just the same for

                   today. My cooperating teacher woke me up again at exactly 06:40 to give me the DepEd

                   link for the Grade 8 Quiz section. There was no flag ceremony, but the students needed


                   to  enter  the  class  link  at  exactly  7:00  AM  for  their  attendance.  Then  I  started  my

                   motivational activity and my discussion. I always needed to have a motivational activity for

                   their last week's lesson and then another motivational activity for this week's lesson. The

                   whole time, students are listening, and they are really respectful and quiet. There are some

                   who answer using Tagalog. But still, there are some who are using English as their medium


                   for this subject. After the discussion, I explained their asynchronous activities and then

                   followed  their  last  week's  activities.  Then  after  this,  my  CT  sent  me  a  link  to  have  a

                   conversation to update her on what I experienced yesterday and for today. I need to report

                   everything because she also needs to monitor my experiences.

                   Day 18: 27 October 2021

                          Today I will be handling Grade 8 Alcala and it’s just the same that my CT will be

                   sending again a Google Meet link using my DepEd account. My lesson is just the same


                   and I prepared different activities and motivational activities for this section. Some of my

                   students in this class are absent because they need to get their vaccinations for this day.

                   Ai didn’t encounter any problems in terms of technical, but my environment this day is very

                   noisy, so I need to change my area to something more quiet so the students cannot focus

                   when I’m discussing. After our lesson, I uploaded their asynchronous activities again to


                   our Google Classroom. Then I send a report to my cooperating teacher regarding my

                   experience for this day. I take a quick nap, then prepare my materials for tomorrow.]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[17


                   Day 19: 28 October 2021

                          Today, I’ll be handling Grade 8 Makatao. I’ve met again the very cheerful section

                   of my CT. Ma'am Kristina sent me another DepEd link to meet this section, as she did

                   yesterday. I do the classroom management before starting my lesson, then facilitate my


                   motivational activities. The problem for me is my environment, and for my students, it's

                   their internet, signal, or their environment too. My discussion is highly interactive, with

                   everyone responding and participating. They are also flawless, and they fully comprehend

                   our lesson. After our discussion, I uploaded their asynchronous activities to our Google

                   Classroom and checked their attendance before closing the link. Then I send a new report


                   to Ma’am Kristina for my experience this day. Then I take a test before continuing to check

                   and monitor the students' activities for this week.

                   Day 20: 29 October 2021

                          Today, my cooperating teacher tells me to take a rest and just send my lesson plan

                   and instructional materials on Saturday. She tells me to take care of my health first before

                   my task. I just take a few hours to rest before sending her my lesson plan and instructional

                   material so she can approve it. I am still checking the activities of the students because


                   there are lots of students submitting late, so I still need to wait for their grades. After this,

                   I edited my class record and gave reports to my cooperating teacher before the meeting

                   time.  This  report  contains  information  about  the  student’s  attendance,  performances,

                   activities, and behavior. All the students submitting their activities on time have a plus

                   point, and the students that submit their activities slate get a deduction. The participation


                   in  every  discussion  also  gives  points,  and  we  need  to  update  the  parents  about  their

                   children’s performances in online classes. After sending these updates, I will need to finish

                   my power point for next week's lesson and my new motivational activities.]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[18


                   Day 21: 02 November 2021

                          The classes are back. This is Tuesday, and I’ll be handling the Grade 8 Quiz. There

                   is no flag ceremony and I’ll already have access to Google Link using my DepEd account,

                   so my CT didn’t wake up early today. I am just handling my class on my own, and it is nice


                   to see the students cooperating and participating in our synchronous activities. Just like

                   the normal problems, some of my student’s encounter problems with their internet and

                   their  environment.  I  still  need  to  check  their  attendance  and  give  consideration  to  the

                   others.  For  me,  I  also  encounter  some  poor  signal  on  my  internet  and  my  noisy

                   environment because of the vendors in our village. Our class ends at exactly 09:00 AM in


                   the morning, and my students in this section still have a lot of pending activities that they

                   need to submit. Again, I reminded them and uploaded their asynchronous activities to our

                   Google Classroom. After our class, the tasks I need to finish are the report for this day to

                   my cooperating teacher and the update attendance of  the students  for this day. Then

                   prepare for my class tomorrow.

                   Day 22: 03 November 2021

                          It’s Wednesday, and I’ll be meeting the Grade 8 Alcala today. Half of the class are


                   absent because of their vaccination schedule. I still need to discuss their lessons to have

                   their outputs for this week. My coworker informed me that I should award points to students

                   who attend class on this particular day in order to motivate them. The students that are

                   absent are all excused, but they still need to do their asynchronous activities. I’ll start my

                   discussion and present my motivational activities. Some are participating, but the others


                   are just listening. Sometimes when I speak pure English, the students are not active in

                   answering,  but  when  I  speak  in Tagalog, they  are  all  participating.  This  is  one  thing I

                   observe  in  this  section,  but  they  need  to  practice  their  English  so  they  can  improve

                   themselves even though they are in the online classes. My discussion ended well, and

                   there are no internet problems for this day or any technical problems either.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[19


                   Day 23: 04 November 2021

                          Today is Thursday, and I’ll be meeting the Grade 8 Makatao. I’ll start my lesson at

                   exactly  7:00AM.  Some  of  the  students  are  still  entering,  but  I  need  to  be  on  time  in

                   discussing our lesson. I need to be careful with time and need to discuss the lesson and


                   the synchronous activities in a period of two hours with no extension. We started by praying

                   and checking the attendance, then motivational activities and then our lesson proper. This

                   section is also very smart, and it is so nice to handle the class of my cooperating teacher.

                   The students are all answering when I say that their participation will be graded, so the

                   students  are  alive  and  answering  my  questions.  Some  of  my  problems  are  with


                   synchronous activities. I need to be careful about the example that I will be using to avoid

                   confusion for the students. It takes a lot of time for them to answer some of the questions

                   in our synchronous activities. So, I prepared their activities very carefully because I wanted

                   them  to  learn  new  things  every  day.  I  performed  admirably,  and  ten,  I  uploaded  their

                   activities to Google Classroom and prepared my report for today.

                   Day 24: 05 November 2021

                          It's a very cold Friday. It’s raining today and thankfully I don’t have a class today,


                   but I need to do the checking of the outputs for this week and meet my cooperating teacher

                   for the consultation. While waiting for her to send the meet link, I'll just do my task and

                   finish what I need to finish. This routine helps me to be organized more and finish my job

                   easily and prepare things ahead of time. We met at 10:00 AM in the morning, then we

                   discussed the things that I need to improve and the overall feelings I have towards this


                   handling of her students. I always say that I’m very grateful because Ma’am Kristina is very

                   strict with her students, but she treats me like her own family. She is kind and sweet to me

                   and she never shouts. She never gives negative comments but key points to improve. That

                   is why it helps me to relax more and focus on the experiences I need to gain to become

                   better.]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[20


                   Day 25: 08 November 2021

                          It's a cold morning. I woke up at 5:00AM to prepare for my class. This is a good

                   improvement because I can now wake early and not rush myself anymore. My students

                   also wake up early, and they enter our meet link at 06:40 AM. I prepared for the flag


                   ceremony first, to play it at 06:50 AM. When I played the song for the flag ceremony, my

                   cooperating  teacher  suddenly  joined  the  meeting  just  to  observe  her  students.  The

                   students didn’t know that Ma’am Kristina would be there, then one of the students suddenly

                   sent a wrong message to the GC and Ma’am Kristina saw it. After the flag ceremony,

                   Ma’am Kristina called the attention of those students and asked why he was chatting while


                   listening to the National Anthem, and then she reminded the section of Grade 8 MakaDiyos

                   to respect me as their teacher. It gives the students a warning early in the morning. After

                   that, Ma’am Kristina left the meeting, and I started to check their attendance and continued

                   to our lesson proper after the motivation. The students are still shocked because there are

                   only a few students answering. I felt that they are still nervous. I ended up in our class after

                   checking their activities and attendance so they could rest and do the other activities.

                   Day 26: 09 November 2021


                          It is a cold morning again. I feel the atmosphere of December already. My students

                   in this section all wake up early too. There is no flag ceremony today, and other students

                   will give an excuse letter for their events that they need to attend. I’ll discuss any internet

                   or  technical  problems  encountered  for  this  day.  Students  are  participating,  and  my

                   cooperating teacher didn’t join the link and discuss my lesson properly and present the


                   activities. Some students ask questions about the asynchronous activities, while others

                   simply leave after the attendance is checked. This day is very cold and I feel tired when

                   speaking. I always remember that I need to focus on the activities that need students'

                   participation. The other activities are uploaded, and I need to check and monitor their

                   performance for my report this day.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[21


                   Day 27: 10 November 2021

                          Today is my mother’s birthday, but I need to discuss my lesson before preparing

                   the party for my mother. It’s a little bit noisy this day, so I need to move to the HOA office

                   in our village just to have a better environment for my lesson this day. I’ll be meeting Grade


                   8 Alcala and it was nice to see them all back and fully vaccinated already. I need to flash

                   back to the lesson last week so they can cope before presenting the new lesson to their

                   class. The students are all answering and they read in advance so they can answer my

                   questions  regarding  our  topic.  I  feel  the  students  are  all  doing  their  best  to  finish  this

                   second  grade.  Their  lessons  focus  on  grammar,  so  I  am  always  reminded  by  my


                   cooperating teacher to be careful in giving examples and terms when discussing. After my

                   lesson, they got all perfect in our activities, and I uploaded their synchronous activities.

                   After this, I prepare my report first, then prepare for my mother’s birthday party.

                   Day 28: 11 November 2021

                          Thursday, my bright day, the cheerful section again. I encountered a problem today

                   in technical terms. I forgot to plug my laptop in, then it shut down while I was discussing

                   our lesson. The good thing is that I entered using my cellphone and the students had still


                   not left the meeting. They waited for me to come back, and that is a rare thing I experienced

                   in this online practice teaching. I apologized to them and continued my discussion and

                   presented the synchronous activities to them. I’m still shocked by what happened, but the

                   good thing is the students see it as normal and they understand the circumstances that

                   happen in this online class. After they answered the activities, I checked their attendance


                   and uploaded the asynchronous activities. Again, I reminded them of their lack of output

                   and that some were turning in without attachments, and I gave a lot of consideration. After

                   this, I sent a message to my cooperating teacher about what happened, and she says that

                   she trains the students very well. I prepare my report for this day and send it to her later.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[22


                   Day 29: 12 November 2021

                          My  cooperating  teacher  attended  today's  meeting  to  discuss  the  students'

                   performances in front of their parents. Some students don’t want to continue in the online

                   class anymore, and there are lots of students transferring from module to online class this


                   week. My cooperating teacher accepted them, and I need to update my class record and

                   need to give a new set of activities for the late enrollees. It was a busy day for me. After

                   the meeting, I need to finish my lesson plan for next week's classes. I need to prepare my

                   instructional materials and activities too. I need to get the approval of my cooperating

                   teacher today or tomorrow for the approved lesson that I’ll be discussing next week. I take


                   a little rest and go back with the outputs of the students that I need to check. I have part-

                   time jobs, so it is so challenging and drains my energy. I finished my task at 07:00 PM and

                   I need to create a PowerPoint presentation for the activities and prepare well and read too.

                   Day 30: 15 November 2021

                          On a beautiful day, I’ll be meeting my grade 8 MakaDiyos and preparing my flag

                   ceremony  presentation.  I  just  started  by  praying  and  checking  their  attendance  and

                   motivation for the lesson proper. I didn't encounter technical problems or poor internet. But


                   some  of  the  students  in  the  section  are  absent  for  the  scheduled  vaccination.  My

                   cooperating teacher didn’t enter our link, and so I discussed and gave some examples,

                   asking the students their opinions regarding different pictures. The students in this section

                   are all smart and approachable. This section is cheerful sometimes but also helps me

                   boost my confidence in teaching by participating and giving my full attention throughout


                   the class. I am not good at speaking English, but they loved me just by being me. They

                   appreciate the things I do for them, and they always give their best too. The students'

                   environments sometimes cause the problems, and their parents sometimes listen in on

                   our classes every Monday. I felt pressed, but I continued to do my best to vividly discuss

                   our lesson.]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[23


                   Day 31: 16 November 2021

                          Today is Tuesday and I’ll be meeting my Grade 8 Quiz. There are lots of virtual

                   activities  in  National  this  week  and  my  cooperating  teacher  told  me  to  encourage  the

                   students to join because this will be graded too and it shows their support to the school.


                   We still have a class, so we started it at exactly 7:00 AM. Today it is also raining, so I

                   encountered poor signal on my internet and I apologize to my students. I will check their

                   attendance,  then  present  my  motivational  activity  and  proceed  to  my  lesson.  I  didn’t

                   encounter any other problems. I just finished my class with a cold. Some of the students

                   are still sleepy, and some are still participating. After my classes, I uploaded their activities


                   for this week and then prepared for my report that I needed to send to my cooperating

                   teacher today.

                   Day 32: 17 November 2021

                          Today  is  Wednesday,  and  I’ll  be  meeting  my  Grade  8  Alcala.  My  cooperating

                   teacher today joined our meeting and the students didn’t know it. I just take a deep breath

                   and prepare myself by focusing on the flow of the presentation. I am very nervous about

                   my English and I felt that I would be using some Tagalog words today. But I still try to keep


                   calm and focus on my preparations. Our classes started, and I’ll focus on the motivational

                   activity because this is the part that my cooperating tells me that I need to be careful about

                   because every lesson in a week needs to have student participation. It is very challenging

                   at first, but I am still trying my best to come up with some good activities that everyone can

                   relate  to.  After  this,  I  proceed  to  my  lesson  proper  and  give  a  lot  of  questions  to  my


                   students, so my cooperating teacher sees my improvement in teaching. I have finished my

                   lesson and can now relax. Then my coworker says that I don’t need to meet her in a meet

                   link because they are busy, but I still need to submit my report for this day. I check and

                   monitor the students' activities first and then proceed to my task for the day.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[24


                   Day 33: 18 November 2021

                   Today is Thursday, and I’ll be meeting the Grade 8 Makatao. I’ll start my lesson at exactly

                   7:00 a.m. Some of the students are still entering, but I need to be on time in discussing

                   our  lesson.  I  need  to  be  careful  with  time  and  need  to  discuss  the  lesson  and  the


                   synchronous activities in a period of two hours with no extension. We started by praying

                   and  checking  the  attendance,  followed  by  motivational  activities  and  then  our  lesson

                   proper.  This  section  is  also  very  smart,  and  it  is  so  nice  to  handle  the  class  of  my

                   cooperating teacher. The students are all answering when I say that their participation will

                   be graded, so the students are alive and answering my questions. Some of my problems


                   are with synchronous activities. I need to be careful about the example that I will be using

                   to avoid confusion for the students. It takes a lot of time for them to answer some of the

                   questions  in  our  synchronous  activities.  So,  I  prepared  their  activities  very  carefully

                   because I wanted them to learn new things every day. I did an excellent job, and ten, I

                   uploaded their activities to Google Classroom and finished my report for today.

                   Day 34: 19 November 2021

                          Today is Friday, and I don’t have a class today, but I need to do the checking of


                   the outputs for this week and meet my cooperating teacher for the consultation. While

                   waiting for her to send the meet link, I'll just do my task and finish what I need to finish.

                   This routine helps me to be organized more, finish my job easily, and prepare things ahead

                   of time. We met at 10:00 AM in the morning, then we discussed the things that I needed

                   to improve and the overall feelings I have towards this teacher's handling of her students.


                   I always say that I’m very grateful because Ma’am Kristina is very strict with her students,

                   but she treats me like her own family. She is kind and sweet to me, and she never shouts.

                   She never gives negative feedback, only suggestions for improvement. That is why it helps

                   me to relax more and focus on the experiences I need to gain to become better.]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[25


                   Day 35: 22 November 2021

                   On a beautiful day, I’ll be meeting my grade 8 MakaDiyos and preparing my flag ceremony

                   presentation. I just started by praying and checking their attendance and motivation for the

                   lesson proper. I didn't encounter  technical  problems or  poor internet. But  some of  the


                   students in the section are absent for the scheduled vaccination. My cooperating teacher

                   did not enter our link, so I talked about it and gave some examples, asking the students

                   what they thought about various pictures. The students in this section are all smart and

                   approachable. This section is cheerful sometimes but also helps me boost my confidence

                   in teaching by participating and giving my full attention throughout the class. I am not good


                   at speaking English, but they loved me just by being me. They appreciate what I do for

                   them and always give their best effort. The students' environments sometimes cause the

                   problems, and their parents sometimes listen in on our classes every Monday.

                   Day 36: 23 November 2021

                          I’ll be handling the Grade 8 quizzes. There is no flag ceremony, and I’ll already

                   have access to Google Link using my DepEd account, so my CT didn’t wake up early

                   today. I am just handling my class on my own, and it is nice to see the students cooperating


                   and participating in our synchronous activities. Just like the normal problems, some of my

                   student’s encounter problems with their internet and their environment. I still need to check

                   their attendance and give consideration to the others. For me, I also encounter some poor

                   signal on my internet and my noisy environment because of the vendors in our village. Our

                   class ends at exactly 09:00 AM in the morning, and my students in this section still have a


                   lot of pending activities that they need to submit. Again, I reminded them and uploaded

                   their asynchronous activities to our Google Classroom. After our class, the tasks I need to

                   finish  are  the  report  for  this  day  to  my  cooperating  teacher  and  the  updating  of  the

                   attendance of the students for this day. Then prepare for my class tomorrow.]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[26


                   Day 37: 24 November 2021

                          It’s Wednesday, and I’ll be meeting the Grade 8 Alcala today. Half the class is

                   absent because of their vaccination schedule. I still need to discuss their lessons to have

                   their outputs for this week. My coworker informed me that I should award points to students


                   who attend class on this particular day in order to motivate them. The students that are

                   absent are all excused, but they still need to do their asynchronous activities. I’ll start my

                   discussion and present my motivational activities. Some are participating, but the others

                   are just listening. Sometimes when I speak pure English, the students are not active in

                   answering,  but  when  I  speak  in Tagalog, they  are  all  participating.  This  is  one  thing I


                   observe  in  this  section,  but  they  need  to  practice  their  English  so  they  can  improve

                   themselves even though they are in the online classes. My discussion ended well, and

                   there are no internet problems for this day or any technical problems either.

                   Day 38: 25 November 2021

                          Today is Thursday, and I’ll be meeting the Grade 8 Makatao. I’ll start my lesson at

                   exactly  7:00  a.m.  Some  of  the  students  are  still  entering,  but  I  need  to  be  on time  in

                   discussing our lesson. I need to be careful with time and need to discuss the lesson and


                   the synchronous activities in a period of two hours with no extension. We started by praying

                   and  checking  the  attendance,  followed  by  motivational  activities  and  then  our  lesson

                   proper.  This  section  is  also  very  smart,  and  it  is  so  nice  to  handle  the  class  of  my

                   cooperating teacher. The students are all answering when I say that their participation will

                   be graded, so the students are alive and answering my questions. Some of my problems


                   are with synchronous activities. I need to be careful about the example that I will be using

                   to avoid confusion for the students. It takes a lot of time for them to answer some of the

                   questions  in  our  synchronous  activities.  So,  I  prepared  their  activities  very  carefully

                   because I wanted them to learn new things every day. I did an excellent job, and ten, I

                   uploaded their activities to Google Classroom and finished my report for today.]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[27


                   Day 39: 26 November 2021

                          Today is Friday, and I don’t have a class today, but I need to do the checking of

                   the outputs for this week and meet my cooperating teacher for the consultation. While

                   waiting for her to send the meet link, I'll just do my task and finish what I need to finish.


                   This routine helps me to be organized more, finish my job easily, and prepare things ahead

                   of time. We met at 10:00 AM in the morning, then we discussed the things that I needed

                   to improve and the overall feelings I have towards this teacher's handling of her students.

                   I always say that I’m very grateful because Ma’am Kristina is very strict with her students,

                   but she treats me like her own family. She is kind and sweet to me, and she never shouts.


                   She never gives negative feedback, only suggestions for improvement. That is why it helps

                   me to relax more and focus on the experiences I need to gain to become better.

                   Day 40: 29 November 2021

                          Today  is  Monday,  and  I’ll  be  handling  Grade  8  MakaDiyos.  The  students  are

                   advised to finish their 2nd grade outputs because next week they will need to release their

                   grades. I just started my class and then gave them time to finish their activities that they

                   didn’t turn in on time. The consequences are that they will have received a deduction for


                   not doing their activities on time. I need to finish checking their outputs, so after our lesson

                   I need to evaluate and check the students' outputs for the meeting of my cooperating

                   teaching and the parents. In our class today, the students were still participating, and I

                   didn’t  encounter  any  technical  or  poor  internet  issues  this  day.  I  uploaded  their

                   asynchronous  activities  and  waited  for the  late  submission  of  the  outputs  of the  other


                   students.  I  also  uploaded  the  advanced  lesson  and  activities  of  Garde  8  Quisumbing

                   because tomorrow is a holiday but they still need to complete some activities for their

                   outputs this week. The students need to have guidance in answering and checking their

                   missing outputs. I need to update my class record and finish my report for today.]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[28


                   Day 41: 01 December 2021

                          It’s Wednesday, and I’ll be meeting the Grade 8 Alcala today. Half of the class are

                   absent because of their vaccination schedule. I still need to discuss their lessons to have

                   their outputs for this week. My coworker informed me that I should award points to students


                   who attend class on this particular day in order to motivate them. The students that are

                   absent are all excused, but they still need to do their asynchronous activities. I’ll start my

                   discussion and present my motivational activities. Some are participating, but the others

                   are just listening. Sometimes when I speak pure English, the students are not active in

                   answering,  but  when  I  speak  in Tagalog, they  are  all  participating.  This  is  one  thing I


                   observe  in  this  section,  but  they  need  to  practice  their  English  so  they  can  improve

                   themselves even though they are in the online classes. My discussion ended well, and

                   there are no internet problems for this day or any technical problems either.

                   Day 42: 02 December 2021

                          It’s Wednesday, and I’ll be meeting the Grade 8 Alcala today. Half of the class are

                   absent because of their vaccination schedule. I still need to discuss their lessons to have

                   their outputs for this week. My coworker informed me that I should award points to students


                   who attend class on this particular day in order to motivate them. The students that are

                   absent are all excused, but they still need to do their asynchronous activities. I’ll start my

                   discussion and present my motivational activities. Some are participating, but the others

                   are just listening. Sometimes when I speak pure English, the students are not active in

                   answering,  but  when  I  speak  in Tagalog, they  are  all  participating.  This  is  one  thing I


                   observe  in  this  section,  but  they  need  to  practice  their  English  so  they  can  improve

                   themselves even though they are in the online classes. My discussion ended well, and

                   there are no internet problems for this day or any technical problems either.]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[29


                   Day 43: 03 December 2021

                          My cooperating teacher has given me one week to handle the students without her.

                   Because all of the Grade 8 teachers are in seminars this week, my cooperating teacher

                   reminds me to finish my monitoring and checking by December 10. Then she’ll send me a


                   schedule  for  my  practice  demonstration  from  December  13  to  December  17.  From

                   December 20 to 24, I need to submit my chosen topic and prepare a lesson plan and

                   different  instructional  materials  for  the  approval  of  the  Head  Teacher  in  the  English

                   Department. The principal will also be observing me on December 6, Monday. I have lots

                   to prepare and lots to accomplish. But before this, I need to prepare my lesson plan for


                   next week and myself because that will be my last week handling my students on my own.

                   I will finish my final lesson with them to focus on my upcoming practice demonstration.

                   Day 44: 06 December 2021

                          I am very nervous this Monday because Sir Magdaleno, the principal, will be visiting

                   and observing my demonstration today. I have prepared all the materials I will need for the

                   lesson for  this week. Sir Magdaleno, please join the meet link at  exactly 06:40 AM to

                   observe my whole demonstration. I prepared some notes for this week and really studied


                   my lesson. I started by preparing the flag ceremony, prayer, checking the attendance and

                   other classroom management, then my motivational activity presentation. In my lesson

                   proper and in my synchronous activities, I always remind my students that they have 1 or

                   2 minutes to answer the given activities so I can finish my demonstration at exactly 09:00

                   AM. My overall demonstration this day was all good and my cooperating teacher also saw


                   my improvements. It was nice to see myself also seeing the progress every day, and I am

                   proud of myself in my own way of teaching my students. I am nervous but still finished my

                   demonstration  this  afternoon.  Sir  Magdaleno  and  my  cooperating  teacher  give  their

                   comments and tell me some key points that I needed to think about, especially in my final

                   demo. After that, I prepared my report and uploaded the students' activities from this day.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[30


                   Day 45: 07 December 2021

                          My cooperating teacher has a seminar today that she needs to attend, so I will

                   handle the Grade 8 Quiz without her today. When we discuss our lesson, my students

                   prefer to speak in Tagalog rather than English. I didn’t get angry about this, but I helped


                   them to compose it in English. Because Ma’am Kristina always tells me that this is an

                   English class and I need to guide each student to learn the basics of English, especially in

                   speaking. I don’t encounter any problems, but my students are still having trouble in their

                   poor signal and noisy environment. The students are smart in this section too. It was nice

                   to see them try and help themselves to understand the basics of English. Some of the


                   students will not be heard, but I created different activities that I will test each student's

                   understanding of in every lesson. I prepared my report for this day and checked some late

                   outputs from the students.

                   Day 46: 08 December 2021

                          Today is a holiday. It's a celebration of the Feast of the Immaculate Conception.

                   The students are also resting today. But my class for this day needs to complete the activity

                   for this week. Even though today is a holiday, there are lots of activities that need to be


                   checked and evaluated. I sent some educational videos to help each section understand

                   the Subject Verb Agreement rules. There are lots of DepEd that I check to support the

                   students' lessons every week. It is necessary to complete the task this week, so I am

                   attempting to complete it all this week. I followed up with some students that had a lot of

                   absent and missing in their class records. After doing this, I take a rest and continue with


                   my task. I still need to send a report for this day to my cooperating teacher.]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[31


                   Day 47: 09 December 2021

                          Today is Thursday, and I’ll be meeting the Grade 8 Makatao. I’ll start my lesson at

                   exactly  7:00  a.m.  Some  of  the  students  are  still  entering,  but  I  need  to  be  on time  in

                   discussing our lesson. I need to be careful with time and need to discuss the lesson and


                   the synchronous activities in a period of two hours with no extension. We started by praying

                   and  checking  the  attendance,  followed  by  motivational  activities  and  then  our  lesson

                   proper.  This  section  is  also  very  smart,  and  it  is  so  nice  to  handle  the  class  of  my

                   cooperating teacher. The students are all answering when I say that their participation will

                   be graded, so the students are alive and answering my questions. Some of my problems


                   are with synchronous activities. I need to be careful about the example that I will be using

                   to avoid confusion for the students. It takes a lot of time for them to answer some of the

                   questions  in  our  synchronous  activities.  So,  I  prepared  their  activities  very  carefully

                   because I wanted them to learn new things every day. I did an excellent job, and ten, I

                   uploaded their activities to Google Classroom and finished my report for today.

                   Day 48: 10 December 2021

                   Today is Friday, and I don’t have a class today, but I need to do the checking of the outputs


                   for this week and meet my cooperating teacher for the consultation. While waiting for her

                   to send the meet link, I'll just do my task and finish what I need to finish. This routine helps

                   me to be organized more, finish my job easily, and prepare things ahead of time. We met

                   at 10:00 AM in the morning, then we discussed the things that I needed to improve and

                   the overall feelings I have towards this teacher's handling of her students. I always say


                   that I’m very grateful because Ma’am Kristina is very strict with her students, but she treats

                   me like her own family. She is kind and sweet to me, and she never shouts. She never

                   gives negative feedback, only suggestions for improvement. That is why it helps me to

                   relax more and focus on the experiences I need to gain to become better.]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[32




                   Day 49: 13 December 2021

                   Today is Monday and I’ll be handling Grade 8 MakaDiyos, the students are advising to

                   finish their 2ndGrading outputs because next week will need to release their grades. I just


                   started my class and then give them time to finish their activities that they didn’t turned in

                   on time. The consequences are they will have received a deduction because of not doing

                   their activities on time. I need to finish checking their outputs so after our lesson I need to

                   evaluate and check the student’s outputs for the meeting of my cooperating teaching and

                   the parents. In our class today the students still participating and I didn’t encounter any


                   technical or poor internet this day. I uploaded their asynchronous activities an waited for

                   the late submission of outputs of the other students. The I also uploaded the advance

                   lesson and activities of Garde 8 Quisumbing because tomorrow is holiday but still they

                   need to answer some activities for their outputs this week. The students need to have a

                   guidance in answering and checking their missing outputs. I need to update my class

                   record and finish my report for this day.

                   Day 50: 14 December 2021


                          Today, I’m handling the grade 8 quiz. This day will be my practice demonstration.

                   Just like the other day, I prepared and did my practice demonstration for my students. My

                   cooperating gives me two weeks because I will take my demonstration on January 3, 2022.

                   I prepare different motivational activities and practice my speaking skills in English. I didn’t

                   encounter any problems today, and I finished my practice demonstration. My students are


                   all participating, and they also understand my situation and give me their full cooperation

                   on this day. After my practice demonstration, I needed to check and finish all the students'

                   outputs  before  December  24.  I  also  need  to  submit  my  report  for  this  day,  and  my

                   colleagues are also busy with their seminars in the school. She asks me to really monitor

                   her students because the seminars she’s attending are all important too, and I understand

                   her. I finished my task at exactly 08:30 PM and am still checking for the other sections'

                   outputs.]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[33


                   Day 51: 15 December 2021

                          It was a cold morning today; I will miss getting up every morning to prepare for my

                   classes. I will be meeting my Grade 8 Alcala and, like yesterday, I needed to take my

                   discussion seriously this week because this is my practice demonstration. My cooperating


                   teacher always tells me that to be good or to become better and build my best, I need to

                   prepare myself early. Practice and preparation are also keys to improving and becoming

                   a better educator. I checked the attendance of my students and explained to them that I

                   would only be their teacher from this week to next week. I spent my time with them by

                   enjoying our few minutes in our class. My grade 8 students are all smart and respectful.


                   They are all smart, but I didn’t feel that they intimidated me. I am comfortable with them

                   and I appreciate their efforts to cooperate and listen to me in our classes. I need to do

                   another report about this day and submit it to my cooperating teacher.

                   Day 52: 16 December 2021

                          The end of this week is approaching, this is my last day for this week in my practice

                   demonstration and I’ll be meeting Grade 8 Makatao today. Like the yesterday I inform my

                   students about having this week and final week next week to meet them. My students here


                   are very cheerful I will be missing them too. I started my recorded demonstration and the

                   students are all participating in the class. Their participation always is part of their grading

                   system so the students also thinks that they are having their own obligation too in our

                   classes.  The  most  important  thing  is  that  they  are  engaging  with  the  lesson,  they

                   understand and their outputs the evidences that they are learning. After our class, I follow


                   up their missing outputs and I am doing my task in preparing a report for this day and

                   submit  to  my  cooperating  teacher  later.  I  experienced  poor  connection  today  and  my

                   students  never  completed  in  our  google  meeting.  But  I  still  understand  and  give

                   consideration because that what is my cooperating teacher reminding me always.]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[34


                   Day 53: 17 December 2021

                          The end of this week is approaching, this is my last day for this week in my practice

                   demonstration and I’ll be meeting Grade 8 Makatao today. Like the yesterday I inform my

                   students about having this week and final week next week to meet them. My students here


                   are very cheerful I will be missing them too. I started my recorded demonstration and the

                   students are all participating in the class. Their participation always is part of their grading

                   system so the students also thinks that they are having their own obligation too in our

                   classes.  The  most  important  thing  is  that  they  are  engaging  with  the  lesson,  they

                   understand and their outputs the evidences that they are learning. After our class, I follow


                   up their missing outputs and I am doing my task in preparing a report for this day and

                   submit  to  my  cooperating  teacher  later.  I  experienced  poor  connection  today  and  my

                   students  never  completed  in  our  google  meeting.  But  I  still  understand  and  give

                   consideration because that what is my cooperating teacher reminding me always.

                   Day 54: 20 December 2021

                          I wake up 04:00 AM today, this is my last week handling my students and my last

                   Monday handling the Grade 8 MakaDiyos. I started my demonstration in preparing the flag


                   ceremony  this  morning.  Then  prayer,  checking  their  attendance  and  proceed  to  my

                   motivational activities. My last topic this week is about Logos, Ethos and Pathos. I finis the

                           nd
                   whole 2  Grading topics and the students are all having a great time in our classes. After
                   my  lesson  proper,  I  proceed  to  my  synchronous  activities  and  my  final  motivational

                   quotation and announcement for them. I also open up that their section will be the one


                   who will attend my final demonstration on January 03, 2022. My Grade 8 MakaDiyos ae

                   all smart and active. They are the section that will be present on my final demo. After this,

                   my cooperating teacher join the meet and updates the students missing activities for the

                   2   Grading  outputs.  After  this  I  will  be  meeting  my  CT  for  her  comments  about  my
                    nd
                   discussion today and the things to improve again. I also need to submit a report and finish

                   the class record of Grade 8 MakaDiyos today.]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[35


                   Day 55: 03 January 2022

                          Today is the day! This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity, and now is the time for

                   me to reflect on my most important key takeaways as a student teacher. I am very nervous.

                   I didn’t get enough sleep, but I still chose to start my new beginnings. I already have the


                   link to the panel and my students are already entering. I didn't help with the flag ceremony

                   because I had to start at 8:00 a.m. and only had two hours to complete my demonstration.

                   I am very nervous and I didn’t use any scripts because I wanted my English speaking to

                   develop on my own and not rely on any scripted materials. I prepared my lesson for today's

                   presentation. I am struggling with our poor connection, but I still continue, and the students


                   are all answering. This is the best thing I ever felt that the students were really focusing on

                   our lesson. They are answering because they know the answer and they ask because they

                   are curious. This day has made me extremely happy. Even though my English speaking

                   is not that good, I can see that I can be a good educator in the future.

                   Day 56: 04 January 2022

                          After my final demonstration yesterday, I needed to finish checking the late outputs

                   of my students. This is also the day I’ll be meeting Grade 8 Quisumbing for the last time. I


                   prepared my last presentation to them, and we had the last activity. I’ve finished checking

                   all the outputs  of the students  in this section, and I’ve met my cooperating teacher to

                   discuss the grades and outputs of the students in this section. Then, after sending all of

                   the records of the students, I leave for the Google classroom and for their group chat in

                   messenger. I have a good time and have gained beautiful memories with them, and they


                   help me grow in certain experiences. Some of the students sent me a message and a

                   letter of appreciation, and I’ll be treasurer after this program.]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[36


                   Day 57: 05 January 2022

                   This is my final day, and I'll see Grade 8 Alcala for the last time. I'm working on my final

                   presentation for them and the final activity. I finished checking all of the students' outputs

                   in this area and met with my cooperating teacher to discuss the students' grades and


                   outputs  in  this  section.  Then,  after  sending  all  of  the  students'  records  to  Google

                   Classroom and their group chat in Messenger, I leave. I'm having a terrific time with them

                   and have made some wonderful memories with them, and they're helping me grow via

                   these experiences. After the program, some of the students sent me a note and a letter of

                   appreciation, stating that I would be treasurer. There are still some students who need to


                   submit their outputs, and I will help my cooperating teacher to check them and tally all of

                   their scores for them to have a grade for this quarter.

                   Day 58: 06 January 2022

                   My last day to meet with Grade Makatao, this section makes me laugh every Thursday,

                   because they are so bright and I love their dedication to learning English. There are still

                   some students who have not yet submitted their outputs and there are still some students

                   who have a lot of no-output remarks, but I will take the time to help them submit all of it so


                   they  can  have  a  grade  for  the  Second  Quarter  outputs.  After  checking  all  of  the  late

                   outputs,  I  also  need  to  meet  my  cooperating  teacher  for  the  monitoring  and  give  my

                   farewell message to my students for the last time. I’ll be missing them a lot but still I am

                   grateful to become part of their life in a very short period of time. I always treasure all the

                   experiences I have gained together with this student. I left to their Group Chat and leave


                   their google classroom this day.]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[37


                   Day 59: 07 January 2022

                   Friday I need to submit all the grades of the students together with my class record for the

                   evaluation. I also send some of my papers to my cooperating teacher for her to sign. I met

                   my cooper for the last time, and we had a conversation about her experiences. She shares


                   a lot of things I need to improve and the things I already have when she observes my final

                   demonstration. My farewell conversation with my cooperating teacher was the best. She

                   shares a lot of ideas and strategies that I need to learn and understand. She gave me a

                   lot of pointers and takeaways. I also give thanks for the last time to my Grade 8 MakaDiyos

                   for their help. I also submitted and presented all the things needed by my cooperating


                   teacher. Ma'am Kristina also thanked me for being very sweet and giving all of my efforts

                   in handling her classes. This was a memorable day, and I don't want it to be forgotten. I

                   will be seeing them someday, and I'll be proud that I became part of their journey as their

                   temporary teacher at that time.

                   Day 60: 08 January 2022

                   This is my virtual clearance day. I have submitted all the documents and records I have

                   on my drive. I also followed up on all the things that I needed for my e-portfolio with my


                   cooperating  teacher.  I'm  already  missing  my  students,  and  I've  been  missing  the

                   messages about their outputs. Some of the students are still asking for help, and other

                   students are sending the warmest messages. My cooperating teacher is still asking some

                   of the students for their missing outputs. I helped my students who were not active and

                   followed up on their activities. My cooperating teacher thanked me, and she sent all the


                   documents I needed for this final output.]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[38


                                            COMMON CLASSROOM PROBLEM




                          I  encountered  various  issues  prior  to  our  Virtual  Student  Teaching  Internship

                   Program when we took our assistantship at the private school we had to leave last year.

                   We were given the privilege to observe a live preparation, and the teachers we interviewed

                   faced a lot of problems in this new normal. Now that I have experience handling virtual

                   classes, the most common problems I have encountered are the following:

                          First, I’ve experienced a noisy environment. It is the season where the people here


                   in our village are constructing their houses. We are also in front of the Home Owners

                   Association office,  where there is always an event that affects my discussion  with my

                   students. Some of my students also have a lot of distractions in their home; their parents

                   are arguing; their dogs are barking; I can hear some vendors selling in their home; etc.

                   This is very challenging to continue because I am not the only one distracted, but also my


                   students. My students can focus if they hear the sound from their classmate’s speaker. It

                   is consuming our time. Instead, we are done discussing that part. I need to repeat it again

                   before proceeding to another part of the lesson. Some of my students don’t have a Wi-Fi

                   connection in their houses, so looking for the signal is their biggest problem for the day.

                   They join our meet link in a short period of time, and then if they leave, it is hard for them

                   to go back in, so when I am calling their names, they are not responding anymore. Because

                   of  this  problem,  my  patience  and  consideration  are  the  biggest  gifts  I  can  give  to  my


                   students.

                          Aside  from  that,  I  also  experience  technical  problems,  but  it’s  not  always

                   happening. My laptop suddenly went out of battery, and I forgot to charge it right away. My

                   laptop  suddenly  shut  down  while  I  was  discussing  the  end  of  my  lesson.  That  is  so

                   frustrating when it happens, because I need to go back right away because we only have


                   two hours to handle the grade 8 classes before they attend their next classes. These are

                   the common problems I have encountered in my internship. My students are well-behaved

                   and respectful, and that is why I don’t need to tell them to open up because my cooperating]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[39


                   teacher always tells them to open their cameras at all times as part of their participation.

                   According  to  Mikaela  G.  Amadora  (2020),  there  are  some  challenges  that  can  be

                   experienced in this new normal, which are also problems that can be encountered in this

                   Online Distance Learning. It has an impact on both teachers and students.


                          1.Internet accessibility

                          To be honest, our country struggles  with the internet. A stumbling block in the

                   implementation of remote learning in general. Although there are internet plans available,

                   they are not all made equal. As a result, there was never a day in an online class when a

                   student didn't complain about anything like "Can someone inform the professor I/he/she


                   was disconnected?" " "Oops! What happened to him? "I have inconsistent Wi-Fi," says the

                   professor, who doesn't aware he's been cut off, "Do you guys see/hear me?””. We live in

                   the city, but we still have errors. What about students who are stuck in distant areas where

                   the signal isn't as strong as it is in cities? They had to "move mountains" only to get a

                   couple of bars.

                          2.  Audio Clarity

                          Although a bad internet connection can cause audio issues, the type of microphone


                   utilized could also be a factor. Distracting problems with undesired echo and background

                   noises, either from the professor or from the student reciting, are common. Being on the

                   phone, particularly with headphones with a built-in microphone, can only go you so far.

                   The majority of my classmates had chosen to purchase a separate microphone in order to

                   have sufficient audio clarity when reciting in class. Those who can afford it will benefit. It


                   may or may not be pricey, but it is still an additional cost.

                          3.  Outdated Device & Software

                          I was happy with my equipment before to the pandemic. They weren't the most

                   recent, but they all served my purposes well. When online education started, everything

                   changed. My instruments had suddenly become inadequate. They'd gone Jurassic and

                   couldn't  keep  up  any  longer.  Because  the  majority  of  classes  are  held  via  video

                   conference, most platforms require an upgraded system to function properly. To cut a long]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[40


                   tale  short,  I  required  a  system  and  device  upgrade.  Unfortunately,  it  has  become  a

                   necessity that not everyone can afford. Not now, when the majority of jobs are on a knife's

                   edge.

                          4.  System Glitch


                          The application used during online classes, like every student, has its bad days.

                   From a student's perspective, it may appear as simple as opening our device and logging

                   in, but the reality is that we may experience a system glitch that we are unaware of, such

                   as  the  application  crashing,  being  abruptly  removed  from  an  ongoing  class,  the

                   application's incompatibility with certain devices, and so on.


                          5.  Short Attention Span

                          This is a problem that is not only technical, but also universal. Being attentive and

                   focused in a regular classroom setting requires self-discipline. It takes a lot of willpower to

                   stay awake and concentrate in an online class. The already limited attention span has

                   shrunk even further. We can't help but succumb to the comfort of working from home

                   because everyone else is doing so. Multitasking became more common and sleeping off

                   got simpler. We tend to get distracted easily on our iPhones, our pets, and deliveries rather


                   than the ongoing class lessons due to the absence of interaction during online classes.



                          These are just a few of the challenges that my coworkers, students, and I have

                   dealt with. Although online classes have certain advantages, this should not prevent us

                   from being sensitive to and aware of the various situations in which we all find ourselves.


                   As the number of COVID cases in our country grows, we must learn to be resilient and

                   continue to aid our classmates as #NoStudentGetsLeftBehind.]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[41



                                           FINAL DEMONSTRATION TEACHING




                          I have a lot of experience in teaching demonstrations, but my final demonstration

                   as a pre-service teacher will always be my favorite. I want it to become memorable and

                   I've been praying that my final demonstration will be the best one that I’ll never forget.

                          My  cooperating  teacher  gave  me  two  weeks  before  my  final  demonstration  to

                   practice and prepare everything I'll need on January 3, 2022. I’ll be the first one in our

                   section who will have the final demonstration in the year of 2022. My cooperating teacher


                   checked  and  approved  my  lesson  plan,  instructional  materials,  and  motivational,

                   synchronous, and asynchronous activities that I’ll be using in my final demonstration. I

                   chose the lesson of Recognizing Positive and Negative Messages. I like this lesson. This

                   is for weeks seven and eight. I’ve watched DepEd videos about this topic and am looking

                   for different motivational activities that will help my students to answer more. I draft the


                   details that I want to teach them and focus on a certain moral lesson that will give them

                   another point of view in life. The Head and master teacher of the English Department also

                   need to approve the materials I’ll be using. Thankfully, my cooperating teacher is always

                   helping me. She is always encouraging me to give myself some key points and focus on

                   the things I need to focus on. She is saying that I will need to remember to be who I am

                   and express my own style of teaching, and the first step is always the hardest one.

                          Christmas and the new year have come and gone, and while I have enjoyed those


                   events, I have spent the majority of my time preparing for my final demonstration. I can’t

                   sleep and I am having an upset stomach in the weeks before my final demo day. I still

                   need  to  be  healthy  to  focus,  so  I  leave  my  practice  and  exercise  so  I  can  build  my

                   confidence more. There are lots of people helping me to practice and motivating me. On

                   the night of January 1, 2022, I cried because I don't think I can do it; I prayed, and a voice


                   in my head said, "You can do it, just give it your all." I can’t sleep. I feel pressure and

                   nervous. But after I cried, I got up and practiced again and prepared my area where I would

                   be setting up my laptop and the things I needed.]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[42


                          My final demonstration day started at exactly 08:00 A.M. in the morning. Before

                   8:00 A.M., I wake up early and prepare and test the things I will be using that day. I pray

                   first and eat my breakfast. All of a sudden, research partner Ms. Mary Rose Morana came

                   by our house seeking help because their internet is unstable. After we talked, I prepared


                   myself and dry-ran my lesson. I also met my cooperating teacher and my grade eight

                   MakaDiyos that morning before my demonstration. The students were also preparing their

                   water bottles and pens/notebooks for the discussion later. I uploaded ahead of time an

                   educational  video  that  is  related  to the  lesson  I‘ll  be  discussing  with  them  later.  I  feel

                   nervous  already  and  my  hands  are  shaking.  I  am  calming  myself  on  the  day  of  my


                   demonstration.

                          My students that day are all helping me that day. They also wake up early just to

                   be sure that they will be part of my final demo. Some of my students ask me what help

                   they can give, and they also practice their English because they want to participate in the

                   discussion. I am really happy with how these students dedicated themselves to helping

                   me pass my final demonstration. These students never gave me any headaches from day

                   one until now. They are all so cheerful on the day of the demonstration. All my students


                   send me a letter of motivation and encourage me to do my best that day.

                          My final demonstration started at exactly 08:00 A.M. and I felt so nervous, but I

                   remember my cooperating teacher always saying that if you feel nervous, it means you

                   are prepared. In my final demonstration I didn’t need to have a virtual flag ceremony. It

                   started with a greeting and the student greeted me also. Then it proceeded to the prayer.


                   In prayer, there was a student already assigned that I called that day. After the prayer, I

                   proceeded to check their attendance. All the students were present, but I didn’t need to

                   call on all of them. After this, I proceed to give them a motivational quote. First I ask them

                   about  their  new  years  and  they  explain  what  they  understood  from  the  motivation

                   presented on the screen. All of them answer and all of them participate. This is the one

                   thing that I need to do because the student's participation is my main goal in every lesson

                   that  I’ll  be  teaching  them.  After  this,  I  proceed  to  my  motivational  activities.  The  first]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[43


                   motivational activity I’ve presented is they need to tell if the image they are seeing is a

                   positive or a negative one. All of the students participated and they got the correct answer.

                   They also explained each picture why it is negative or positive. Then after this, I proceed

                   to  the  second  activity,  which  is  choosing.  If  the  sentences  do  have  some  negative


                   emotions, they need to draw a sad emoji, and if there is a positive in the sentence, they

                   will draw a happy emoji. The students enjoyed this activity and they all participated and

                   got the correct answer. The motivational activities I presented are very important because

                   they are about Fredrickson's theory. It says that both positive and negative emotions have

                   evolutionary advantages; negative emotions encourage people to survive in life-or-death


                   situations,  but  positive  emotions  encourage  us  to  develop  our  skills  and  build  new

                   resources. It will help my Grade 8 students understand even more the differences between

                   positive and negative messages. After motivational activities, I proceed to ask what they

                   have observed or learned in those activities. When my students answer, I always praise

                   them  because  my  cooperating  teacher  said  that  I  need  to  acknowledge  or  appreciate

                   students' answers all of the time. It is one way of giving them good feedback.

                          I proceed to my lesson proper or to my discussion of the main lesson of the day. I


                   experienced my internet connection suddenly becoming weak. But it changes back again

                   to become stable. I am starting to discuss the lesson, and I always ask my students about

                   the lesson before proceeding. I studied a lot for my lesson, and it was a very nice lesson

                   for me. Because of my nervousness, my English is not always good when I discuss my

                   lesson. I used some informal words, but it didn’t affect my discussion. I am really having a


                   hard time speaking English all the time, but I tried that day. There was no Tagalog word

                   that came to my mind that day, and I was focusing on my lesson seriously. I know that my

                   speaking  skills  are  not  good,  but  for  others  it’s  not  good,  but  for  me  it  is  the  biggest

                   improvement  I  have  seen  in  myself.  I  was  overjoyed  and  wanted  to  cry  because  my

                   discussion was coming to an end. Then I ask the students if they understand my lesson

                   and what the key takeaways are from our lesson. The students answered and cheerfully

                   participated. After that, I flashed on the screen my synchronous activities. I explained to]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[44


                   them the directions and how they could answer this activity. I said that they only had three

                   minutes to answer the first activity. While answering the activity, I need to remind them

                   how many minutes they only have after this activity. I called the students who wanted to

                   volunteer to answer the activity. Then, after this one, we moved on to the second activity,


                   and I explained the direction for that activity once more. I need to remind them of the

                   minutes they only have in the first activity. Then we need to check the second activity for

                   their output for this day. After this, I asked the students the importance of recognizing the

                   negative and positive messages, and they answered excellently. They are now aware of

                   these  things.  Then,  we  proceed  to  write  their  assignments  and  reminders  for  their


                   asynchronous activities. At the end of my PowerPoint, I include contact information for

                   them to contact me if they have any questions about the school outputs. I checked their

                   attendance before ending our class. I ended my final demonstration at exactly 09:00 A.M.

                   that morning. I am still nervous and I want to cry. I was so proud of myself that I survived

                   that day, and I’m very thankful to those people who helped me.

                          I used the DepEd template for my lesson plan because my cooperating teacher

                   required me to use it. The PowerPoint design I use is black and white with some colors


                   because my students like a PowerPoint that has different colors. I also used educational

                   videos  and  motivational  activities  that  had  emoji’s  or  emoticons  and  pictures.  I  didn’t

                   prepare much because in virtual I need to be careful with the time I consume in my final

                   demonstration.  My  cooperating  teacher  says  that  it  will  be  hard  if  I'm  using  some

                   applications because some of my students can’t join. I need to be fair in preparing an


                   online activity. Any activities that help my students' creativity and they can enjoy the short

                   period of time to learn? I need to be realistic even in my final demonstration because it will

                   determine my teaching style. My PowerPoint has fewer words and more pictures because

                   my  students  love  pictures.  They  enjoyed  a  type  of  discussion  with  a  lot  of  color  and

                   pictures. I can get their attention with that kind of style in my presentation. My lesson plan

                   has a lot of activities and questions to prepare. The DepEd modules also provides some]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[45


                   activities but I didn’t use it my cooperating suggest to me that I can create my own set of

                   activities for improving my student’s vocabulary.

                          In teaching grade eight students I enjoyed it and seeing them helping me to have

                   a good result in my final demonstration is one of the amazing experiences that I will never


                   forget. After my final demonstration the panelists is giving their comments. The first one

                   who gives the comment is Ma’am Mildred Sebastian she is our adviser and she says that

                   I know my lesson very well and I am very confident. But she also says that I still to improve

                   my English because there still  words I mispronounce and  etc. Next panelist is Ma’am

                   Estelita A. Villa our Coordinator she’s says that good moments too, next is Mx. Audrey


                   Borilla our instructor in Teacher Education Department she says good comments and the

                   things needs to improve. Next is my cooperating teacher my Kristina Soriano, says good

                   comments about me and my big improvement from day one to my final demonstration day.

                   The last two panelists are Ma’am Lourdes Panganiban, Master Teacher and Ma’am Cecile

                   Ferrer,  Head  Teacher  of  English  Department.  The  last  two  panelists  also  gave  they

                   positive comments and the things that I need to improve too. The overall comments to me

                   was that I really know  what I been teaching, I am confident about  my  lesson  and my


                   students are all participating. The things I need to improve is all about my English speaking

                   skills. I am still nervous but I know my weaknesses and what they see is the thing that I

                   been working on to improve. All of the emotions I feel t in the day of my final demonstration

                   will be my lesson that I will bring wherever I go.

                          All of the panelists are congratulating me and I cried that day, because I never


                   dream that I can go this long in education course. Even though our final demonstration

                   happens  virtually,  my  classmates  and  I  prepare  a  lot  and  give  our  best  in  our  final

                   demonstration. Some of us will be great, some are good and there is also some of us are

                   improving and this program will always our favorite.]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[46


                                     OVERALL REFLECTION AND SELF-APPRAISAL




                          The experience that I have encountered in face-to-face demonstration to virtual

                   demonstration has helped me to be flexible to become a future educator. I still have a lot

                   of training to do and practice before I can use English as my medium of communication in

                   the future. I have seen my improvement in building my confidence and believing in myself

                   that I can be a good educator too. I have seen my potential and I need to strengthen

                   because of the help of the people who are always supporting me and guiding me through


                   this journey.

                          As of 2020, I always think that virtual distance learning will be a hindrance to us as

                   future educators someday because we feel that we cannot learn a lot and we can’t practice

                   our profession in this kind of set up. Because of the help of the instructor and professor,

                   they help us to understand how we can understand the routine in virtual teaching. This


                   helps us and me to become more resourceful and creative. When it comes to creativity, I

                   am grateful because the improvement in my creativity is upgrading. Regarding preparing

                   my  lesson  plans  and  instructional  materials,  I  have  seen  my  improvements  too,  from

                   choosing the right colors and design, to adding details that I’ll be adding and delivering the

                   information. In preparing different motivational activities, I also improve a lot, and I have

                   my journal where my list of activity ideas is there to help me to lessen my time spent

                   thinking about what activities I can present to my students. I'm also practicing my craft and


                   arts skills, so even if I’ll be teaching in a face-to-face or virtual set up, my skills will still

                   improve and it may help me to have a beautiful classroom for my future students.

                          I have seen my improvement in creating different objectives in different lessons

                   because I have experience in preparing different lesson plans in private and public. This

                   experience helps me to develop my critical skills. My communication skills also improved.


                   I still have training and practice to do, but I have seen my communication improve when I

                   have this opportunity to teach students within 60 days. I have teaching experience but the

                   medium I have been using has been Filipino. However, in 60 days of training as an intern]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[47


                   for our Practice Teaching, this program has helped me a lot, particularly in building my

                   confidence in using the English language when teaching. I am always afraid to speak

                   English using the English language because I think that my surroundings will laugh at me.

                   But I tried, and I am still learning. Today I embrace myself even more and now I don’t have


                   to be afraid and hide in my comfort zone anymore. I still get nervous, but I know that I am

                   doing the best I can and am preparing myself to teach in the field in the future. I am always

                   ready.  I  am  taking  classes  to  gain  more  skills,  and  I  am  always  acknowledging  my

                   experiences that will help me become a good educator. In this program, I have been given

                   a chance to deeply understand how teaching is incredible because there are lots of things


                   that  need  studying  and  the  learning  is  continuous.  I  also  understand  the  different

                   approaches that I need to know and distinguish between the good approaches I can use

                   in the future. This program helps me to deeply appreciate the life of an educator because

                   it teaches me to be skillful not only in the field but also in virtual classes. There are a lot of

                   differences that I discovered in applying different styles in teaching, and I now understand

                   why  creating  objectives  and  activities  is  a  matter  that  needs  to  be  considered  very

                   important. In learning and familiarizing myself with all the theories and approaches, I hope


                   they stay in my heart and not only in my mind. Understanding the students’ needs and

                   monitoring their performances are all the things that I need to take note of in the future.

                   My improvements are not only in physical but also in emotional and spiritual wellbeing.

                   This  is  because  being  a  future  educator  is  a  profession  that  needs  a  lot  of  love  and

                   consideration for my future students.


                          Furthermore,  from  virtual  field  study  to  virtual  assistantship  to  virtual  practice

                   teaching, I have learned a lot and my skills in preparing myself for virtual demonstration

                   improve every day. I explore every virtual application and platform that may help my virtual

                   classes and am still discovering different tools that I may use in the present and in the

                   future. I am grateful because I have sufficient knowledge in technology; it is not a major

                   issue  for  me;  all  I  want  is  a  lot  of  practice  in  face-to-face  demonstrations  when  the

                   circumstances  allow.  I  a  lot  of  time  to  list  and  I  intend  to  try  and  incorporate  any]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[48


                   improvements I have made in my daily practice using the English medium. In my four years

                   learning about education, I have seen my heart in this and my passion for teaching is

                   burning. I don’t really like this course, but my circumstances in life lead me to take this

                   path. I’ve learned a lot, and every day I grow and appreciate all the things that teachers


                   provide to their students. My training in this field will help me to become the best version

                   of myself in the future. All the people I’ve met or encountered on this path have helped me

                   a lot, inspired me and guided me every step of this journey. I have less doubt in myself

                   today and I embrace different changes or lessons in my life while pursuing this career.

                   This virtual distance learning is a challenge for us, but we still continue and improve every


                   day.

                          I  have  seen  the  process  of  the  lives  of  the  future  teachers  if  they  pursue  this

                   profession. It helps me understand the things I need to accept when I choose this path,

                   and the lives of the teachers are important and should be highlighted. The struggles and

                   efforts they put in for all of their students cannot be compensated with a million or billions

                   of dollars. It’s an eye-opener for me and my classmates that we chose the right profession

                   that may help the world. I have witnessed the public and private teachers' differences in


                   this program. How do public teachers survive the week in this virtual distance learning

                   while handling modular distance eLearning too? I have seen how they manage their time

                   and still give time to their families. It was a very helpful takeaway that I will never forget in

                   my life.

                          One of my best experiences in this program is that when I handled four sections,


                   the students in each section never disrespected me. They treat me like their adviser, and

                   they never show uninterested behavior. I appreciate the participation of my students and

                   having practice teaching, even if it's virtual. It’s like another experience you should not

                   forget. My creativity improves every day and I need to use it every day because helping a

                   student a lot is not just focusing on giving information but also sharing creative activities

                   to improve their creativity too. It was a very challenging day, but I am thankful it happened

                   and I met them in a short period of time. Virtual Practice Teaching prepares us for what to]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[49


                   expect in the field, and we should really prepare ourselves to become a better teacher for

                   the future generation that is coming. In addition, my communication skills developed a lot

                   because in this program, writing and reading are essential. You are not just obliged, but

                   you have a responsibility to help yourself to become better every day. All the lessons and


                   topics that I have encountered in this program give me another perspective that educators

                   are not just choosing their career, but choosing a purpose that helps others. In my four

                   years taking this program, I have experienced a lot, and I never imagined that I could

                   survive all of these struggles. But I am wrong. I survive and every day I grow and grow

                   more to become one of the future educators for our nation.


                          In  conclusion,  all  the  face-to-face  and  virtual  experiences  in  this  field  give  me

                   different experiences that I can use when I am in the field. My confidence in teaching and

                   my  potential  for  becoming  a  future  educator  have  been  seen  by  many  people.  My

                   knowledge,  optimistic  style,  creativity,  and  determination  help  me  a  lot  to  survive  this

                   program. I have knowledge and skills in teaching, whether it is face-to-face or on virtual

                   platforms. It has been seen by a lot of people too. From my day one as a freshman to now

                   that I am a senior, I have changed and improved a lot. My communication skills have


                   improved and I am more confident now than in the past. I still feel nervous, but my self-

                   doubt is now low and my confidence helps me enjoy my journey as a future educator. On

                   this virtual platform, I note different techniques I can use as my reference. I am thankful to

                   all the people who help me and guide me, especially my cooperating teachers while I am

                   taking my practice teaching. I have a lot of realizations from my improvements and from


                   the life of an educator. I never dreamed of becoming a teacher because I don’t have a lot

                   of patience. But after taking this program, I evaluated the whole process of becoming an

                   educator.  It  is  not  only  necessary  to  be  patient,  but  I  must  also  be  passionate  about

                   education and educators. Choosing this path means choosing to help without anything in

                   return. The time and effort that educators give in this career cannot be paid in any amount.

                   Educators are one of the greatest gifts that the world has because without them there will

                   be no other profession that will exist. I can confidently say that I am now involved with my]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[50


                   chosen profession. I may not be the best, but I will strive to be a good role model for my

                   future students and an educator who inspires others to pursue this profession.

                          There is always room for improvement and learning is always there to guide us in

                   our overall experience in every situation. The life of  an educator is not just  a job that


                   involves handling different individuals. It is about supporting and guiding each individual

                   to fully mold their dreams into reality. helping them to choose opportunities, ways and

                   acceptance. preparing them for what comes next in their life choices. This is a life that

                   gives others light so they can see their pathways in life. I am proud of myself and I am

                   grateful for what has come in my life in choosing this blessing to bless others.]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[51



                                                       REFERENCES




                   Garcia, C. (2021). Recognizing Positive and Negative Messages Conveyed in the Text|
                   English 8 Quarter 2 Module 5. https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=LHGudCDigIw

                   Amadora  M.  (2020).  Common  Problems  that  Occur  During  Online  Classes.
                   https://mb.com.ph/2020/09/18/common-problems-that-occur-during-online-classes/

                   English  Grade  8  PIVOT  4A  Learner’s  Material  Quarter  2  Pages  32-36.  (First  Edition).
                   Department of Education Region IV-A CALABARZON

                   Positive  and  Negative  Messages  Introduction.  English  Grade  8  PIVOT  4A  Learner’s
                   Material Quarter 2 Pages 110-130. (First Edition). Department of Education Region IV-A
                   CALABARZON]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[52
























                                                       APPENDICES]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[53


                   Appendix 1. Student information sheet

                                           STUDENT TEACHER INFORMATION SHEET

                                               During the period of Student-Teaching

                                     Begin: October 4, 2021              End: January 03, 2022

                                                                                     Female
                   Name:          Christine Jewel R. Gallos                   Gender:


                   Civil Status:   Single                                     Birthday:   December 22, 1995

                   Major Field of Study:   English

                   Home Address:  Blk 24 Lot 12 Alaska St. Sampaguita Village, Brgy. Inocencio, TMC, Cavite


                   Type of Community in which you have lived the major part of your life:   Rural

                   Father’s   Name:    Richard    S.
                      Gallos               High School Undergraduate
                   Educational Attainment:
                   Occupation: Factory Worker
                   Mother’s Name: Aida R. Gallos
                   Educational Attainment:  College Undergraduate

                   Occupation: Barangay Tanod
                   Family’s    Approximate      Annual
                      Income:   10,000/monthly
                   Family’s    Approximate     Monthly
                      Allowance :   10,00/monthly
                   Number of Children in the Family:   3
                   Older than you:    None                       Younger than you: 2

                   Type of High School graduated from:  Private School
                   How are you being supported in College:
                                                     /
                   ☐    Parents                      ☐  Working Student           ☐  Relatives
                   ☐    Brother/Sister               ☐  Scholarship               ☐  Veterans
                                                      /

                   After graduation, what employment will you seek:  Teaching Profession
                   What occupations other than teaching are you considering after graduation?
                       1.  Digital Marketer
                       2.  Events Coordinator
                       3.  Café Owner

                   What is your reason for pursuing teaching as your course?
                   My circumstances led me to this course; I discovered my calling in teaching, and I
                   decided to put my knowledge to good use by sharing it with everyone who wanted to
                   learn.

                   Which of the following activities do you really like to participate in?
                   ☐  /   Reading                   ☐  Meeting                  ☐  Conversing with people
                                                                                /
                    /
                                                     /
                   ☐    Art                         ☐  Music                    ☐  Dancing
                    /
                   ☐    Movies                      ☐  Athletics                ☐  Tennis
                                                                                 /
                   ☐    Swimming                    ☐  Hunting                  ☐  Camping
                                                                                 /
                   ☐    Card-playing                ☐  Chess                    ☐  Photography

                   Membership in an organization:    Hatag Eskwela
                                                     CORA Volunteers
                                                     OXFAM Philippines
                                                     ECO-Volunteers Philippines
                                                     Theatro of Phenomenal Students

                                                     Federation of Central Student Government

                                                     Central Student Government Tanza Campus
                                                     Circle of Potential Educators
                                                     Anglicists Guild]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[54


                   Honors/Awards received for excellence in school work:

                                Standardized Aptitude Test for Teachers PASSER – 2019
                                                nd
                                Full Scholar – 2  Semester, 2018-2019
                                                nd
                                Full Scholar – 2  Semester, 2019-2020
                                Full Scholar –  1  Semester, 2020-2021
                                                 st
                                                   nd
                                Partial Scholar -  2  Semester, 2020-2021
                                 nd
                                2  Best Researcher Paper (National Research Conference in
                                Arts, Science and Health) - 2019

                                Young Educator Awardee – A.Y 2019-2020
                                Outstanding Student Leader -  A.Y 2019-2020
                                Outstanding Student Leader -  A.Y 2020-2021


                   Talents or skills which you believe are relevant in your student-teaching:
                   I  am  an  excellent  listener  and  an  encourager.  I  enjoyed  reading
                   because it allowed me to share many different experiences and relate
                   them  to real-life circumstances.  I am adaptable and versatile in any
                   situation.

                   What special experiences would you like to get during your student-teaching?
                        1.  When it comes to dealing with my future pupils, I want them to be respectful of
                           all teachers and have good manners, even if I am not present.

                        2.  Because my cooperating teacher is very helpful to me, I want to be a good
                           cooperating teacher in my future student teacher.]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[55



                   Appendix 2. Endorsement letter]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[56


                   Appendix 3. Lesson plan for the final demonstration teaching]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[57]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[58]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[59]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[60]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[61]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[62]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[63]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[64


                   Appendix 4. Guide questions

                                                    GUIDE QUESTIONS


                   What does the Teacher need to think about before beginning?

                       1.  Why am I teaching this lesson?

                              ●  Required curriculum?

                              ●  Student interest in topic?


                              ●  My interest in topic?

                       2.  What do I hope to accomplish?

                              ●  Skill to be developed?

                              ●  Concepts to be discussed for understanding?

                              ●  Product to be produced?

                       3.  Who are the students?

                              ●  Range of abilities?


                              ●  Range of ages?

                              ●  Ethnic diversity and varying cultures?

                       4.  What is the time frame for teaching this lesson?

                              ●  Part of a unit?

                              ●  One period or block schedule?


                              ●  Isolated lesson?

                       5.  How will I begin the lesson to capture student attention?

                              ●  Story or anecdote?

                              ●  Relevance to their lives?

                              ●  Props or visual displays?]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[65


                       6.  Will I need other resources to teach this lesson?

                              ●  Audio visual or technology?

                              ●  Student hand-outs?

                              ●  Manipulative or visual displays?


                       7.  How will students spend their time during the lesson?

                              ●  Small group discussions? Individual? Large group?

                              ●  Hands on activity or experiment?

                              ●  Taking notes or observing?

                       8.  How will this lesson be assessed?


                              ●  Formal? Quiz or test?

                              ●  Informal? Observation of learning?

                              ●  Open-ended question? Written? Verbal?

                       9.  How will I close the lesson or close the class period?

                              ●  Review and summary?

                              ●  Collecting papers and giving assignments?

                              ●  Allowing time for homework or question?


                       10. Will there be homework or enrichment activities offered?

                              ●  How will I collect later? Is it required or extra?

                              ●  Will it count? What is the cooperating teacher’s policy?

                              ●  How will I grade it?

                       11. How will I know if I succeeded in teaching the lesson?


                              ●  Self-assessment?

                              ●  Response of students?

                              ●  Cooperating teacher impart?

                   How will the next lesson relate or build on this one?]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[66


                   Appendix 5. Student teaching rating scale]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[67


                   Appendix 6. Daily time record]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[68]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[69]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[70]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[71




                   Appendix 7. Case study sheet

                                                       CASE STUDY SHEET


                   Name:__________________________  School:__________________________
                   Date of Birth:___________________        Date:____________________________
                   Parents: _______________________         Siblings:_________________________
                   Referral Source:
                   __________________________________________________________________

                   Reasons for referral (specific problem including observable symptoms):
                   __________________________________________________________________

                   Family  Background  (family  relationship,  home  environments,  socio-economic
                   status):
                   __________________________________________________________________
                   Physical   History   (disabilities,   speech   defects,   vision,   height,   weight:
                   __________________________________________________________________


                   School history:
                                 ______________________________________________________
                                 ______________________________________________________
                                 ____
                   Test Data:
                                 Achievement, including reading level:
                                 ______________________________________________________
                                 Aptitude, including mental ability:
                                 ______________________________________________________
                                 Personality and social adjustment (general behavior patterns):

                                 ______________________________________________________
                                 Vocational interest:

                                 ______________________________________________________

                   Interest, hobbies, and experiences:
                                 ______________________________________________________

                   Plan (vocational or educational):
                                 ______________________________________________________

                   General appraisal, interpretation, and hypotheses:
                                 ______________________________________________________
                   Recommendations:
                   __________________________________________________________________
                   __________________________________________________________________
                          Source:
                                 Shertzer and Stone. (1981).  Fundamentals of Guidance.]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[72


                   Appendix 8. Clearance from cooperating school]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[73


                   Appendix 9. Form 138a]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[74


                   Appendix 10. Form 137]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[75


                   Appendix 11. School register]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[76


                   Appendix 12. The pre-service teacher














                                                       Portrait picture

                                          Maximum of 1 picture per page if portrait


















                             Appendix figure 1. Christine Jewel R. Gallos, the pre-service teacher]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[77





































                                Appendix figure 2. Christine Jewel with her co-practice teacher


































                                   Appendix figure 2.1 Christine Jewel with her co-practice teacher]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[78


                   Appendix 13. The cooperating school



































                        Appendix figure 3. Trece Martires City National High School-Main Campus



































                        Appendix figure 3.1 Trece Martires City National High School-Main Campus]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[79


                   Appendix 14. The cooperating teacher
















































                              Appendix  figure  4.  Christine  Jewel  with  her  cooperating

                      teacher]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[80


                   Appendix 15. The students

























                                        Appendix figure 5. Christine Jewel with Class A




































                                          Appendix figure 6. Christine Jewel with Class B]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[81


























                                       Appendix figure 7. Christine Jewel with Class C




































                                        Appendix figure 8. Christine Jewel with Class D]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[82


                   Appendix 16. The observation phase



































                                 Appendix figure 9. Observing the class discussion A



































                                   Appendix figure 9.1 Observing the class discussion B]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[83


                   Appendix 17. The actual teaching phase

































                                        Appendix figure 10.  Teaching the class  A


































                                       Appendix figure 10.1 Teaching the class B]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[84











                                                          3.5” x 5”

                                                     Landscape picture

                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape










                                               Appendix figure 10.2 Teaching the class C









                                                           3.5” x 5”

                                                      Landscape picture

                                          Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape










                                               Appendix figure 10.3 Teaching the class D]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[85


                   Appendix 18. The final demonstration teaching



































                                Appendix figure 11.  Final demonstration with class A


































                                 Appendix figure 11.1 Final demonstration with panelists]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[86


                   Appendix 19. The instructional materials

























                                    Appendix figure 12.  Final demonstration power point
























                          Appendix figure 12.1 Final demonstration power point inspirational message]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[87



























                         Appendix figure 12.2 Final demonstration power point recall a lesson

























                             Appendix figure 12.3 Final demonstration power point objectives]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[88


























                                                                                 st
                            Appendix figure 12.4 Final demonstration power point 1  activity
























                                                                                  st
                             Appendix figure 12.5 Final demonstration power point 1  activity]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[89





























                                                                                   st
                             Appendix figure 12.6 Final demonstration power point 1  activity

























                              Appendix figure 12.7 Final demonstration power point 1  activity
                                                                                    st]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[90





























                                                                                      nd
                                Appendix figure 12.8 Final demonstration power point 2  activity

























                                                                                    nd
                              Appendix figure 12.9 Final demonstration power point 2  activity]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[91









                                                           3.5” x 5”

                                                      Landscape picture

                                         Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape











                             Appendix figure 12.10 Final demonstration power point lesson proper

























                              Appendix figure 12.11 Final demonstration power point lesson proper]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[92









                                                          3.5” x 5”

                                                     Landscape picture

                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape











                            Appendix figure 12.12 Final demonstration power point lesson proper

























                             Appendix figure 12.13 Final demonstration power point lesson proper]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[93











                                                         3.5” x 5”

                                                    Landscape picture

                                       Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape










                            Appendix figure 12.14 Final demonstration power point lesson proper

























                            Appendix figure 12.15 Final demonstration power point lesson proper]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[94


























                            Appendix figure 12.16 Final demonstration power point lesson proper
























                            Appendix figure 12.17 Final demonstration power point lesson proper]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[95












                                                          3.5” x 5”

                                                     Landscape picture

                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape










                          Appendix figure 12.18 Final demonstration power point lesson proper

























                           Appendix figure 12.19 Final demonstration power point lesson proper]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[96



























                             Appendix figure 12.20 Final demonstration power point lesson proper
























                             Appendix figure 12.21 Final demonstration power point lesson proper]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[97









                                                           3.5” x 5”

                                                      Landscape picture

                                         Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape











                              Appendix figure 12.22 Final demonstration power point lesson proper
























                Appendix figure 12.23 Final demonstration power point lesson proper]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[98












                                                          3.5” x 5”

                                                     Landscape picture

                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape










                               Appendix figure 12.24 Final demonstration power point summary
























                            Appendix figure 12.25 Final demonstration power point assessment task 1]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[99









                                                          3.5” x 5”

                                                     Landscape picture

                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape










                    Appendix figure 12.26 Final demonstration power point assessment task 1 answers









                                                          3.5” x 5”

                                                     Landscape picture

                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape










                           Appendix figure 12.27 Final demonstration power point assessment task 2]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[100









                                                          3.5” x 5”

                                                     Landscape picture

                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape










                            Appendix figure 12.28 Final demonstration power point assessment task 2 answers

























                             Appendix figure 12.29 Final demonstration power point homework]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[101













                                                          3.5” x 5”

                                                     Landscape picture


                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape














                              Appendix figure 12.30 Final demonstration power point references













                                                          3.5” x 5”


                                                     Landscape picture

                                        Maximum of 2 pictures per page if landscape














                                     Appendix figure 12.31 Final demonstration power point]]></page></pages></Search>