<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="23"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[AREA III












            CURRICULUM AND






                       INSTRUCTION]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[PARAMETER F












              ADMINISTRATIVE





                        SUPPORT FOR






                                EFFECTIVE





                        INSTRUCTION]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[SYSTEM - INPUTS







                        AND PROCESS]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[S.1.            The institution has policies on:


                        S.1.1.  substitution or special


                                       arrangements whenever a

                                       teacher is on leave or absent;]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Policies on Scheduling and Conduct


                         of Classes - Make Up Classes

























                      Lifted from 2009 CvSU Manual of


                       Operations, Volume 1, pp 87-88]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ________________________________________________________________________  88


                                                  Special class- below         --  ten (10) students;


                                 Should  the  class  size  fall  below  the  minimum  number,  the
                              Department  Head  should  be  informed  immediately  to  decide
                              whether  to  dissolve  the  class  or  to  maintain  it  as  a  special  class
                              approved by the Dean of the College. Should the class be dissolved,
                              faculty  members  should  advise  the  student  to  transfer  to  other
                              classes.
                          d)    First  Day  of  Classes.  During  the  first  day  of  classes,  faculty
                              members should sign the registration forms of their students and
                              collect their class cards or registration forms. The class cards serve
                              as evidence that the students are officially enrolled in the class.
                                         A  student  is  considered  officially  enrolled  only  after  the
                                         following steps are satisfied:
                                       University Registrar has duly certified the enrollment on
                                         the registration cards.

                                         University Cashier has stamped on the required forms an
                                         acknowledgement of payment of fees, and

                                       Professors/instructors  have  placed  their  initials  or
                                         signatures on the registration cards.
                                     The  class  list,  issued  by  the  Office  of  the  University
                              Registrar, provides the name of the students, regular or irregular,
                              officially  enrolled  in  a  course.  Faculty  members  should  get  their
                              class lists from their Department Head on the first day of classes.
                                         Moreover,  faculty  members  should  orient  the  students
                              about the objectives, contents and requirements of the course, and
                              explain  the  bases  for  evaluating  students’  performance.  It  is
                              recommended  that  the  students  be  provided  with  a  copy  of  the
                              course syllabus.

                          e)  Class Meetings and Dismissal of Classes. Punctuality should  be
                              observed at all times in the conduct of classes. If the class should
                              start at 7 a.m., the faculty should be in the classroom at exactly

                               7 a.m. Classes should be dismissed at least five (5) minutes before
                              the end of each period to allow students to move and transfer to
                              their next class.

                          f) Make-Up Classes. Faculty members who miss their classes due to
                              official  functions  should  conduct  make-up  activities/classes.
                              Make-up  activities/classes  should  be  for  both  extra  and  regular
                              teaching  assignments.  Request  forms  for  make-up  classes  are
                              available at the Dean’s Office.

                                                                                                           88]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Make Up Class Slip]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          414-3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                             Teacher Education Department

                                                 MAKE UP CLASS SLIP
                                           ________ Semester, AY 2020 – 2021

                                      CLASS NOT ATTENDED
                              Year and                                                        Date and Time of
         Date and Time                         Subject                 Reason                  Make Up Class
                              Section








        Requested by:                              Recommending Approval:              Approved:


        _________________________                  MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSC
        Instructor/Professor Concerned             Department Chair                    Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
  414-3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
 www.cvsu.edu.ph

 Teacher Education Department

 MAKE UP CLASS SLIP
 ________ Semester, AY 2020 – 2021

 CLASS NOT ATTENDED
 Year and                         Date and Time of
 Date and Time   Subject   Reason   Make Up Class
 Section








 Requested by:             Recommending Approval:      Approved:


 _________________________      MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN      NOEL A. SEDIGO, MSC
 Instructor/Professor Concerned      Department Chair         Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                        CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                               Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                          414-3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph

                                             Teacher Education Department

                                                 MAKE UP CLASS SLIP
                                           ________ Semester, AY 2021 – 2022

                                      CLASS NOT ATTENDED
                              Year and                                                        Date and Time of
         Date and Time                         Subject                 Reason                  Make Up Class
                              Section








        Requested by:                              Recommending Approval:              Approved:


        _________________________                  MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN                GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
        Instructor/Professor Concerned             Department Chair                    Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
  414-3979 ǀ  410-5247 ǀ  437-0693
 www.cvsu.edu.ph

 Teacher Education Department

 MAKE UP CLASS SLIP
 ________ Semester, AY 2021 – 2022

 CLASS NOT ATTENDED
 Year and                         Date and Time of
 Date and Time   Subject   Reason   Make Up Class
 Section








 Requested by:             Recommending Approval:      Approved:


 _________________________      MILDRED A. SEBASTIAN      GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
 Instructor/Professor Concerned      Department Chair         Campus Administrator]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Policies on Scheduling and Conduct


                         of Classes - Make Up Classes

























                      Lifted from 2009 CvSU Manual of


                           Operations, Volume 2, p 99]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[CvSU MANUAL OF OPERATIONS
                   ______________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                         99

                   unit  heads/deans  should  justify  that  the  change  would  benefit  their
                   unit/college in particular and the University in general. If a faculty member
                   pursued  a  program  authorized  by  the  University  but  which  is  not  in  line
                   with his field of specialization or not needed by his college/unit, he will be
                   required  to  transfer  to  another  college/unit  within  the  University  System
                   that needs such field of study/specialization.

                           A  scholar  who  changes  his  field  of  specialization  without  prior
                   approval  will  be  required  to  reinstate  and  refund  in  full  all  expenses
                   incurred during his scholarship to include tuition and other fees, stipend,
                   book allowance, thesis allowance, salary and other financial incentives.


                   Section 9. Leave of Absence

                          A total maximum leave of absence equivalent to one school year may
                   be granted to the faculty member or staff on scholarship upon prior request
                   based on meritorious reasons subject to the submission of an approved LOA
                   from  the  graduate  school  and  approval  of  the  University  President  upon
                   recommendation of the Scholarship Committee. The scholar on LOA shall be
                   required  to  reinstate  to  the  University  and  shall  not  be  entitled  to
                   allowances  of  a  scholar.  The  period  of  reinstatement  is  good  only  for  the
                   length  of  the  approved  LOA  unless  otherwise  approved  by  higher
                   authorities.

                   Section10. Length of Study

                          Faculty members and staff on scholarship are allowed a maximum of
                   two  (2)  years  to  finish  their  MA/MS/MBA/related  degrees  and  three  (3)
                   years to finish their Ph.D./DBA/related degrees excluding the period of their
                   approved LOA.


                   Section 11. Extension of Scholarship

                          Extension  of  scholarship  beyond  the  period  specified  in  Section  10
                   may be allowed only for five (5) months with full privileges upon certification
                   of  the  Adviser  that  the  scholar  can  finish  the  course  within  the  extension
                   period  and  the  Scholarship  Committee  has  determined  that  normal  credit
                   loads have been taken every semester. An additional extension for less than
                   or  maximum  of  five  (5)  months  only  on  official  time  and  without  stipend
                   could  be  granted  for  meritorious  reasons  and  certification  of  the  adviser
                   and/or dean of the graduate school.



                                                                                                           99]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                           CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                        Tanza Campus
                                                Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                     (046) 414-3979
                                                    www.cvsu.edu.ph


               23 August 2021


               DR. HERNANDO D. ROBLES
               President
               This University
                                                                                      A-210901-2321
                                                                                      ED

               Dear Dr. Robles:                                                       09-01-2021

               Good day!

               This is to inform you of my intention to take maternity leave from work from August 20, 2021
               to December 2, 2021. Rest assured that I will do my best to make up for any important matters
               upon my return. I have attached the medical certificate from my doctor and other maternity
               details.

               I am hoping for your kind approval regarding this request. Thank you very much.


               Very truly yours,


               MARY ROSE E. ELAMPARO
               Instructor I


               Recommending Approval:


               GIL D. RAMOS, MAHisto
               Campus Administrator



               MA. AGNES P. NUESTRO, PhD
               Vice President for Academic Affairs



               Approved:


            for: HERNANDO D. ROBLES, EdD, CEO VI
               University President

                                                                     O - 2080
                                                                     ED
                                                                     09-10-2021]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[August 2021

                                    0               0





















                                            for:]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>