<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="31"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[I.4.            The following updated records are


                        made available to concerned parties:


                        I.4.5.  other records such as:

                                        I.4.5.2.  alumni directory;]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                     CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                              Tanza Campus
                                                                           Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                ( 414-3979
                                                                                www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                                            LIST OF GRADUATES
                                                                      SECOND SEMESTER AY, 2021 - 2022

         No.               Name                           Course/Program                                               Address
          1  ALCANA JOCELYN C.                 BS Business Management               Blk 31 Lot 12 Ph6, Carissa Homes, Punta, Tanza, Cavite
          2  ALFARO ROCKY NEIL E.              BS Hospitality Management            B-41, L-23 Sunrise Place, Tres Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
          3  ALIVIA NOREN B.                   BSE major in English                 422 B-1, L-30, P-1 St. Henry Homes, Amaya II, Tanza, Cavite
          4  AMISTOSO CHRISTIAN S.             BS Business Management               P-1, L-13, B-8, S-6, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          5  ANTONIO SPHENLER G.               BS Business Management               Brgy. De Ocampo, Trece Martires City, Cavite
          6  ARROYO KIM                        BS Business Management               B-4, L-1, S-25, P-2, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          7  ASIDO ANNSHERINA G.               BS Business Management               B-16, L-38, P-1, Carissa Homes Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          8  AZUELO MICHELLE ANNE B.           Diploma in Hospitality Management    B2 L20 S7 Pabahay Ph1, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          9  BAJO JENELYN D.                   BSE major in English                 B-8, L-4, S-17, P-2, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          10 BARAOED SHEENA MAE D.             BS Business Management               P-1 Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          11 BARRISO CHRISTIAN J.              BS Hospitality Management            B-3, L-5, P-3, Brgy. Aguado, Trece Martires City, Cavite
          12 BASA MARY JOY B.                  BS Hospitality Management            B-15, L-16, S-15, P-2, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          13 BASCO DANICA ANNA Q.              BS Hospitality Management            B-11, L-4, S-19, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          14 BERNALES IZZA C.                  BS Hospitality Management            B-33, L-24 Sunrise Place P-2, Brgy. Tres Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
          15 BRANZUELA KASSELLE SHANE L.       BSE major in English                 B-7, L-2, S-17, Belvedere III, Pasong Kawayan II, Gen. Trias, Cavite
          16 BRIONES GRACE ANNE L.             BSE major in English                 B-57, L-11, P-2, Carissa, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          17 BRUNO JANICA EUNICE B.            BSE major in English                 Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
          18 BUENA KAYLA C.                    BSE major in English                 Calle 30, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          19 CABIQUE JOLINA MAY S.             BS Business Management               B-11, L-19, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          20 CABUHAT REMELIE D.                BS Business Management               093 Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
          21 CAJULIS MILDRED S.                BS Business Management               P-1, S-6, B-8, L-11, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          22 CALINDATAS IVY O.                 BS Business Management               Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          23 CASICAS RYAN JAY T.               BS Information Technology            B-7, L-19, P-1, S-2, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          24 CASTRO JACQUELYN A.               BSE major in Mathematics             B-14, L-10, P-2, Lumina, Tanza, Cavite
          25 COROS ELSA C.                     BSE major in English                 Brgy. Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite
          26 CRUZ MA. SOFIA S.                 Diploma in Hospitality Management    Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          27 CUEVA MARK ANTHONY D.             BS Hospitality Management            B-4, L-4, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          28 CUPINO ANGELIKA M.                BS Hospitality Management            B-13, L-6, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          29 DALIGCON GELDAIN L.               BS Business Management               B-34, L-20, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          30 DE CLARO ELLEN GRACE P.           BS Business Management               B-4, L-8, Castillon Homes, The Residences, Brgy. Pasong Kawayan 2, General Trias, Cavite
          31 DE TORRES JOYCE D.                BSE major in Mathematics             B-15, L-13, S-35, Belleview, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          32 DELA PEÑA LORIE JANE F.           BS Business Management               L-1, B-22, P-6, Punta Carissa, Tanza, Cavite
          33 DELOS REYES MARY DALE A.          BS Business Management               B-27, L-6, West Plain Subd., Brgy. De Ocampo, Trece Martires City, Cavite



                                                                                                                                                    Page 1 of 4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza Campus
 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 ( 414-3979
 www.cvsu.edu.ph


 LIST OF GRADUATES
 SECOND SEMESTER AY, 2021 - 2022

 No.   Name  Course/Program        Address
 1  ALCANA JOCELYN C.  BS Business Management  Blk 31 Lot 12 Ph6, Carissa Homes, Punta, Tanza, Cavite
 2  ALFARO ROCKY NEIL E.  BS Hospitality Management  B-41, L-23 Sunrise Place, Tres Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
 3  ALIVIA NOREN B.  BSE major in English  422 B-1, L-30, P-1 St. Henry Homes, Amaya II, Tanza, Cavite
 4  AMISTOSO CHRISTIAN S.  BS Business Management  P-1, L-13, B-8, S-6, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 5  ANTONIO SPHENLER G.  BS Business Management  Brgy. De Ocampo, Trece Martires City, Cavite
 6  ARROYO KIM   BS Business Management  B-4, L-1, S-25, P-2, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 7  ASIDO ANNSHERINA G.  BS Business Management  B-16, L-38, P-1, Carissa Homes Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 8  AZUELO MICHELLE ANNE B.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  B2 L20 S7 Pabahay Ph1, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 9  BAJO JENELYN D.  BSE major in English  B-8, L-4, S-17, P-2, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 10 BARAOED SHEENA MAE D.  BS Business Management  P-1 Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 11 BARRISO CHRISTIAN J.  BS Hospitality Management  B-3, L-5, P-3, Brgy. Aguado, Trece Martires City, Cavite
 12 BASA MARY JOY B.  BS Hospitality Management  B-15, L-16, S-15, P-2, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 13 BASCO DANICA ANNA Q.  BS Hospitality Management  B-11, L-4, S-19, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 14 BERNALES IZZA C.  BS Hospitality Management  B-33, L-24 Sunrise Place P-2, Brgy. Tres Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
 15 BRANZUELA KASSELLE SHANE L.  BSE major in English  B-7, L-2, S-17, Belvedere III, Pasong Kawayan II, Gen. Trias, Cavite
 16 BRIONES GRACE ANNE L.  BSE major in English  B-57, L-11, P-2, Carissa, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 17 BRUNO JANICA EUNICE B.  BSE major in English  Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
 18 BUENA KAYLA C.  BSE major in English  Calle 30, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 19 CABIQUE JOLINA MAY S.  BS Business Management  B-11, L-19, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 20 CABUHAT REMELIE D.  BS Business Management  093 Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
 21 CAJULIS MILDRED S.  BS Business Management  P-1, S-6, B-8, L-11, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 22 CALINDATAS IVY O.  BS Business Management  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 23 CASICAS RYAN JAY T.  BS Information Technology  B-7, L-19, P-1, S-2, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 24 CASTRO JACQUELYN A.  BSE major in Mathematics  B-14, L-10, P-2, Lumina, Tanza, Cavite
 25 COROS ELSA C.  BSE major in English  Brgy. Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite
 26 CRUZ MA. SOFIA S.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 27 CUEVA MARK ANTHONY D.  BS Hospitality Management  B-4, L-4, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 28 CUPINO ANGELIKA M.  BS Hospitality Management  B-13, L-6, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 29 DALIGCON GELDAIN L.  BS Business Management  B-34, L-20, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 30 DE CLARO ELLEN GRACE P.  BS Business Management  B-4, L-8, Castillon Homes, The Residences, Brgy. Pasong Kawayan 2, General Trias, Cavite
 31 DE TORRES JOYCE D.  BSE major in Mathematics  B-15, L-13, S-35, Belleview, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 32 DELA PEÑA LORIE JANE F.  BS Business Management  L-1, B-22, P-6, Punta Carissa, Tanza, Cavite
 33 DELOS REYES MARY DALE A.  BS Business Management  B-27, L-6, West Plain Subd., Brgy. De Ocampo, Trece Martires City, Cavite



                                                                Page 1 of 4]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[34 DELOS SANTOS MARK CHRISTIAN R.    BS Information Technology            B-5, L-22, P-2A, Belvedere Town, Paradahan I, Tanza, Cavite
          35 DIAZ KHAILA M.                    BSE major in English                 B-1, L-25, S-33, Belleview Meadows, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          36 DICHOSO JOSEPHINE N.              BSE major in Mathematics             B-11, L-47, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          37 ECLEONEL JESSICA N.               BS Hospitality Management            Remulla Drive, Sahud-Ulan, Tanza, Cavite
          38 ENCARNACION JHEANN L.             BS Business Management               B-10, L-12, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          39 ESPENILLA JANNESA L.              BS Business Management               B-16, L-48, Heart Foundation, Punta I, Tanza, Cavite
          40 ESTERA JUNEL F.                   BS Business Management               0286 Calle 30, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          41 FELIZARDO PAULA V.                BS Business Management               B-11, L-28, P-3A, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          42 FERNAN RYAN V.                    BS Business Management               P-2, Pabahay, S-19, B-7, L-21, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          43 FRESADO JENNY D.                  BS Hospitality Management            B-23, L-8, Grandiosa Subd., Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite
          44 GADORES MARK JHON O.              BSE major in English                 Dasmariñas City, Cavite
          45 GALLOS CHRISTINE JEWEL R.         BSE major in English                 B-24, L-12, Alaska St., Sampaguita Village, Brgy, Inocencio, Trece Martires City, Cavite
          46 GAMUYAO FELIPE A.                 BS Hospitality Management            Sitio Burol, Tejeros Convention, Rosario, Cavite
          47 GARZON JOHN CHRISTOPHER B.        BS Information Technology            B-39, L-12, P-2-1A, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          48 GEAMAL MARY ANNE O.               BS Hospitality Management            B-3, L-23, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          49 GENESIS ALYSSA R.                 BS Business Management               P-2, B-5, L-7, S-25, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          50 GEROLLO JERFAULYN A.              BS Business Management               B-43, L-29, Brgy. Acacia, Silang, Cavite
          51 GIANAN KIMBERLY MAE B.            BS Business Management               BLK 56 lot 36 phase7 Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          52 GONZALES AENDRIAN U.              Diploma in Hospitality Management    098, Brgy Tres Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
          53 GOTERA SUSAN B.                   BS Business Management               B-9, L-11, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          54 GRAPANI JESSA D.                  BS Business Management               B-12, L-4, Kalliste Subd., Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          55 IGNACIO CRISTINA P.               BS Hospitality Management            B-12, L-7, P-2, S-16, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          56 IGTOS REYMER JOY A.               BS Business Management               B-42, L-11, P-1A, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          57 ILAGAN MABELAINE M.               BS Hospitality Management            B-7, L-5, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          58 JOAQUIN RJ ROMULO A.              BS Business Management               B-7, L-19, P-3B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          59 LAPIG JOANNA LEI P.               BSE major in English                 Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          60 LATRE LOTLOT J.                   BS Business Management               B-10, L-11, Castillon Homes, Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
          61 LLAVOR GERDA FLOR M.              BS Information Technology            P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          62 LOMUNTAD ARIEL D.                 BSE major in English                 B-6, L-30, Workers Ville, Bunga, Tanza, Cavite
          63 MACABENTA RAMESIS F.              BSE major in English                 B-40, L-20, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          64 MADRIO MARY ANNA B.               BS Business Management               B-25, L-21, P-5, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          65 MAGBANUA ROMEL M.                 Diploma in Hospitality Management    Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          66 MAIWAT LAURENCE N.                BSE major in English                 B-2, L-39, S-12, Belvedere III, Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
          67 MANALO JOY                        BSE major in English                 Heart Foundation, Brgy. Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite
          68 MANGUIAT AIRA KLARISSE H.         BS Hospitality Management            B-01, L-107, Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite
          69 MARCELINO LOVELYN V.              BS Hospitality Management            Brgy. Saluysoy, Trece Martires City, Cavite
          70 MARCOSO RYAN M.                   BS Information Technology            Paradahan I, Tanza, Cavite
          71 MARQUEZ EMIE ROSE C.              BS Hospitality Management            Brgy. Punta I, Tanza, Cavite
          72 MEDRANO GISELLE L.                BS Business Management               P-1, B-8, L-3, S-6, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          73 MELITON GLORIA P.                 BS Information Technology            Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          74 MEQUIABAS CARL CHRISTIAN T.       BS Business Management               B-25, L-19, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          75 MIRAMBEL JOHN MARK D.             BSE major in English                 Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
          76 MISLOS MARVIN T.                  BS Information Technology            Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          77 MOLINAS CARLA A.                  BS Business Management               P-3, B-34, L-38, Carissa Homes, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          78 MONZALES JEREMIAH E.              BS Business Management               B-12, L-2, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          79 MORADA JOFHEL J.                  BS Business Management               B-4, L-3, S-25, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite



                                                                                                                                                    Page 2 of 4]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[34 DELOS SANTOS MARK CHRISTIAN R.  BS Information Technology  B-5, L-22, P-2A, Belvedere Town, Paradahan I, Tanza, Cavite
 35 DIAZ KHAILA M.  BSE major in English  B-1, L-25, S-33, Belleview Meadows, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 36 DICHOSO JOSEPHINE N.  BSE major in Mathematics  B-11, L-47, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 37 ECLEONEL JESSICA N.  BS Hospitality Management  Remulla Drive, Sahud-Ulan, Tanza, Cavite
 38 ENCARNACION JHEANN L.  BS Business Management  B-10, L-12, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 39 ESPENILLA JANNESA L.  BS Business Management  B-16, L-48, Heart Foundation, Punta I, Tanza, Cavite
 40 ESTERA JUNEL F.  BS Business Management  0286 Calle 30, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 41 FELIZARDO PAULA V.  BS Business Management  B-11, L-28, P-3A, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 42 FERNAN RYAN V.  BS Business Management  P-2, Pabahay, S-19, B-7, L-21, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 43 FRESADO JENNY D.  BS Hospitality Management  B-23, L-8, Grandiosa Subd., Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite
 44 GADORES MARK JHON O.  BSE major in English  Dasmariñas City, Cavite
 45 GALLOS CHRISTINE JEWEL R.  BSE major in English  B-24, L-12, Alaska St., Sampaguita Village, Brgy, Inocencio, Trece Martires City, Cavite
 46 GAMUYAO FELIPE A.  BS Hospitality Management  Sitio Burol, Tejeros Convention, Rosario, Cavite
 47 GARZON JOHN CHRISTOPHER B.  BS Information Technology  B-39, L-12, P-2-1A, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 48 GEAMAL MARY ANNE O.  BS Hospitality Management  B-3, L-23, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 49 GENESIS ALYSSA R.  BS Business Management  P-2, B-5, L-7, S-25, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 50 GEROLLO JERFAULYN A.  BS Business Management  B-43, L-29, Brgy. Acacia, Silang, Cavite
 51 GIANAN KIMBERLY MAE B.  BS Business Management  BLK 56 lot 36 phase7 Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 52 GONZALES AENDRIAN U.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  098, Brgy Tres Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
 53 GOTERA SUSAN B.  BS Business Management  B-9, L-11, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 54 GRAPANI JESSA D.  BS Business Management  B-12, L-4, Kalliste Subd., Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 55 IGNACIO CRISTINA P.  BS Hospitality Management  B-12, L-7, P-2, S-16, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 56 IGTOS REYMER JOY A.  BS Business Management  B-42, L-11, P-1A, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 57 ILAGAN MABELAINE M.  BS Hospitality Management  B-7, L-5, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 58 JOAQUIN RJ ROMULO A.  BS Business Management  B-7, L-19, P-3B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 59 LAPIG JOANNA LEI P.  BSE major in English  Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 60 LATRE LOTLOT J.  BS Business Management  B-10, L-11, Castillon Homes, Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
 61 LLAVOR GERDA FLOR M.  BS Information Technology  P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 62 LOMUNTAD ARIEL D.  BSE major in English  B-6, L-30, Workers Ville, Bunga, Tanza, Cavite
 63 MACABENTA RAMESIS F.  BSE major in English  B-40, L-20, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 64 MADRIO MARY ANNA B.  BS Business Management  B-25, L-21, P-5, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 65 MAGBANUA ROMEL M.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 66 MAIWAT LAURENCE N.  BSE major in English  B-2, L-39, S-12, Belvedere III, Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
 67 MANALO JOY   BSE major in English  Heart Foundation, Brgy. Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite
 68 MANGUIAT AIRA KLARISSE H.  BS Hospitality Management  B-01, L-107, Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite
 69 MARCELINO LOVELYN V.  BS Hospitality Management  Brgy. Saluysoy, Trece Martires City, Cavite
 70 MARCOSO RYAN M.  BS Information Technology  Paradahan I, Tanza, Cavite
 71 MARQUEZ EMIE ROSE C.  BS Hospitality Management  Brgy. Punta I, Tanza, Cavite
 72 MEDRANO GISELLE L.  BS Business Management  P-1, B-8, L-3, S-6, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 73 MELITON GLORIA P.  BS Information Technology  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 74 MEQUIABAS CARL CHRISTIAN T.  BS Business Management  B-25, L-19, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 75 MIRAMBEL JOHN MARK D.  BSE major in English  Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
 76 MISLOS MARVIN T.  BS Information Technology  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 77 MOLINAS CARLA A.  BS Business Management  P-3, B-34, L-38, Carissa Homes, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 78 MONZALES JEREMIAH E.  BS Business Management  B-12, L-2, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 79 MORADA JOFHEL J.  BS Business Management  B-4, L-3, S-25, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite



                                                                Page 2 of 4]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[80 MORAÑA MARY ROSE S.               BSE major in English                 521 A Brgy. Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite
          81 MORTEGA DARWIN C.                 BS Information Technology            Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          82 MURALLOS MANILYN O.               BS Hospitality Management            P-2, Carissa Homes, Tanza, Cavite
          83 NAVA JEIZEL D.                    BS Business Management               B-5, L-17, S-15, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          84 NORBE ROMEO P.                    BSE major in Mathematics             P-3B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          85 NUÑEZ JOSAN V.                    BS Business Management               B-2, L-39, S-12, Belvedere III, Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
          86 OJEÑAR MARY-ANN G.                BSE major in Mathematics             Paradahan II, Pabahay 2000, Tanza, Cavite
          87 OLAN ANGELIKA L.                  BS Business Management               MM Worker Ville, Bunga, Tanza, Cavite
          88 OROG JAMES M.                     BS Hospitality Management            Langkaan II, FCIE, Dasmariñas City, Cavite
          89 PAJULAS JENNY S.                  BS Business Management               Belleview Meadows, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          90 PANTE BERNARD E.                  BSE major in English                 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          91 PASCO JAMAICA Q.                  BS Hospitality Management            275 Tramo, Amaya I, Tanza, Cavite
          92 PECENIO CELESTIE S.               BS Business Management               B-13, L-2, P-1, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          93 PENES MAYRILLE SHEY A.            BSE major in English                 P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          94 PEREZ PRINCESS GIA V.             BSE major in English                 B-36, L-31, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta, Tanza, Cavite
          95 PERUCHO JORIEL O.                 BSE major in English                 Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          96 PINGKIAN ELIZABETH A.             BSE major in Mathematics             Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite
          97 PISAW MARY ROSE A.                BS Business Management               B-5, L-14, S-22, P-2, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
          98 PLACEROS AN MARIE B.              BS Hospitality Management            B-30, L-57, P-7, Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite
          99 PLASENCIA LAHREN GRACE G.         BS Business Management               B-9, L-22, Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
         100 POMOY TRESHA MAE A.               BS Business Management               Brgy. Santiago, General Trias, Cavite
         101 PRESTO FLORIDA MAE C.             BS Business Management               Arahan Compound, Punta 2, Tanza, Cavite
         102 QUINES GERALDINE D.               BSE major in Mathematics             Belleview Meadows, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         103 QUINTANA DAVE JHON P.             BS Business Management               B-43, L-21, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         104 QUISTO HONEY ROSE R.              BSE major in English                 B-43, L-3, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         105 REDUBLA NICOLE C.                 BS Hospitality Management            B-173, L-3, Bixbite St., Grand Cedar Crest Antel Grand Village, Bacao II, General Trias, Cavite
         106 REGULACION CHIMNIEDEL G.          BS Business Management               B-3, L-9, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         107 REYES LORIVIC P.                  BS Business Management               B-3, L-5, S-25, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         108 REYES MA. WOODELYN P.             BSE major in Mathematics             B-7, L-40, S-19, P-2, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         109 REYES SHARINE ANGELU I.           BS Hospitality Management            B-12, L-7, P-2, S-16, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         110 RIN JAN ERIC C.                   BSE major in English                 P-4, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         111 RIVERA MICA ELLA P.               BS Business Management               B-10, L-10, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         112 ROSARIO IMEE M.                   BSE major in English                 B-155, L-4&6, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta I, Tanza, Cavite
         113 ROSAS MARIEL G.                   BS Hospitality Management            B-3, L-9, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         114 SAGADAL JESSICA C.                BS Business Management               B-23, 1408 Grandiosa, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         115 SALVADOR JAYRALD C.               BS Hospitality Management            Purok I, Brgy. Panungyanan, General Trias, Cavite
         116 SANCHEZ GIRLIE L.                 BS Hospitality Management            Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
         117 SANDOY CLAIRE P.                  BS Business Management               Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
         118 SANTOS AYN CLARICE A              BS Information Technology            Carissa, Tanza, Cavite
         119 SEREÑO LEME JANE B.               BS Business Management               Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         120 SERRANO JOHN ALDRIN B.            BS Business Management               B-79, L-6, P-3A, Carissa Homes, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         121 SIXTA REMY ROSE R.                BSE major in English                 Paradahan I, Tanza, Cavite
         122 SOSA JESICA M.                    BS Hospitality Management            347 Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
         123 SUMALDE CRISTINE JOY T.           BS Business Management               B-1, L-31, P-2, Lumina, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite



                                                                                                                                                    Page 3 of 4]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[80 MORAÑA MARY ROSE S.  BSE major in English  521 A Brgy. Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite
 81 MORTEGA DARWIN C.  BS Information Technology  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 82 MURALLOS MANILYN O.  BS Hospitality Management  P-2, Carissa Homes, Tanza, Cavite
 83 NAVA JEIZEL D.  BS Business Management  B-5, L-17, S-15, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 84 NORBE ROMEO P.  BSE major in Mathematics  P-3B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 85 NUÑEZ JOSAN V.  BS Business Management  B-2, L-39, S-12, Belvedere III, Pasong Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
 86 OJEÑAR MARY-ANN G.  BSE major in Mathematics  Paradahan II, Pabahay 2000, Tanza, Cavite
 87 OLAN ANGELIKA L.  BS Business Management  MM Worker Ville, Bunga, Tanza, Cavite
 88 OROG JAMES M.  BS Hospitality Management  Langkaan II, FCIE, Dasmariñas City, Cavite
 89 PAJULAS JENNY S.  BS Business Management  Belleview Meadows, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 90 PANTE BERNARD E.  BSE major in English  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 91 PASCO JAMAICA Q.  BS Hospitality Management  275 Tramo, Amaya I, Tanza, Cavite
 92 PECENIO CELESTIE S.  BS Business Management  B-13, L-2, P-1, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 93 PENES MAYRILLE SHEY A.  BSE major in English  P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 94 PEREZ PRINCESS GIA V.  BSE major in English  B-36, L-31, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta, Tanza, Cavite
 95 PERUCHO JORIEL O.  BSE major in English  Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 96 PINGKIAN ELIZABETH A.  BSE major in Mathematics  Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite
 97 PISAW MARY ROSE A.  BS Business Management  B-5, L-14, S-22, P-2, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 98 PLACEROS AN MARIE B.  BS Hospitality Management  B-30, L-57, P-7, Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite
 99 PLASENCIA LAHREN GRACE G.  BS Business Management  B-9, L-22, Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
 100 POMOY TRESHA MAE A.  BS Business Management  Brgy. Santiago, General Trias, Cavite
 101 PRESTO FLORIDA MAE C.  BS Business Management  Arahan Compound, Punta 2, Tanza, Cavite
 102 QUINES GERALDINE D.  BSE major in Mathematics  Belleview Meadows, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 103 QUINTANA DAVE JHON P.  BS Business Management  B-43, L-21, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 104 QUISTO HONEY ROSE R.  BSE major in English  B-43, L-3, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 105 REDUBLA NICOLE C.  BS Hospitality Management  B-173, L-3, Bixbite St., Grand Cedar Crest Antel Grand Village, Bacao II, General Trias, Cavite
 106 REGULACION CHIMNIEDEL G.  BS Business Management  B-3, L-9, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 107 REYES LORIVIC P.  BS Business Management  B-3, L-5, S-25, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 108 REYES MA. WOODELYN P.  BSE major in Mathematics  B-7, L-40, S-19, P-2, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 109 REYES SHARINE ANGELU I.  BS Hospitality Management  B-12, L-7, P-2, S-16, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 110 RIN JAN ERIC C.  BSE major in English  P-4, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 111 RIVERA MICA ELLA P.  BS Business Management  B-10, L-10, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 112 ROSARIO IMEE M.  BSE major in English  B-155, L-4&6, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta I, Tanza, Cavite
 113 ROSAS MARIEL G.  BS Hospitality Management  B-3, L-9, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 114 SAGADAL JESSICA C.  BS Business Management  B-23, 1408 Grandiosa, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 115 SALVADOR JAYRALD C.  BS Hospitality Management  Purok I, Brgy. Panungyanan, General Trias, Cavite
 116 SANCHEZ GIRLIE L.  BS Hospitality Management  Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
 117 SANDOY CLAIRE P.  BS Business Management  Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
 118 SANTOS AYN CLARICE A  BS Information Technology  Carissa, Tanza, Cavite
 119 SEREÑO LEME JANE B.  BS Business Management  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 120 SERRANO JOHN ALDRIN B.  BS Business Management  B-79, L-6, P-3A, Carissa Homes, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 121 SIXTA REMY ROSE R.  BSE major in English  Paradahan I, Tanza, Cavite
 122 SOSA JESICA M.  BS Hospitality Management  347 Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
 123 SUMALDE CRISTINE JOY T.  BS Business Management  B-1, L-31, P-2, Lumina, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite



                                                                Page 3 of 4]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[124 TABUA ANGEL L.                    BS Business Management               0110 Carissa Homes, Phase 1, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         125 TAMIO RAVEN C.                    BS Hospitality Management            B-12, L-60, Heart Foundation, Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
         126 TESORERO GINA T.                  BS Business Management               B-35, L-44&46, P-7, Carissa Homes, Tanza, Cavite
         127 TURLA MARIA NIÑA M.               BS Business Management               B-14, L-2, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         128 TUTAS ANALIE V.                   Diploma in Hospitality Management    Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         129 UBALEZ JO MYCA P.                 BSE major in Mathematics             B-17, L-25, P-2, Hesper St., Sunrise Place, Brgy. Tres Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
         130 VILLAFLOR CHARITY D.              BS Business Management               B-4, L-5, S-10, P-1, Brgy. Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
         131 VITOBINA IAN EFRAME A.            BS Hospitality Management            Amaya I, Tanza, Cavite
         132 VOLANTE ROSE ANN G.               BSE major in English                 B-6, L-16, P-1, S-8, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         133 YAÑEZ BRIX AUBREY C.              BS Hospitality Management            B-13, L-6, S-23, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
         134 YNOPIA ELMER G.                   BSE major in Mathematics             B-11, L-13, P-3A, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite


         Prepared by:                                                               Reviewed by:



         CHARLENE L. DELAS ALAS                                                     NOEMI A. PERIDA
         Registrar Aide                                                             Campus Registrar


         Noted by:



         GIL D. RAMOS
         Campus Administrator






























                                                                                                                                                    Page 4 of 4]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[124 TABUA ANGEL L.  BS Business Management  0110 Carissa Homes, Phase 1, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 125 TAMIO RAVEN C.  BS Hospitality Management  B-12, L-60, Heart Foundation, Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite
 126 TESORERO GINA T.  BS Business Management  B-35, L-44&46, P-7, Carissa Homes, Tanza, Cavite
 127 TURLA MARIA NIÑA M.  BS Business Management  B-14, L-2, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 128 TUTAS ANALIE V.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 129 UBALEZ JO MYCA P.  BSE major in Mathematics  B-17, L-25, P-2, Hesper St., Sunrise Place, Brgy. Tres Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
 130 VILLAFLOR CHARITY D.  BS Business Management  B-4, L-5, S-10, P-1, Brgy. Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
 131 VITOBINA IAN EFRAME A.  BS Hospitality Management  Amaya I, Tanza, Cavite
 132 VOLANTE ROSE ANN G.  BSE major in English  B-6, L-16, P-1, S-8, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 133 YAÑEZ BRIX AUBREY C.  BS Hospitality Management  B-13, L-6, S-23, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 134 YNOPIA ELMER G.  BSE major in Mathematics  B-11, L-13, P-3A, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite


 Prepared by:  Reviewed by:



 CHARLENE L. DELAS ALAS  NOEMI A. PERIDA
 Registrar Aide  Campus Registrar


 Noted by:



 GIL D. RAMOS
 Campus Administrator






























                                                                Page 4 of 4]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                                             Tanza Campus
                                                                         Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                               ( 414-3979
                                                                               www.cvsu.edu.ph



                                                                          LIST OF GRADUATES
                                                                   FIRST SEMESTER AY, 2021 - 2022

          No.                    Name                                        Course/Program                                          Address
                                                          Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in    L-14, B-14, S-16, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           1   BAYONAS, ERICSON C.
                                                          Marketing Management                                   Cavite
                                                          Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
           2   BOMBON, ROWENA I.                                                                                 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                          Marketing Management
                                                          Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in    B-19, L-14, P-3B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           3   LABADAN, IVIE ROSE L.
                                                          Marketing Management                                   Tanza, Cavite
                                                          Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
           4   LORIO, MARY JANE D.                                                                               Grandiosa Village, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                          Marketing Management
                                                          Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
           5   MAYORMITA, ROZEL C.                                                                               Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                          Marketing Management
                                                          Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in    B-12, L-31, P-1, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           6   TADEO, JOHN PAUL
                                                          Marketing Management                                   Tanza, Cavite
           7   FRANCISCO, MA. PAULA T.                    Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English       Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-73, L-5, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
           8   NAMOR, PATRICIA G.                         Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-13, L-11, S-15, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           9   PADASAS, MAE ANN G.                        Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-80, L-7, P-1A, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           10 APOLINARIO, LADY CAMILLE C.                 Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
           11 CASTILLO, GERLIE M.                         Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics   Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite





                                                                                                                                                 Page 1 of 2]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza Campus
 Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 ( 414-3979
 www.cvsu.edu.ph



 LIST OF GRADUATES
 FIRST SEMESTER AY, 2021 - 2022

 No.   Name  Course/Program                     Address
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   L-14, B-14, S-16, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 1  BAYONAS, ERICSON C.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 2  BOMBON, ROWENA I.        Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-19, L-14, P-3B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 3  LABADAN, IVIE ROSE L.
 Marketing Management        Tanza, Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 4  LORIO, MARY JANE D.      Grandiosa Village, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 5  MAYORMITA, ROZEL C.      Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-12, L-31, P-1, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 6  TADEO, JOHN PAUL
 Marketing Management        Tanza, Cavite
 7  FRANCISCO, MA. PAULA T.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                             B-73, L-5, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 8  NAMOR, PATRICIA G.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Cavite
                             B-13, L-11, S-15, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 9  PADASAS, MAE ANN G.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Cavite
                             B-80, L-7, P-1A, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 10 APOLINARIO, LADY CAMILLE C.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                             Tanza, Cavite
 11 CASTILLO, GERLIE M.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite





                                                             Page 1 of 2]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[B-13, L-6, S-11, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           12 DELOS SANTOS, JARED B.                      Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-11, L-3, San Lorenzo Ruiz I, Dasmariñas City,
           13 JULIANES, SHERLIBETH M.                     Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-26, L-10, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           14 PANES, HANA NICOLE S.                       Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite


          Prepared by:                                                                           Reviewed by:



          CHARLENE L. DELAS ALAS                                                                 NOEMI A. PERIDA
          Registrar Aide                                                                         Campus Registrar



          Noted by:



          GIL D. RAMOS
          Campus Administrator





























                                                                                                                                                 Page 2 of 2]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[B-13, L-6, S-11, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 12 DELOS SANTOS, JARED B.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                             Cavite
                             B-11, L-3, San Lorenzo Ruiz I, Dasmariñas City,
 13 JULIANES, SHERLIBETH M.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                             Cavite
                             B-26, L-10, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 14 PANES, HANA NICOLE S.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                             Tanza, Cavite


 Prepared by:  Reviewed by:



 CHARLENE L. DELAS ALAS  NOEMI A. PERIDA
 Registrar Aide  Campus Registrar



 Noted by:



 GIL D. RAMOS
 Campus Administrator





























                                                             Page 2 of 2]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                        Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                                                 ( 414-3979 ǀ  ( 410-5247 ǀ  (437-0693
                                                                            www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                                             Tanza Campus


                                                                          LIST OF GRADUATES
                                                                              AY 2019 - 2020


           No.                   Name                                       Course/Program                                          Address
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-73, L-21, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta I,
            1   COMODAS, JENNY V.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-15, L-18, Carissa Homes, P-2, Bagtas,
            2   COMPUESTO, RINA D.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
            3   DALAURAO, DANILO F.                                                                              Carissa Homes, Punta I, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Marketing Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
            4   EGAY, JOYCE ANGELIE N.                                                                           Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Marketing Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
            5   GANTALA, JOHN BERNARD C.                                                                         Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Marketing Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
            6   HOBANIL, MARVIN G.                                                                               Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Marketing Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
            7   IGMASIN, MA. RIZA O.                                                                             Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Marketing Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
            8   PADOGINOG, RICHELLE JOY F.                                                                       Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Marketing Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     P-2, Pabahay, B-7, L-17, S-19, Bagtas, Tanza,
            9   PADOGINOG, VICTOR JR.  A.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
           10 TURCATO, ANTONETH R.                                                                               Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Marketing Management
                                                                                                                 430 First St., CS Fojas Subd., Daang Amaya II,
           11 ABARRO, RHONIEL ANTHONY H.                 Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
           12 SORIANO, MELANDRO F.                       Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English        L-21, B-4, Amor Ville, Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite




                                                                                                                                                 Page 1 of 4]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
 ( 414-3979 ǀ  ( 410-5247 ǀ  (437-0693
 www.cvsu.edu.ph


 Tanza Campus


 LIST OF GRADUATES
  AY 2019 - 2020


 No.   Name  Course/Program                     Address
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-73, L-21, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta I,
 1  COMODAS, JENNY V.
 Marketing Management        Tanza, Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-15, L-18, Carissa Homes, P-2, Bagtas,
 2  COMPUESTO, RINA D.
 Marketing Management        Tanza, Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 3  DALAURAO, DANILO F.      Carissa Homes, Punta I, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 4  EGAY, JOYCE ANGELIE N.   Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 5  GANTALA, JOHN BERNARD C.  Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 6  HOBANIL, MARVIN G.       Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 7  IGMASIN, MA. RIZA O.     Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 8  PADOGINOG, RICHELLE JOY F.  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   P-2, Pabahay, B-7, L-17, S-19, Bagtas, Tanza,
 9  PADOGINOG, VICTOR JR.  A.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 10 TURCATO, ANTONETH R.     Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
                             430 First St., CS Fojas Subd., Daang Amaya II,
 11 ABARRO, RHONIEL ANTHONY H.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Tanza, Cavite
 12 SORIANO, MELANDRO F.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English  L-21, B-4, Amor Ville, Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite




                                                             Page 1 of 4]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[B-12, L-4, P-1A, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           13 VARGAS, IRISH ANGEL D.                     Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-3, L-4, S-30, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           14 PENES, MARIELLE SHEYANNE A.                Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-10, L-11, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           15 ROMERO, ELLA MAE D.                        Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                                                                                                                 Cavite
           16 BARONDA, JUAN CARLO M.                     Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           131 Retiree Village 1, Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite

                                                                                                                 B-141, L-38, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta 1,
           17 BUITRE, NIKEE MAE                          Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
           18 CAADLAWON, CONSTANCIO II B.                Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           B-25, L-8, P-6, Carissa, Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite

           19 DULLANO, HANNAH GAY D.                     Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

                                                                                                                 P-3, B-17, L-19, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           20 ESCARDA, MIA D.                            Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-27, L-2, P-3B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           21 GRAGASIN, APPLE S.                         Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
           22 OPON, MARWIN P.                            Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           Villa Juanita, Sahud-Ulan, Tanza, Cavite

                                                                                                                 S-32, B-2, L-8, Belleview Meadows, Bagtas,
           23 PESASICO, SIEGFRED JR. B.                  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
           24 SADAGNOT, MARIZTELA H.                     Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-9, L-39, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
           25 SALAZAR, GLENN HUBERT O.                   Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-41, L-23 Sunrise Place, Tres Cruses, Tanza,
           26 ALFARO, ROCKY NEIL E.                      Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-3, L-5, P-3, Brgy. Aguado, Trece Martires
           27 BARRISO, CHRISTIAN J.                      Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 City, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-15, L-16, S-15, P-2, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza,
           28 BASA, MARY JOY B.                          Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-11, L-4, S-19, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           29 BASCO, DANICA ANNA Q.                      Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-33, L-24 Sunrise Place P-2, Brgy. Tres
           30 BERNALES, IZZA C.                          Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-1, L-1, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           31 CONDES, JASMINE E.                         Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite


                                                                                                                                                 Page 2 of 4]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[B-12, L-4, P-1A, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 13 VARGAS, IRISH ANGEL D.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Tanza, Cavite
                             B-3, L-4, S-30, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 14 PENES, MARIELLE SHEYANNE A.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                             Cavite
                             B-10, L-11, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 15 ROMERO, ELLA MAE D.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics
                             Cavite
 16 BARONDA, JUAN CARLO M.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  131 Retiree Village 1, Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite

                             B-141, L-38, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta 1,
 17 BUITRE, NIKEE MAE  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Tanza, Cavite
 18 CAADLAWON, CONSTANCIO II B.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  B-25, L-8, P-6, Carissa, Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite

 19 DULLANO, HANNAH GAY D.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

                             P-3, B-17, L-19, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 20 ESCARDA, MIA D.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Tanza, Cavite
                             B-27, L-2, P-3B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 21 GRAGASIN, APPLE S.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Tanza, Cavite
 22 OPON, MARWIN P.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  Villa Juanita, Sahud-Ulan, Tanza, Cavite

                             S-32, B-2, L-8, Belleview Meadows, Bagtas,
 23 PESASICO, SIEGFRED JR. B.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Tanza, Cavite
 24 SADAGNOT, MARIZTELA H.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                             B-9, L-39, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 25 SALAZAR, GLENN HUBERT O.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-41, L-23 Sunrise Place, Tres Cruses, Tanza,
 26 ALFARO, ROCKY NEIL E.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
                             B-3, L-5, P-3, Brgy. Aguado, Trece Martires
 27 BARRISO, CHRISTIAN J.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             City, Cavite
                             B-15, L-16, S-15, P-2, Brgy. Bagtas, Tanza,
 28 BASA, MARY JOY B.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
                             B-11, L-4, S-19, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 29 BASCO, DANICA ANNA Q.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
                             B-33, L-24 Sunrise Place P-2, Brgy. Tres
 30 BERNALES, IZZA C.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cruses, Tanza, Cavite
                             B-1, L-1, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 31 CONDES, JASMINE E.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite


                                                             Page 2 of 4]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[B-4, L-4, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           32 CUEVA, MARK ANTHONY D.                     Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-13, L-6, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           33 CUPINO, ANGELIKA M.                        Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
           34 ECLEONEL, JESSICA N.                       Diploma in Hospitality Management                       Remulla Drive, Sahud-Ulan, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-23, L-8, Grandiosa Subd., Punta 1, Tanza,
           35 FRESADO, JENNY D.                          Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite

           36 GAMUYAO, FELIPE JR. A.                     Diploma in Hospitality Management                       Sitio Burol, Tejeros Convention, Rosario, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-3, L-23, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           37 GEAMAL, MARY ANNE O.                       Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-12, L-7, P-2, S-16, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           38 IGNACIO, CRISTINA P.                       Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-7, L-5, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           39 ILAGAN, MABELAINE M.                       Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
           40 MANGUIAT, AIRA KLARISSE H.                 Diploma in Hospitality Management                       B-01, L-107, Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite

           41 MARCELINO, LOVELYN V.                      Diploma in Hospitality Management                       Brgy. Saluysoy, Trece Martires City, Cavite

           42 MARQUEZ, EMIE ROSE C.                      Diploma in Hospitality Management                       Brgy. Punta I, Tanza, Cavite


           43 MURALLOS, MANILYN O.                       Diploma in Hospitality Management                       P-2, Carissa Homes, Tanza, Cavite

           44 OROG, JAMES M.                             Diploma in Hospitality Management                       Langkaan II, FCIE, Dasmariñas City, Cavite

           45 PASCO, JAMAICA Q.                          Diploma in Hospitality Management                       275 Tramo, Amaya I, Tanza, Cavite


           46 PLACEROS, AN MARIE B.                      Diploma in Hospitality Management                       B-30, L-57, P-7, Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-173, L-3, Bixbite St., Grand Cedar Crest Antel
           47 REDUBLA, NICOLE C.                         Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Grand Village, Bacao II, General Trias, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-12, L-7, P-2, S-16, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           48 REYES, SHARINE ANGELU I.                   Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-3, L-9, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           49 ROSAS, MARIEL G.                           Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 Purok I, Brgy. Panungyanan, General Trias,
           50 SALVADOR, JAYRALD C.                       Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Cavite


                                                                                                                                                 Page 3 of 4]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[B-4, L-4, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 32 CUEVA, MARK ANTHONY D.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
                             B-13, L-6, S-31, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 33 CUPINO, ANGELIKA M.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
 34 ECLEONEL, JESSICA N.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Remulla Drive, Sahud-Ulan, Tanza, Cavite
                             B-23, L-8, Grandiosa Subd., Punta 1, Tanza,
 35 FRESADO, JENNY D.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite

 36 GAMUYAO, FELIPE JR. A.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Sitio Burol, Tejeros Convention, Rosario, Cavite
                             B-3, L-23, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 37 GEAMAL, MARY ANNE O.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
                             B-12, L-7, P-2, S-16, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 38 IGNACIO, CRISTINA P.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
                             B-7, L-5, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 39 ILAGAN, MABELAINE M.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
 40 MANGUIAT, AIRA KLARISSE H.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  B-01, L-107, Mulawin, Tanza, Cavite

 41 MARCELINO, LOVELYN V.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Brgy. Saluysoy, Trece Martires City, Cavite

 42 MARQUEZ, EMIE ROSE C.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Brgy. Punta I, Tanza, Cavite


 43 MURALLOS, MANILYN O.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  P-2, Carissa Homes, Tanza, Cavite

 44 OROG, JAMES M.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Langkaan II, FCIE, Dasmariñas City, Cavite

 45 PASCO, JAMAICA Q.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  275 Tramo, Amaya I, Tanza, Cavite


 46 PLACEROS, AN MARIE B.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  B-30, L-57, P-7, Punta 1, Tanza, Cavite
                             B-173, L-3, Bixbite St., Grand Cedar Crest Antel
 47 REDUBLA, NICOLE C.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Grand Village, Bacao II, General Trias, Cavite
                             B-12, L-7, P-2, S-16, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 48 REYES, SHARINE ANGELU I.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
                             B-3, L-9, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 49 ROSAS, MARIEL G.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite
                             Purok I, Brgy. Panungyanan, General Trias,
 50 SALVADOR, JAYRALD C.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Cavite


                                                             Page 3 of 4]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[51 SANCHEZ, GIRLIE L.                         Diploma in Hospitality Management                       Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite

           52 SOSA, JESICA M.                            Diploma in Hospitality Management                       347 Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite

           53 TABORNAL, AERON T.                         Diploma in Hospitality Management                       Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-12, L-60, Heart Foundation, Sanja Mayor,
           54 TAMIO, RAVEN D.                            Diploma in Hospitality Management
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite

           55 VITOBINA, IAN EFRAME A.                    Diploma in Hospitality Management                       Amaya I, Tanza, Cavite




          Prepared by:                                                                           Reviewed by:



          NOEMI A. PERIDA                                                                        MARY ANN L. ANONAS
          Registrar Aide                                                                         Campus Registrar



          Noted by:



          NOEL A. SEDIGO
          Campus Administrator
























                                                                                                                                                 Page 4 of 4]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[51 SANCHEZ, GIRLIE L.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite

 52 SOSA, JESICA M.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  347 Sanja Mayor, Tanza, Cavite

 53 TABORNAL, AERON T.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite
                             B-12, L-60, Heart Foundation, Sanja Mayor,
 54 TAMIO, RAVEN D.  Diploma in Hospitality Management
                             Tanza, Cavite

 55 VITOBINA, IAN EFRAME A.  Diploma in Hospitality Management  Amaya I, Tanza, Cavite




 Prepared by:  Reviewed by:



 NOEMI A. PERIDA  MARY ANN L. ANONAS
 Registrar Aide  Campus Registrar



 Noted by:



 NOEL A. SEDIGO
 Campus Administrator
























                                                             Page 4 of 4]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
                                                                 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
                                                        Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
                                                                 ( 414-3979 ǀ  ( 410-5247 ǀ  (437-0693
                                                                            www.cvsu.edu.ph


                                                                             Tanza Campus


                                                                          LIST OF GRADUATES
                                                                             AY 2018 - 2019


           No.                   Name                                       Course/Program                                          Address
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     Paradahan II, P-1, B-9, L-8, S-12, Pabahay
            1   BEATO, JESSUS L.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    2000, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-3, L-80, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
            2   CATABAY,  JANNAH NINA C.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-6, L-11, P-1, Borland, Sanja Mayor, Tanza,
            3   CORTEZ, ABEGAIL P.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-3, L-6, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
            4   CRUZ, MARIANE JOYCE H.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-9, L-2, P-2, S-20, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
            5   FRANCISCO, LOVELY JOY D.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     P-1, S-6, B-8, L-8, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
            6   LUMANTAD, GERBY G.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-40, L-20, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
            7   MACABENTA, RONIELA MARIMAR F.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-12, L-21, S-23, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
            8   MENDOZA, ABIGAIL JOY S.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in     B-11, L-6, S-20, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
            9   PACAMPARRA, JOLINA P.
                                                         Marketing Management                                    Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
           10 TOMALE, ROSELYN R.                                                                                 B-10, L-8, S-31, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Marketing Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant
           11 ABANES, CRISELDA JEAN B.                                                                           B-8, L-2, S-24, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant             B-8, L-6, S-20, P-2 Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           12 ARENAS, JESSIELYN L.
                                                         Management                                              Cavite



                                                                                                                                                 Page 1 of 4]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Republic of the Philippines
 CAVITE STATE UNIVERSITY
 Tanza ǀ Trece Martires City ǀ Gen. Trias City Campus
 ( 414-3979 ǀ  ( 410-5247 ǀ  (437-0693
 www.cvsu.edu.ph


 Tanza Campus


 LIST OF GRADUATES
 AY 2018 - 2019


 No.   Name  Course/Program                     Address
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   Paradahan II, P-1, B-9, L-8, S-12, Pabahay
 1  BEATO, JESSUS L.
 Marketing Management        2000, Tanza, Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-3, L-80, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 2  CATABAY,  JANNAH NINA C.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-6, L-11, P-1, Borland, Sanja Mayor, Tanza,
 3  CORTEZ, ABEGAIL P.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-3, L-6, S-17, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 4  CRUZ, MARIANE JOYCE H.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-9, L-2, P-2, S-20, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 5  FRANCISCO, LOVELY JOY D.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   P-1, S-6, B-8, L-8, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 6  LUMANTAD, GERBY G.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-40, L-20, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 7  MACABENTA, RONIELA MARIMAR F.
 Marketing Management        Tanza, Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-12, L-21, S-23, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 8  MENDOZA, ABIGAIL JOY S.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in   B-11, L-6, S-20, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 9  PACAMPARRA, JOLINA P.
 Marketing Management        Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Business Management major in
 10 TOMALE, ROSELYN R.       B-10, L-8, S-31, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Marketing Management
 Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant
 11 ABANES, CRISELDA JEAN B.  B-8, L-2, S-24, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Management
 Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant   B-8, L-6, S-20, P-2 Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 12 ARENAS, JESSIELYN L.
 Management                  Cavite



                                                             Page 1 of 4]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant
           13 CLORES, DINDO A.                                                                                   P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant             B-1, L-25, S-33, Belleview Meadows, Bagtas,
           14 DIAZ, JANELLA M.
                                                         Management                                              Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant
           15 HONORICA, ROJEA                                                                                    Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Management
                                                         Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant
           16 MARQUEZ, MERYLLE G.                                                                                B-1, L-1, S-20, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                         Management
                                                                                                                 B-7, L-6, S-1, P-1 Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           17 ARIMADO, MAYZEL R.                         Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-6, L-12, P-5, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
           18 BARRIDO, NICEL P.                          Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 S-15, B-3, L-28, P-3, Belvedere, Pasong
           19 CAMPOS, JAYCEE V.                          Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-3, L-1, S-5, P-7, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas,
           20 CAPUZ, LEE ROBIN A.                        Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 P-1, S-8, B-8, L-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           21 CORDERO, MARK ALQUIN C.                    Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-7, L-5, S-18, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           22 CURIOSO, JEFFREY S.                        Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
           23 DELOS SANTOS, CHARLON JAKE L.              Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           P-2, Pabahay Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite


           24 EJORCADAS, ADRIANE Z.                      Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-136, L-34, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta 1,
           25 EUSOYA, MA. JESSICA S.                     Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
           26 FAUNI, CHARLES D.                          Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           B-2, L-4, S-28, Pabahay, Tanza, Cavite

                                                                                                                 B-4, L-12, S-20, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           27 GADO,  PATRICK M.                          Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-3, L-9, S-22, P-2, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas,
           28 GUTANG, JASMIN S.                          Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-13, L-03, S-15, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           29 IMUS, CHARRYL B.                           Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-3, L-1, S-20, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           30 JAMON, JAY MARK P.                         Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
           31 LIGAN, JONA R.                             Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           Brgy. Sapang I, Ternate, Cavite



                                                                                                                                                 Page 2 of 4]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant
 13 CLORES, DINDO A.         P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Management
 Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant   B-1, L-25, S-33, Belleview Meadows, Bagtas,
 14 DIAZ, JANELLA M.
 Management                  Tanza, Cavite
 Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant
 15 HONORICA, ROJEA          Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Management
 Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant
 16 MARQUEZ, MERYLLE G.      B-1, L-1, S-20, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
 Management
                             B-7, L-6, S-1, P-1 Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 17 ARIMADO, MAYZEL R.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-6, L-12, P-5, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 18 BARRIDO, NICEL P.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             S-15, B-3, L-28, P-3, Belvedere, Pasong
 19 CAMPOS, JAYCEE V.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Kawayan II, General Trias, Cavite
                             B-3, L-1, S-5, P-7, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas,
 20 CAPUZ, LEE ROBIN A.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Tanza, Cavite
                             P-1, S-8, B-8, L-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 21 CORDERO, MARK ALQUIN C.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-7, L-5, S-18, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 22 CURIOSO, JEFFREY S.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
 23 DELOS SANTOS, CHARLON JAKE L.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  P-2, Pabahay Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite


 24 EJORCADAS, ADRIANE Z.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                             B-136, L-34, P-7, Carissa Homes, Punta 1,
 25 EUSOYA, MA. JESSICA S.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Tanza, Cavite
 26 FAUNI, CHARLES D.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  B-2, L-4, S-28, Pabahay, Tanza, Cavite

                             B-4, L-12, S-20, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 27 GADO,  PATRICK M.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-3, L-9, S-22, P-2, Pabahay 2000, Bagtas,
 28 GUTANG, JASMIN S.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Tanza, Cavite
                             B-13, L-03, S-15, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 29 IMUS, CHARRYL B.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-3, L-1, S-20, P-2, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 30 JAMON, JAY MARK P.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
 31 LIGAN, JONA R.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  Brgy. Sapang I, Ternate, Cavite



                                                             Page 2 of 4]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[32 MATEO, JERRIK E.                           Bachelor of Science in Information Technology           Belleview, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-7, L-15, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           33 MENESE, PRENSLY R.                         Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-21, L-4, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
           34 MIADO, ELMER S.                            Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-14, L-11, S-30, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           35 PEREZ, CHRISTIAN F.                        Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 S-22, B-11, L-12, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           36 RAMIREZ, NELSON JR. M                      Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-43, L-5, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
           37 RIVERA, FRANKCO LUIS A.                    Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-14, L-1, S-30, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
           38 SAGDULLAS, ARTENIAN J.                     Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-7, L-8, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
           39 SAGER, ALJON A.                            Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-27, L-29, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           40 TEJADA,  APOLLO RAFAEL                     Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-35, L-23, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
           41 BALIOS, RECEL M.                           Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-7, L-7, P-1B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
           42 BANATE, SHARMAINE M.                       Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-7, L-7, P-1B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
           43 BANATE, SHEENA M.                          Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-2, L-14, S-33, Bellview Meadows, Bagtas,
           44 BORCES, JEAN NICOLE A.                     Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Tanza, Cavite
                                                                                                                 B-14, L-8, Grandiosa Lane, Punta I, Tanza,
           45 DE DIOS, DANIEL DAVID O.                   Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                                                                                                                 Cavite
           46 FULAY, MARYBELLE B.                        Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English        B-11, L-22, P-5, Carissa, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

           47 GARCIA, IVY JOYCE D.                       Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English        Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

           48 GREFALDEO, ARJHANE M.                      Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English        B-1, L-2, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Cavite


           49 JAZMINES, CHEEVAH ADARINE J.               Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English        Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite

           50 MONTECALVO, GEL JOHN A.                    Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English        Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite



                                                                                                                                                 Page 3 of 4]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[32 MATEO, JERRIK E.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology  Belleview, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite
                             B-7, L-15, S-7, P-1, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 33 MENESE, PRENSLY R.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-21, L-4, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 34 MIADO, ELMER S.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-14, L-11, S-30, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 35 PEREZ, CHRISTIAN F.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             S-22, B-11, L-12, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 36 RAMIREZ, NELSON JR. M  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-43, L-5, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 37 RIVERA, FRANKCO LUIS A.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-14, L-1, S-30, P-3, Pabahay, Bagtas, Tanza,
 38 SAGDULLAS, ARTENIAN J.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-7, L-8, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 39 SAGER, ALJON A.  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Cavite
                             B-27, L-29, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 40 TEJADA,  APOLLO RAFAEL  Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
                             Tanza, Cavite
                             B-35, L-23, P-3, Carissa Homes, Bagtas,
 41 BALIOS, RECEL M.   Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Tanza, Cavite
                             B-7, L-7, P-1B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 42 BANATE, SHARMAINE M.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Cavite
                             B-7, L-7, P-1B, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza,
 43 BANATE, SHEENA M.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Cavite
                             B-2, L-14, S-33, Bellview Meadows, Bagtas,
 44 BORCES, JEAN NICOLE A.   Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Tanza, Cavite
                             B-14, L-8, Grandiosa Lane, Punta I, Tanza,
 45 DE DIOS, DANIEL DAVID O.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English
                             Cavite
 46 FULAY, MARYBELLE B.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English  B-11, L-22, P-5, Carissa, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

 47 GARCIA, IVY JOYCE D.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

 48 GREFALDEO, ARJHANE M.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English  B-1, L-2, P-2, Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Cavite


 49 JAZMINES, CHEEVAH ADARINE J.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English  Paradahan II, Tanza, Cavite

 50 MONTECALVO, GEL JOHN A.   Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English  Carissa Homes, Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite



                                                             Page 3 of 4]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[51 ORTIZ, AMARAH F.                           Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English        Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

           52 PRADILLA, AILYN C.                         Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics    Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite




          Prepared by:                                                                           Reviewed by:



          NOEMI A. PERIDA                                                                        MARY ANN L. ANONAS
          Registrar Aide                                                                         Campus Registrar



          Noted by:



          NOEL A. SEDIGO
          Campus Administrator


































                                                                                                                                                 Page 4 of 4]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[51 ORTIZ, AMARAH F.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite

 52 PRADILLA, AILYN C.  Bachelor of Secondary Education major in Mathematics  Bagtas, Tanza, Cavite




 Prepared by:  Reviewed by:



 NOEMI A. PERIDA  MARY ANN L. ANONAS
 Registrar Aide  Campus Registrar



 Noted by:



 NOEL A. SEDIGO
 Campus Administrator


































                                                             Page 4 of 4]]></page></pages></Search>